<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:09:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.4</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Ethereum (ETH) Price Bounces Bullishly: Back to Uptrend Territory?</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/eth-price-bounces-bullish-uptrend/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan James]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum (ETH) Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethereum's recent bounce at $2,867 hints at a potential correction conclusion. However, uncertainty looms over its future trajectory amid the ongoing market turbulence.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/eth-price-bounces-bullish-uptrend/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Bounces Bullishly: Back to Uptrend Territory?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The Ethereum (ETH) price has recently found support at the 0.382 Fibonacci level, around $2,867, prompting a bullish rebound. This development raises the question: Could this mark the conclusion of the correction?</strong></p>



<p>ETH has undergone a pronounced corrective phase over the past few weeks. However, the recent bounce from significant support levels suggests a potential reversal in this trend.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ethereum-s-quick-recovery-from-0-382-fib-support-at-2-867">Ethereum&#8217;s Quick Recovery from 0.382 Fib Support at $2,867</h2>



<p>The Ethereum price recently rebounded from the 0.382 Fibonacci support level around $2,867. After an initial bounce, it retraced back to this support level. However, Ethereum experienced a sustained upward trajectory during the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/eth-price-forecast-correction-decline-expected/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subsequent rebound over several days</a>.</p>



<p>Ethereum is encountering significant resistance at the 50-day <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/moving-averages-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Exponential Moving Average</a> (EMA), around $3,277. Furthermore, notable Fibonacci resistance levels lie at approximately $3,320 and $3,650. It&#8217;s important to note that the corrective phase will likely conclude upon surpassing the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/eth-hodling-to-trigger-rally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">golden ratio resistance at around $3,650</a>.</p>



<p>Breaking out of the parallel descending channel would signal a bullish trend reversal for Ethereum. In such a scenario, Ethereum could potentially target or surpass its previous high of around $4,095.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/ethereum-restaking-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum Restaking: What Is It And How Does It Work?</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="850" height="567" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-135.png" alt="Ethereum (ETH/USD) Price Chart. " class="wp-image-504437" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-135.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-135-360x240.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-135-768x512.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-135-150x100.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ethereum (ETH/USD) Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ETHUSD/?exchange=BITSTAMP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Moreover, the daily chart&#8217;s EMAs continue to exhibit a golden crossover, indicative of a bullish trend in the short to medium term. Additionally, the bullish crossover of the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/moving-averages-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Moving Average Convergence/Divergence indicator</a> (MACD) lines and the upward movement of the MACD histogram in recent days further support the bullish outlook.</p>



<p>However, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/rsi-indicator/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Relative Strength Index</a> (RSI) remains neutral, providing no indication of bullish or bearish momentum.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ethereum-faces-death-cross-on-4-hour-chart">Ethereum Faces Death Cross on 4-Hour Chart</h2>



<p>In Ethereum&#8217;s 4-hour chart, a death cross materialized recently, solidifying the short-term bearish sentiment. However, if Ethereum sustains its upward momentum and surpasses the 0.382 Fibonacci resistance level around $3,320, it could prompt the EMAs to undergo a golden crossover.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s32698.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ETHUSD_2024-04-24_10-56-08_038f9-850x567.png" alt="ETH Chart Analysis BeInCrypto" class="wp-image-168653"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ethereum (ETH/USD) Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ETHUSD/?exchange=BITSTAMP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Such a development would signal a return to a bullish trend in the short term. Additionally, current indicators lean towards a bullish outlook. </p>



<p>The MACD histogram is on an upward trajectory, accompanied by the bullish crossover of the MACD lines, while the RSI remains in neutral territory.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-macd-lines-cross-bearishly-on-weekly-chart">MACD Lines Cross Bearishly on Weekly Chart</h2>



<p>In Ethereum&#8217;s weekly chart, the recent bearish crossover of the MACD lines and the downward trend of the MACD histogram over the past few weeks suggest a prevailing bearish sentiment.</p>



<p>Despite Ethereum&#8217;s decline of approximately 30.5% from its peak seven weeks ago, the recent bounce from the 0.382 Fibonacci support level around $2,867 has led to a recovery of approximately 15%.</p>



<p>The ongoing presence of bullish confirmation from the EMAs and the neutral stance of the RSI indicates a somewhat optimistic outlook for Ethereum at present.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s32698.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ETHUSD_2024-04-24_10-56-37_06518-850x567.png" alt="ETH Chart Analysis BeInCrypto" class="wp-image-168654"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ethereum (ETH/USD) Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ETHUSD/?exchange=BITSTAMP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Further upward movement and price recovery for Ethereum seems plausible. However, a significant bullish signal would only manifest if <a href="https://beincrypto.com/eth-re-enters-rally-trigger-zone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum surpasses the golden ratio</a> at approximately $3,650.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ethereum-slides-23-7-analysis-of-this-month-s-drop">Ethereum Slides 23.7%: Analysis of This Month&#8217;s Drop</h2>



<p>So far this month, Ethereum has experienced a decline of approximately 23.7%, which may mark the extent of its correction. Additionally, the MACD indicators in the monthly chart do not indicate any bearish signals.</p>



<p>Rather, the MACD lines continue to maintain a bullish stance, while the MACD histogram shows upward momentum, and the RSI remains within neutral territory. In the medium term, should Ethereum breach the 0.382 Fibonacci support level, the critical golden ratio support is anticipated to be around $2,050.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s32698.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ETHUSD_2024-04-24_10-57-16_1e2cc-850x567.png" alt="ETH Chart Analysis BeInCrypto" class="wp-image-168655"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ethereum (ETH/USD) Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ETHUSD/?exchange=BITSTAMP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Sustaining Ethereum above this level is crucial for maintaining the bullish trajectory. However, if Ethereum were to dip below this level, significant support would be expected to materialize, potentially at the 50-month EMA of around $1,860.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ethereum-vs-bitcoin-eth-s-persistent-downward-trend">Ethereum vs. Bitcoin: ETH&#8217;s Persistent Downward Trend</h2>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-eth-bitcoin-btc-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Against Bitcoin</a>, Ethereum&#8217;s price trend remains bearish, with the cryptocurrency finding notable support at approximately 0.043 BTC. Ethereum is currently within a 3.5% range of this crucial support level. Moreover, the MACD histogram is displaying a downward trend this month.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/ethereum-price-prediction/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Prediction 2024/2025/2030</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s32698.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ETHBTC_2024-04-24_10-57-48_04d72-850x567.png" alt="Ethereum (ETH/BTC) Price Chart. " class="wp-image-168656"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ethereum (ETH/BTC) Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ETHBTC/?exchange=BINANCE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>With the MACD lines already in a bearish cross and the RSI approaching oversold territory, Ethereum&#8217;s potential for a bullish rebound at the golden ratio support around 0.043 BTC is promising. Ethereum will likely face resistance at the 50-month EMA at approximately 0.05614 BTC if it achieves this.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/eth-price-bounces-bullish-uptrend/">Ethereum (ETH) Price Bounces Bullishly: Back to Uptrend Territory?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_Ethereum_ETH_4-covers_bullish.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_Ethereum_ETH_4-covers_bullish.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons Why SpaceCatch Is the Popular Game of 2024</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/5-reasons-why-spacecatch-is-one-of-the-popular-game-of-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What do you say about a game that brings you one step closer to your fitness goal while having lots of fun and reaping in-game rewards that have real-world value? It&#8217;s not possible, you might be thinking, and we say that it&#8217;s possible, and even more, the game is up and running! Moreover, as you &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/5-reasons-why-spacecatch-is-one-of-the-popular-game-of-2024/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/5-reasons-why-spacecatch-is-one-of-the-popular-game-of-2024/">5 Reasons Why SpaceCatch Is the Popular Game of 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>What do you say about a game that brings you one step closer to your fitness goal while having lots of fun and reaping in-game rewards that have real-world value?</strong></p>



<p><em>It&#8217;s not possible</em>, you might be thinking, and we say that it&#8217;s possible, and even more, the game is up and running! Moreover, as you <a href="https://spacecatch.io/try-the-game" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">enroll and become the Metaverse catcher</a>, you can contribute to the game&#8217;s development.</p>



<p><a href="https://spacecatch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SpaceCatch</a> is the comprehensive blockchain and Web3 game that uses the latest and most advanced technologies to offer you a unique adventure with a paramount mission while joining a vibrant and extensive community.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-reasons">Reasons</h2>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-1-the-ultimate-fight-and-an-unforgettable-tale"><strong>1. The Ultimate Fight and an Unforgettable Tale</strong></h4>



<p>As the Earth is in danger of greedy aliens aiming to take the planet by storm, Metaverse catchers must be the heroes of this story and save us all from this invasion.</p>



<p>Users must be creative, young catcher, as these aliens are sneaky, and some missions are enigmatic, but cooperation is vital in this mysterious world. So, be sure to step up your game, build a hero, and defeat them all!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-2-advanced-technologies-for-all-catchers"><strong>2. Advanced Technologies for All Catchers</strong></h4>



<p>There&#8217;s no need to be scared, as SpaceCatch equips its catchers with some of advanced technologies to ensure a fair battle, especially when the aliens are AI-powered.</p>



<p>So, besides having the most thrilling experience of your life, you also level up and reach new ground. Let&#8217;s see what tech SpaceCatch embodies.</p>



<p>First, SpaceCatch uses Move-to-Earn and Play-to-Earn mechanics to get you moving out of your couch. Moreover, the entire gameplay and progress are fueled by NFT boosters, which can be acquired by doing free physical activity or purchasing them from other players.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you can see, you can either gather them for you and make a profit or buy them directly from other catchers.</p>



<p>Once you get outside, the Augmented and Virtual Reality technologies combine to seamlessly blend exterior reality with gameplay directly on your iOS or Android phone.</p>



<p>As a side note, SpaceCatch caters to both outdoor and indoor, as it features small indoor mini-games and training areas. Yet, it&#8217;s best to take your battles outside for big commissions.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-3-sustainable-tokenomics"><strong>3. Sustainable Tokenomics</strong></h4>



<p>Often, we saw other crypto, blockchain, or Web3 games that focus solely on rewarding their players, like that is the only aspect a player is looking for. Indeed, gratification could be the cherry on top, but it&#8217;s worth nothing if the game is unsustainable, which makes the value of that reward equal to nothing.</p>



<p>Therefore, SpaceCatch flips this narrative and caters to deflationary tokenomics, whereby the in-game rewards also have real-world value. Besides this, remember that you can trade or sell the item, so there&#8217;s no need to have double items, which are useless.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-4-true-ownership-makes-spacecatch-go-round"><strong>4. True Ownership Makes SpaceCatch Go Round!</strong></h4>



<p>Since the game integrates Web3 and blockchain features, all players can leverage them to trade, rent, and borrow items from one another, which adds to better ecosystem sustainability and true ownership.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-5-player-driven-economy-nbsp"><strong>5. Player Driven Economy&nbsp;</strong></h4>



<p>As settled, SpaceCatch was created to offer all its catchers more than an immersive game, yet players&#8217; gameplay drives its economy. Therefore, player autonomy and diverse monetization opportunities create an open in-game economy that keeps you all engaged and leads to a thriving community.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-become-the-earth-saviour">Become the Earth Saviour</h2>



<p>As the Public Beta is already launched, you still have time to enroll through the <a href="https://spacecatch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official website</a> while competing against sneaky aliens with a vibrant and eager-to-win community through <a href="https://t.me/spacecatch_io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Telegram</a>, <a href="https://discord.gg/spacecatchers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Discord</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/spacecatch_io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X (Twitter)</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@spacecatch_io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTube</a>, <a href="https://instagram.com/spacecatch_io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Instagram</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/@spacecatch" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Medium</a>, <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/spacecatch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CoinMarketCap</a>, or <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/spacecatch" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CoinGecko</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/5-reasons-why-spacecatch-is-one-of-the-popular-game-of-2024/">5 Reasons Why SpaceCatch Is the Popular Game of 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/2024-04-18-09.20.08-1.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/2024-04-18-09.20.08-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BloFin Sponsors TOKEN2049 Dubai and Celebrates the SideEvent: WhalesNight AfterParty 2024</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/blofin-sponsors-token2049-dubai-and-celebrates-the-sideevent-whalesnight-afterparty-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BloFin, a fastest-growing exchange platform, proudly announces its platinum sponsorship of TOKEN2049 Dubai and its exclusive SideEvent: WhalesNight AfterParty 2024. Following our previous role as the Gold Sponsor at TOKEN2049 Singapore, the BloFin team, now the Platinum Sponsor of TOKEN2049, continues to shine on this stage with its enthusiasm and original dedication to contributing to &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blofin-sponsors-token2049-dubai-and-celebrates-the-sideevent-whalesnight-afterparty-2024/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blofin-sponsors-token2049-dubai-and-celebrates-the-sideevent-whalesnight-afterparty-2024/">BloFin Sponsors TOKEN2049 Dubai and Celebrates the SideEvent: WhalesNight AfterParty 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>BloFin, a fastest-growing exchange platform, proudly announces its platinum sponsorship of TOKEN2049 Dubai and its exclusive SideEvent: WhalesNight AfterParty 2024. </strong></p>



<p>Following our previous role as the Gold Sponsor at TOKEN2049 Singapore, the BloFin team, now the Platinum Sponsor of TOKEN2049, continues to shine on this stage with its enthusiasm and original dedication to contributing to the cryptocurrency industry. </p>



<figure class="overflow-x-auto wp-block-table"><table class="w-full mb-2 table-auto"><tbody><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/mRZlR9GQj4HmfE9EKtFkEPZMcqIGfybJMCINFpis-keorRnexE9auyCtGUOI0CYb_d8wbr1RKJjYYLuNs6qQnZay7-3Xdo837OR_hQXK5-sDJX3mLPE6mXLfGLQcrRV59aubq1SD7ivwfbq0jegSgQ" width="351" height="175"></td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/KUoPYnZSIbk_2VK8zL3Gv5MNL8E-Sj9Fvq0q4mzubUE_ykvPShprrwKKNU-6DACcl8XhLwsGf0hEiGUBqQZ8s3WbSuTsttJ_WMX5i3BDSH0yZwVzQs3BdwBCX2kmY4HKWNvlhUXgopDOAMQfEBBY7A" width="168" height="168"></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>BloFin successfully sponsored TOKEN2049 Dubai, which witnessed an extraordinary gathering of industry leaders, enthusiasts, KOLs, and innovators. Our participation in this prestigious event not only reaffirmed our commitment to fostering innovation within the blockchain ecosystem but also demonstrated our dedication to driving industry development forward.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-an-unforgettable-night-whalesnight-afterparty-2024"><strong>An Unforgettable Night: WhalesNight AfterParty 2024</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/TMxjVnIg_bVFLeOcHv4TmOtc1JagqEXdOSsR1TNtbhIjPyzH3pZcsDbpRSvW2Elrzja-jptH4sTWJW1dKxhSbzJoKMTlsZ8tvfEbaNai3A_JxZ6Kg3Z50oTbzJOHKdcKmsp3wf-qpB3XMe7YBEb6mA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>As part of the conference, BloFin hosted the highly anticipated WhalesNight AfterParty 2024, promising an unforgettable evening of networking and celebration.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-gratitude-in-spotlight-heartfelt-thanks-to-valued-partners-and-media"><strong>Gratitude in Spotlight: Heartfelt Thanks to Valued Partners and Media</strong></h2>



<p>BloFin extends its gratitude to its esteemed media partners, including U.Today, BeInCrypto, CoinTelegraph MENA, and Crypto.news, whose support has been instrumental in promoting this event. Additionally, BloFin appreciates the steadfast support and participation of its significant partners, KOLs, and attendees.</p>



<figure class="overflow-x-auto wp-block-table"><table class="w-full mb-2 table-auto"><tbody><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/x-j8onJoLCmsbenIEV8si9JlZcQyRdj96hv1-1tu0aFiNRZx37Ef668UyFgCNNbQ0aPftiYnVJvmnpRs_srUmOZ3whRF1qYVGKUhts1cCny6sNPXAGXYhSUCgdYtRSjMwSrppYek5W6cq4PE1ZGtoA" width="251" height="122"></td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/xpim3V-FrajjDtv-le8t9WxMzD5Kg-6mD4taTupJwQz2v_7y_ASm-w_lbKcrGt633koSUHdrjCpu_KAWP9UTYC16uAM5T8BcMHApntFJ7G9eIZrkJfMEnd5g9FwO8ocFdt6G8wnuACsvZBjFbTiXYA" width="268" height="123"></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>The Dubai Whales Night offers the BloFin team a valuable opportunity to meet with users and friends. Matt, CEO of BloFin, shared his insights and expressed his excitement at the WhalesNight AfterParty. He stated &#8220;We understand the importance of trust. We will continue to provide our users with safe, reliable, and fast services.&#8221;</p>



<p>As we continue to expand our reach and enhance our offerings, we remain steadfast in our mission to empower individuals and institutions to unlock the full potential of blockchain technology. Together, we embark on an exciting journey towards the future!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-about-blofin"><strong>About BloFin</strong></h2>



<p>As the fastest-growing crypto exchange, BloFin offers premium perps &amp; futures trading services with over 320 USDT-M trading pairs and 100X trading volume. Now, it provides more high-quality products including spot trading, copy trading, earning, API access, and more. Ensuring utmost user fund security, BloFin has partnered with Fireblocks to safeguard users&#8217; assets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blofin-sponsors-token2049-dubai-and-celebrates-the-sideevent-whalesnight-afterparty-2024/">BloFin Sponsors TOKEN2049 Dubai and Celebrates the SideEvent: WhalesNight AfterParty 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/1-Cover.jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="600" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/1-Cover.jpeg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Threats to Block Chinese Banks Globally Could Ease China’s Crypto Ban</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/china-embrace-crypto-us-sanctions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amid US threats to sanction Chinese banks, there's growing speculation that China might relax its crypto ban to maintain financial fluidity.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/china-embrace-crypto-us-sanctions/">US Threats to Block Chinese Banks Globally Could Ease China’s Crypto Ban</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Amid rising geopolitical tensions, the US government is contemplating imposing sanctions on certain Chinese banks. </strong></p>



<p>According to a report by the Wall Street Journal, these measures aim to disconnect these banks from the global financial system. The primary concern is their involvement in facilitating trade that bolsters Russia’s military capabilities against Ukraine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-will-china-resort-to-crypto-if-the-us-imposes-sanctions">Will China Resort to Crypto if the US Imposes Sanctions?</h2>



<p>Although China claims that it has not provided weapons to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/market-tumbles-after-major-russia-ukraine-war-escalation-us-interest-hike/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Russia since the Ukraine invasion</a> began, the US <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/u-s-takes-aim-at-chinese-banks-aiding-russia-war-effort-fcf76dcc?st=2hbnx4gcsgzpgve&amp;reflink=article_copyURL_share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">argues</a> that the export of dual-use items like chips and machinery has critically strengthened Russia’s military. These proposed sanctions are seen as an &#8220;escalatory option&#8221; to be employed if diplomatic efforts fall short.</p>



<p>Historically, countries isolated from the global financial network have turned to cryptocurrencies as a workaround. For example, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/venezuela-usdt-bypass-us-sanction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Venezuela’s state-run oil company, PDVSA, has shifted to using Tether (USDT)</a> to evade renewed US sanctions. This move aims to protect its oil revenues from international banking constraints.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/best-usdt-wallet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">9 Best Crypto Wallets to Store Tether (USDT)</a></strong></p>



<p>Similarly, Russia has leveraged cryptocurrencies to sidestep Western sanctions. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/russian-smugglers-tether-buy-weapons/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Russian firms are reportedly using Tether’s USDT </a>to acquire vital components for military hardware. This strategy facilitates transactions that conventional financial systems less easily trace. </p>



<p>The increasing use of cryptocurrency in these contexts highlights its usage by countries to bypass <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-intensifies-sanctions-russian-institutions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">economic sanctions</a>.</p>



<p>Given these developments, growing speculation exists about China’s potential response to being similarly isolated. Traditionally, China has been strict in regulating cryptocurrencies, driven by concerns over financial instability and unauthorized capital outflows.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Study the reallocation of Chinese capital from stocks and real estate to gold. A similar phenomenon has been happening with Bitcoin in China but not at full potential because of the restricted access. We will open this dam,&#8221; Venture Capitalist Andrew Kang <a href="https://twitter.com/Rewkang/status/1782384548610711568" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The possibility of Chinese banks facing exclusion from the global financial system could prompt a reevaluation of this stance. Particularly, it could encourage a more favorable regulatory approach to crypto. </p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-regulation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crypto Regulation: What Are the Benefits and Drawbacks?</a></strong></p>



<p>Such a shift would align with the global trend of integrating cryptocurrencies into economic systems, especially in contexts where countries cannot access traditional financial avenues.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/china-embrace-crypto-us-sanctions/">US Threats to Block Chinese Banks Globally Could Ease China’s Crypto Ban</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/bic_China_neutral_6.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/bic_China_neutral_6.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria Intensifies Crypto Clampdown: Top Exchanges Under Scrutiny</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/nigeria-intensifies-crypto-clampdown/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan James]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) is intensifying its scrutiny of major cryptocurrency platforms, instructing financial institutions to monitor and report activities involving Bybit, KuCoin, OKX, and Binance.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/nigeria-intensifies-crypto-clampdown/">Nigeria Intensifies Crypto Clampdown: Top Exchanges Under Scrutiny</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In an escalating effort to regulate the burgeoning cryptocurrency market, the Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) has sharpened its focus on several leading global cryptocurrency platforms, warning financial entities nationwide. </strong></p>



<p>In a letter that came to light this week, CBN directed financial institutions to closely monitor and report on the activities involving Bybit, KuCoin, OKX, and Binance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nigeria-s-cbn-to-arrest-usdt-traders-in-economic-probe">Nigeria&#8217;s CBN to Arrest USDT Traders in Economic Probe</h2>



<p>The mandate instructs Deposit Money Banks (DMBs), Non-Bank Financial Institutions (NBFIs), and Other Financial Institutions (OFIs) to flag and restrict accounts suspected of engaging in cryptocurrency transactions. The CBN&#8217;s directive particularly demands implementing a post-no-debit (PND) order for six months on relevant accounts. Additionally, warning of heavy sanctions for non-compliance.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the CBN clarified its stance on illicit activities amid these developments. It stated that any individual or &#8220;suspected agent&#8221; clandestinely trading or facilitating the sale of USDT would face arrest. This move continues the CBN&#8217;s campaign to probe economic disturbances within Nigeria.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="484" height="850" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-136-484x850.png" alt="CBON Press Release." class="wp-image-504472" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-136-484x850.png 484w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-136-205x360.png 205w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-136-768x1348.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-136-875x1536.png 875w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-136-150x263.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-136.png 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">CBON Press Release. Source: <a href="https://x.com/rektjeets/status/1783073319085863279" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Despite the broad sweep of the directive, local cryptocurrency exchanges seem to have been spared in the recent circular. Nathaniel Luz, CEO of Flincap, remarked on the omission of indigenous crypto exchanges. He attributes it to their proactive efforts in obtaining necessary operational licenses.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>“It’s noteworthy that the recent circular did not mention any indigenous crypto exchanges, likely because many Nigerian crypto companies, such as Flincap, have been actively pursuing the required licenses,” <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2024/04/24/nigeria-directs-entities-to-identify-those-dealing-crypto-with-bybit-kucoin-okx-and-binance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a> Nathaniel Luz, CEO of Flincap.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Read More: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/kucoin-legal-status/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Is KuCoin Safe in 2024? Exploring the Crypto Exchange’s Legal Status</a></strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-binance-under-fire-nigeria-alleges-tax-evasion-detains-executives">Binance Under Fire: Nigeria Alleges Tax Evasion, Detains Executives</h2>



<p>Similarly, Binance has come under fire from the Nigerian Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) over <a href="https://beincrypto.com/nigeria-charges-binance-tax-evasion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">allegations of tax evasion</a>. This includes omissions in VAT and Company Income Tax. This legal challenge against Binance follows a hefty $4.3 billion penalty for <a href="https://beincrypto.com/cz-binance-stake-fails-travel-approval-judge/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">breaching US anti-money laundering regulations</a>. Which underscores the crypto giant&#8217;s global regulatory pressures.</p>



<p>Moreover, the Nigerian government&#8217;s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-nigeria-hostages/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">detention of two Binance senior executives</a> has raised a potential diplomatic fray, given their links to the US and UK. Observers perceive the detentions as part of Nigeria&#8217;s broader financial reforms aimed at stabilizing the Naira and curtailing crypto operations implicated in currency manipulation</p>



<p>Nonetheless, the latest actions by Nigerian authorities reflect an intensified approach to crypto oversight that resonates with the global trend of tighter regulation in the digital currency space.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/nigeria-intensifies-crypto-clampdown/">Nigeria Intensifies Crypto Clampdown: Top Exchanges Under Scrutiny</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/bic_nigeria_crypto_5-covers.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/bic_nigeria_crypto_5-covers.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>So.Social Redefines the Web3 Social Landscape</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/so-social-redefines-the-web3-social-landscape/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Web3 technologies are gaining momentum, aided by the most recent Bitcoin halving, attracting billions of users to start exploring decentralized technologies. So.Social&#8217;s recently released new set of social protocols are not just another social network like Friend.Tech or Farcaster, but an innovative blend of decentralized social networks, assets, and cutting-edge AI technologies. Let us explore &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/so-social-redefines-the-web3-social-landscape/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/so-social-redefines-the-web3-social-landscape/">So.Social Redefines the Web3 Social Landscape</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Web3 technologies are gaining momentum, aided by the most recent Bitcoin halving, attracting billions of users to start exploring decentralized technologies. </strong></p>



<p>So.Social&#8217;s recently released new set of social protocols are not just another social network like Friend.Tech or Farcaster, but an innovative blend of decentralized social networks, assets, and cutting-edge AI technologies.</p>



<p>Let us explore the project&#8217;s backstory, core features, and groundbreaking technologies in more detail.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-saag-model"><strong>The &#8220;SAAG&#8221; Model</strong></h2>



<p>So.Social stands as the pioneering protocol merging SocialFi, AI, Assets, and GameFi into a single entity, leading users towards social interaction 3.0: Full Self-Sovereignty. The integration of tokenomics and social networks incentivizes community members, captivates users&#8217; attention through gaming, and allows AI technologies to serve as a realistic community tool.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-so-social-aims-to-address-several-key-issues"><strong>So.Social Aims to Address Several Key Issues</strong></h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>User Privacy:</strong> Users often worry about the privacy of their data, especially in regards to how platforms use their personal information for advertising and data sales. Government regulations tend to support user concerns over platform revenue.</li>



<li><strong>Unfair Revenue Distribution</strong>: Users feel that platforms do not fairly distribute the value they create through their social interactions. Larger platforms might take a significant portion of earned income, leaving creators with less.</li>



<li><strong>Content Censorship</strong>: Users want free speech but face strict content moderation policies from the platforms they use. These policies can stifle discussions and limit free expression.</li>



<li><strong>Lack of Trust in Governance</strong>: Users must inherently trust social platforms for financial transactions without any guarantee of transparency. For instance, when making charitable donations, users must trust the platform and recipient without further verification options.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-makes-so-social-unique"><strong>What Makes So.Social Unique</strong></h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Social Infrastructure Layer</strong>: Changing the way social platforms are structured, So.Social introduces a new social infrastructure layer. This layer can be viewed as a foundational structure that gives platforms more flexibility and lets users control how they interact socially.</li>



<li><strong>Social Consensus Mechanisms</strong>: Groups, communities, or societies have different ways of making collective decisions, including through voting, discussions, or negotiations. Strong social consensus mechanisms are important in ensuring that decisions represent the opinions of the majority while considering the views of everyone involved and are key to healthy community governance.</li>



<li><strong>Sovereign DAO</strong>: So.Social&#8217;s protocols empower users to achieve genuine community governance by offering a practical approach to community management. So.Social adopters can define rules and contracts for their social interactions, enhancing transparency and trust within the community.</li>



<li><strong>Stakeholder Governance</strong>: In So.Social&#8217;s ecosystem, all members become stakeholders, bridging the gap between regular users and investors. Every member has the opportunity to earn based on their contributions to the community. This tokenized system encourages active participation in social activities and fosters deeper community engagement and the creation of valuable content.</li>



<li><strong>Community Growth Mechanisms: </strong>Through the introduction of a &#8220;GroupUp&#8221; model, users are encouraged to invite new members or connect with other users to unlock additional rights and revenue opportunities. This leads to organic growth and strengthens user engagement and consensus within the community. Additionally, So.Social innovatively leverages AI technologies to ensure fair and scientific asset distribution. By depersonalizing this process, a platform may guarantee fairness and transparency in revenue distribution and decision making.</li>
</ul>



<p>This groundbreaking approach transforms the online social landscape, offering a glimpse into the tokenized future of social networks driven by Web3 technology.</p>



<p>&#8220;So.Social is at the forefront of a new paradigm of social interactions, and our social protocols empower users to shape each interaction to their wishes, ensuring transparency, fairness, and trust. Importantly, it grants every community member cultural and financial sovereignty. We envision a future that addresses the social needs of all users,&#8221; explained Ian, So.Social Co-founder.</p>



<p>So.Social is pleased to invite all builders and users to come together and create a new social ecosystem. Reach out now to So.Social through the <a href="https://forms.gle/bzxWLAdVKRzanMkm6." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">form</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Learn more about So.Social at <a href="https://so.social/">here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/so-social-redefines-the-web3-social-landscape/">So.Social Redefines the Web3 Social Landscape</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/20240424-123136.jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="700" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/20240424-123136.jpeg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Injective&#8217;s Tokenomic Changes Aim for Unprecedented Deflation: Price Impact</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/injective-tokenomics-upgrade-price-impact/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 09:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Injective (INJ) Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Injective's INJ 3.0 tokenomics revamp introduces major changes to minting and inflation, aiming to establish it as a leading deflationary asset in the crypto space.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/injective-tokenomics-upgrade-price-impact/">Injective&#8217;s Tokenomic Changes Aim for Unprecedented Deflation: Price Impact</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The Injective community has approved transformative changes to its tokenomics, launching the Injective 3.0 system. </strong></p>



<p>This revision modifies INJ&#8217;s minting mechanics and introduces features designed to make it &#8220;one of the most deflationary assets in crypto.&#8221; These changes aim to quadruple the deflationary pressure on INJ over the next two years.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-can-injective-inj-surge-45">Can Injective (INJ) Surge 45%?</h2>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/injective-protocol/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">INJ is the native token</a> of a Cosmos-based Layer 1 blockchain, managed by the non-profit Injective Foundation. The recent endorsement of the INJ 3.0 proposal, <a href="https://hub.injective.network/proposal/392/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">unveiled</a> on April 19, is built on two main adjustments. </p>



<p>Firstly, it revises INJ&#8217;s inflationary bounds by setting the lower and upper limits at 4% and 7%, respectively. These limits will be incrementally enforced and reassessed in the second quarter of 2026.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/tokenomics-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tokenomics Explained: The Economics of Cryptocurrency Tokens</a></strong></p>



<p>Furthermore, the update substantially increases the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-high-staking-inflation-rates/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">inflation rate</a> change parameter from 0.1 to 0.5. Consequently, this makes INJ&#8217;s inflation rate more reactive to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/injective-stakes-coins-tvl-surges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">staking activity</a>, thereby enhancing network security and user engagement.</p>



<p>Jenna Peterson, CEO of the Injective Foundation, discussed the strategic importance of these updates. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;With these vital updates approved through governance by the broader Injective community, INJ 3.0 aims for INJ to surpass even the sound monetary properties of Bitcoin,&#8221; Peterson <a href="https://blog.injective.com/en/the-block-injective-community-increases-injs-deflation-by-400/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Also, Eric Chen, the CEO of Injective Labs, emphasized the community&#8217;s overwhelming approval of the proposal, noting a 99.99% approval rate.</p>



<p>On the trading front, INJ dropped over 50% from its <a href="https://beincrypto.com/inj-price-new-all-time-high/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all-time high</a> within one month. However, its current market behavior indicates a bullish reversal. Technical analysis reveals that INJ has formed a cup and handle chart pattern, which is a strong bullish signal. </p>



<p>This pattern suggests <a href="https://beincrypto.com/inj-price-prediction-escape-consolidation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a potential breakout</a> if INJ can move past the critical resistance level at $29.85. Achieving this could propel the price to around $41.47, reflecting an increase of over 45%.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/cup-handle-pattern/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">A Guide to the Cup and Handle Pattern in Technical Analysis</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="493" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/INJUSDT_2024-04-24_14-56-16-850x493.png" alt="Injective (INJ) Price Performance" class="wp-image-504444" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/INJUSDT_2024-04-24_14-56-16-850x493.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/INJUSDT_2024-04-24_14-56-16-360x209.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/INJUSDT_2024-04-24_14-56-16-768x445.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/INJUSDT_2024-04-24_14-56-16-1536x891.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/INJUSDT_2024-04-24_14-56-16-2048x1188.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/INJUSDT_2024-04-24_14-56-16-150x87.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Injective (INJ) Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://in.tradingview.com/symbols/INJUSDT/?exchange=BINANCE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;If it flips the key level, be ready for huge pump,&#8221; crypto analyst Nihilus <a href="https://twitter.com/nihilus_XBT/status/1781802218900848946" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/injective-tokenomics-upgrade-price-impact/">Injective&#8217;s Tokenomic Changes Aim for Unprecedented Deflation: Price Impact</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Injective_INJ_4-covers_bullish.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Injective_INJ_4-covers_bullish.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s Why Hedera (HBAR) Price Surged 100% in 24 Hours</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/why-hbar-price-surged-recently/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan James]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 09:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hedera (HBAR) News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hedera's (HBAR) price surged 100% in 24 hours, driven by BlackRock's tokenization of its US Treasury money market fund on the platform in partnership with Archax and OwneraIO, a milestone for real-world asset tokenization.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/why-hbar-price-surged-recently/">Here&#8217;s Why Hedera (HBAR) Price Surged 100% in 24 Hours</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In a landmark development for real-world asset tokenization, Hedera&#8217;s (HBAR) price surged an impressive 100% within 24 hours.</strong></p>



<p> This remarkable rally came as BlackRock, the world&#8217;s largest asset manager, announced the tokenization of its US Treasury money market fund on Hedera in collaboration with Archax and OwneraIO.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-hedera-s-blockchain-advances-tradfi-integration-spurs-market-growth">Hedera&#8217;s Blockchain Advances: TradFi Integration Spurs Market Growth</h2>



<p>This integration of traditional finance (TradFi) with Hedera&#8217;s blockchain technology signifies a major milestone, highlighting the network&#8217;s ability to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hedera-price-breakout-fed-integration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">attract institutional-grade projects</a> due to its high speed, robust security, and low fees. Archax&#8217;s expansion of tokenized money market fund offerings has played a pivotal role in enhancing the range of financial instruments accessible to institutional clients.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>“The addition of MMF shares tokenised on Hedera, enabled by Archax, is a huge vote of confidence. Hedera&#8217;s unmatched speed, security, and low-cost infrastructure is ideally suited for the institutional-grade tokenisation of real-world assets made possible by Archax.” Shayne Higdon, CEO of The HBAR Foundation, <a href="https://www.hbarfoundation.org/blog-post/archax-increases-tokenised-money-market-fund-offerings" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">commented</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>With this move, Hedera not only demonstrates its growing relevance in the financial sector but also confirms investor confidence in the network&#8217;s capability to handle significant financial instruments. </p>



<p><strong>Read More: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/rwa-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What Are Tokenized Real-World Assets (RWA)?</a></strong></p>



<p>As Hedera continues <a href="https://x.com/HBAR_foundation/status/1782759384742813951" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">facilitating blockchain integration</a> into mainstream finance, HBAR&#8217;s price response underscores the market&#8217;s enthusiasm for innovation and institutional adoption in the crypto space.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-hbar-climbs-into-top-30-as-trading-volume-surges">HBAR Climbs Into Top 30 as Trading Volume Surges</h2>



<p>Following the announcement, HBAR saw an impressive 100% gain in price. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hedera-price-breakout-fed-integration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HBAR hit a two-year high</a> of $0.18 before the price began to correct. Currently, it sits at a 57% price gain on the day. </p>



<p>Additionally, the total market cap of HBAR currently sits at $4.7 billion. The rapid surge in price has seen HBAr climb into the top 30, currently sitting at 26. It is also worth noting the announcement has seen <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hedera-transaction-volume-40x-q1-pangolin-dex/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trading volume for HBAR</a> climb to an impressive $2 billion at the time of writing. </p>



<p>This makes it the fourth-highest volume-traded altcoin (excluding stablecoins) behind Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Solana.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="769" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-133-850x769.png" alt="Hedera (HBAR) 24-Hour Price Performance." class="wp-image-504426" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-133-850x769.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-133-360x326.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-133-768x695.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-133-150x136.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-133.png 886w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Hedera (HBAR) 24-Hour Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/hedera-hashgraph/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">BeInCrypto</a> </figcaption></figure>



<p>On the daily chart, HBAR appears to be witnessing a price correction following the impressive price increase. Which is to be expected. The price is testing daily support around the $0.13 area according to the 0.5 Fibonacci retracement. This could represent a notable area to average back in for buyers. </p>



<p><strong>Read More: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/hbar-price-prediction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hedera (HBAR) Price Prediction 2024/2025/2030</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="429" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-134-850x429.png" alt="Hedera (HBAR/USDT) Price Chart. " class="wp-image-504433" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-134-850x429.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-134-360x182.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-134-768x387.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-134-150x76.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-134.png 1459w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Hedera (HBAR/USDT) Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/HBARUSDT/?exchange=BINANCE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The $0.18 &#8211; $0.20 area also represents a strong resistance level. Flipping this could see the price push toward its all-time high. Finally, a correction below $0.125 would likely see the correction continue lower.  </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/why-hbar-price-surged-recently/">Here&#8217;s Why Hedera (HBAR) Price Surged 100% in 24 Hours</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Hedera_HBAR_4-covers_bullish.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bic_Hedera_HBAR_4-covers_bullish.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Solana Network Update Scheduled for Late May</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/solana-update-live-on-may/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 08:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana (SOL) News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Solana is preparing to launch a crucial update, version v1.18, aimed at addressing network congestion, with significant testing and infrastructure enhancements underway.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-update-live-on-may/">New Solana Network Update Scheduled for Late May</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Solana is gearing up for a significant update, set to be released on May 27 for its mainnet beta. The version v1.18 is crucial in tackling the network&#8217;s ongoing congestion issues. </strong></p>



<p>The forthcoming v1.18 aims to bolster Solana&#8217;s infrastructure significantly.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-solana-s-roadmap-to-v1-18-update">Solana&#8217;s Roadmap to V1.18 Update</h2>



<p>The congestion problems have recently worsened due to an increase in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/meme-coin-solana-transaction-failure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bot-driven transactions involving meme coins</a>, leading to a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-war-ddos-attacks-competitors/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spike in transaction failures</a>.</p>



<p>Solana&#8217;s development team has been actively implementing <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-timely-vote-credit-proposal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a series of upgrades</a> designed to enhance network performance in response to these challenges. Notably, on April 13, in collaboration with Anza, a key infrastructure developer, they introduced <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-sol-price-congestion-fixes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">version 1.18.11 on the devnet</a>. The validators are currently testing the v1.18.</p>



<p>Validators play a vital role in the blockchain ecosystem. They confirm transactions and help secure the network, making their input essential for the new update&#8217;s success. </p>



<p>The feedback from this testing phase will be instrumental in ensuring the success of the upcoming mainnet-beta launch.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/solana-vs-ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Solana vs. Ethereum: An Ultimate Comparison</a></strong></p>



<figure class="overflow-x-auto wp-block-table"><table class="w-full mb-2 table-auto"><thead><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><th class="whitespace-nowrap py-3.5 px-2.5 lg:px-4 s4 s4--ns lg:s3 lg:s3--ns lg:s3--medium lg:s3--normal-case text-grey-600 text-left">Week #</th><th class="whitespace-nowrap py-3.5 px-2.5 lg:px-4 s4 s4--ns lg:s3 lg:s3--ns lg:s3--medium lg:s3--normal-case text-grey-600 text-left">Monday Date</th><th class="whitespace-nowrap py-3.5 px-2.5 lg:px-4 s4 s4--ns lg:s3 lg:s3--ns lg:s3--medium lg:s3--normal-case text-grey-600 text-left">Goals</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">1</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">2024-01-22</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Create a v1.18 branch. Update the master branch version to 2.0.0. Testnet: Upgrade to v1.18.0.</td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">5</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">2024-02-19</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Devnet: Upgrade to v1.18</td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">8</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">2024-04-30</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Tag Mainnet-beta Upgrade Candidate (MUC) on the v1.18 branch.<br>Testnet: Upgrade to MUC</td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">9</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">2024-05-06</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Testnet: Live downgrade to v1.17, upgrade to MUC (100%).<br>Mainnet-beta: Ask for volunteers to take 10% of the stake to to v1.18</td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">10</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">2024-05-13</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Mainnet-beta: Ask for volunteers to take 25% of the stake to v1.18</td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">11</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">2024-05-20</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Testnet: Live downgrade to v1.17, upgrade to MUC (100%).<br>Mainnet-beta: Ask for volunteers to take 10% of the stake to v1.18</td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">12</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">2024-05-27</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Mainnet-beta: Recommend all nodes upgrade to v1.18</td></tr></tbody></table><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">v1.18 Release Schedule. Source: <a href="https://github.com/anza-xyz/agave/wiki/v1.18-Release-Schedule" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GitHub</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Adding to their proactive measures, the developers <a href="https://twitter.com/SolanaStatus/status/1779727821834686592" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">released</a> version 1.17.31 on April 15. This version, which aimed at congestion relief, was recommended for immediate use by MainnetBeta validators. It is part of a broader effort to stabilize the network amid fluctuating transaction volumes.</p>



<p>Despite these technical strides, Solana has faced significant market volatility. Since the start of the month, its value has dropped by over 22%.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="493" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SOLUSD_2024-04-24_13-10-13-850x493.png" alt="Solana (SOL) Price Performance" class="wp-image-504405" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SOLUSD_2024-04-24_13-10-13-850x493.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SOLUSD_2024-04-24_13-10-13-360x209.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SOLUSD_2024-04-24_13-10-13-768x445.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SOLUSD_2024-04-24_13-10-13-1536x891.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SOLUSD_2024-04-24_13-10-13-2048x1188.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SOLUSD_2024-04-24_13-10-13-150x87.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Solana (SOL) Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://in.tradingview.com/symbols/SOLUSD/?exchange=BINANCE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>It reached a low of $116 earlier in April. However, the price has rebounded, now trading at approximately $158.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-update-live-on-may/">New Solana Network Update Scheduled for Late May</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_-Solana_SOL_2-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_-Solana_SOL_2-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meme Coin BONK Could Soon Continue Parabolic Bull Run</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/meme-coin-bonk-continue-parabolic-run/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan James]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meme coin Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BONK, a meme coin on Solana, surged to $0.00002753, signaling its highest value since early April. This rally reflects cautious optimism in the market.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/meme-coin-bonk-continue-parabolic-run/">Meme Coin BONK Could Soon Continue Parabolic Bull Run</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>BONK, a prominent meme coin within the Solana ecosystem, has witnessed a remarkable rally in a market that has recently been characterized by cautious optimism.</strong></p>



<p>On Wednesday, BONK&#8217;s value surged to $0.00002753, marking its most substantial price point since the beginning of April.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-is-meme-coin-mania-back">Is Meme Coin Mania Back?</h2>



<p>The meme coin&#8217;s value has more than doubled, registering an increase of 118% from its lowest level this month, positioning it as the top performer among its peers. This upward trajectory for BONK aligns with a broader recovery observed across the cryptocurrency sector. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="427" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-850x427.png" alt="BONK Price Chart." class="wp-image-504397" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-850x427.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-360x181.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-768x386.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-150x75.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127.png 1465w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">BONK Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BONKUSDT/?exchange=BINANCE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Market analysts attribute <a href="https://beincrypto.com/meme-coin-bonk-bull-rally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BONK&#8217;s explosive rebound to investors</a> capitalizing on recent price dips. Historically, assets often undergo a corrective recovery following substantial declines, and BONK&#8217;s comeback appears to mirror this trend. The resurgence of interest in meme coins also plays a role in BONK&#8217;s ascent. </p>



<p>Other tokens in this category, such as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/pepe-new-ath-by-april-end/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PEPE</a>, dogwifhat (WIF), and MAGA (TRUMP), have <a href="https://beincrypto.com/meme-coins-shib-pepe-bonk-wif-doge-rally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">registered considerable gains</a>. Market data underlines that BONK&#8217;s rally is amidst heightened trading activity. CoinGecko reported a <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bonk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">trading volume</a> that soared above $531 million on Wednesday, a significant leap from $177 million the previous day.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/meme-coins/">What Are Meme Coins?</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="409" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-128-850x409.png" alt="Top Meme Coin Performances. " class="wp-image-504404" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-128-850x409.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-128-360x173.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-128-768x370.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-128-150x72.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-128.png 1074w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Top Meme Coin Performances. Source: <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/categories/meme-token" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Coingecko</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Investor enthusiasm for BONK and similar digital assets may signal a shifting sentiment within the crypto market, suggesting a possible sustained period of risk-on trading behavior. As meme coins continue to captivate the market&#8217;s interest, BONK&#8217;s recent performance might hint at the start of a potential parabolic bull run for the viral token.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-revolut-expands-crypto-offerings-by-listing-bonk">Revolut Expands Crypto Offerings by Listing BONK</h2>



<p>In a strategic move to diversify its cryptocurrency offerings, global neobank Revolut has announced the <a href="https://www.revolut.com/en-IS/blog/post/bonk-token-launch-eu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">listing of the BONK</a> token. This latest addition enriches Revolut&#8217;s robust trading platform, which already features over 150 carefully selected digital currencies. </p>



<p>Including BONK demonstrates Revolut&#8217;s ongoing dedication to delivering a comprehensive and market-leading trading experience to its users worldwide. BONK now joins the likes of SHIB, PEPE, and FLOKI among the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solana-bonk-crypto-token-revolut-partnership/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">meme coins currently available on the Revolut</a> platform. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-bonk-price-analysis-a-rally-gathering-momentum">BONK Price Analysis: A Rally Gathering Momentum</h2>



<p>The BONK token is catching the eye of cryptocurrency enthusiasts as its price sees a noteworthy ascent on the charts.  The 4-hour chart reveals BONK has triumphed past resistance on the .382 Fibonacci line, achieving a 7.35% increase to a price point of $0.00002659 in today&#8217;s trading. The chart indicates a strong uptrend, with a Fibonacci retracement suggesting a significant rebound off the lower levels.</p>



<p>Closing above the key support (green line) will see BONK likely push toward the 0.5 Fib line next (blue line). <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bonk-price-analysis-bull-run/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">This would note a new monthly high for BONK</a>. </p>



<p><strong>Read More: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-buy-solana-meme-coins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to Buy Solana Meme Coins: A Step-By-Step Guide</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="428" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-129-850x428.png" alt="BONK Price Chart. " class="wp-image-504406" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-129-850x428.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-129-360x181.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-129-768x387.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-129-150x76.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-129.png 1461w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">BONK Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BONKUSDT/?exchange=BINANCE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tradingview</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Notably, the Relative Strength Index (RSI) is charting upwards, indicating growing momentum, yet still below the overbought territory. This trend points to potential continued growth without immediate signs of a pullback. As BONK carves out a recovery path, it stands as a token to watch in the coming days, with traders and investors anticipating its next move in the volatile meme coin arena.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/meme-coin-bonk-continue-parabolic-run/">Meme Coin BONK Could Soon Continue Parabolic Bull Run</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/bic_BONK_3-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/bic_BONK_3-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao Could Spend 3 Years in Prison</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/changpeng-zhao-three-year-prison/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 05:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Changpeng Zhao News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Changpeng "CZ" Zhao, former Binance CEO, could serve three years following his guilty plea for major legal violations, highlighting significant consequences in the crypto industry.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/changpeng-zhao-three-year-prison/">Former Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao Could Spend 3 Years in Prison</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Changpeng &#8220;CZ&#8221; Zhao, founder and former CEO of Binance, the world&#8217;s largest crypto exchange, faces a potential three-year prison sentence. </strong></p>



<p>This development follows his guilty plea to charges that he helped the company violate anti-money laundering laws and sanctions</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-binance-co-founder-changpeng-zhao-s-trial-starts-on-april-30">Binance Co-Founder Changpeng Zhao&#8217;s Trial Starts on April 30</h2>



<p>According to Reuters, Federal prosecutors have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/us-seeks-36-months-jail-binance-founder-zhao-2024-04-24/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">argued</a> for a 36-month incarceration for Zhao, underlining the gravity of his offenses under the Bank Secrecy Act. In addition, the sentencing memo filed on Tuesday recommends a substantial $50 million fine. </p>



<p>Prosecutors in the case have pointed out the broad impact of Zhao&#8217;s actions on the financial system&#8217;s integrity, calling for a stricter sentence. They intend to punish Zhao and deter similar future conduct by others in the industry.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Given the magnitude of Zhao&#8217;s willful violation of US law and its consequences, an above-guidelines sentence of 36 months is warranted,&#8221; US prosecutors said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This stance represents a notable shift from the earlier plea agreement, which suggested <a href="https://beincrypto.com/changpeng-zhao-faces-jail-sentence/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a maximum of 18 months</a>.</p>



<p>The legal proceedings involving Zhao have experienced delays. His sentencing has been pushed back to April 30. Since his initial court appearance in Seattle last year, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/cz-binance-stake-fails-travel-approval-judge/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Zhao has not been able to return to Dubai</a>, where he lives with his partner and children.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/changpeng-zhao-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Who Is Changpeng Zhao? A Deep Dive Into the Ex-CEO of Binance</a></strong></p>



<p>Meanwhile, Binance itself has also pleaded guilty to related charges. The company agreed to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-pay-doj-fine-without-selling-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pay $4.3 billion in fines</a> and to report to a court-appointed monitor, though this official has yet to be appointed.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/changpeng-zhao-three-year-prison/">Former Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao Could Spend 3 Years in Prison</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_Changpeng_Zhao_CZ_-covers_negative_2.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_Changpeng_Zhao_CZ_-covers_negative_2.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Worldcoin Plans to Sell Up to $195 Million in WLD Tokens: Price Impact</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/worldcoin-unleash-195-million-wld-price/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 04:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=504284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Worldcoin is set to sell 36 million WLD tokens, potentially raising $195 million to expand its digital identity services, amid a challenging market.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/worldcoin-unleash-195-million-wld-price/">Worldcoin Plans to Sell Up to $195 Million in WLD Tokens: Price Impact</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Worldcoin, a crypto-based digital identity project, recently revealed expansion plans by selling WLD tokens. It intends to release between 0.5 million and 1.5 million tokens each week for up to six months</strong>.<strong> </strong></p>



<p>This sale might introduce 36 million WLD tokens in the circulating supply. Consequently, this would represent an 18.6% increase in the existing supply of 193 million tokens.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-worldcoin-aims-to-release-195-million-worth-of-wld-tokens">Worldcoin Aims to Release $195 Million Worth of WLD Tokens</h2>



<p>The fresh 36 million tokens are worth around $195 million based on the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/worldcoin-wld/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current market price</a>.</p>



<p>Having achieved <a href="https://beincrypto.com/worldcoin-world-app-users-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a significant milestone</a> of over 5 million <a href="https://beincrypto.com/worldcoin-new-orb-design-scrutiny/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">orb-verified World ID</a> users across 160 countries, Worldcoin says that it is experiencing growing demand for its services. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;To meet the increasing demand for orb-verified World IDs around the world and support the growth of the Worldcoin network, World Assets Ltd. (a subsidiary of the Worldcoin Foundation) expects to sell WLD tokens from the World Assets treasury in the coming months,&#8221; Worldcoin <a href="https://worldcoin.org/blog/announcements/circulating-supply-update-sales-trading-firms" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">announced</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/buy-worldcoin-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Where To Buy Worldcoin (WLD): 5 Best Platforms for 2024</a></strong></p>



<p>This initiative aims to cater primarily to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/deutsche-borse-crypto-trading-institutions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">institutional trading</a> firms outside the US, adhering to specific legal restrictions to prevent these tokens from entering the US market again.</p>



<p>The planned sale incorporates several safeguards, such as a potential 40-day lock-up period to prevent immediate resale of the tokens, especially to US persons or on platforms accessible within the US. By engaging multiple trading firms in a competitive process, World Assets strives to secure sale prices that align closely with the prevailing market rates.</p>



<p>However, the market context for this sale is challenging. Since March 10, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/worldcoin-price-could-dip/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Worldcoin&#8217;s price</a> has plummeted by over 54%. </p>



<p>The addition of millions of new tokens could potentially depress the price further, especially since WLD is currently struggling to maintain a support level of $5.37. A breakdown below this threshold could trigger additional losses.</p>



<p>Conversely, there is optimism among some market participants. A crypto trader, Alpha, suggested on X (formerly Twitter) that a potential breakout could lead WLD to double its current value.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>“WLD breakout is next off here! The breakout can target 2x off here towards 12,&#8221; Alpha <a href="https://twitter.com/nmalpha052/status/1782796594858844495" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="850" height="473" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL3EDayWQAEqYNI-850x473.jpeg" alt="Worldcoin (WLD) Price Performance" class="wp-image-504292" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL3EDayWQAEqYNI-850x473.jpeg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL3EDayWQAEqYNI-360x200.jpeg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL3EDayWQAEqYNI-768x428.jpeg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL3EDayWQAEqYNI-150x83.jpeg 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL3EDayWQAEqYNI.jpeg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Worldcoin (WLD) Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://in.tradingview.com/symbols/WLDUSDT/?exchange=BINANCE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Nevertheless, the reality remains that the influx of new tokens might increase selling pressure, further impacting the price negatively.</p>



<p>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, alongside Worldcoin CEO Alex Blania and Max Novendstern, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/social-media-reaction-worldcoin-overwhelmingly-negative/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launched the project</a> in July 2023. Users of the World App can verify their identities by scanning their retinas at stations known as &#8220;Orbs.&#8221; </p>



<p><strong><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/worldcoin-price-prediction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Worldcoin (WLD) Price Prediction 2024/2025/2030</a></strong></strong></p>



<p>In return for providing their biometric data, they are compensated with approximately 25 WLD tokens worth around $135. This innovative exchange underpins the utility and appeal of the Worldcoin ecosystem.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/worldcoin-unleash-195-million-wld-price/">Worldcoin Plans to Sell Up to $195 Million in WLD Tokens: Price Impact</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/bic_worldcoin_orb_negative_covers.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/bic_worldcoin_orb_negative_covers.jpg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
