<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bitcoinist.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 05:44:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/cropped-cropped-cropped-Icon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">225283986</site>	<item>
		<title>Ripple&#8217;s 3-Year Growth Strategy Unveiled By CEO Garlinghouse</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-3-year-growth-strategy-ceo-garlinghouse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 06:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brad Garlinghouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an interview with FOX Business, Ripple CEO Brad Garlinghouse detailed the company’s ambitious plans for growth over the next three years, highlighted by the launch of a US dollar-backed stablecoin and a strategic expansion in international markets amidst ongoing regulatory challenges in the United States. Ripple CEO Unveils 3-Year Growth Plan When inquired about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n_OZ2LypphE" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">interview</a> with FOX Business, Ripple CEO Brad Garlinghouse detailed the company’s ambitious plans for growth over the next three years, highlighted by the launch of a US dollar-backed stablecoin and a strategic expansion in international markets amidst ongoing regulatory challenges in the United States.</p>
<h2>Ripple CEO Unveils 3-Year Growth Plan</h2>
<p>When inquired about the company’s growth story for the next three years, Garlinghouse began by underscoring Ripple&#8217;s significant international presence, with approximately 95% of its customer base located outside the US. &#8220;95% of our customers are non US financial institutions,” he stated.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Garlinghouse explained that Ripple is selling payment solutions and custody solutions around blockchain and crypto. He emphasized the company’s core offerings and conveyed a strong commitment to further expansion.</p>
<p>“We&#8217;re going to keep expanding, even though the US market, as we were talking about earlier, partly from a regulatory point of view, has been slow to adopt, the non-US market has been really, really strong for us. And we&#8217;re going to be the infrastructure around all of that. That is our goal, and we think that opportunity is huge. We think that&#8217;s going to be great for Ripple,” Garlinghouse noted.</p>

<p>In addition to infrastructure, Ripple plans to enhance the utility of XRP, the digital asset central to its payment protocol. Garlinghouse expressed a positive outlook for XRP, linking its success to Ripple’s expansion and the broader adoption of its technologies. &#8220;We think that’s going to be great for Ripple. We think it’s going to be great for XRP,&#8221; he said, reinforcing the symbiotic relationship between Ripple’s growth and the adoption of its associated cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>Garlinghouse then delved into the specifics of the upcoming <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-emerge-tether-upcoming-stablecoin-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">US dollar-backed stablecoin</a>, a pivotal development in Ripple’s strategy to bridge traditional finance with the burgeoning sector of cryptocurrencies. He described the stablecoin as a response to the escalating demand within the stablecoin market, currently valued at $150 billion and potentially rising to over $2 trillion. &#8220;Ripple has always been about how do we bridge this new world with a traditional kind of, people call it TradFi, traditional finance,&#8221; he explained.</p>

<p>This stablecoin aims to provide a reliable and regulatory-compliant option in contrast to competitors like <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/tether-splits-into-four-divisions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Tether</a>, which is based outside of the US and faces different regulatory scrutiny. The initiative represents a strategic move to position Ripple as a leader in compliant, secure, and user-friendly crypto-finance solutions. “I think that market is going to grow a lot. I think a US-based player who is compliance first has a great role to play,” Garlinghouse added.</p>
Regulatory Environment And Advocacy For Clear Guidelines
<p>Garlinghouse also delved into the regulatory environment in the US, critiquing the slow pace of legislative progress which he believes hampers market growth. “Washington is still trying to understand this market,” he commented, expressing concern over potential legislation that might place undue barriers on the burgeoning crypto market.</p>
<p>He was particularly critical of the current administration and regulatory figures, stating, “This administration, I think, has taken a pretty anti-crypto stance led by the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/gary-gensler-says-crypto-needs-disinfectant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">SEC Gary Gensler</a> as the chair has really doesn’t understand it.” He also challenged the narrative put forth by certain politicians, like <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-lawyer-deaton-takes-lead-outpacing-warren/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Senator Elizabeth Warren</a>, who he quoted as saying, “The only people using crypto are bad actors.”</p>
<p>Garlinghouse concluded with a call to action for more informed, pro-innovation policies that align with fostering job creation and economic growth, reminiscent of the early days of the internet boom in Silicon Valley. “This is about leading the next wave of innovation,” he affirmed, urging US policymakers to embrace and facilitate the growth of blockchain and cryptocurrency through clear and supportive regulations. Via X, he <a href="https://twitter.com/bgarlinghouse/status/1781051002512183481" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>How pro-innovation policies in the US will prevail. Step 1 &#8211; replace the SEC leadership and step 2 &#8211; Elizabeth Warren’s staff should read some actual facts on crypto instead of spewing constant misinformation.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>At press time, XRP traded at $0.486.</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-295335" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472" alt="XRP price" width="1024" height="472" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3628 3628w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1536 1536w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=2048 2048w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1140 1140w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-19_07-39-52.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" />
<p>Featured image from CNBC, chart from TradingView.com</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/104492886-GettyImages-635343334-brad-garlinghouse.jpg?fit=620%2C420" width="620" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295332</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mango Markets Exploiter Avraham Eisenberg Convicted In $110M Crypto Fraud</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/avraham-eisenberg-convicted-mango-markets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 03:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Regulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mango]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mango hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mango Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mango Markets DAO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MNGO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MNGO token]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MNGOUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MNGOUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US crypto regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crypto trader Avraham &#8220;Avi&#8221; Eisenberg was found guilty by a Manhattan jury in October 2022 of orchestrating a $110 million fraud scheme targeting the decentralized finance (DeFi) protocol, Mango Markets.  According to prosecutors, Eisenberg, operating under a false identity, allegedly engaged in market manipulation to drive up the price of Mango&#8217;s token, MNGO, and related [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crypto trader Avraham &#8220;Avi&#8221; Eisenberg was found guilty by a Manhattan jury in October 2022 of <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/mango-markets-exploiter-returns-funds-statement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">orchestrating a $110 million fraud</a> scheme targeting the decentralized finance (DeFi) protocol, Mango Markets. </p>
<p>According to prosecutors, Eisenberg, operating under a false identity, allegedly engaged in market manipulation to drive up the price of Mango&#8217;s token, MNGO, and related contracts, ultimately exploiting an exchange feature to withdraw $110 million in cryptocurrency with no intention of repayment.</p>

<h2>Avi Eisenberg&#8217;s Manipulation Scheme Exposed</h2>
<p>During the trial, prosecutors <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-18/crypto-trader-convicted-in-110-million-haul-from-mango-markets" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">revealed </a>that Eisenberg manipulated the price of MNGO tokens to deceive the system and acquire illicit funds. By &#8220;artificially inflating&#8221; the token&#8217;s value, Eisenberg allegedly sought to perpetrate a deliberate fraud against Mango Markets. </p>
<p>Assistant US Attorney Thomas Burnett emphasized Eisenberg&#8217;s intent to &#8220;take the money and run,&#8221; alleging that he meticulously planned and executed the fraud.</p>
<p>Shortly after his significant financial gain, Eisenberg fled to Israel from Puerto Rico, where he resided. However, upon his return to Puerto Rico on December 26, 2022, US authorities arrested him. Eisenberg has <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/latest-updates-the-100m-mango-markets-exploit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">remained in custody </a>since then, as a judge deemed him a flight risk ahead of his trial.</p>
<h2>Prosecution Clash In Mango Markets&#8217; Fraud Trial </h2>
<p>During the trial, Eisenberg&#8217;s defense attorney, Brian Klein, argued that his client had executed a legal trading strategy within the exchange&#8217;s rules. </p>
<p>Klein contended that Eisenberg had taken calculated risks within the confines of the smart contracts governing the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/mango-markets-avraham-eisenberg-wants-to-keep-funds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">decentralized finance</a> platform. Furthermore, he highlighted the platform&#8217;s disclaimer that warned users of the software&#8217;s unaudited nature and associated risks.</p>
<p>Assistant US Attorney Thomas Burnett countered the defense&#8217;s argument, stating that the rules of the Mango Markets platform did not shield Eisenberg from prosecution for fraud and manipulation. </p>

<p>Eisenberg did not testify during the trial, but he played an active role in his defense, taking notes throughout the testimony and frequently suggesting questions for his attorneys to ask the witnesses. </p>
<img decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/oktgLPBM/" alt="Mango Markets" width="1815" height="858" />
<p>Following Eisenberg&#8217;s <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/sec-and-cftc-action-mango-markets-hacker-boost-defi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">conviction</a>, the price of the MNGO token has experienced a notable surge, reaching $0.029. This represents a notable 11.5% increase within the past 24 hours alone.</p>
<p>In broader timeframes, contrasting the performance of the overall cryptocurrency market, MNGO has demonstrated significant gains of 69% and 46% over the past fourteen and thirty days, respectively. These figures indicate a renewed interest in the token after the exploit of the Mango Markets protocol.</p>
<p>However, despite these recent gains, the MNGO token remains significantly below its all-time high of $0.49, achieved in September 2021. The current price reflects a decline of 94% from that peak level.</p>
<p>Featured image from Shutterstock, chart from TradingView.com </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/shutterstock_download-7-25.jpg?fit=462%2C260" width="462" height="260" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295292</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Continues To Struggle: Analytics Firm Reveals What Whales Are Doing</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-struggle-analytics-firm-reveals-whales/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Keshav Verma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 02:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Bearish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Struggle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Whale Selling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin whales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin has continued to struggle recently, and its price even briefly fell below $60,000. Here&#8217;s what the whales are doing while the market panics. How The Bitcoin Whales Are Behaving At The Moment In a new post on X, the market intelligence platform IntoTheBlock revealed how the Bitcoin whales have been behaving recently, given the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin has continued to struggle recently, and its price even briefly fell below $60,000. Here&#8217;s what the whales are doing while the market panics.</p>
<h2>How The Bitcoin Whales Are Behaving At The Moment</h2>
<p>In a new <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1780890849586434138" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">post</a> on X, the market intelligence platform IntoTheBlock revealed how the Bitcoin whales have been behaving recently, given the struggle the asset&#8217;s price has been going through.</p>
<p><a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-whales-strong-despite-bearish-price-action/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Whales</a> popularly refer to BTC investors carrying at least 1,000 tokens in their wallets. At the current exchange rate, this amount is worth about $63.5 million. Due to this massive scale of holdings, the whales can influence the network.</p>

<p>Thus, their behavior can naturally be worth following. First, the analytics firm has discussed the largest entities, even among the whales: the &#8220;<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/shiba-inus-large-holders-accumulated-100m-week-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Large Holders</a>.&#8221; IntoTheBlock categorizes Large Holders as those who own 0.1% or more of the entire circulating Bitcoin supply.</p>
<p>Currently, almost 19.7 million tokens are in circulation, so these large holders would be those holding around 19,700 BTC, which is worth a whopping $1.25 billion.</p>
<p>To track the behavior of the large holders, the analytics firm has referred to its &#8220;Large Holders Netflow&#8221; metric, which uses on-chain data to track the net amount of BTC entering into or exiting the wallets of these humongous entities.</p>
<p>Below is the chart for the indicator that shows how its value has changed over the last few months.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GLb7Qe0XoAAkgnW?format=png&amp;name=900x900" alt="Bitcoin Large Holders Netflow" width="887" height="504" /></p>

<p>As displayed in the graph, the Bitcoin Large Holders Netflow observed some notable positive spikes during March, suggesting that these massive investors had participated in the accumulation.</p>
<p>The metric&#8217;s value has recently stayed near the neutral level, with neither distribution nor accumulation showing any particular dominance. This would mean that the latest price drawdown hasn&#8217;t been an enticing buy-the-dip opportunity for this cohort yet.</p>
<p>The whales, though, have been buying at these recent low prices. The chart below shows the combined balance held by members of this group.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GLb8mMwW8AAXKqG?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Bitcoin Whale Balance" width="905" height="496" /></p>

<p>As the graph shows, the Bitcoin whales made notable selling moves as the cryptocurrency&#8217;s price rose to a <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-breaks-through-69000-setting-new-record/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">new all-time high (ATH)</a> last month.</p>
<p>Following Bitcoin&#8217;s drawdown from this ATH, though, the whales started buying again. As prices have gone lower recently, they have ramped up their rate of accumulation. IntoTheBlock said these investors had bought 16,300 BTC (almost $1.04 billion) over the past week.</p>

<p>Overall, the fact that the whales are accumulating while the large holders have at least not been selling anything significant can perhaps provide a neutral to slightly bullish picture for Bitcoin.</p>
<h2>BTC Price</h2>
<p>At the time of writing, Bitcoin is trading at around $63,400, down 10% over the past week.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium aligncenter" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/vD4abWmN/" alt="Bitcoin Price Chart" width="1534" height="854" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/todd-cravens-QnBrjY-nFUs-unsplash.jpg?fit=632%2C420" width="632" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295225</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Miners Accumulating Just Like In 2020: Is BTC Preparing For $100,000?</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-miners-accumulating-btc-100000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dalmas Ngetich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 01:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spot Bitcoin ETFs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the highly anticipated Bitcoin halving event approaches on April 19, a fascinating trend is emerging among miners. Unlike the pre-halving sell-offs witnessed before the Halvings of 2016 and 2020, miners accumulate, going against previous trends.  Miners Accumulating Bitcoin In a post on X, one analyst, while citing CryptoQuant data, notes that since the beginning [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the highly anticipated Bitcoin halving event approaches on April 19, a fascinating trend is emerging among miners. Unlike the pre-halving sell-offs witnessed before the Halvings of 2016 and 2020, miners accumulate, going against previous trends. </p>
<h2>Miners Accumulating Bitcoin</h2>
<p>In a post on X, one analyst, while citing CryptoQuant <a class="editor-rtfLink" href="https://twitter.com/AxelAdlerJr/status/1780818129007886368" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">data</a>, notes that since the beginning of 2024, the total BTC balance held by miners has grown by a staggering 12,100 BTC, reaching a total of 217,000 BTC. </p>
<p>This behavior starkly contrasts with what happened in 2016 and 2020 before the network slashed miner rewards. Then, reading from data, most miners were sizing down their holdings in anticipation of possible revenue slumps post-Halving. </p>

<p>Halving is set at the protocol level and slashes miner block rewards by half, currently from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC. This way, miners would have to expend more resources to generate the same revenue they would have in the previous epoch. </p>
<p>Accordingly, some small miners tend to liquidate and exit in anticipation of the rising competition. However, some large miners with more resources would take the opportunity to sell coins and buy more efficient miners to stay competitive.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-295233" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645" alt="Bitcoin miner balance | Source: Analyst on X" width="1024" height="645" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645?w=2048 2048w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645?w=1536 1536w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLa8pXWWoAAgDAQ.jpg?resize=1024%2C645?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" />
<p>From the chart, miners continued offloading their BTC post-halving in 2016. However, even with increasing selling pressure, prices rose sharply in 2017, peaking at $20,000 before cooling off in 2018. </p>
<p>As Bitcoin and crypto found adoption following the ICO mania of 2017, the scene became more liquid, and more miners participated, as seen from the rising hash rate post-halving.</p>
<p>Unlike events in 2016, the 2020 halving marked a turning point. As Bitcoin prices skyrocketed towards record highs, miners adopted a holding strategy, rapidly accumulating coins, as the chart shows. This current accumulation trend suggests miners may anticipate a similar price surge.</p>
<h2>Is BTC Ready For A Bull Run To $100,000?</h2>
<p>This shift in miner behavior could positively impact prices. Miners, expected to readjust and become more efficient after April 19, are holding a vote of confidence even amid the current slump. </p>

<p>Overall, a reduction in daily BTC emissions post-Halving, coupled with miners accumulating and institutions pouring in via spot Bitcoin exchange-traded funds (<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/schiff-warns-of-bailouts-from-bitcoin-etfs-buyers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">ETFs</a>), could propel prices even higher. </p>
<a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/k6PZ2Bve/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/k6PZ2Bve/" alt="Bitcoin price trending sideways on the daily chart | Source: BTCUSDT on Binance, TradingView" width="1787" height="904" /></a>
<p>The pace at which prices rise is yet to be seen. Bitcoin is bearish and remains under immense selling pressure following losses on April 13. A bullish breakout above the current range of $74,000 might be the base for more gains towards $100,000.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Crypto-news-Template20.jpg?fit=640%2C362" width="640" height="362" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto-Linked Money-Laundering Scheme Worth $230M Uncovered In Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/hong-kong-money-laundering-scheme-crypto-platform/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Regulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hong Kong crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hong Kong regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tether news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tether Stablecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tether usdt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TetherUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to a South China Morning Post report, Hong Kong customs officers have apprehended three individuals in connection with a massive HK$1.8 billion ($228 million) money-laundering operation that exploited a crypto platform and bank accounts associated with shell companies.  The arrests were made following an investigation into suspicious activities involving “abnormally frequent” and large transactions [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>According to a South China Morning Post <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3259535/hong-kong-customs-arrests-3-over-alleged-hk18-billion-money-laundering-scheme-linked-cryptocurrency" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report</a>, Hong Kong customs officers have apprehended three individuals in connection with a massive HK$1.8 billion ($228 million) money-laundering operation that exploited a crypto platform and bank accounts associated with shell companies. </p>
<p>The arrests were made following an investigation into suspicious activities involving “abnormally frequent” and large transactions in bank accounts lacking tax records, import and export declarations, and physical addresses.</p>
<h2>Suspects Allegedly Used Tether</h2>
<p>During the probe, it was discovered that one of the accounts involved received significant daily deposits of up to HK$39 million ($4.9 million) and facilitated 167 <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-analyst-dogecoin-xrp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">transactions</a>. </p>
<p>Further examination revealed that two suspects allegedly handled HK$760 million, equivalent to 40% of the total funds, through a cryptocurrency platform, specifically Tether.</p>

<p>Florence Yeung Yee-tak, commander of the Financial Investigation Division of the Customs Department, cited alleged challenges in investigating <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/analyst-claims-bitcoin-offers-a-financial-lifeline/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">money laundering </a>related to cryptocurrencies due to their anonymity and &#8220;lack of jurisdictional restrictions.&#8221; </p>
<p>Yee-tak emphasized that the enforcement team relied on intelligence, capital flow analysis, and financial investigations to gather evidence.</p>
<p>In a coordinated operation, customs officers targeted four residences, five companies, and two licensed money service businesses before making the arrests. </p>
<h2>Trio Arrested For Laundering Billions In Crypto</h2>
<p>The trio, consisting of a 42-year-old woman and two men aged 48 and 60, allegedly set up five companies and opened 18 local bank accounts between June 2021 and July 2022. </p>
<p>These companies were reportedly involved in over 1,000 suspicious transactions, receiving funds from undisclosed sources.</p>
<p>Notably, the three arrested suspects did not know each other. The unemployed woman allegedly played a key role in the money laundering, receiving transfers from various companies and crypto <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/schiff-warns-of-bailouts-from-bitcoin-etfs-buyers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">exchanges</a>. </p>
<p>The funds were transferred to other companies or to the two male suspects through licensed money changers.</p>
<p>According to the Customs and Excise Department, the woman managed HK$900 million of the<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/stablecoins-us-senators-unveil-new-regulations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener "> illicit funds</a>, while the 60-year-old driver handled HK$300 million, and the self-employed man dealt with HK$600 million. </p>
<p>Investigations have revealed that the funds originated from a crypto exchange platform and over 200 local and overseas companies. The funds were rapidly transferred to other entities once deposited into the shell companies&#8217; bank accounts.</p>

<p>The shell companies purportedly operated in mobile phone accessories, wholesale machinery, and vehicle parts. However, they engaged in business transactions unrelated to their stated sectors, including agricultural products and food, indicating their role as shell companies. </p>
<p>The operation, code-named &#8220;Racer,&#8221; resulted in the seizure of mobile phones, company documents, stamps, and <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-wins-big-new-us-stablecoin-draft-bill/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">transaction records</a>. Customs confirmed that the source and destination of the funds are still being investigated.</p>
<p>Although the core members of the syndicate are believed to have been apprehended, customs authorities have not ruled out the possibility of further arrests. </p>
<p>The three suspects were arrested on charges of conspiracy to deal with proceeds of an indictable offense, commonly known as money laundering. They have been released on bail but could face a maximum penalty of 14 years imprisonment and a HK$5 million fine if convicted.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/uGlmLwK9/" alt="Crypto" width="1815" height="858" />
<p>Featured image from Shutterstock, chart from TradingView.com </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/shutterstock_download-7-24.jpg?fit=462%2C260" width="462" height="260" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295230</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin HODLers With Zero History Of Selling Just Bought All-Time High Amount</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-hodlers-selling-bought-all-time-high-amount/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Keshav Verma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 23:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin accumulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Accumulation Addresses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Bullish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin HODLers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On-chain data shows the Bitcoin &#8220;accumulation addresses&#8221; have observed all-time high inflows following the latest asset price slump. Bitcoin Accumulation Addresses Have Aggressively Bought The Dip As an analyst in a CryptoQuant Quicktake post pointed out, the total Bitcoin inflows going towards the accumulation addresses have set a new all-time high recently. The &#8220;accumulation addresses&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On-chain data shows the Bitcoin &#8220;accumulation addresses&#8221; have observed all-time high inflows following the latest asset price slump.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Accumulation Addresses Have Aggressively Bought The Dip</h2>
<p>As an analyst in a CryptoQuant Quicktake <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/insights/quicktake/661fd2b12bbda620d3f6123d-Bitcoin-inflows-to-the-Accumulation-Addresses-hit-a-new-all-time-high" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">post</a> pointed out, the total Bitcoin inflows going towards the accumulation addresses have set a new all-time high recently.</p>
<p>The &#8220;<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-bullish-accumulation-addresses-buying-big/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">accumulation addresses</a>&#8221; here refer to wallets that have only a history of receiving transactions and never of sending. This means that these addresses have only purchased coins and have never participated in any selling.</p>

<p>Besides this definition, fewer other restrictions exist for an address to be considered a part of this group. The wallet should have received at least two transfers (as only one transaction wouldn&#8217;t be enough to set the trend one way or another), and its balance should be greater than 10 BTC.</p>
<p>Even if they satisfy these conditions, miners and exchange-associated wallets are still excluded from the group, as they inherently compensate for the sell-side of cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>The accumulation addresses are naturally the opposite of these entities, as these HODLers buy coins and lock them up in their relentless hands, thus effectively removing them from the circulating supply.</p>
<p>There is also one final condition for an address to fall in this category: it must have seen its most recent transfer within the last seven years. Wallets older than this are thought to be lost because of missing keys or just being forgotten, so they don&#8217;t exactly represent the voluntary HODLers of the market.</p>
<p>Now, here is a chart that shows the trend in the Bitcoin inflows going toward these accumulation addresses over the past year:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://i0.wp.com/img.cryptoquant.com/35320/quicktake/7Wyeutlz_0e539fb4ff032ec6e44a81c307a99f3bdb1c5746a0e0565f07b46cbac3a93b56.png?resize=1280%2C806&#038;ssl=1" alt="Bitcoin Accumulation Address Inflow" width="1280" height="806" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>

<p>As the above graph shows, Bitcoin inflows to accumulation addresses have recently achieved a new record. In this spike, 27,700 BTC ($1.75 billion at the current exchange rate) have flowed into the wallets of these perennial HODLers in a single day.</p>
<p>The indicator&#8217;s previous all-time high was witnessed a couple of months ago when the accumulation addresses purchased 25,100 BTC (almost $1.6 billion).</p>
<p>The chart shows that this buying spree occurred during the rally, eventually resulting in BTC touching <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-breaks-through-69000-setting-new-record/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">new highs</a>. As such, the latest strong accumulation from these diamond hands may also be bullish for the asset&#8217;s price.</p>

<p>The chart also shows that the frequency and scale of large purchases from this cohort have been quite extraordinary in recent months.</p>
<p>This trend could be explained by the bullish environment following the approval of spot exchange-traded funds (ETFs) and their buying.</p>
<h2>BTC Price</h2>
<p>Bitcoin briefly slipped below the $60,000 level during the past 24 hours, but the asset has since rebounded back towards $63,500.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium aligncenter" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/cszNLoo1/" alt="Bitcoin Price Chart" width="1534" height="854" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/kanchanara-4KJJezDyo3M-unsplash_263aa0.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295152</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Elon Musk Buying Dogecoin? $45 Million Whale Buy Sparks Speculation In DOGE Community</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/elon-musk-buying-dogecoin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 22:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dogecoin is grabbing headlines and speculation from its wide community of investors after a recent whale accumulation from a crypto exchange. On-chain data shows an accumulation trend from this whale, with the latest being the acquisition of 300 million DOGE tokens worth $45 million at the current market price. These speculations have led to theories [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dogecoin is grabbing headlines and speculation from its wide community of investors after a recent whale accumulation from a crypto exchange. On-chain data shows an accumulation trend from this whale, with the latest being the acquisition of 300 million DOGE tokens worth $45 million at the current market price.</p>
<p>These speculations have led to theories on who the whale buyer might be amidst a continued price decline for Dogecoin, with the most prominent hypothesis being billionaire Elon Musk.</p>
<h2>Whale Accumulating Dogecoin</h2>
<p>Dogecoin is currently on <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/doge/doge-price-prediction-dogecoin-0-12/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">an extended price decline</a>, with its price now down by 25.8% in the past seven days. However, on-chain data shows that a particular whale has been buying the dip, which is a testament to their strong belief in the cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Whale Alerts, a crypto whale transaction tracker, noted a <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/dogecoin-weekly-golden-cross/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">DOGE accumulation</a> from crypto exchange Robinhood into the private wallet &#8220;DDuXGM&#8221; amidst a flurry of <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/dogecoin-whales-800-million-doge/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">other whale transactions</a> in <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-whales-different-behavior-cycles-why/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">other cryptocurrencies</a>. The transaction <a href="https://x.com/whale_alert/status/1780058933421330894" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">involved the movement</a> of 150 million DOGE worth $23.5 million from Robinhood into the unknown wallet.</p>
<p>It is interesting to note that a further investigation into the whale&#8217;s on-chain activities reveals that this was not a one-time buy. The whale had acquired another 150 million and 30 million DOGE tokens worth $23.1 million and $4.8 million respectively in the hours before the last purchase. </p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/elon-musk-latest-tweet-how-much-did-dogecoin-gain-from-it-today/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Elon Musk’s tweets</a> in the hours leading up to the purchase have only fueled speculation that he may be the whale. Just hours before, the billionaire <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1779930431837679625" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">tweeted a meme picture</a> mentioning Dogecoin, which led to some speculations among investors. Musk has been a vocal proponent of Dogecoin for months, and his tweets are known to cause spikes in the price of DOGE. However, it is important to note that his recent tweet failed to do many wonders for the price of DOGE as the crypto continued on its month-lasting correction. </p>
<p>At this point, there are more questions than answers about the mysterious $46 million Dogecoin purchase. Was it indeed Elon Musk or another whale quietly accumulating DOGE? At the time of writing, <a href="https://blockchair.com/dogecoin/address/DDuXGMFNGpGjaAqyDunSMvceMBruc1wwKF" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">this whale address</a> &#8220;DDuXGM&#8221; is holding 2.478 billion DOGE tokens worth $363.6 million.</p>

<p><a href="https://x.com/martypartymusic/status/1780256717798023463" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">According to MartyParty</a>, a prominent crypto influencer, the accumulation could be in response to a recent announcement from BITMAIN, a company producing crypto mining equipment. BITMAIN recently <a href="https://x.com/BITMAINtech/status/1780116184467448288" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">revealed its plans</a> to expand support for DOGE mining after its Antiminer L9 release in May. Bitmain&#8217;s Antiminer L9 model will support mining operations for Litecoin, Dogecoin, and Bells (BEL), which are some of the still-existing proof-of-work blockchains.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, DOGE is trading at $0.144, down by 8.15% in the past 24 hours. <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-major-support-doge/">The significant price correction</a> in the last day means Dogecoin is now in red in a monthly timeframe, and it is now down by 4.55% in the past 30 days. </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/1cy5z5CQ/" alt="Dogecoin price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Elon-Musk-Dogecoin.jpeg?fit=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295160</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Giant Binance Pays Hefty $2M Fine To Reignite India Foothold &#8211; Details</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-giant-binance-pays-hefty-fine-reignite-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Edyme]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance In Dubai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BNB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnbusdt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Changpeng Zhao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Binance, the world&#8217;s leading cryptocurrency exchange, reportedly seeks to re-establish its presence in the Indian market after being banned by the country&#8217;s local government earlier this year. Binance&#8217;s Cost To Return To India According to a recent report from India&#8217;s Economic Times, the exchange intends to return as a registered entity, aiming to comply with the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Binance, the world&#8217;s leading cryptocurrency exchange, <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/technology/binance-coins-a-new-phase-in-india/articleshow/109382161.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">reportedly</a> seeks to re-establish its presence in the Indian market after being banned by the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binances-4-3-billion-settlement-faces-doj-scrutiny/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">country&#8217;s local government</a> earlier this year.</p>
<h2>Binance&#8217;s Cost To Return To India</h2>
<p>According to a recent report from India&#8217;s Economic Times, the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-exchange-founder-charged-money-launder-fraud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">exchange intends</a> to return as a registered entity, aiming to comply with the country&#8217;s anti-money laundering laws and tax regulations.</p>

<p>This strategic move entails paying a hefty $2 million penalty as part of its efforts to &#8220;reform&#8221; its South Asian entity.</p>
<p>Notably, this development follows the<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/india-cracks-down-on-9-overseas-crypto-exchanges/" target="_blank" rel="noopener "> Indian </a>government&#8217;s action against 9 crypto websites, including Binance, in January for their alleged involvement in illegal operations that violated <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/impending-extradition-nigerian-authorities-trace-fleeing-binance-exec-to-kenya-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">local regulations</a>. This crackdown led to the removal of crypto exchange apps from the region&#8217;s Apple and Google stores.</p>
<p>Despite these challenges, Binance South Asia&#8217;s X account noted in January that the exchange remains &#8220;committed to regulatory compliance&#8221; and is working towards full registration with India&#8217;s Financial Intelligence Unit, which oversees digital asset trading activities.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are aware of new changes that have been introduced regarding crypto exchanges on the iOS App Store in India, impacting the Binance App.</p>
<p>The ongoing situation is not unique to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Binance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#Binance</a> and we remain committed to complying with local regulations and maintaining dialogue with…</p>
<p>— Binance South Asia (@BinanceDesi) <a href="https://twitter.com/BinanceDesi/status/1744995162957513194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">January 10, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The exchange also discloses that it seeks to adhere to all applicable regulations, including anti-money laundering measures and tax laws, to ensure a &#8220;smooth re-entry&#8221; into the Indian market.</p>
<h2>Global Expansion And Asset Management Evolution</h2>
<p>The decision to re-enter the Indian market comes amid the exchange&#8217;s <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-clamps-down-a-new-strategy-to-exclude-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">broader strategic shifts</a> and global expansion efforts. Recently, the exchange <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-18/binance-close-to-getting-dubai-vasp-license-after-cz-deal-bnb" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">secured a full crypto license in Dubai</a>, marking its official entry into the Middle Eastern market.</p>
<p>This development follows co-founder Changpeng Zhao&#8217;s agreement to relinquish voting control in the local entity, paving the way for regulatory approval. According to the report, the crypto exchange&#8217;s expansion into Dubai aligns with its vision to establish a &#8220;strong presence&#8221; in key global markets and diversify its geographical footprint.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Binance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#Binance</a> is proud to have received a Virtual Asset Service Provider (VASP) licence from Dubai’s Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority (VARA).</p>
<p>This milestone allows us to extend our services to the retail market alongside qualified and institutional investors.</p>
<p>Read more <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/2935.png" alt="⤵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>— Binance (@binance) <a href="https://twitter.com/binance/status/1780889358444228937?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">April 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The exchange has significantly changed its asset management strategies, notably <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-18/binance-converts-billion-dollar-safu-emergency-fund-into-usdc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">converting its entire Secure Asset Fund for Users (SAFU) into USDC</a>, a stablecoin pegged to the US dollar.</p>

<p>As reported, the SAFU fund, established in 2018 to safeguard user assets during extreme situations, has transitioned to USDC to &#8220;enhance transparency, reliability, and stability.&#8221;</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/tvcMMzdT/" alt="Binance Coin (BNB) price chart on TradingView" width="2770" height="1496" />
<p>Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/CBDC.jpg?fit=634%2C420" width="634" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295181</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
