<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bitcoinist.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 05:05:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/cropped-cropped-cropped-Icon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">225283986</site>	<item>
		<title>VeChain Lands $100 Million Knockout Partnership With UFC &#8211; Details</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/vechain-lands-100-million-deal-with-ufc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 05:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VeChain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=294061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) has landed a heavyweight deal with VeChain, a blockchain logistics firm, in a five-year partnership to the tune of $100 million. This history-making agreement marks UFC&#8217;s first-ever top-level blockchain partnership, while VeChain gains a powerful platform to reach fight fans around the world. Related Reading: Thailand Throws Jab At Crypto [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:329">The Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) has landed a heavyweight deal with VeChain, a blockchain logistics firm, in a five-year partnership to the tune of $100 million. This history-making agreement marks UFC&#8217;s first-ever top-level blockchain partnership, while VeChain gains a powerful platform to reach fight fans around the world.</p>

<h2 data-sourcepos="5:1-5:378"><strong>UFC Flexes Financial Muscle</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="5:1-5:378"><a href="https://www.forbesindia.com/article/crypto-made-easy/vechain-signs-a-100-mn-sponsorship-deal-with-ufc/77231/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">This strategic alliance</a> injects a significant revenue boost for UFC, exceeding their previous sponsorship records according to UFC&#8217;s senior vice president of global partnerships, Paul Asencio. The deal also positions the MMA giant at the forefront of a burgeoning trend, as the cryptocurrency and blockchain industry continues its meteoric rise.</p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="7:1-7:537"><strong>VeChain Poised For Global Exposure</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:537">For VeChain, the partnership presents a golden opportunity. Their brand will be thrust into the global spotlight, reaching an estimated 900 million television households across 175 countries.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:537">This unprecedented exposure will be amplified through prominent placement within UFC events, including branding on the iconic Octagon canvas and digital displays. The blockchain firm will also co-create content with UFC for their digital platforms, further solidifying their presence in the combat sports landscape.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:537"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-294062" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_60e1b5.png?resize=956%2C527" alt="" width="956" height="527" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_60e1b5.png?resize=956%2C527?w=956 956w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_60e1b5.png?resize=956%2C527?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_60e1b5.png?resize=956%2C527?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_60e1b5.png?resize=956%2C527?w=750 750w" sizes="(max-width: 956px) 100vw, 956px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>




<strong>A Deeper Dive Into The Partnership</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:442">This partnership goes beyond simple logo placements. VeChain&#8217;s branding will be woven into the very fabric of UFC events. The &#8220;official blockchain partner&#8221; will see their logo displayed prominently within the Octagon, the center stage for all UFC fights. This constant visual reminder will serve as a powerful marketing tool for VeChain, keeping their name at the forefront of fight fans&#8217; minds.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:442"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/X4qEjBaf/" width="1835" height="883" /></p>

<p data-sourcepos="13:1-13:375">The partnership extends beyond branding and content creation. An annual &#8220;Brand Ambassador Fund&#8221; will offer paid opportunities for UFC athletes to participate in VeChain marketing initiatives. This innovative approach leverages the immense popularity of UFC fighters to further amplify the company&#8217;s reach and connect with a passionate fanbase.</p>
<strong>Not UFC&#8217;s First Crypto Dance</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:513">This isn&#8217;t UFC&#8217;s first foray into the world of cryptocurrency. They previously partnered with Crypto.com, a leading crypto exchange, which resulted in fan bonuses being awarded in Bitcoin. Additionally, UFC collaborated with NFT creator Dapper Labs to release a series of officially licensed non-fungible tokens (NFTs).</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:513">These ventures demonstrate UFC&#8217;s willingness to embrace innovative technologies and explore new revenue streams within the ever-evolving financial landscape.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="17:1-17:513">The partnership signifies a pivotal moment in the convergence of professional sports and blockchain technology. As VeChain leverages UFC&#8217;s massive global audience, this deal has the potential to not only propel VeChain&#8217;s brand recognition but also educate fight fans about the possibilities of blockchain technology.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="17:1-17:513"><em>Featured image from UFC, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_c9dc5b.jpg?fit=632%2C420" width="632" height="420" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">294061</article-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First-Ever Conviction For Crypto Smart Contract Hacking: Nirvana Exploiter Sentenced To 3 Years</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/first-conviction-for-crypto-smart-contract-hacking/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 04:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto exploit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto hackers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto hacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nirvana Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US crypto regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=294008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After orchestrating a series of hacks on two decentralized cryptocurrency exchanges (DEXs) that stole more than $12 million worth of crypto, former security engineer Shakeeb Ahmed was sentenced today to three years in prison, this is the first-ever smart contract hacking conviction in the US.  Ahmed was also ordered to forfeit the stolen crypto and pay [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After orchestrating a series of hacks on two decentralized cryptocurrency exchanges (DEXs) that stole more than $12 million worth of crypto, former security engineer Shakeeb Ahmed was <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdny/pr/former-security-engineer-sentenced-three-years-prison-hacking-two-decentralized" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">sentenced</a> today to three years in prison, this is the first-ever smart contract hacking conviction in the US. </p>
<p>Ahmed was also ordered to forfeit the stolen crypto and pay restitution to the affected exchanges.</p>
<h2>Engineer Exploits Crypto Vulnerabilities In $12 Million Hacks</h2>
<p>According to charging documents and court filings, Ahmed conducted two separate attacks on<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/digitex-futures-exchange-ceo-faces-criminal-charges/" target="_blank" rel="noopener "> decentralized exchanges</a>. In the first incident, which took place on July 2 and 3, 2022, he manipulated fake pricing data to generate approximately $9 million in inflated fees. Subsequently, Ahmed withdrew these fees in the form of cryptocurrency. </p>
<p>Following the theft, Ahmed communicated with the exchange, offering to return the stolen funds, except $1.5 million, if the exchange did not involve law enforcement.</p>

<p>Shortly after, on July 28, 2022, Ahmed targeted another decentralized exchange called Nirvana Finance. Exploiting a vulnerability in Nirvana&#8217;s <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/former-binance-ceo-faces-delay-in-sentencing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">smart contracts</a>, he purchased crypto assets at a lower price than intended and promptly resold them back to Nirvana at a higher price. </p>
<p>Despite Nirvana offering a substantial &#8220;bug bounty&#8221; of up to $600,000 for the return of the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/cybercriminals-make-off-with-81-million-orbit-hack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">stolen funds</a>, Ahmed demanded $1.4 million. This led to the collapse of the exchange, which had lost all its possessed funds, approximately $3.6 million, due to Ahmed&#8217;s attack.</p>
<h2>From Security Expert To Cybercriminal</h2>
<p>The investigation revealed that Ahmed used &#8220;advanced money laundering techniques” to conceal the source and ownership of the stolen funds. </p>
<p>These included token swap transactions, transferring fraud proceeds from the Solana (SOL) <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ftx-bankman-fried-accused-of-criminal-by-ellison/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">blockchain </a>to the Ethereum (ETH) blockchain through &#8220;bridging,&#8221; converting the funds to Monero, and then using overseas exchanges and cryptocurrency mixers such as Samourai Whirlpool.</p>
<p>Ahmed, a US citizen, held a senior security engineer position at an international technology company at the time of the attacks. His resume showcased expertise in reverse engineering smart contracts and conducting <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/sam-bankman-fried-guilty-on-7-criminal-counts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">blockchain audits</a>, skills that he utilized to execute the hacks. </p>

<p>In addition to the three-year prison term, Ahmed was sentenced to three years of supervised release. He must forfeit approximately $12.3 million, including a significant amount of cryptocurrency, and pay the affected exchanges over $5 million in restitution. Commenting on Shakeeb Ahmed&#8217;s sentencing, US Attorney Damian Williams said </p>
<blockquote><p>Today, Shakeeb Ahmed was sentenced to prison in the first-ever conviction for the hack of a smart contract and ordered to forfeit all of the stolen crypto.  No matter how novel or sophisticated the hack, this Office and our law enforcement partners are committed to following the money and bringing hackers to justice.  And as today’s sentence shows, time in prison — and forfeiture of all the stolen crypto — is the inevitable consequence of such destructive hacks.</p></blockquote>
<img decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/V3V7ubR6/" alt="Crypto" width="1815" height="858" />
<p>Featured image from Shutterstock, chart from TradingView.com </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Downloader.la-661973ccf03e0.jpg?fit=633%2C420" width="633" height="420" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">294008</article-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Firms $104 Million Collapse: Australian Watchdog After Two Unlicensed Companies</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-firms-104-million-collapse-australian-watchdog-after-two-unlicensed-companies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rubmar Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 03:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia crypto adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[australian crypto firms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[australian regulator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Funds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto mining firms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=294007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to local reports, the Australian Securities and Investment Commission (ASIC) has started legal procedures against two crypto companies and their directors for operating unlicensed in the country. Allegedly, the companies participated in an elaborate scheme that resulted in the loss of AU$ 160 million, worth $104 million, from investors. Related Reading: Hong Kong Set [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400;">According to local reports, the Australian Securities and Investment Commission (ASIC) has started legal procedures against two crypto companies and their directors for operating <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/red-flag-for-etoro-philippines-investigates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">unlicensed</a> in the country. Allegedly, the companies participated in an elaborate scheme that resulted in the loss of AU$ 160 million, worth $104 million, from investors.</p>

<h2 style="font-weight: 400;">ASIC After Unlicensed Mining Companies</h2>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Australian regulator commenced civil procedures against the NGS Group companies and their directors, Brett Mendham, Ryan brown, and Mark Ten Caten. The NGS Blockchain crypto mining companies include NGS Crypto, NGS Digital, and NGS Group.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">ASIC <a href="https://asic.gov.au/about-asic/news-centre/find-a-media-release/2024-releases/24-073mr-asic-obtains-federal-court-orders-appointing-receivers-over-digital-currency-assets-of-blockchain-mining-companies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">alleges</a> that the NGS companies targeted Australian investors to acquire blockchain mining packages with a fixed-rate return. The regulator also accuses the companies of allegedly encouraging investors to use self-managed super funds (SMSFs) and convert the money into crypto.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">According to the NGS Crypto <a href="https://ngscrypto.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">website</a>, the company was formed in 2018 as a blockchain firm. As part of the NGS Group, the firm “aims to help members generate consistent returns.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Australian regulator stated in their press release that these financial services are being provided without the proper licensing. Due to this, ASIC is seeking “interim and final injunctions against the NGS Companies.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"> ASIC Chair Joe Longo urged Australian users to consider the risks involving self-managing the SMSFs before using the funds to invest in crypto-related investment products like those offered by the NGS Group.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Moreover, ASIC’s Chair warned the industry about the regulator’s standard to scrutinize crypto products:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">These proceedings should also send a message to the crypto industry that products will continue to be scrutinised by ASIC to ensure they comply with regulatory obligations in order to protect consumers.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Australian regulator applied to the Federal Court to designate liquidators responsible for the companies’ digital assets. The request was made because the regulator believed the investor’s assets were “at risk of dissipation.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Wednesday, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/us-sec-faces-another-legal-blow-ripple-clo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">the court</a> approved the request and prevented Mendham from leaving the country. The preliminary investigations revealed that over 450 Australians invested AU$62 million, approximately $41 million, through the NGS Companies.</p>
<h2 style="font-weight: 400;">Crypto Funds Busted For Irregularities</h2>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Similarly, over 100 investors are owed over AUD$ 100 million, around $64.6 million, by the now-collapsing DCA Capital, Digital Commodity Assets, and the Digital Commodity Assets Fund.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Recently, investigations started after investors denounced the crypto funds operated by Ash Balanian, an alleged former NASA mission scientist. As a result, liquidators were appointed to the three companies managed by Balanian.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Per the <a href="https://www.theage.com.au/national/victoria/up-to-150-million-at-risk-as-two-aussie-bitcoin-schemes-go-bust-20240411-p5fj62.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report</a>, the fund was geared at wealthy investors, requiring a minimum deposit of AU$ 50,000. Investors discovered irregularities in the fund’s management, which resulted in the authorities’ involvement.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Numerous investors were concerned as they considered that <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/australian-asset-manager-to-launch-bitcoin-etf-on-cboe-in-q2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">the funds</a> failed to hold the required licenses and &#8220;breached managed investment scheme requirements.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Wednesday, the Australian Federal Court ordered the freezing of Balanian’s assets, worth AU$55 million, and the crypto fund manager to hand over his passport.</p>

<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-294011 aligncenter" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL_2024-04-12_08-13-31.png?w=980&#038;resize=980%2C473" alt="crypto, total crypto market cap" width="980" height="473" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL_2024-04-12_08-13-31.png?w=1064 1064w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL_2024-04-12_08-13-31.png?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL_2024-04-12_08-13-31.png?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL_2024-04-12_08-13-31.png?w=980&#038;resize=980%2C473 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL_2024-04-12_08-13-31.png?w=750 750w" sizes="(max-width: 980px) 100vw, 980px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/caleb-JmuyB_LibRo-unsplash.jpeg?fit=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">294007</article-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Litecoin Belief: 62.5% Of All LTC Investors Are HODLers</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/litecoin-belief-62-5-of-all-ltc-investors-hodlers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Keshav Verma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 02:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Litecoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[litecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin Belief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin Bullish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin Conviction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin HODLers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin Long-Term Holders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin Milestone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ltcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On-chain data shows that Litecoin&#8217;s long-term holders have achieved a new record: 62.5% of all LTC investors now qualify as these HODLers. There Are Now More Than Five Million Litecoin Long-Term Holders According to data from the market intelligence platform IntoTheBlock, the LTC network recently reached a new milestone in terms of its long-term holder [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On-chain data shows that Litecoin&#8217;s long-term holders have achieved a new record: 62.5% of all LTC investors now qualify as these HODLers.</p>
<h2>There Are Now More Than Five Million Litecoin Long-Term Holders</h2>
<p>According to data from the market intelligence platform <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1778713110355788129" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IntoTheBlock</a>, the LTC network recently reached a new milestone in terms of its long-term holder count.</p>
<p>The &#8220;<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/hodling-steady-bitcoin-long-term-holder-supply-ath/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">long-term holders</a>&#8221; (LTHs) here refer to Bitcoin investors who have held their coins for more than a year without moving or selling them. Note that IntoTheBlock chose this cutoff; other analytics firms have an LTH threshold between 5 and 6 months.</p>

<p>Statistically, the longer an investor holds onto their coins, the less likely they become to sell at any point. As such, the LTHs, who hold for relatively long periods, are considered to carry a strong resolve.</p>
<p>Historically, the LTHs rarely show selling activity, regardless of whatever happens in the rest of the market. The fickle-minded part of the sector that holds for relatively low timespans is called the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-short-term-holders-4-5-profits-nov-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">short-term holder</a> (STH) group.</p>
<p>Participating STHs in selloffs isn&#8217;t uncommon; it happens whenever significant volatility emerges, whether in the form of a rally or crash. On the other hand, it can be a notable event when the LTHs sell.</p>
<p>One way to track the behavior of the LTHs is through the total number of addresses that qualify for the cohort. Below is the chart shared by the analytics firm that reveals the trend in this metric for Litecoin since the start of the year.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GK9B71dW4AEpU2w?format=jpg&amp;name=large" alt="Bitcoin Long-Term Holders" width="1716" height="426" /></p>

<p>As displayed in the above graph, the number of Litecoin LTH addresses has grown significantly over the last few months and has now reached the 5 million mark.</p>
<p>This means that more than five million LTC wallets haven&#8217;t made any move since at least a year ago. This corresponds to 62.5% of all addresses on the blockchain currently carrying some non-zero balance.</p>
<p>This is a significant amount and suggests that most of the holder base has been interested in HODLing the cryptocurrency. Naturally, supply staying locked in the wallets of these diamond hands can be bullish due to how supply-demand dynamics tend to play out.</p>

<p>Remember that any increases in the LTH addresses don&#8217;t imply that HODLers are currently buying Litecoin. Rather, it suggests that some investors acquired coins a year ago, and they have only now been able to qualify for the group.</p>
<p>Thus, the metric has a delay of 1 year attached between when <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-bullish-accumulation-addresses-buying-big/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">accumulation</a> happened and when it registers an increase. Selling doesn&#8217;t carry the same restriction, as investors are immediately ejected from the cohort if they transfer their coins on the network.</p>
<h2>LTC Price</h2>
<p>Litecoin has continued to trade inside a range recently, as its price is currently floating around $95.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium aligncenter" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/w3FAP2CO/" alt="Litecoin Price Chart" width="1534" height="854" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/michael-fortsch-fYSVVQqiqPs-unsplash.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293961</article-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Maxi Slams Ethereum ETF: Calls It A &#8216;Proof-of-Stake Scam&#8217; Unfit For SEC Approval</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-maxi-slams-ethereum-etf-call-proof-of-stake/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Edyme]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 01:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spot ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spot Ethereum ETF]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Ethereum (ETH) community has continued to eagerly await news on approving a spot Ethereum Exchange-Traded Fund (ETF) slated to occur by May. However, as the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) maintains a conspicuous silence on the matter, speculation has risen on the likelihood of the approval. This speculation is further fuelled by the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Ethereum (ETH) community has continued to eagerly await news on approving a spot Ethereum Exchange-Traded Fund (ETF) slated to occur by May.</p>
<p>However, as the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) maintains a conspicuous silence on the matter, speculation has risen on the<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/sec-delays-decision-on-grayscales-ethereum-etf-here/" target="_blank" rel="noopener "> likelihood of the approval</a>.</p>
<p>This speculation is further fuelled by the scarcity of concrete details regarding the approval process, leaving investors and enthusiasts worried and anticipating.</p>

<h2>Bitcoin Maxi Weighs In Ethereum Spot ETF Approval</h2>
<p>In the spot Ethereum ETF debate, notable voices from the cryptocurrency space have offered their perspectives.</p>
<p>Renowned Bitcoin maximalist and advisor to the president of El Salvador, Max Keiser, has recently <a href="https://twitter.com/maxkeiser/status/1778571668887093517?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">expressed</a> skepticism regarding the SEC&#8217;s cautious approach to <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/spot-ethereum-etf-delay-is-a-good-thing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">approving an Ethereum ETF</a>.</p>
<p>Keiser, known for his staunch advocacy of Bitcoin and skepticism towards alternative cryptocurrencies, dismissed Ethereum as a &#8220;proof-of-stake scam,&#8221; suggesting it lacks the regulatory backing necessary for SEC approval.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The SEC is right not to approve an Ethereum (ETH) ETF</p>
<p>It’s a proof-of-stake scam that fails on all requirements the SEC would look for. <a href="https://t.co/nLz8boTGtW" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">https://t.co/nLz8boTGtW</a></p>
<p>— Max Keiser (@maxkeiser) <a href="https://twitter.com/maxkeiser/status/1778571668887093517?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">April 11, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Keiser&#8217;s sentiment echoes that of Bloomberg’s Senior ETF Analyst, Eric Balchunas, who also recently shared a conservative outlook on the likelihood of an ETH spot ETF receiving regulatory approval.</p>
<p>Balchunas estimated the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-spot-etf-expert-predicts-approval-odds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">chances of approval at a mere 25%</a>, further fueling uncertainty surrounding the prospect of an Ethereum ETF.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Re Eth ETF approval, we are holding the line at 25% odds altho tbh it is a very pessimistic 25%. The lack of engagement seems to be purposeful vs procrastination. No positive signs/intel anywhere you look. Personally hope they do approve it but it just ain&#8217;t looking good. <a href="https://t.co/nuBdCDE18L" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">https://t.co/nuBdCDE18L</a></p>
<p>— Eric Balchunas (@EricBalchunas) <a href="https://twitter.com/EricBalchunas/status/1772372601098162624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">March 25, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Additionally, VanEck CEO Jan <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/spot-ethereum-etfs-unlikely-get-sec-approval/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Van Eck expressed anticipation of a potential rejection</a> of their Ethereum ETF application, citing prolonged regulatory reviews and lack of clarity from the SEC.</p>
<h2>Spot ETH ETF Gains Regulatory Interest Overseas</h2>
<p>Amidst the uncertainty surrounding the US SEC&#8217;s stance on Ethereum ETFs, reports suggest a contrasting regulatory environment in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/h-k-seen-approving-bitcoin-ether-etfs-as-soon-as-monday-1.2058422" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a>, Hong Kong regulators may soon <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/hong-kong-greenlight-spot-bitcoin-ether-etfs-monday/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">approve exchange-traded funds investing directly in Bitcoin and Ethereum</a>, signaling a potential shift in global regulatory attitudes towards cryptocurrency investment products.</p>
<p>If approved, these ETFs could offer investors new avenues for exposure to the digital asset market. Several firms are poised to launch ETFs pending regulatory clearance from the Securities and Futures Commission.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/w1mVWV3y/" alt="Ethereum (ETH) price chart on TradingView" width="2770" height="1496" />
<p>Among the prospective issuers awaiting approval are international arms of Chinese asset manager Harvest Fund Management Co. and a partnership between Bosera Asset Management (International) Co. and HashKey Capital.</p>

<p>Upon receiving regulatory approval, these firms have indicated their intent to launch ETFs investing in BTC and ETH, highlighting the growing demand for cryptocurrency investment products in global markets.</p>
<p>Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Ethereum-Bullish-Outlook.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293993</article-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pro-XRP Lawyer Deaton Takes The Lead, Outpacing Warren In Pivotal Senate Contest</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-lawyer-deaton-takes-lead-outpacing-warren/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pro-XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pro-XRP lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro-XRP lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple (XRP)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple Chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple news XRP news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[John Deaton, a pro-XRP lawyer and crypto advocate, is running for a seat in the US Senate against Elizabeth Warren, known for her skepticism on cryptocurrencies, when US regulators are stepping up their enforcement actions and crackdowns on the crypto industry. Notably, Deaton&#8217;s campaign has gained significant support from industry leaders, indicating a growing demand [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>John Deaton, a pro-XRP lawyer and crypto advocate, is running for a seat in the US Senate against <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-deaton-sen-warren-cover-up-sbf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Elizabeth Warren</a>, known for her skepticism on cryptocurrencies, when US regulators are stepping up their enforcement actions and crackdowns on the crypto industry.</p>
<p>Notably, Deaton&#8217;s campaign has gained significant support from industry leaders, indicating a growing demand for change in crypto regulation frameworks and a shift in approach towards the industry.</p>
<h2>Crypto Industry Backs Pro-XRP Lawyer’s Senate Campaign</h2>
<p>According to a local <a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/2024/04/12/nation/john-deaton-loans-campaign-1-million-against-elizabeth-warren/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report </a>from Boston, Deaton, running as a Republican candidate, has personally loaned his campaign $1 million, showcasing his commitment to his uphill battle against Senator Warren. </p>
<p>Since announcing his candidacy in mid-February, Deaton has also raised $360,690 from individual contributors, leaving him with nearly $1.4 million cash on hand. </p>

<p>According to the Federal Election Commission, Deaton <a href="https://x.com/EleanorTerrett/status/1778797246751904135" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">outraised </a>Warren in the race&#8217;s first quarter, with Deaton raising a total of $1.36 million to Warren&#8217;s $1.1 million.   </p>
<p>Notable donations have come from influential figures such as <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/cardano-chief-backs-xrp-lawyer-deaton/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Charles Hoskinson</a>, co-founder of Ethereum; Anthony Scaramucci, former communications director for Donald Trump and vocal crypto investor; and Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss, co-founders of Gemini exchange.</p>
<p><a href="https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-attorney-deaton-worries-sen-warren/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Ripple</a> CEO Brad Garlinghouse and the company&#8217;s executive chairman and co-founder, Chris Larsen, also <a href="https://x.com/sentosumosaba/status/1778792881123426753" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">contributed</a> the maximum $6,600 each, split between the primary and general election campaigns, underscoring Deaton&#8217;s support from key industry players. </p>
<p>However, it should be noted that Deaton faces a challenging campaign against Warren, who has a significant financial advantage with $4.4 million in her campaign <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-lawyer-coinbase-sec-today/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">war chest</a>. This solidifies her position as the &#8220;heavy favorite&#8221; to win the Senate battle against the pro-XRP attorney in what is considered a &#8220;reliably blue state.&#8221;</p>
<h2>High-Stakes Senate Race</h2>
<p>A spokesperson for Warren emphasized that her campaign is powered by “small-dollar donations,” emphasizing grassroots support rather than “special interests attempting to elevate candidates.” </p>
<p>Nevertheless, Deaton&#8217;s challenge against Warren extends beyond a political rivalry, representing the ongoing debate surrounding the role of cryptocurrencies and their <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-lawyer-deaton-sec-us-interests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">regulation</a> in the United States. </p>
<p>Deaton has previously stated, &#8220;Regular people are sick and tired of different rules being applied to Washington insiders. We need real leadership in Washington, DC.&#8221;</p>
<p>Deaton, an ex-US Naval officer from Detroit who attended Eastern Michigan University and New England Law Boston, moved to Massachusetts from Rhode Island in late January, shortly before he announced his Senate candidacy. </p>

<p>While Warren&#8217;s record of service and establishment support pose significant challenges, the crypto industry&#8217;s endorsement and call for change, coupled with the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/john-deaton-prefers-two-cryptos-over-xrp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">growing adoption</a> of cryptocurrencies, gives Deaton significant leverage in his campaign. </p>
<p>The outcome of this high-profile race will not only determine a political representative but also shape the future of cryptocurrency regulation in the United States.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/nrTLfWex/" alt="XRP" width="1815" height="858" />
<p>As of this writing, XRP is trading at $0.59, marking a significant drop in value over the past month. The cryptocurrency has seen losses of up to 12.4% over the past 30 days.</p>
<p>Featured image from iStock, chart from TradingView.com </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Downloader.la-66195f1893226.jpg?fit=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293994</article-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Analyst Says Dogecoin Is Poised To Run 100% To $0.4, Here’s When</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-run-100-to-0-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 22:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Dogecoin price has continued to trend around the $0.19-$0.2 level after encountering significant resistance from the bears at this level. This has caused a suppressed price action over the last week, stopping the meme coin’s advancement in its tracks. However, the outlook still remains bullish for the DOGE price, with crypto analysts expecting the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p2">The <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-whales-doge-price/">Dogecoin price</a> has continued to trend around the $0.19-$0.2 level after encountering significant resistance from the bears at this level. This has caused a suppressed price action over the last week, stopping the meme coin’s advancement in its tracks. However, the outlook still remains bullish for the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-ethereum-shiba-inu/">DOGE price</a>, with crypto analysts expecting the rally to continue soon and the price to double.</p>
<h2 class="p2">Dogecoin Forms Bull Flag Pattern</h2>
<p class="p2">The Dogecoin performance over the past month has been quite encouraging, and despite hitting a roadblock with its rally, it has continued to show bullish tendencies. The most recent of the bullish moves which the meme coin has pulled is the formation of a bull flag pattern on its chart.</p>

<p class="p2">Crypto analyst Trader Tardigrade <a href="https://x.com/TATrader_Alan/status/1778346751109251372" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">revealed</a> in an X (formerly Twitter) article that the cryptocurrency’s chart had showed something interesting on the daily chart. According to the analysis, the movements that Dogecoin has made over the last few weeks has led to a bull flag formation on the daily chart.</p>
<p class="p2">Now, the main driver of the rally that is supposed to follow this formation is the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-mvrv-ratio-negative/">DOGE price</a> breaking out from the bull flag, which is yet to happen. But as the crypto analyst explains, a breakout from here would send Dogecoin’s price at least 2x higher than its current level.</p>
<p class="p2">A successful break above the $0.205 level would confirm this bullish formation. However, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-shiba-inu-price-red/">DOGE</a> has been unable to achieve this, still <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-stalls-at-0-2-doge/">trading below $0.2 at the time of writing</a>. This could also be a hard-won battle for the meme coin as Bitcoin’s uncertain moves continue to drag the crypto market down.</p>
<h2 class="p2">When Will DOGE Make This Move?</h2>
<p class="p2">The month of April is expected to be bullish for the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-pepe-wif-meme-coin/">Dogecoin price</a>, and the crypto analyst’s price shows this. The expected timeframe for the bullish breakout is sometime this month, which would put it in the next few weeks. Trader Tardigrade’s target shows an over 100% increase from the current price level, reaching as high as $0.4 in the short term.</p>

<p class="p2">This move could be spurred on by the Bitcoin halving happening this month, which is expected to propel bullish sentiment. Expectations for the Bitcoin price are that it will reach $80,000, and this move would no doubt pull up the rest of the crypto market, causing coins like Dogecoin to surge.</p>
<p class="p2">At the time of writing, the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-doge-sights-on-0-3/">DOGE price</a> was trending at $0.19, with a 1.61% decrease in the last 24 hours. However, on the weekly time frame, its price is up 14%, coming in second to <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/toncoin-flips-cardano-dogecoin/">Toncoin (TON)</a> for the best performer in the top 10.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/1ze4VtsH/" alt="Dogecoin price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Dogecoin-price.png?fit=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293907</article-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance-backed Gopax Exchange Makes Strides: Revenue Soars 97% Despite Challenges</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/binance-backed-gopax-exchange-makes-strides-reven/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Edyme]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 21:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BNB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnbusdt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gopax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Streami]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A recent financial report from Streami, the parent company of Gopax, revealed that the South Korean cryptocurrency exchange experienced significant revenue growth and a notable reduction in net losses in 2023. Gopax&#8217;s Revenue Surge And Net Loss Reduction Despite challenges related to liquidity issues and regulatory scrutiny, Gopax narrowed its net loss to 51.3 billion [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent financial <a href="https://dart.fss.or.kr/dsaf001/main.do?rcpNo=20240412001438" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report</a> from Streami, the parent company of Gopax, revealed that the South Korean cryptocurrency exchange experienced significant revenue growth and a notable reduction in net losses in 2023.</p>
<h2>Gopax&#8217;s Revenue Surge And Net Loss Reduction</h2>
<p>Despite challenges related to liquidity issues and regulatory scrutiny, Gopax narrowed its net loss to 51.3 billion Korean won ($37 million) last year, compared to 90.6 billion won in the previous year.</p>
<p>The financial report further showcased Gopax&#8217;s notable performance in 2023, with a roughly 97% year-over-year growth in revenue, reaching 3.1 billion won. Additionally, the exchange reduced its net operating loss by 78% to approximately 17 billion won.</p>
<p>As reported, these positive results were largely attributed to the resurgence of bullish sentiment in the South Korean crypto market, which emerged as one of the <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-12-05/korean-crypto-traders-influence-jumps-as-won-overtakes-dollar-during-rally" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">&#8220;most active&#8221; crypto markets globally</a> in 2023.</p>
<p>Despite its revenue growth, Gopax encountered notable hurdles, particularly regarding its association with Genesis Global Capital, which had a subsequent halt of withdrawals stemming from a liquidity crisis associated with its involvement in FTX in 2022.</p>
<p>The situation resulted in substantial losses for Gopax, with funds from its GoFi-linked debt stuck in Genesis Global Capital, totaling 63.7 billion won. However, Binance, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-reopens-south-koreas-crypto-market-gopax/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Gopax&#8217;s major shareholder, stepped in to address liquidity issues</a> and &#8220;acquired&#8221; the exchange in February 2023, aiming to penetrate the South Korean market.</p>
<p>According to the report, Binance&#8217;s acquisition positioned the global exchange as the largest shareholder in Gopax, holding a 67.45% stake.</p>
<h2>Binance&#8217;s Global Challenges And Resilience</h2>
<p>However, Binance itself has been navigating regulatory challenges from several corners globally. Among these challenges is the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/changpeng-zhao-ordered-to-surrender-passport/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">$4.3 billion fine settlement</a> with the US Department of Justice and even the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-executive-case-in-nigeria-postponed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">crackdown from the Nigerian government</a>.</p>
<p>Additionally, the crypto exchange has recently <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-users-philippines-face-access-restriction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">faced a ban from the Philippines Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</a>. As <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/all-crypto-lost-binance-users-cant-retrieve-funds-after-philippines-sec-ban/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">reported</a>, the SEC’s decision was based on Binance’s failure to obtain the necessary license from the commission to operate as an investment and trading platform in the region.</p>
<p>SEC Chairman Emilio Aquino noted:</p>
<blockquote><p>The SEC has identified the aforementioned [Binance] platform and concluded that the public’s continued access to these websites/apps poses a threat to the security of the funds of investing  Filipinos.</p></blockquote>
<p>In response to these regulatory hurdles globally, Binance&#8217;s CEO, Richard Teng, recently<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-ceo-drops-bombshell-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener "> outlined a new strategy focused on addressing</a> &#8220;cultural issues&#8221; and &#8220;enhancing compliance efforts.&#8221;</p>

<p>Notably, despite all of these challenges Binance has faced recently, the exchange&#8217;s native token, BNB, has maintained its trading value above $600, boasting green days up by 6.6% in the past 7 days and 2.2% in the past 24 hours with a current market price of $612.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/LzfndZ96/" alt="BNB price chart on TradingView amid Gopax news" width="2770" height="1496" />
<p>Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Retail-Traders-Fuel-February-Crypto-Rally.webp?fit=509%2C339" width="509" height="339" /><article-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293962</article-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
