<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bitcoinist.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:33:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/cropped-cropped-cropped-Icon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">225283986</site>	<item>
		<title>Ethereum Spot ETF Saga: Grayscale Takes Bold Step With S-3 Form Filing</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/grayscale-files-3-form-for-spot-ethereum-etf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Godspower Owie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ARK Invest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin ETFs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eleanor Terrett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETFs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum Exchange-Traded Funds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum Trust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fox Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GBTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grayscale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hashdex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Invesco Galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mini Ethereum ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mini-Me Spot Bitcoin ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYSE Arca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Securities Act of 1933]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Van Eck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As optimism around Ethereum Spot Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs) continues to dwindle, Grayscale Investments, the world&#8217;s leading digital asset manager, has filed an S-3 Registration Statement for its Ethereum Trust, marking a major advancement in its Ether investment services. Grayscale Ethereum Trust Sets Stage For Growth Popular Fox Business journalist Eleanor Terrett reported that the company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As optimism around <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/spot-ethereum-etf-delay-is-a-good-thing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Ethereum Spot Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs)</a> continues to dwindle, Grayscale Investments, the world&#8217;s leading digital asset manager, has filed an S-3 Registration Statement for its Ethereum Trust, marking a major advancement in its Ether investment services.</p>
<h2>Grayscale Ethereum Trust Sets Stage For Growth</h2>
<p>Popular Fox Business journalist Eleanor Terrett <a href="https://x.com/EleanorTerrett/status/1782863981759074459" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">reported</a> that the company filed the S-3 registration statement with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), requesting to convert its Ethereum Trust into a spot ETH ETF. </p>

<p>According to Terrett, Grayscale&#8217;s Ethereum Trust product is already registered with the SEC, thus, it does not need to file an S-1 form like other ETH ETF issuers or applicants such as Van Eck, Blackrock, Ark Invest, Hashdex, Invesco Galaxy.</p>
<p>With the recent filing, Grayscale has now submitted all the necessary paperwork for the regulatory watchdog to consider its ETH ETF application and provide a ruling. However, the document has not yet been made accessible to the general public.</p>
<p>Terret also reported that the asset firm has filed for an S-1 mini Ethereum ETF under the ticker ETH, similar to that of its Bitcoin mini-me ETF filed under the ticker BTC. In March, the asset manager applied to the SEC for approval to spin out a portion of GBTC shares in order to launch the new mini-me BTC ETF.</p>
<p>Specifically, Grayscale came up with the strategy to halt its ever-increasing <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/back-to-back-negative-bitcoin-etf-flows/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">GBTC outflows</a> since the approval of BTC ETFs in the US. However, the mini-me Bitcoin ETF has yet to receive a green light from the agency.</p>
<h2>ETF Shares To Be Listed On NYSE Arca</h2>
<p>It is noteworthy that the company filed the S-3 form with the Commission under the Securities Act of 1933. The firm made the move after NYSE Arca filed Form 19b-4 for the Grayscale Ethereum Trust.</p>

<p>With the approval of NYSE Arca&#8217;s application on form 19b-4 to list shares and the effectiveness of form S-3 to register the shares, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/grayscale-unveils-new-staking-focused-income-fund/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Grayscale</a> plans to list its ETH ETF on NYSE Arca under the ticker ETHE and issue shares continuously. These shares will be made available solely through a prospectus method.</p>
<p>Although the shares have been registered with the SEC through a registration statement, they have not yet been deemed operational. Prior to when the registration statement takes effect, neither the shares nor purchase bids may be accepted, and any sale of these shares will be deemed unlawful.</p>
<p>By submitting the S-3 registration statement, Grayscale hopes to improve regulatory compliance and lucidity for its <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-fees-lowest-since-january-bottom-signal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">ETH</a> Trust. As a result, it will provide prospective investors with more assurance and clarity when negotiating the intricacies of cryptocurrency investments. </p>
<p>This move demonstrates Grayscale&#8217;s proactive response to the rising demand from institutional and retail investors for Ethereum exposure, enhancing its stand as a leader in the digital asset market.</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/ijeRA2sP/" alt="Ethereum" width="2273" height="1351" />

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/iStock-1414797199.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296319</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogecoin Contributor Issues Critical Alert On Memecoins</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-contributor-alert-on-memecoins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a nuanced critique published on X, a prominent Dogecoin contributor known as @Mishaboar has issued a significant warning concerning the trading of meme coins, especially those that secure listings on cryptocurrency exchanges almost immediately after their release. The contributor, who is a key figure within the Dogecoin community, used his platform to outline the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a nuanced critique published on X, a prominent Dogecoin contributor known as @Mishaboar has issued a significant warning concerning the trading of meme coins, especially those that secure listings on cryptocurrency exchanges almost immediately after their release. The contributor, who is a key figure within the Dogecoin community, used his platform to outline the potential pitfalls that unsuspecting investors might face.</p>
<h2>The Risks Of Memecoins</h2>
<p>@Mishaboar <a href="https://twitter.com/mishaboar/status/1782835678335598620" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">expressed</a> deep concerns regarding the current trend in the crypto markets where meme coins quickly achieve market capitalizations in the millions or even billions of dollars, facilitated by almost instantaneous listings on major exchanges. He stated, &#8220;There is an explosion in tokens that go up to crazy market caps, with instant listings (within days) on large exchanges (sometimes in spite of red flags).&#8221; This phenomenon, he argued, typically indicates significant backing from <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-crypto-rollercoaster-ride-for-2-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">venture capitalists</a> (VCs) and crypto exchanges themselves.</p>

<p>According to @Mishaboar, the rapid listing of these tokens is often prearranged through partnerships between token creators and crypto exchanges. &#8220;These big players usually hold a large portion of the tokens and may strike deals with exchanges before the tokens launch,&#8221; he explained. This arrangement allows them to profit from initial trading surges, while also increasing the nominal liquidity on their platforms at minimal cost. Such practices raise questions about the transparency and fairness of the token launch and listing process.</p>
<p>He also highlighted the role of influencers in shaping the market perception of these tokens. &#8220;Influencers tend to create a narrative around these tokens claiming they are &#8216;community run&#8217;, that they are your &#8216;frens&#8217;, but this is often really not the case,&#8221; @Mishaboar noted. He argued that these narratives are crafted to mask the centralized, profit-driven nature of these token launches, misleading the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-community-doge-day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">community</a> about the true character and governance of these tokens.</p>
<p>Revisiting past controversies, @Mishaboar brought up unresolved questions about potential insider trading activities of BOME, especially regarding how platforms like <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/breaking-binance-founder-zhao-3-years-in-jail/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Binance </a>quickly list new and risky tokens. &#8220;I have a question regarding Binance&#8217;s involvement in the launch of certain tokens. Specifically, does Binance have pre-launch agreements with any of the artists or creators of these tokens?&#8221; he asked. This question aims to uncover whether there&#8217;s a deliberate strategy to manage risks for users or if the rapid listing process inherently increases the risks for them.</p>

<p>Expanding on the general risks associated with memecoins, @Mishaboar differentiated between various types of tokens. He emphasized that while some memecoins might have a community aspect, others are &#8220;100% VC backed&#8221; and are typically those that see instant exchange listings. &#8220;Not all tokens are the same,&#8221; he declared, urging traders to recognize the high-risk nature of these investments.</p>
Dogecoin&#8217;s Status And Future Outlook
<p>Addressing a user&#8217;s concerns about Dogecoin&#8217;s projects and asset status, @Mishaboar provided reassurances about the ongoing development and stability of Dogecoin&#8217;s network. &#8220;Dogecoin&#8217;s network is chugging along just fine, and 1.14.7 was released a couple of months ago,&#8221; he confirmed. He highlighted the continuous efforts of volunteer developers who have significantly reduced technical debt since 2021, improving the overall health of the network.</p>
<p>He added, “We will have new releases of Dogecoin Core (the reference implementation) and there are companies and organizations and indie devs building stuff for it. As for companies (e.g. like X or <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-gains-momentum-as-musk-hints-at-future-tesla-payments-is-doge-going-to-the-moon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Tesla</a>) integrating it into their platforms, this is really up to these companies and the laws they must comply to. Technically there is nothing missing in Dogecoin that would prevent them from adopting it.”</p>
<p>In concluding his extensive remarks, @Mishaboar reiterated the importance of vigilance and informed decision-making in the cryptocurrency market. He reminded his audience that despite the allure of quick profits, the volatile nature of memecoins means that trading them is akin to gambling, with risks varying significantly across different tokens and market caps.</p>
<p>At press time, Dogecoin traded at $0.1615.</p>
<img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-296388" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472" alt="Dogecoin price" width="1024" height="472" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3628 3628w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1536 1536w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=2048 2048w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1140 1140w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DOGEUSD_2024-04-24_14-57-07.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" />

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-24-14.53.51-A-digital-illustration-of-a-Dogecoin-in-a-wide-format.-The-coin-should-prominently-feature-the-Shiba-Inu-dog-face-which-is-the-mascot-of-Dogecoin-se.webp?fit=640%2C366" width="640" height="366" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296365</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin&#8217;s Borderless Power: IMF Recognizes Positive Impact On Global Finance</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-imf-sees-positive-impact-on-global-finance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IMF]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst economic turmoil and stringent regulations, citizens in countries like Argentina and Venezuela have turned to Bitcoin as a lifeline. The International Monetary Fund (IMF) examines how individuals in these nations are leveraging Bitcoin to manage their finances, bypassing capital controls through off-blockchain transactions. Related Reading: Sam Bankman-Fried Turns Rat, Cooperates In Lawsuit Vs. FTX [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[











<p>Amidst economic turmoil and stringent regulations, citizens in countries like Argentina and Venezuela have turned to Bitcoin as a lifeline. The International Monetary Fund (IMF) examines how individuals in these nations are leveraging Bitcoin to manage their finances, bypassing capital controls through off-blockchain transactions.</p>

<p>This trend underscores the resilience and adaptability of cryptocurrencies in providing financial autonomy to individuals in challenging economic environments.</p>
<p>The IMF has released a groundbreaking report titled &#8220;<a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/WP/Issues/2024/04/05/A-Primer-on-Bitcoin-Cross-Border-Flows-Measurement-and-Drivers-547429#:~:text=Bitcoin%20cross%2Dborder%20flows%20respond,to%20avoid%20capital%20flow%20restrictions." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">A Primer on Bitcoin Cross-Border Flows</a>,&#8221; shedding light on the increasing relevance of the world&#8217;s most popular cryptocurrency in facilitating international financial exchanges.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-296267" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_816d57.png?resize=873%2C351" alt="" width="873" height="351" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_816d57.png?resize=873%2C351?w=873 873w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_816d57.png?resize=873%2C351?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_816d57.png?resize=873%2C351?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_816d57.png?resize=873%2C351?w=750 750w" sizes="(max-width: 873px) 100vw, 873px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>

<h2><strong>Understanding The Dynamics Of Bitcoin Transactions</strong></h2>
<p>The report also uncovers a fascinating correlation between<a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> Bitcoin</a> flows and traditional economic markers. Contrary to conventional wisdom, cryptocurrency-specific factors such as market volatility and user sentiment exert a stronger influence on crypto transactions than traditional indicators.</p>
<p>This suggests that cryptocurrencies, with their unique adoption dynamics, possess the potential to serve as a hedge against conventional financial risks, offering individuals and businesses a novel avenue for diversification and risk management.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/AQRFrL1k/" width="1835" height="883" /></p>

<h2><strong>Navigating Regulatory Challenges In The Crypto Landscape</strong></h2>
<p>While recognizing the promising role of Bitcoin in fostering cross-border commerce and financial inclusion, the IMF report sounds a note of caution regarding regulatory oversight. The inherent anonymity of cryptocurrency transactions raises concerns about their potential misuse for illicit activities such as money laundering.</p>
<p>Consequently, the report underscores the imperative for global cooperation in establishing clear and consistent regulations to mitigate risks and foster a secure environment for cryptocurrency transactions.</p>

<p>The call for comprehensive cryptocurrency regulation echoes across borders, as policymakers grapple with the complexities of overseeing a rapidly evolving financial ecosystem. Clear and transparent regulations not only address the risks associated with Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies but also lay the groundwork for a more predictable and stable financial environment.</p>
<p>By striking a delicate balance between fostering innovation and safeguarding against potential abuses, regulators can pave the way for continued growth and innovation in the cryptocurrency industry.</p>
<strong>Embracing The Potential Of Bitcoin</strong>
<p>As Bitcoin&#8217;s influence on global finance continues to expand, the IMF report serves as a timely reminder of the opportunities and challenges associated with cryptocurrencies. While Bitcoin holds immense promise in facilitating cross-border transactions and promoting financial inclusion, effective regulation is essential to mitigate risks and ensure the integrity of the financial system.</p>
<p>By embracing the potential of Bitcoin while proactively addressing regulatory challenges, policymakers can harness the transformative power of cryptocurrencies to shape a more inclusive and resilient global economy.</p>
<p><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>












]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_47b5f0.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296260</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance Founder Changpeng Zhao Faces 3 Years In Jail</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/breaking-binance-founder-zhao-3-years-in-jail/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance CZ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BNB Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Changpeng Zao]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Changpeng Zhao, the founder and CEO of Binance, the largest cryptocurrency exchange globally, faces a sentencing recommendation of three years imprisonment from the US Department of Justice (DOJ). This follows his guilty plea last year to charges concerning severe lapses in the company’s anti-money laundering (AML) controls, as mandated by the US Bank Secrecy Act. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Changpeng Zhao, the founder and CEO of Binance, the largest cryptocurrency exchange globally, faces a sentencing <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.328570/gov.uscourts.wawd.328570.78.0.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">recommendation</a> of three years imprisonment from the US Department of Justice (DOJ). This follows his <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/changpeng-zhao-ordered-to-surrender-passport/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">guilty plea</a> last year to charges concerning severe lapses in the company’s anti-money laundering (AML) controls, as mandated by the US Bank Secrecy Act.</p>
<h2>A &#8220;Message&#8221; To The Binance Founder And The World</h2>
<p>Zhao’s explicit disregard for US regulations was underscored by the DOJ in a scathing sentencing memorandum. They quoted Zhao&#8217;s own words, highlighting his approach to legal compliance: &#8220;Better to ask for forgiveness than permission,&#8221; suggesting a strategic bypass of regulatory requirements to expedite Binance’s market expansion and profitability.</p>
<p>The DOJ laid out the case against Zhao, describing how his decisions to flout US laws were integral to Binance&#8217;s business strategy, which aggressively targeted US customers without adhering to requisite legal standards. &#8220;Zhao’s willful violation of US law was no accident or oversight. He made a business decision that violating US law was the best way to attract users, build his company, and line his pockets,&#8221; the US Attorney’s Office stated.</p>

<p>According to the DOJ, Zhao&#8217;s actions enabled Binance to operate a &#8216;Wild West&#8217; model of cryptocurrency exchange, inviting illicit financial flows. The memorandum notes, &#8220;As a result, Zhao is one of richest people in the world and a celebrity in the crypto industry. Zhao bet that he would not get caught, and that if he did, the consequences would not be as serious as the crime.&#8221;</p>
<p>The prosecution detailed how Zhao&#8217;s failure to implement an effective AML program led Binance to process hundreds of millions of dollars worth of transactions violating US sanctions against<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-under-fire-report-says-it-bypassed-sanction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener "> Iran and other countries,</a> quantifying the total at approximately $898 million.</p>
<p>The sentencing memorandum emphasizes the gravity and scale of these violations, stating, &#8220;Zhao knew that his decision not to implement an effective AML program would result in Binance facilitating transactions between US users and users in Iran and other sanctioned countries and regions in violation of US law.&#8221;</p>

<p>In light of these findings, the DOJ is recommending a sentence that would go beyond the federal guidelines, suggesting a 36-month term of imprisonment to &#8220;reflect the seriousness of the offense, promote respect for law, afford adequate deterrence, and serve as just punishment for Zhao’s criminal acts.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zhao’s sentencing is poised to set a precedent in the regulatory oversight of the crypto industry, particularly concerning compliance with US financial laws. The outcome will likely resonate across the crypto landscape, potentially reshaping how exchanges operate in compliance with US regulations. The DOJ’s closing remarks in the memorandum drive home the broader implications of Zhao&#8217;s sentencing: &#8220;The sentence in this case will not just send a message to Zhao but also to the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>The final sentencing decision, expected to be <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/former-binance-ceo-faces-delay-in-sentencing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">delivered</a> on April 30, marks a crucial juncture for the legal scrutiny of crypto operations within the United States.</p>
<p>At press time, BNB traded at $607.7.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-296308" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472" alt="BNB price" width="1024" height="472" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3628 3628w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1536 1536w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=2048 2048w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1140 1140w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BNBUSD_2024-04-24_10-51-21.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" />

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/39330af9-0cb4-4dc9-8d05-fb7c24c348a7_eee40472.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296262</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Charity Gets A Digital Boost: $2 Billion In Crypto Donations Empower US Causes</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/charity-gets-crypto-boost-2-billion-in-donations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 09:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Assets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[American charities are experiencing a windfall thanks to a new kind of currency: cryptocurrency. By accepting donations in crypto such as Bitcoin, Ethereum, and other digital assets, non-profits are witnessing a surge in contributions, streamlining processes, and reaching new donor demographics. Related Reading: Sam Bankman-Fried Turns Rat, Cooperates In Lawsuit Vs. FTX Celebrity Backers This [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[




<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:281">American charities are experiencing a windfall thanks to a new kind of currency: cryptocurrency. By accepting donations in crypto such as Bitcoin, Ethereum, and other digital assets, non-profits are witnessing a surge in contributions, streamlining processes, and reaching new donor demographics.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="5:1-5:371">This year alone, the two largest US charities have reportedly raised over $2 billion through crypto donations, according to a recent <a href="https://www.banklesstimes.com/news/2024/04/23/over-dollar2b-in-crypto-donations-2-out-of-3-leading-us-charities-now-embrace-crypto-contributions-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report by Bankless Times</a>. This represents a massive leap from the $125 million collected in donations throughout 2022. The Giving Block, a platform facilitating digital currency donations for charities, has been instrumental in this shift.</p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="7:1-7:67"><strong>Crypto Donations: A Boon For Efficiency And Convenience</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:410">The rise of crypto donations offers several advantages for both charities and donors. Platforms like <a href="https://thegivingblock.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Giving Block</a> simplify transactions, allowing donors to bypass complex international money transfers. This expedites the process and ensures donations reach their intended causes faster. Additionally, this type of donations often appeal to a younger, tech-savvy generation comfortable with digital transactions.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:410"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-296223 size-large" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_081004.png?resize=666%2C660" alt="" width="666" height="660" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_081004.png?w=731 731w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_081004.png?w=424 424w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_081004.png?w=666 666w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_081004.png?w=64 64w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_081004.png?w=75 75w" sizes="(max-width: 666px) 100vw, 666px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:300">For charities, accepting crypto donations translates to a wider funding pool. It allows them to tap into a global network of investors who may not have traditionally participated in philanthropy. This diversification can be crucial for organizations seeking to expand their reach and impact.</p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="13:1-13:72"><strong>Regulatory And Security Challenges</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:463">While the influx of crypto donations presents exciting opportunities, it also comes with challenges. Charities must navigate a complex regulatory landscape to ensure compliance with <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/k/knowyourclient.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Know Your Client (KYC)</a> and Anti-Money Laundering (AML) laws.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:463">These regulations are essential for preventing fraud and maintaining the integrity of the financial system. However, navigating KYC/AML compliance can be a time-consuming and resource-intensive process for nonprofits.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:463"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/YiYZ8n8m/" width="1835" height="883" /></p>

<p data-sourcepos="17:1-17:279">Furthermore, the digital nature of cryptocurrency exposes charities to cybersecurity risks. Hackers may target these organizations to steal donated funds. To mitigate these risks, charities need to invest in robust cybersecurity measures and stay updated on the latest threats.</p>
<strong>The Future Of Philanthropy: A Promising Outlook</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:513">Despite these challenges, the trend of crypto donations in the nonprofit sector shows no signs of slowing down. With the increasing adoption of Bitcoin and growing public confidence in digital transactions, charities are likely to see a continued rise in digital currency contributions.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:513">As the regulatory environment evolves and security protocols strengthen, crypto donations hold the potential to revolutionize philanthropic giving, fostering a more efficient, transparent, and globally connected giving ecosystem.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:513"><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>





]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_1f59ed.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296222</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Market Shakeup? New Whales Invest 2X More Than Established Players</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-new-whales-invest-2x-more-than-old-players/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whales]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The tides are shifting in the Bitcoin sea. A recent analysis by CryptoQuant, a blockchain analytics firm, paints a picture of a changing investor landscape, with a new breed of &#8220;whales&#8221; – high-volume crypto holders – entering the fray and established players holding their ground. Related Reading: Halving Hype Debunked: Binance Founder Says Don’t Fall [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:291">The tides are shifting in the Bitcoin sea. A recent analysis by CryptoQuant, a blockchain analytics firm, paints a picture of a changing investor landscape, with a new breed of &#8220;whales&#8221; – high-volume crypto holders – entering the fray and established players holding their ground.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="5:1-5:344">This influx of fresh capital is significant. CryptoQuant CEO Ki Young Ju reports that these &#8220;new whales,&#8221; likely hailing from traditional finance and entering through Bitcoin ETFs, have amassed a staggering $111 billion worth of Bitcoin. This edges the holdings of established, &#8220;long-term whales&#8221; whose collective stash sits at $67 billion.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The new whales&#8217; initial investment in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#Bitcoin</a> is almost twice the old whales&#8217; cumulative total. <a href="https://t.co/SU5Aiw1nJB" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/SU5Aiw1nJB</a></p>
<p>— Ki Young Ju (@ki_young_ju) <a href="https://twitter.com/ki_young_ju/status/1782613796852576759?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="7:1-7:447"><strong>Crypto Newcomers With Deep Pockets</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:447">While the financial firepower of these new whales is undeniable, their profit picture paints a different story. Unlike their seasoned counterparts who boast over 200% in unrealized profits, these newcomers are experiencing a much more modest 1.5% gain. This suggests they might have entered the <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">crypto market</a> at a higher price point, potentially during the recent surge towards the $67,000 resistance level.</p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="9:1-9:514"><strong>Miners Making Hay</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:514">Despite the contrasting fortunes of New and Long-Term Whales, the overall market sentiment seems bullish. CryptoQuant&#8217;s analysis extends beyond whales, revealing healthy profits for miners as well.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:514">Small miners are leading the pack with an impressive 130% in unrealized profits, while their larger counterparts haven&#8217;t done too shabby either, sitting at a comfortable 81%. This robust mining profitability indicates a healthy network, with miners diligently securing the <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bitcoin</a> blockchain.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:514"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/gPYie1Gl/" width="1835" height="883" /></p>

<strong>Bullish Outlook</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:394">Ju believes this data combination points towards a prolonged bull run. The fact that New Whales haven&#8217;t cashed out for significant profits suggests they&#8217;re in it for the long haul, potentially anticipating further price increases. This aligns with the ongoing interest in <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-etfs-set-for-big-boost-ceo-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin ETFs</a>, with Fidelity&#8217;s IBIT leading the pack in terms of new investments last week.</p>
<strong>The $67,000 Question</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="13:1-13:328">However, the path forward isn&#8217;t entirely smooth sailing. Bitcoin is currently struggling to decisively break through the <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$67,000 resistance level.</a> This could be a point of contention in the near future, with bulls pushing for a breakout and bears looking for a potential correction.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:515">The cryptocurrency market is witnessing a fascinating dynamic. New investors with deep pockets are entering, established whales are holding firm, and miners are profiting handsomely. While the short-term price movement of Bitcoin remains to be seen, the overall market sentiment seems to favor a continuation of the bull run.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:515"><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_f72b4b.jpg?fit=612%2C420" width="612" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296228</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple Replaced XRP With USDT For US Clients, Here&#8217;s Why</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-replaced-xrp-with-usdt-us-clients/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 05:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple USDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In yesterday’s court filing opposing the US Securities and Exchange Commission&#8217;s (SEC) motion for remedies and final judgment, Ripple disclosed significant changes to its On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) operations in the United States. The filing clarified that its US-based ODL services have shifted from using XRP to Tether (USDT) as a bridge currency. Why Ripple Chose [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In yesterday’s court <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-responds-to-sec-remedies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">filing</a> opposing the US Securities and Exchange Commission&#8217;s (SEC) motion for remedies and final judgment, Ripple disclosed significant changes to its On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) operations in the United States. The filing clarified that its US-based ODL services have shifted from using XRP to Tether (USDT) as a bridge currency.</p>
<h2>Why Ripple Chose USDT</h2>
<p>This strategic pivot was a response to the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-lawyer-outline-what-sec-misses-summary-judgment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">summary judgment</a> in the SEC lawsuit which found that institutional sales fell under the US security laws. Since the ruling, non-US entities have been the sole contracting parties for XRP sales contracts to ODL customers. The filing highlights that &#8220;the company’s remaining ODL business in the United States uses a non-XRP bridge currency.&#8221;</p>
<p>Monica Long, President of Ripple, elaborated in an internal email, details of which were <a href="https://twitter.com/sentosumosaba/status/1782854543178715467" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">shared</a> by prominent XRP community member Crypto Eri (@sentosumosaba) on social media platform X. Long stated:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Immediately following the Order, we took steps to migrate each US-based ODL customer from using XRP as the bridge currency in ODL to using USDT (or the contract was terminated). We should continue to use USDT (or BTC or other vetted stablecoins) for US based flows unless otherwise approved by Legal.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>This adjustment reflects the company’s effort to ensure its service offerings align with US legal standards while still supporting global operations largely unaffected by the SEC&#8217;s scrutiny. The email emphasizes the strategic role of <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/will-ripple-sign-singapore-as-cbdc-customer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">the Singapore subsidiaries,</a> which now handle most contractual relationships for selling XRP to new ODL customers, particularly those outside the US Long notes:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Ripple’s Singapore subsidiaries have been the primary contracting entity for Commitment to Sell XRP contracts to new ODL customers, who are predominantly foreign. And since the Order, non-US entities have exclusively been the contracting parties for XRP sales contracts to ODL customers.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>The restructuring within Ripple’s business model underscores a significant geographical and operational pivot. Most of ODL customers are located in the Asia-Pacific region, leveraging the monetary corridors between non-US entities and countries. The licensing of Ripple Markets APAC Pte Ltd by the Monetary Authority of Singapore facilitated this, as Long further explained:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>To service our ODL customers, we should continue to leverage our foreign subsidiaries who are licensed by local regulators to lawfully conduct such activity.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Moreover, the court filing revealed the company&#8217;s financial dependencies and operational strategies preceding the SEC lawsuit. Ripple’s accounting expert, Anthony Bracco, <a href="https://twitter.com/WKahneman/status/1782612833387344041" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">calculated</a> that the company operated at a loss from April 1, 2014, through December 22, 2020, without the revenue from XRP sales. This detail highlights the financial impact of XRP sales on Ripple&#8217;s overall business stability during that period.</p>
<p>&#8220;Bracco calculated Ripple’s monetary operating costs and income taxes paid, which total [redacted]. Deducting those expenses from Ripple’s pre-Complaint revenue from Institutional Sales in that period, which totals [redacted], and further deducting income taxes, which total [redacted], Ripple had a loss of [redacted],&#8221; the filing states.</p>
<p>At press time, XRP traded at $0.549.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-296229" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472" alt="XRP price" width="1024" height="472" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3628 3628w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1536 1536w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=2048 2048w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1140 1140w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-24_07-36-00.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" />

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/shutterstock_1103967176-1.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296219</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Bitcoin Mining: Paypal Proposes Reward System For “Sustainable” Miners</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/green-bitcoin-mining-paypal-proposes-reward-system-for-sustainable-miners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rubmar Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 03:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin clean energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Miners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto mining industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=296176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PayPal’s Blockchain Research Group has joined Energy Web and DMG Blockchain Solutions to support “sustainable” Bitcoin mining. According to the paper, the collaboration “presents an opportunity to accelerate the clean energy transition” using crypto-economic incentives. Related Reading: Crypto Expert Confirms Rotation Has Begun Post-Bitcoin Halving, Are Investors Moving Away From BTC? PayPal Research On Bitcoin [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400;">PayPal’s Blockchain Research Group has joined Energy Web and DMG Blockchain Solutions to support “sustainable” Bitcoin mining. According to the paper, the collaboration “presents an opportunity to accelerate the clean energy transition” using crypto-economic incentives.</p>

<h2 style="font-weight: 400;">PayPal Research On Bitcoin Mining</h2>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">In a recently <a href="https://pyusd.mirror.xyz/P2fyue5RNhdOAV_IREgLPkj70vk-7zLAAw7Rk39s0iw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">published</a> paper, PayPal’s Blockchain Research Group (BRG) proposed “the possibility for a more sustainable future” in Bitcoin mining. The investigation revealed that, as of April 2, data estimates the annualized emissions to be over 85 million metric tons of carbon dioxide due to Bitcoin’s Proof-of-Work (PoW) consensus mechanism:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The reason behind this significant impact is the proof-of-work (PoW) consensus mechanism that secures the Bitcoin network. In PoW, miners engage in a competitive race to find solutions (<em>i.e.</em>, cryptographic hashes) for Bitcoin blocks, requiring powerful computational hardware like ASIC machines.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">This race and its demand for robust <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-mining-3-5-million-scheme-man-indicted-for-alleged-cryptojacking-operation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">computational power</a> require significant electricity. Miners’ use of carbon-based energy sources consequentially “results in the underlying greenhouse gas emissions footprint of the Bitcoin network.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a solution, PayPal’s BRG aims to “incentivize desired activity with crypto-economics” to improve and optimize “existing, proven strong networks.” Additionally, the firm wishes to support “more environmentally responsible” mining and encourage other miners to shift towards cleaner energy sources.”</p>
<h2 style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin Rewards For “Green Mining”</h2>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The paper suggests routing on-chain transactions to “green miners” via low transaction fees with a BTC reward “locked” in a multisig payout address. The rewards would serve as an incentive to mine these transactions, as only green miners would be eligible to receive them.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The solution is based on identifying miners that use low-emissions energy sources. After identification, their public keys, referred to as “green keys,” would be used to reward miners with <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-tidal-wave-blackrock-etf-leads-inflows/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin</a> in a trust-independent method through a “1-of-<em>n</em> multisig script.” As a result, the payout address would allow the miners with green keys to claim the rewards.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-296196 aligncenter" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captura-de-Pantalla-2024-04-23-a-las-11.43.18-a.-m.png?w=980&#038;resize=980%2C569" alt="Bitcoin, BTC" width="980" height="569" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captura-de-Pantalla-2024-04-23-a-las-11.43.18-a.-m.png?w=1203 1203w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captura-de-Pantalla-2024-04-23-a-las-11.43.18-a.-m.png?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captura-de-Pantalla-2024-04-23-a-las-11.43.18-a.-m.png?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captura-de-Pantalla-2024-04-23-a-las-11.43.18-a.-m.png?w=980&#038;resize=980%2C569 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captura-de-Pantalla-2024-04-23-a-las-11.43.18-a.-m.png?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captura-de-Pantalla-2024-04-23-a-las-11.43.18-a.-m.png?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 980px) 100vw, 980px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>

<p style="font-weight: 400;">Providers such as Energy Web would help to identify the green miners and onboard them to the solution. The non-profit organization offers a “Green Proofs for Bitcoin” initiative that promotes transparency and “supports alignment between Bitcoin mining and global decarbonization effort.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Miners would apply for and share their sustainable mining certifications through the Green Proofs for Bitcoin validation platform.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Moreover, the proposed solution has been successfully tested with DMG. The firm broadcasted multiple low-fee transactions to test how effectively they would operate under different levels of on-chain <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/shiba-inu-large-transactions-spike-over-1000/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">transaction volumes.</a></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Depending on the transaction volume, the low-fee ones would “either take a long time to confirm or eventually be dropped by the network.” This would increase the green miners’ chances to pick them up.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Per the paper, the trade-offs were “acceptable,” however, alternative solutions could be evaluated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">It is possible to design alternative solutions where transactions and rewards can be sent to miners via a private mechanism rather than using the public mempool.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Exploring technologies like smart contracts or the lighting network is also proposed as an alternative way to address the issues. However, they could come at the expense of “trust dependence and a more complex implementation.”</p>
<p>However, it is worth noting that Bitcoin mining has been controversial. While many legacy companies, such as PayPal and others, have targeted the network due to its alleged intense electrical consumption and carbon emissions, other research has pointed to the increasing use of renewable energy and the low carbon emissions the nascent industry produces, as seen in the chart below.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-296207 size-large" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-mining-cambridge.jpg?resize=980%2C528" alt="bitcoin mining Cambridge " width="980" height="528" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-mining-cambridge.jpg?w=1280 1280w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-mining-cambridge.jpg?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-mining-cambridge.jpg?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-mining-cambridge.jpg?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-mining-cambridge.jpg?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-mining-cambridge.jpg?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 980px) 100vw, 980px" data-recalc-dims="1" />
<p>In an article posted by Forbes, analyst Jonathan Buck <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2023/07/07/everything-you-need-to-know-about-bitcoin-and-the-environment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">pointed out</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>the CCAF has determined that the bitcoin industry uses a significant amount of renewable energy, sometimes more than half, depending on the jurisdiction. This is a testament to the industry&#8217;s commitment to sustainability and its potential role in the green revolution.</p></blockquote>

<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-296195 aligncenter" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSDT_2024-04-23_08-20-21.png?w=980&#038;resize=980%2C468" alt="BTC, BTCUSDT, Bitcoin" width="980" height="468" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSDT_2024-04-23_08-20-21.png?w=1077 1077w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSDT_2024-04-23_08-20-21.png?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSDT_2024-04-23_08-20-21.png?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSDT_2024-04-23_08-20-21.png?w=980&#038;resize=980%2C468 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSDT_2024-04-23_08-20-21.png?w=750 750w" sizes="(max-width: 980px) 100vw, 980px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/dmytro-demidko-xZJpKskRdOg-unsplash.jpeg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">296176</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
