<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bitcoinist.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 17:05:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/cropped-cropped-cropped-Icon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">225283986</site>	<item>
		<title>Pro-XRP Lawyer Deaton Takes The Lead, Outpacing Warren In Pivotal Senate Contest</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-lawyer-deaton-takes-lead-outpacing-warren/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pro-XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pro-XRP lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro-XRP lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple (XRP)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple Chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple news XRP news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[John Deaton, a pro-XRP lawyer and crypto advocate, is running for a seat in the US Senate against Elizabeth Warren, known for her skepticism on cryptocurrencies, when US regulators are stepping up their enforcement actions and crackdowns on the crypto industry. Notably, Deaton&#8217;s campaign has gained significant support from industry leaders, indicating a growing demand [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>John Deaton, a pro-XRP lawyer and crypto advocate, is running for a seat in the US Senate against <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-deaton-sen-warren-cover-up-sbf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Elizabeth Warren</a>, known for her skepticism on cryptocurrencies, when US regulators are stepping up their enforcement actions and crackdowns on the crypto industry.</p>
<p>Notably, Deaton&#8217;s campaign has gained significant support from industry leaders, indicating a growing demand for change in crypto regulation frameworks and a shift in approach towards the industry.</p>
<h2>Crypto Industry Backs Pro-XRP Lawyer’s Senate Campaign</h2>
<p>According to a local <a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/2024/04/12/nation/john-deaton-loans-campaign-1-million-against-elizabeth-warren/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report </a>from Boston, Deaton, running as a Republican candidate, has personally loaned his campaign $1 million, showcasing his commitment to his uphill battle against Senator Warren. </p>
<p>Since announcing his candidacy in mid-February, Deaton has also raised $360,690 from individual contributors, leaving him with nearly $1.4 million cash on hand. </p>

<p>According to the Federal Election Commission, Deaton <a href="https://x.com/EleanorTerrett/status/1778797246751904135" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">outraised </a>Warren in the race&#8217;s first quarter, with Deaton raising a total of $1.36 million to Warren&#8217;s $1.1 million.   </p>
<p>Notable donations have come from influential figures such as <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/cardano-chief-backs-xrp-lawyer-deaton/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Charles Hoskinson</a>, co-founder of Ethereum; Anthony Scaramucci, former communications director for Donald Trump and vocal crypto investor; and Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss, co-founders of Gemini exchange.</p>
<p><a href="https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-attorney-deaton-worries-sen-warren/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Ripple</a> CEO Brad Garlinghouse and the company&#8217;s executive chairman and co-founder, Chris Larsen, also <a href="https://x.com/sentosumosaba/status/1778792881123426753" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">contributed</a> the maximum $6,600 each, split between the primary and general election campaigns, underscoring Deaton&#8217;s support from key industry players. </p>
<p>However, it should be noted that Deaton faces a challenging campaign against Warren, who has a significant financial advantage with $4.4 million in her campaign <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-lawyer-coinbase-sec-today/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">war chest</a>. This solidifies her position as the &#8220;heavy favorite&#8221; to win the Senate battle against the pro-XRP attorney in what is considered a &#8220;reliably blue state.&#8221;</p>
<h2>High-Stakes Senate Race</h2>
<p>A spokesperson for Warren emphasized that her campaign is powered by “small-dollar donations,” emphasizing grassroots support rather than “special interests attempting to elevate candidates.” </p>
<p>Nevertheless, Deaton&#8217;s challenge against Warren extends beyond a political rivalry, representing the ongoing debate surrounding the role of cryptocurrencies and their <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/pro-xrp-lawyer-deaton-sec-us-interests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">regulation</a> in the United States. </p>
<p>Deaton has previously stated, &#8220;Regular people are sick and tired of different rules being applied to Washington insiders. We need real leadership in Washington, DC.&#8221;</p>
<p>Deaton, an ex-US Naval officer from Detroit who attended Eastern Michigan University and New England Law Boston, moved to Massachusetts from Rhode Island in late January, shortly before he announced his Senate candidacy. </p>

<p>While Warren&#8217;s record of service and establishment support pose significant challenges, the crypto industry&#8217;s endorsement and call for change, coupled with the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/john-deaton-prefers-two-cryptos-over-xrp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">growing adoption</a> of cryptocurrencies, gives Deaton significant leverage in his campaign. </p>
<p>The outcome of this high-profile race will not only determine a political representative but also shape the future of cryptocurrency regulation in the United States.</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/nrTLfWex/" alt="XRP" width="1815" height="858" />
<p>As of this writing, XRP is trading at $0.59, marking a significant drop in value over the past month. The cryptocurrency has seen losses of up to 12.4% over the past 30 days.</p>
<p>Featured image from iStock, chart from TradingView.com </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Downloader.la-66195f1893226.jpg?fit=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Analyst Says Dogecoin Is Poised To Run 100% To $0.4, Here’s When</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-run-100-to-0-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 22:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Dogecoin price has continued to trend around the $0.19-$0.2 level after encountering significant resistance from the bears at this level. This has caused a suppressed price action over the last week, stopping the meme coin’s advancement in its tracks. However, the outlook still remains bullish for the DOGE price, with crypto analysts expecting the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p2">The <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-whales-doge-price/">Dogecoin price</a> has continued to trend around the $0.19-$0.2 level after encountering significant resistance from the bears at this level. This has caused a suppressed price action over the last week, stopping the meme coin’s advancement in its tracks. However, the outlook still remains bullish for the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-ethereum-shiba-inu/">DOGE price</a>, with crypto analysts expecting the rally to continue soon and the price to double.</p>
<h2 class="p2">Dogecoin Forms Bull Flag Pattern</h2>
<p class="p2">The Dogecoin performance over the past month has been quite encouraging, and despite hitting a roadblock with its rally, it has continued to show bullish tendencies. The most recent of the bullish moves which the meme coin has pulled is the formation of a bull flag pattern on its chart.</p>

<p class="p2">Crypto analyst Trader Tardigrade <a href="https://x.com/TATrader_Alan/status/1778346751109251372" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">revealed</a> in an X (formerly Twitter) post that the cryptocurrency’s chart had showed something interesting on the daily chart. According to the analysis, the movements that Dogecoin has made over the last few weeks has led to a bull flag formation on the daily chart.</p>
<p class="p2">Now, the main driver of the rally that is supposed to follow this formation is the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-mvrv-ratio-negative/">DOGE price</a> breaking out from the bull flag, which is yet to happen. But as the crypto analyst explains, a breakout from here would send Dogecoin’s price at least 2x higher than its current level.</p>
<p class="p2">A successful break above the $0.205 level would confirm this bullish formation. However, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-shiba-inu-price-red/">DOGE</a> has been unable to achieve this, still <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-stalls-at-0-2-doge/">trading below $0.2 at the time of writing</a>. This could also be a hard-won battle for the meme coin as Bitcoin’s uncertain moves continue to drag the crypto market down.</p>
<h2 class="p2">When Will DOGE Make This Move?</h2>
<p class="p2">The month of April is expected to be bullish for the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-pepe-wif-meme-coin/">Dogecoin price</a>, and the crypto analyst’s price shows this. The expected timeframe for the bullish breakout is sometime this month, which would put it in the next few weeks. Trader Tardigrade’s target shows an over 100% increase from the current price level, reaching as high as $0.4 in the short term.</p>

<p class="p2">This move could be spurred on by the Bitcoin halving happening this month, which is expected to propel bullish sentiment. Expectations for the Bitcoin price are that it will reach $80,000, and this move would no doubt pull up the rest of the crypto market, causing coins like Dogecoin to surge.</p>
<p class="p2">At the time of writing, the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-doge-sights-on-0-3/">DOGE price</a> was trending at $0.19, with a 1.61% decrease in the last 24 hours. However, on the weekly time frame, its price is up 14%, coming in second to <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/toncoin-flips-cardano-dogecoin/">Toncoin (TON)</a> for the best performer in the top 10.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/1ze4VtsH/" alt="Dogecoin price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Dogecoin-price.png?fit=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293907</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance-backed Gopax Exchange Makes Strides: Revenue Soars 97% Despite Challenges</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/binance-backed-gopax-exchange-makes-strides-reven/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Edyme]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 21:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BNB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnbusdt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gopax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Streami]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A recent financial report from Streami, the parent company of Gopax, revealed that the South Korean cryptocurrency exchange experienced significant revenue growth and a notable reduction in net losses in 2023. Gopax&#8217;s Revenue Surge And Net Loss Reduction Despite challenges related to liquidity issues and regulatory scrutiny, Gopax narrowed its net loss to 51.3 billion [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent financial <a href="https://dart.fss.or.kr/dsaf001/main.do?rcpNo=20240412001438" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report</a> from Streami, the parent company of Gopax, revealed that the South Korean cryptocurrency exchange experienced significant revenue growth and a notable reduction in net losses in 2023.</p>
<h2>Gopax&#8217;s Revenue Surge And Net Loss Reduction</h2>
<p>Despite challenges related to liquidity issues and regulatory scrutiny, Gopax narrowed its net loss to 51.3 billion Korean won ($37 million) last year, compared to 90.6 billion won in the previous year.</p>
<p>The financial report further showcased Gopax&#8217;s notable performance in 2023, with a roughly 97% year-over-year growth in revenue, reaching 3.1 billion won. Additionally, the exchange reduced its net operating loss by 78% to approximately 17 billion won.</p>
<p>As reported, these positive results were largely attributed to the resurgence of bullish sentiment in the South Korean crypto market, which emerged as one of the <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-12-05/korean-crypto-traders-influence-jumps-as-won-overtakes-dollar-during-rally" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">&#8220;most active&#8221; crypto markets globally</a> in 2023.</p>
<p>Despite its revenue growth, Gopax encountered notable hurdles, particularly regarding its association with Genesis Global Capital, which had a subsequent halt of withdrawals stemming from a liquidity crisis associated with its involvement in FTX in 2022.</p>
<p>The situation resulted in substantial losses for Gopax, with funds from its GoFi-linked debt stuck in Genesis Global Capital, totaling 63.7 billion won. However, Binance, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-reopens-south-koreas-crypto-market-gopax/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Gopax&#8217;s major shareholder, stepped in to address liquidity issues</a> and &#8220;acquired&#8221; the exchange in February 2023, aiming to penetrate the South Korean market.</p>
<p>According to the report, Binance&#8217;s acquisition positioned the global exchange as the largest shareholder in Gopax, holding a 67.45% stake.</p>
<h2>Binance&#8217;s Global Challenges And Resilience</h2>
<p>However, Binance itself has been navigating regulatory challenges from several corners globally. Among these challenges is the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/changpeng-zhao-ordered-to-surrender-passport/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">$4.3 billion fine settlement</a> with the US Department of Justice and even the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-executive-case-in-nigeria-postponed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">crackdown from the Nigerian government</a>.</p>
<p>Additionally, the crypto exchange has recently <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-users-philippines-face-access-restriction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">faced a ban from the Philippines Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</a>. As <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/all-crypto-lost-binance-users-cant-retrieve-funds-after-philippines-sec-ban/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">reported</a>, the SEC’s decision was based on Binance’s failure to obtain the necessary license from the commission to operate as an investment and trading platform in the region.</p>
<p>SEC Chairman Emilio Aquino noted:</p>
<blockquote><p>The SEC has identified the aforementioned [Binance] platform and concluded that the public’s continued access to these websites/apps poses a threat to the security of the funds of investing  Filipinos.</p></blockquote>
<p>In response to these regulatory hurdles globally, Binance&#8217;s CEO, Richard Teng, recently<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-ceo-drops-bombshell-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener "> outlined a new strategy focused on addressing</a> &#8220;cultural issues&#8221; and &#8220;enhancing compliance efforts.&#8221;</p>

<p>Notably, despite all of these challenges Binance has faced recently, the exchange&#8217;s native token, BNB, has maintained its trading value above $600, boasting green days up by 6.6% in the past 7 days and 2.2% in the past 24 hours with a current market price of $612.</p>
<img decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/LzfndZ96/" alt="BNB price chart on TradingView amid Gopax news" width="2770" height="1496" />
<p>Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Retail-Traders-Fuel-February-Crypto-Rally.webp?fit=509%2C339" width="509" height="339" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>XRP ETF Debate Is Heating Up As Ripple CEO Joins The Conversation</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-etf-debate-ripple-ceo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 19:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP ETF news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the Spot Bitcoin Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs) were approved, market experts have continued to give their opinions on the possibility of other crypto ETFs, such as an XRP ETF launching soon. Ripple’s CEO Brad Garlinghouse has now joined the conversation, as he recently commented on whether or not the market could witness other crypto funds [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/breaking-spot-bitcoin-etfs-approved-by-us-sec/">Spot Bitcoin Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs) were approved</a>, market experts have continued to give their opinions on the possibility of other crypto ETFs, such as an <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-spot-etf-coming-to-the-us/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">XRP ETF</a> launching soon. <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-ceo-battle-sec/#:~:text=Ripple&#039;s%20CEO%2C%20Brad%20Garlinghouse%2C%20has,SEC)%20continues%20to%20heat%20up.">Ripple’s CEO Brad Garlinghouse</a> has now joined the conversation, as he recently commented on whether or not the market could witness other crypto funds soon enough. </p>
<h2>“There Will Be Other ETFs”</h2>
<p>Garlinghouse mentioned during an appearance at the Paris Blockchain Week that he “thinks there will be other ETFs.” However, he added that this will take “a little bit of time” because of the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/crypto/sec-announcement-crypto/#:~:text=What%20The%20SEC&#039;s%20Latest%20Announcement%20Means%20For%20The%20Crypto%20Industry,-by%20Scott%20Matherson&amp;text=A%20recent%20announcement%20by%20the,actions%20have%20had%20on%20it." rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Securities and Exchange Commission’s (SEC)</a> reservations about crypto assets. The Commission is known for its enforcement actions against several crypto projects, including Ripple.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-ceo-dogecoin-details/">Garlinghouse</a> further suggested that XRP would be among those crypto assets with its ETF when the time comes, as he noted that XRP and Bitcoin were the only crypto tokens with regulatory clarity. XRP achieved this status following <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-judge-deems-xrp-sale-non-investment-contract/">Judge Analisa Torres’s ruling</a> that the crypto token wasn’t a security. </p>
<p>Unlike Garlinghouse, some other market experts haven’t sounded optimistic about whether an XRP ETF could come soon. Van Buren Capital&#8217;s general partner, Scott Johnsson, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ripple-sec-spot-xrp-etf/">mentioned</a> that the SEC&#8217;s likelihood of approving an XRP ETF is “very slim.” He further opined that Gary Gensler will need to be replaced before the SEC can approve an XRP ETF.</p>
<p>Ark Invest’s CEO Cathie Wood also <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/cathie-wood-bitcoin-is-king-of-security/">once predicted</a> that there would only likely be <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/evaluating-performance-bitcoin-etfs-since-launch/">Bitcoin and Ethereum Spot ETFs</a> in the US, thereby shoving aside the idea of an XRP ETF. Back then, she mentioned that it would be surprising to see “anything but Bitcoin and Ether being approved by the SEC,” possibly due to the SEC’s non-recognition of other crypto assets besides those two.</p>
<h2>What Needs To Happen Before An XRP ETF Can Launch</h2>
<p>In addition to the SEC’s reservations about the XRP token, Bloomberg analyst James Seyffart <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-etf-approved-in-2024/">highlighted</a> another factor that could impede the launch of an XRP ETF. He stated that the absence of XRP on a regulated market like the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-futures-cme-q3-breaks-all-time-highs/">Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME)</a> makes it more unlikely for the SEC to approve an XRP ETF. </p>

<p>His comment relates to the fact that the SEC previously rejected the applications for a Spot Bitcoin ETF on the grounds that they were susceptible to market manipulation. However, in the Grayscale case, the court <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/breaking-grayscale-scores-victory-against-us-sec-spot-bitcoin-etf-imminent/">ruled</a> that the spot and futures markets were correlated. This paved the way for the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/breaking-spot-bitcoin-etfs-approved-by-us-sec/">subsequent approval</a> of these funds since Bitcoin futures were already listed on the CME.</p>
<p>Therefore, the potential listing of XRP futures on the CME could also pave the way for XRP ETFs since issuers can argue that the CME, being a regulated market, can help prevent <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/sec-prove-bitcoin-is-not-manipulated/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">market manipulation</a>. </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/jOoV6Lol/" alt="XRP price chart from Tradingview.com (Ripple CEO XRP ETF)" width="3286" height="1530" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP-ETF.jpeg?fit=299%2C168" width="299" height="168" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293904</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HashKey Partners With TON Foundation To Enable Toncoin Cash Conversion Through Telegram</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/hashkey-ton-foundation-toncoin-telegram/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Toncoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram Open Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Open Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TON price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toncoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toncoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TONUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TONUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a significant development, HashKey Group, the operator of one of the two licensed cryptocurrency exchanges in Hong Kong, has announced a collaboration with The Open Network (TON), the blockchain operator created by Telegram Messenger.  According to a South China Morning Post report, the partnership aims to allow users in the Asia-Pacific region to exchange [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant development, HashKey Group, the operator of one of the two licensed cryptocurrency exchanges in Hong Kong, has announced a collaboration with <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/shiba-inu-telegram-admin-compromised/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">The Open Network</a> (TON), the blockchain operator created by Telegram Messenger. </p>
<p>According to a South China Morning Post <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-xl/news/other/telegram-s-blockchain-teams-with-hashkey-in-asia-for-off-ramp-services-to-exchange-toncoin-cryptocurrency-for-cash/ar-BB1lvOUB#:~:text=HashKey%20Group%2C%20operator%20of%20one,so%2Dcalled%20Toncoins%20for%20cash." target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report</a>, the partnership aims to allow users in the Asia-Pacific region to exchange their Toncoin for cash, creating an on-ramp and off-ramp for the cryptocurrency. </p>
<p>The agreement also encompasses the joint exploration of new ecosystem projects, mentorship opportunities, networking, and other incubation activities, as the Open Network Foundation announced.</p>
<h2>TON Foundation Prioritizes Compliance </h2>
<p>The Foundation was established following Telegram&#8217;s decision to abandon its TON blockchain due to a <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/16325310/241/securities-and-exchange-commission-v-telegram-group-inc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">settlement </a>with the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in 2020. </p>
<p>Despite this setback, the foundation has continued to develop the blockchain and integrated it into Telegram through a <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/security-firm-warns-of-telegram-bot-token-risks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">mini app</a> and business arrangements. </p>
<p>Although the Foundation aims to maintain a separate identity from Telegram, its blockchain&#8217;s primary utility remains closely linked to the popular messaging app, which boasts over <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/telegram-unveils-crypto-wallet-800-million-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">900 million global users</a>.</p>

<p>The collaboration with HashKey is viewed as a significant opportunity by the TON Foundation. HashKey&#8217;s regulatory compliance measures, particularly in adhering to know-your-customer (KYC) rules, are expected to facilitate the integration of Toncoin into the Telegram ecosystem. </p>
<p>The Open Network Foundation President Steve Yun emphasized the importance of compliance and expressed confidence in “strategically” following the requirements to ensure regulatory adherence.</p>
<p>The Foundation views Telegram&#8217;s “mini app ecosystem” as a crucial driver for adopting its blockchain. Moreover, the blockchain has secured premium real estate within the Telegram app, making its <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/usdt-integration-allows-telegram-users-send-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">blockchain </a>the default wallet option in the sidebar. </p>
<p>However, the network faces regulatory challenges, restricting the use of the cryptocurrency function within Telegram for individuals in certain jurisdictions, including the US, China, and Hong Kong.</p>
<h2>Asia&#8217;s ‘Super App’ Market For Toncoin Adoption</h2>
<p>According to the report, TON recognizes Asia as a natural fit for its expansion due to the region&#8217;s familiarity with the concept of &#8220;super apps.&#8221; The partnership with HashKey aims to leverage the existing &#8220;super app&#8221; culture prevalent in Asia-Pacific, with renowned platforms such as Line, Kakao, and WeChat. </p>
<p>HashKey recently launched a global <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/telegram-ton-deepen-integration-with-crypto-feature/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">crypto exchange</a> and received an upgraded license from Hong Kong&#8217;s Securities and Futures Commission, enabling it to sell crypto-related investment products to retail investors. </p>
<p>Notably, HashKey aims to surpass Coinbase&#8217;s trading volume by 2030, positioning itself as a formidable competitor in the crypto exchange landscape.</p>

<p>Ultimately, the partnership between HashKey Group and the Open Network Foundation opens new avenues for Toncoin adoption and cash conversion in the Asia-Pacific region. </p>
<p>By integrating Toncoin into the Telegram ecosystem, both organizations aim to cater to millions of potential Asian users who are already familiar with the &#8220;super app&#8221; concept. </p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/O7X4HpCF/" alt="TON" width="1815" height="858" />
<p>Currently, the native token of the blockchain, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/toncoin-flips-cardano-dogecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">TON</a>, is trading at $7.14, reflecting a slight decline of nearly 3% within the last 24 hours. However, an analysis of the 1-day TON/USD chart reveals a noteworthy upward trend spanning the past 30 days. The token has exhibited substantial gains during this period, amounting to 63%. </p>
<p>Featured image from Shutterstock, chart from TradingView.com </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/photo-1636743091340-af4ee8147080.avif?resize=630,420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293984</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogecoin Developer Sounds Warning Ahead Of Coinbase’s DOGE And PEPE Futures Listing</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-coinbase-doge-pepe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 16:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dogecoin developer and contributor, Mishaboar has warned the Dogecoin community of the risks involved in engaging the cryptocurrency leverages and derivatives market. He explains that the current market is too volatile and unpredictable for investors, cautioning that investors could end up losing badly.  Mishaboar Says “Stay Away” From Crypto Derivatives In a recent X (formerly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dogecoin developer and contributor, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-bitcoin-spot-etfs/">Mishaboar</a> has warned the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-community-doge-day/">Dogecoin community</a> of the risks involved in engaging the cryptocurrency leverages and derivatives market. He explains that the current <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/all/dogecoin-doge-leads-gains-among-top-coins/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">market is too volatile and unpredictable</a> for investors, cautioning that investors could end up losing badly. </p>
<h2>Mishaboar Says “Stay Away” From Crypto Derivatives</h2>
<p>In a recent X (formerly Twitter) post, Mishaboar <a href="https://x.com/mishaboar/status/1778259578980835460?s=46" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">firmly advised</a> Dogecoin investors and traders to stay away from leverage and derivatives in crypto. The developer’s warning comes amidst the growing anticipation within the Dogecoin community, spurred by Coinbase’s recent announcement of a potential <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-coinbase-futures-listing/">listing for Dogecoin futures</a> this April. </p>

<p>Mishaboar has warned <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/dogecoin-is-bullish-crypto-analyst/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">DOGE investors</a> to avoid the leverages and derivatives market at all times, but more so in the coming weeks. Responding to an inquiry from community members seeking clarification for his statements, Mishaboar elaborated that cryptocurrency trading is inherently a risky business; however, the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-derivatives-hints-historic-2021-performance/">leverages and derivatives market</a> had a higher risk level, to the point of it being unacceptable. </p>
<p>“The unfairness and risk you expose yourself to is not worth it in a market where assets are already so volatile,” Mishaboar wrote. </p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/mishaboar/status/1778262175078908256?s=46" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">likened</a> trading in this crypto market to playing in a gambling house where the odds are stacked against traders, highlighting that traders would be essentially playing against the owners of the casino as well as <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitmexs-calls-crypto-exchanges-ditch-market-makers/">market makers</a> with access to liquidity and other advantages on their side. </p>
<p>Additionally, Mishaboar explained his reasoning for advising traders to steer clear away of the derivatives market during this period. The Dogecoin developer <a href="https://x.com/mishaboar/status/1778410282349387873?s=46" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">highlighted</a> the upcoming <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-halving-a-look-at-post-halving-performance/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Bitcoin halving event</a> as a catalyst for potential market turbulence, stressing that unpredictability and volatility would significantly elevate risks. </p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/mishaboar/status/1778409150705291690?s=46" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">disclosed</a> that the large influx of liquidity from new markets and conflict of interest from exchanges would also add another layer of complexity in <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/ripple-ceo-5-trillion-in-2024/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">predicting market movements</a>. Moreover, since many players within this market are aiming to utilize <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-whales-doge-price/">Dogecoin</a> to initiate trades, they could be exposed to significant risks that result in them losing all their funds. </p>
<h2>Coinbase To List Dogecoin And Pepe Futures This April</h2>
<p>In a recent blog post, Coinbase, an American crypto exchange, <a href="https://wwwi.coinbase.com/blog/coinbase-derivatives-has-successfully-launched-bitcoin-cash-and-litecoin" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> that it was gearing up to list Dogecoin futures in the later stages of April. This development was made in alignment with Coinbase’s expansion strategy to extend their futures contracts to meet the needs of their growing network of traders. </p>

<p>Additionally, the announcement comes at a time when <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin-cash/bitcoin-cash-bch-15-coinbase-futures-listing/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Coinbase launched their new Bitcoin Cash </a>and Litecoin futures contracts. The exchange revealed that expanding its offerings to these cryptocurrencies would improve access to digital asset trading and enable traders to participate with reduced capital within a regulated framework.  </p>
<p>In addition to its upcoming Dogecoin futures listing, Coinbase revealed in an X post published on Thursday that it would be adding support for the popular frog-themed meme coin, Pepe (PEPE), in its perpetual futures offerings. These futures labeled 1000PEPE-PERP will be available for trading on April 18 on Coinbase International Exchange and Coinbase Advanced.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/1ze4VtsH/" alt="Dogecoin price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Dogecoin_63d5d5.jpeg?fit=300%2C168" width="300" height="168" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293906</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Exchange Deposits Stay Low: Whales Disinterested In Selling?</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-exchange-deposits-low-whales-selling/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Keshav Verma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Bullish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Exchange Deposits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin exchange inflows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Selling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin whales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On-chain data shows the Bitcoin exchange inflows have remained low recently, a sign that the whales have been disinterested in selling. Bitcoin Inflows For Binance &#38; OKX Have Stayed Low Recently As pointed out by CryptoQuant founder and CEO Ki Young Ju in a post on X, the BTC deposits for cryptocurrency exchanges Binance and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On-chain data shows the Bitcoin exchange inflows have remained low recently, a sign that the whales have been disinterested in selling.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Inflows For Binance &amp; OKX Have Stayed Low Recently</h2>
<p>As pointed out by CryptoQuant founder and CEO Ki Young Ju in a <a href="https://twitter.com/ki_young_ju/status/1778596992924700909" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">post</a> on X, the BTC deposits for cryptocurrency exchanges Binance and OKX have been low recently.</p>
<p>The on-chain indicator of interest here is the &#8220;<a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-exchange-inflow-mean-spikes-pullback-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">exchange inflow</a>,&#8221; which keeps track of the total amount of Bitcoin that&#8217;s being transferred to the wallets attached to centralized exchanges.</p>

<p>When the value of this metric is high, it means that the investors are depositing a large number of tokens to these platforms right now. As one of the main reasons why holders would transfer to the exchanges is for selling-purposes, this kind of trend can have bearish implications for the asset.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the indicator being low implies these platforms aren&#8217;t observing that many deposits currently. Depending on the trend in the opposite metric, the exchange outflow, such a value may be either bullish or neutral for the cryptocurrency&#8217;s price.</p>
<p>Now, here is a chart that shows the trend in the Bitcoin exchange inflow for Binance and OKX over the past few years:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GK7VguJa8AAL4ry?format=jpg&amp;name=large" alt="Bitcoin Binance &amp; OKX Exchange Inflow" width="1396" height="944" /></p>

<p>Binance is the largest exchange in the world on the basis of trading volume, while OKX is generally number two behind it in the same metric. While these two platforms certainly don&#8217;t make up for the entire cryptocurrency market, the user behavior on them would still provide an estimation about the wider pattern.</p>
<p>As is visible in the chart, the exchange inflow for Binance and OKX has been at relatively low levels for quite a while now. When BTC observed its rally towards a new all-time high (ATH) earlier in the year, the deposits saw a slight uptrend, but recently, the inflows slumped back to low values.</p>
<p>This would suggest that the appetite for selling, particularly from the whales, just hasn&#8217;t been there for the cryptocurrency. Even the ATH break could only entice a few large users of the platforms to push towards selling.</p>
<p>The behavior is in contrast to, for example, the second half of the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-shatters-profit-taking-streak-2021-bull-run/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">2021 bull run</a>, which can be seen in the chart. The rally back then had not only observed some exceptional inflow spikes, but the baseline inflows had also generally been higher than recent levels.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the two major tops of the rally had also coincided pretty well with extremely large inflows, so going by this pattern, the current rally may not be near a top yet.</p>

<p>Though, it remains to be seen whether this same trend would continue to hold for this cycle, given the fresh emergence of the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/us-banks-wall-street-giants-buy-bitcoin-etfs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">spot exchange-traded funds (ETFs)</a>.</p>
<p>The ETFs have provided an alternate means to gain exposure to the asset, meaning that cryptocurrency exchanges may not carry the same relevance in the market anymore.</p>
<h2>BTC Price</h2>
<p>At the time of writing, Bitcoin is floating around $70,400, up more than 5% over the last seven days.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium aligncenter" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/wr9msyWq/" alt="Bitcoin Price Chart" width="1534" height="854" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/thomas-lipke-kkXDhAUnxYI-unsplash.jpg?fit=640%2C394" width="640" height="394" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293928</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong Set To Greenlight Spot Bitcoin And Ether ETFs By Monday: Report</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/hong-kong-greenlight-spot-bitcoin-ether-etfs-monday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short Ether ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spot Bitcoin ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spot Ethereum ETF]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=293940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hong Kong is on the cusp of approving its first spot Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH) exchange-traded funds (ETFs) with potential final approvals as early as Monday, according to Bloomberg, citing two people familiar with the matter. This move positions Hong Kong as a pivotal player in the Asian cryptocurrency market and underscores its ambition [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong is on the cusp of approving its first spot Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH) exchange-traded funds (ETFs) with potential final approvals as early as Monday, according to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-12/hong-kong-bitcoin-ether-etf-approval-expected-as-soon-as-monday" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a>, citing two people familiar with the matter. This move positions Hong Kong as a pivotal player in the Asian cryptocurrency market and underscores its ambition to become a leading digital-asset hub.</p>
<h2>Approval For The Spot Bitcoin, ETH ETFs On Monday?</h2>
<p>The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) of Hong Kong is reportedly finalizing the approval process, with Harvest Global Investments and a partnership between Bosera Asset Management (International) Co. and HashKey Capital poised to receive the first set of approvals. These approvals are contingent upon completing the necessary listing arrangements with Hong Kong Exchanges &amp; Clearing Ltd. (HKEX), aiming for a product launch by the end of April.</p>

<p>Unlike the futures-based crypto ETFs currently available in Hong Kong, these spot-crypto ETFs will allow for direct investment in the actual cryptocurrencies, Bitcoin and Ether. This method could offer a more tangible asset base for investors, contrasting with derivatives-based investments. The <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/breaking-spot-bitcoin-etfs-approved-by-us-sec/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">introduction</a> of similar ETFs in the United States on January 11 this year has been linked to increased market activity and significant capital inflows into the sector.</p>
<p>Notably, the upcoming Hong Kong ETFs will utilize an &#8220;in-kind creation model,&#8221; as <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-etfs-to-receive-green-light-in-hong-kong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">reported</a> earlier by Bitcoinist. This model facilitates the actual exchange of cryptocurrencies in the creation and redemption processes, which could reduce costs and improve liquidity—a notable advancement over traditional ETF structures and the US peers.</p>

<p>Moreover, the rollout of these ETFs is strategically timed, as the global crypto community anticipates the upcoming <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/why-bitcoin-halving-could-bring-uncertainty-to-mining-industry/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin Halving</a> event in just eight days, which historically influenced market dynamics. This strategic launch could attract substantial new investments not only by Hong Kongers but also from the wider Chinese and Asian market.</p>
<p>This development follows a series of regulatory advancements in Hong Kong, including the implementation of a <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/hong-kong-takes-decisive-crypto-step-preparing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">regulatory regime</a> for virtual asset service providers and the approval of virtual asset management funds. The introduction of these spot ETFs is seen as a continuation of these efforts to foster a regulated and stable environment for digital assets, enhancing investor protection and integrating digital assets more closely with traditional financial sectors.</p>
<p>According to Singapore-based Matrixport, the investment vehicle could unlock up to $25 billion in demand from Chinese investors through the Southbound Stock Connect program.</p>
<p>At press time, BTC price did not show any major reaction to the news and traded at $70,656.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-293948" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472" alt="Bitcoin price" width="1024" height="472" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3628 3628w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1536 1536w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=2048 2048w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1140 1140w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-12_14-35-53.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" />

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-12-14.40.05-A-wide-format-artistic-image-displaying-the-flag-of-Hong-Kong-in-the-background-stretched-across-the-length-of-the-image.-In-the-foreground-a-large.webp?fit=640%2C366" width="640" height="366" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293940</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
