<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bitcoinist.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:39:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/cropped-cropped-cropped-Icon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Bitcoinist.com</title>
	<link>https://bitcoinist.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">225283986</site>	<item>
		<title>Shiba Inu Shibarium Faces Technical Glitch: Network Outage Hinders User Experience</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/shiba-inu-shibarium-faces-technical-glitch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Godspower Owie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daal Dhairya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MetaMask]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remote Procedure Call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shib]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shibarium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shibariumscan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIBUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIBUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trust Wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wallet Connect]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst the burgeoning landscape of cryptocurrency solutions, Shiba Inu&#8217;s layer 2 protocol Shibarium suffered a major setback due to a temporary network outage within the platform that affected users&#8217; seamless operations and experience.  Shibarium Faces Temporary Service Disruption Popular Shiba Inu developer Kaal Dhairya shared the information on the X (formerly Twitter) platform today while [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amidst the burgeoning landscape of cryptocurrency solutions, Shiba Inu&#8217;s layer 2 protocol <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/shibarium-breaks-the-internet-again-with-over-400-million-layer-2-transactions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Shibarium</a> suffered a major setback due to a temporary network outage within the platform that affected users&#8217; seamless operations and experience. </p>
<h2>Shibarium Faces Temporary Service Disruption</h2>
<p>Popular <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/shiba-inu-staking-platform-passes-4-key-proposals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Shiba Inu</a> developer Kaal Dhairya <a href="https://x.com/kaaldhairya/status/1782200776443715882" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">shared</a> the information on the X (formerly Twitter) platform today while offering an update on the development. This development underscores the difficulty in upholding reliable network infrastructure in the face of increasing demand and changing technological environments.</p>

<p>It is important to note that since the launch of Shibarium, the feature has had several network outages. Following its founding in August last year, Shibarium witnessed a significant technical problem, which resulted in the failure of its mainnet Remote Procedure Call (RPC). </p>
<p>Shibarium consequently underwent a rigorous two-week scaling period before relaunching on the main net and continuing to function ever since. Kaal Dhairya noted that networking problems amongst Shibarium validators caused the recent temporary service outage. Specifically, these Shibrium validators are organizations in charge of verifying transactions on the platform and preserving the integrity of the network.</p>
<p>Although the network has fully recovered, several services, such as the platform&#8217;s block explorer Shibariumscan and external RPCs, may still be unavailable until the suggested actions are taken, indicating the team&#8217;s continued effort to resolve the technical issues.</p>
<p>The post read:</p>
<blockquote><p>There was a temporary Shibarium outage caused because of networking issues amongst the validators. The network is back up and running now, some services like Shibariumscan or external RPCs can still remain down until the steps provided are implemented.</p></blockquote>
<p>Given some services are still down, Dhairya has urged every external team working on the platform&#8217;s infrastructure, like RPC, to get in touch in order to arrange for more efficient communication over shared Slack and Telegram channels.</p>
<h2>Latest UI Update On The Layer 2 Solution</h2>
<p>The recent mishap came in light of the<a href="https://x.com/ShibariumNet/status/1781005662618620311" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> inception</a> of the latest User Interface (UI) upgrade on the layer 2 protocol designed to help link Shibarium to other leading platforms and improve the blockchain experience for users. &#8220;We expanded wallet compatibility with MetaMask, Coinbase Wallet, Rainbow, Trust Wallet, and Wallet Connect to let you Shibas connect the way you want,&#8221; the team stated.</p>

<p>According to the team, user experience and speed were their top priorities while rebuilding the platform. Thus, they are constantly working to improve the utilization and potency of <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/how-well-does-blockchain-technology-protect-your-personal-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">blockchain technology</a>. </p>
<p>With this new UI update, the solution&#8217;s performance is bound to improve, making it more rapid, smoother, and more accessible than ever. This upgrade is also indicative of Shibarium&#8217;s consistent efforts to expand accessibility and usability in the context of <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/cfos-weigh-in-on-the-efficiency-costs-and-user-benefits-of-decentralized-finance-and-traditional-banking/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">decentralized finance</a>.</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/XabIWpE5/" alt="Shibarium" width="2273" height="1351" />

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/iStock-1327123774.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295844</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sam Bankman-Fried Turns Rat, Cooperates In Lawsuit Vs. FTX Celebrity Backers</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/sam-bankman-fried-turns-rat-cooperates-in-lawsuit-vs-ftx-celebrity-backers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Bankman-Fried]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SBF]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The drama surrounding the FTX collapse continues to unfold with a surprising twist. Sam Bankman-Fried, the crypto wunderkind turned convicted fraudster, has agreed to cooperate with investors suing the company&#8217;s celebrity endorsers, including sports stars Tom Brady and Shaquille O&#8217;Neal, and actor Larry David. Related Reading: Crypto Industry Faces New Threat: Section 702 US Surveillance [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:310">The drama surrounding the FTX collapse continues to unfold with a surprising twist. Sam Bankman-Fried, the crypto wunderkind turned convicted fraudster, has agreed to cooperate with investors<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-19/ftx-investors-settle-with-sam-bankman-fried-to-pursue-promoters" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> suing the company&#8217;s celebrity endorsers,</a> including sports stars Tom Brady and Shaquille O&#8217;Neal, and actor Larry David.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="5:1-5:374">This move comes as a shock considering Bankman-Fried is currently appealing his 25-year prison sentence for defrauding FTX customers. The class-action lawsuit against the celebrity endorsers accuses them of deception and making false claims about the safety of FTX&#8217;s crypto assets. Investors believe Bankman-Fried&#8217;s insider knowledge can significantly strengthen their case.</p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="7:1-7:65"><strong>Sam Bankman-Fried: Playing The Snitch Role</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:324">Bankman-Fried, once hailed as a crypto messiah, saw his empire crumble in November 2022 when FTX filed for bankruptcy. The exchange, which rose to prominence thanks in part to a star-studded marketing campaign featuring A-listers like Tom Brady and Shaquille O&#8217;Neal, experienced a liquidity crisis and ultimately imploded.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A group of FTX investors and customers has agreed to drop their claims against co-founder Sam Bankman-Fried in exchange for his cooperation against other defendants in lawsuits over the cryptocurrency exchange’s collapse. <a href="https://t.co/9xmQo0rgpi" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://t.co/9xmQo0rgpi</a></p>
<p>— Bloomberg Crypto (@crypto) <a href="https://twitter.com/crypto/status/1781413767638597721?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:327">Now, from his Brooklyn jail cell, Bankman-Fried appears to be <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-xl/news/other/jailed-ftx-founder-sam-bankman-fried-turns-on-his-celebrity-endorsers/ar-AA1nq2fp" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">playing a new game.</a> In exchange for his cooperation, investors have agreed to drop any future civil claims against him. This deal, if approved by a judge, could significantly reduce his legal exposure. But what exactly motivated Bankman-Fried to make this move?</p>
<p data-sourcepos="13:1-13:276">Some legal experts speculate that Bankman-Fried sees this as an opportunity to potentially curry favor with the court during his criminal appeal. Others believe this might be a calculated attempt to deflect some of the blame for the FTX debacle onto the celebrity endorsers.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="13:1-13:276"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/RwxIX5jh/" width="2475" height="1163" /></p>

<h2 data-sourcepos="15:1-15:50"><strong>Can Bankman-Fried Deliver The Knockout Punch?</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="17:1-17:246">The lawsuit hinges on the ability to prove that the celebrity endorsers knowingly misled investors about FTX. Sam Bankman-Fried&#8217;s cooperation could be crucial in providing evidence of their involvement and understanding of the company&#8217;s operations.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="19:1-19:275">For example, if Sam Bankman-Fried can reveal internal emails or communications where he warned celebrities about potential risks associated with FTX products, it could significantly bolster the case against them. However, the effectiveness of his cooperation might be limited.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:239">Celebrity endorsement deals often involve carefully crafted scripts and limited due diligence on the part of the talent. If Bankman-Fried can&#8217;t provide concrete proof of deliberate deception by the endorsers, the lawsuit could fall flat.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="23:1-23:421">The fallout from the FTX collapse continues to reverberate throughout the crypto industry. This latest development, with a disgraced CEO potentially turning state&#8217;s witness against celebrity icons, is sure to inject even more drama into an already captivating saga.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="23:1-23:421"><em>Featured image from Eduardo Munoz/Reuters, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_08cf47.png?fit=562%2C420" width="562" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295808</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swiss Referendum To Oblige Bitcoin Holdings For Central Bank</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/swiss-referendum-bitcoin-central-bank/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Swiss National Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SNB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swiss Central Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swiss National Bank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A group of Swiss Bitcoin advocates led by Yves Bennaïm has initiated a referendum to amend the Swiss constitution in a way that would mandate the Swiss National Bank (SNB) to include BTC alongside gold in its currency reserves, as reported by local media. The proposed amendment to the Swiss constitution is succinct yet significant. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of Swiss Bitcoin advocates led by Yves Bennaïm has initiated a referendum to amend the Swiss constitution in a way that would mandate the Swiss National Bank (SNB) to include BTC alongside gold in its currency reserves, as reported by <a href="https://www.nzz.ch/wirtschaft/nun-kommt-die-volksinitiative-welche-die-nationalbank-zum-kauf-von-bitcoin-verpflichten-will-ld.1827256" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">local media</a>.</p>
<p>The proposed amendment to the Swiss constitution is succinct yet significant. It seeks to modify the clause that currently mandates the SNB to &#8220;build up sufficient currency reserves from its earnings; part of these reserves shall be held in <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-eyes-the-gold-throne-market-guru-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">gold</a>,&#8221; to now include &#8220;and Bitcoin.&#8221; This change, though minimal in wording, could usher a substantial shift in the fiscal management of the nation.</p>
<h2>Will The Swiss Central Bank (Have To) Adopt Bitcoin?</h2>
<p>Yves Bennaïm, a figure deeply ingrained in the Swiss crypto scene and a board member of the Bitcoin Association Switzerland, articulated that the initiative is not just about altering the reserve assets but is a strategic move to &#8220;protect our sovereignty and neutrality&#8221; in an uncertain global economy. According to Bennaïm, the aim is also to &#8220;initiate a debate&#8221; on the future financial direction of Switzerland.</p>

<p>Support comes from within the industry, notably from Luzius Meisser, President of the asset management division at Bitcoin Suisse. Meisser, who is set to present his case at the SNB&#8217;s Annual General Meeting this Friday, April 26 at 10 am CET, stated, &#8220;Bitcoin is more robust in the long term than euro and dollar investments, which are susceptible to inflationary pressures that could devalue the SNB’s investments.&#8221; He also noted that Bitcoin could serve as a declaration of Switzerland&#8217;s financial independence from major central banks like the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-is-worthless-ecb-president/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">European Central Bank</a>.</p>
<p>The initiative has garnered attention from various sectors of the finance world. Leon Curti, Head of Research at Digital Asset Solutions, remarked on the evolving status of Bitcoin in global markets, noting that its <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/cftc-chair-only-bitcoin-is-a-commodity-not-ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">classification as a commodity</a> by the US Securities and Exchange Commission &#8220;is a legitimization that could ease the SNB’s transition towards including it in its reserves.&#8221;</p>
<p>From an academic perspective, Professor Gunther Schnabl, who leads the Institute for Economic Policy at the University of Leipzig and has previously advised the European Central Bank, supports the notion. Schnabl highlighted the precarious state of traditional reserve assets, stating, &#8220;Government debt has risen sharply in most industrialized countries, meaning that the risk of default has increased.&#8221; He advocates for Bitcoin as a viable tool for risk diversification within the SNB&#8217;s foreign currency reserves.</p>

<p>However, not all feedback is positive. Critics point to Bitcoin&#8217;s historic volatility and the regulatory uncertainties that still surround digital currencies. They argue that such characteristics might not align with the traditionally conservative strategies employed by national central banks.</p>
Swiss National Bank Could Be $32.9 Billion Richer
<p>Two years ago, Thomas Jordan, the outgoing SNB Chairman, had <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-very-interesting-concept-swiss-snb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">dismissed</a> a similar proposal, stating that Bitcoin did not meet the requirements for currency reserves &#8220;from today&#8217;s perspective.&#8221; The SNB has yet to comment on whether its stance has changed in light of the new proposal and the evolving regulatory and economic landscape.</p>
<p>Luzius Meisser estimates that an aggressive buying strategy could have significantly enriched Switzerland&#8217;s reserves given past Bitcoin price appreciation. &#8220;If the SNB had commenced buying CHF 1 billion worth of Bitcoin every month starting in 2022, Switzerland could be around 30 billion francs ($32.9 billion) richer today,&#8221; Meisser claims, citing the strong performance of Bitcoin compared to traditional assets like German government bonds.</p>
<p>In Switzerland, any citizen can initiate a national referendum to amend the constitution, provided they gather 100,000 valid signatures from fellow Swiss citizens. The referendum, if successful, would not only impact Switzerland’s financial strategy but could also serve as a benchmark for other nations. As the SNB prepares for its upcoming Annual General Meeting, all eyes will be on how it addresses this unprecedented proposal.</p>
<p>At press time, BTC traded at $66,254.</p>
<img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-295803" src="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472" alt="Bitcoin price" width="1024" height="472" srcset="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3628 3628w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=640 640w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=768 768w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=980 980w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1536 1536w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=2048 2048w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=750 750w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=1140 1140w, https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-22_07-43-02.png?resize=1024%2C472?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" />

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-22-07.05.34-A-digital-representation-of-a-Bitcoin-coin-in-the-foreground-with-the-Swiss-flag-waving-in-the-background.-The-Bitcoin-should-appear-shiny-and-metalli.webp?fit=640%2C366" width="640" height="366" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295789</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Industry Faces New Threat: Section 702 US Surveillance Bill Passed</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-industry-faces-new-threat-section-702-us-surveillance-bill-passed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 17:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[section 702]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Senate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The US Senate has voted to reauthorize Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA), a move that has sparked widespread debate and concern among civil liberties advocates and members of the crypto community. Related Reading: Halving Hype Debunked: Binance Founder Says Don’t Fall For This Bitcoin Myth Section 702, originally introduced as a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Senate has voted to reauthorize Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA), a move that has sparked widespread debate and concern among civil liberties advocates and members of the crypto community.</p>

<p>Section 702, originally introduced as a counterterrorism measure, grants the US government broad authority to collect data from various sources, including tech giants like Google and Facebook, without the need for a warrant.</p>
<p>Despite opposition from civil liberties groups and some senators, the bill passed with a landslide vote of 60-34, setting the stage for its extension for an additional two years pending US President Joe Biden&#8217;s signature.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is bad.</p>
<p>Crypto is not just about trading tokens, it&#8217;s part of a broader ethos of protecting freedom and privacy and keeping power in the hands of the little guy.</p>
<p>And these values unfortunately continue to be under attack, globally. <a href="https://t.co/iFM932IBP6" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://t.co/iFM932IBP6</a></p>
<p>— vitalik.eth (@VitalikButerin) <a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1781712882645795202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<h2><strong>Crypto Industry Braces For Impact</strong></h2>
<p>Amidst the renewed debate over privacy and government surveillance, the crypto industry finds itself at the forefront of the conversation. With its emphasis on decentralization and anonymity, the industry is particularly vulnerable to the expanded powers granted by Section 702.</p>
<p>Civil liberties activists have long argued that Section 702&#8217;s broad powers are ripe for abuse and could lead to the indiscriminate collection of data on US citizens. Senator Ron Wyden has labeled it as one of history’s most dramatic expansions of government surveillance authority, sparking fears over the erosion of privacy rights.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NEWS: Wyden Statement on Reauthorization of FISA 702 Without Reforms to Warrantless Surveillance of Americans <a href="https://t.co/ywCNELcpuV" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://t.co/ywCNELcpuV</a></p>
<p>— WydenPress (@WydenPress) <a href="https://twitter.com/WydenPress/status/1781539538545844563?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<h2><strong>Regulatory Crackdowns Loom Large</strong></h2>
<p>The renewal of Section 702 raises the specter of increased regulatory scrutiny and compliance requirements for crypto businesses. Entities such as the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), and the Department of Justice (DOJ) could intensify their crackdowns on businesses, including decentralized exchanges, to ensure compliance with surveillance and data collection requirements.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/Vs40cx7J/" width="1835" height="883" /></p>

<strong>Contrasting Perspectives</strong>
<p>While some senators, like Senator Elizabeth Warren, advocate for surveillance measures targeting users within the crypto industry, others express skepticism over the potential implications for privacy and civil liberties. The revelation of improper searches by government agencies, including the FBI, further underscores the need for robust oversight and accountability measures.</p>
<strong>Collaboration And Controversy In The Crypto Sphere</strong>
<p>Despite the concerns surrounding government surveillance, there are also instances of collaboration between crypto companies and law enforcement agencies in combating illicit activities. Tether CEO&#8217;s disclosure of collaboration with the FBI and the Secret Service to combat terror funding highlights the complex relationship between the crypto industry and regulatory authorities.</p>

<p>As the debate over Section 702 continues to unfold, the crypto industry finds itself at a crossroads. The renewal of the controversial surveillance law poses significant challenges to the industry&#8217;s core principles of decentralization and privacy, while also raising questions about the role of government oversight in emerging technologies.</p>
<p><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_874dbb.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295756</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Pundit Says Bitcoin Halving Is A &#8216;Buy The News&#8217; Event</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/crypto-pundit-says-bitcoin-halving-is-a-buy-the-news-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The fourth Bitcoin halving has now been completed and crypto investors look forward to its outcome in terms of the price of Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies. As the biggest crypto asset, the price of most altcoins are largely correlated with Bitcoin&#8217;s, making the halving event very important to all investors.  Related Reading: Stablecoins Get A [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fourth Bitcoin halving <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/halving-block-bitcoin-840000/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">has now been completed</a> and crypto investors <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/fourth-bitcoin-halving-completed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">look forward to its outcome</a> in terms of the price of Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies. As the biggest crypto asset, the price of most altcoins are largely correlated with Bitcoin&#8217;s, making the halving event very important to all investors. </p>

<p>According to Matt Hougan, CIO of crypto index fund provider Bitwise Asset Management, the just concluded Bitcoin halving presents a buying opportunity for crypto investors. </p>
<h2><b>Is Bitcoin Halving A &#8216;Buy The News&#8217; Opportunity?</b></h2>
<p>Bitcoin halving events are highly anticipated in the crypto world. While speaking in <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/video/2024/04/19/bitcoin-prices-will-rally-substantially-after-this-weeks-halving-says-bitwise-cio-matt-hougan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">an interview with CNBC Squawk Box</a>, Hougan noted that Bitcoin prices will rally substantially after the halving, making it a &#8220;buy the news&#8221; event, especially when looking at the long term.</p>
<p>Hougan went ahead to analyze Bitcoin&#8217;s price action in the months after the halving, noting how the asset&#8217;s price rallied substantially in the year after the last three halvings. Hougan credits this price increase to the supply crunch in the months after the halvings. </p>
<p>“The amount of new supply of Bitcoin coming into the market is being cut in half. We’re removing $11 billion of annual supply. I think big picture, that has to be good for price and that’s what I would expect over the next year,” Hougan said. </p>
<p>When asked about the potential of Bitcoin being used as a <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/inflationary-concerns-rise-as-us-cpi-exceeds-predictions-bitcoin-price-reacts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">store of value</a> amidst <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/why-did-dogecoin-shiba-inu-and-other-meme-coins-crash/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">geopolitical tensions</a>, particularly in the <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/4/13/israeli-army-says-iran-has-launched-drones-at-israel" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Middle East</a>, Hougan noted the crypto&#8217;s ability is best seen in the big picture. </p>
<p>&#8220;If you look big picture, its done a great job of protecting us against inflation post-COVID. I think eventually it will be a good hedge against geopolitical disruptions,&#8221; Hougan said.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/K4i1ih0B/" width="1835" height="883" /></p>

<h2><b>What’s Next For Bitcoin?</b></h2>
<p>The <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-halving-could-catalyzed-100000-price-surge-bitwise-ceo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">recently concluded Bitcoin halving</a> saw the rewards given to miners slashed from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC. The idea and design behind each halving are pretty simple. With fewer new bitcoins entering circulation, existing bitcoins could become more valuable. In each of the three previous halvings, the price of bitcoin fluctuated in the first few months, but it ended up being much higher one year later</p>
<p>For example, the price of Bitcoin lingered for at least nine months after the 2020 halving before finally going on a 458% price surge. If history were to repeat itself, a similar 450% surge would put the price of Bitcoin around $345,000 in the first quarter of 2025.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, Bitcoin is trading at $64,870. Bitcoin is currently up by over 130% in the yearly timeframe leading up to the just concluded halving. A similar 130% surge in a yearly timeframe after the halving puts the price of Bitcoin around $150,000 by mid-2025. </p>

<p>Interestingly, this price range sits better with Anthony Scaramucci, founder of SkyBridge Capital, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/skybridge-chief-sees-bitcoin-soaring-to-170k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">who predicted</a> the BTC price would reach at least $170,000 by the end of the current market cycle.</p>
<p><em>Featured image from Pixabay, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_4e3bbc.webp?fit=640%2C366" width="640" height="366" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295759</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wealth Whisperers Go Crypto: Bitcoin ETFs Set For Big Boost From Unexpected Source</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-etfs-set-for-big-boost-ceo-says/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 12:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the financial world witnesses a seismic shift in the landscape of cryptocurrency investment, institutional players are making bold moves into the realm of Bitcoin Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs). Bitwise CEO Hunter Horsley&#8217;s recent proclamation has sent ripples through the industry, forecasting a staggering surge in Bitcoin ETF holdings by wealth management firms by the end [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the financial world witnesses a seismic shift in the landscape of <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/bitcoin" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">cryptocurrency</a> investment, institutional players are making bold moves into the realm of Bitcoin Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs).</p>
<p>Bitwise CEO Hunter Horsley&#8217;s recent proclamation has sent ripples through the industry, forecasting a staggering surge in Bitcoin ETF holdings by wealth management firms by the end of 2024. This prediction underscores a broader trend of growing institutional interest and confidence in Bitcoin, signaling a new era for digital asset adoption.</p>

<h2><strong>Bitcoin ETFs Gain Momentum Amidst Changing Market Dynamics</strong></h2>
<p>The emergence of <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/investing/bitcoin-etfs-explained/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Bitcoin ETFs</a> as a preferred investment vehicle for institutional investors is highlighted by the rapid ascent of BlackRock&#8217;s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT), which stands on the cusp of surpassing Grayscale&#8217;s Bitcoin Trust (GBTC) as the largest Bitcoin fund globally.</p>
<p>With IBIT&#8217;s assets swelling to approximately $17.3 billion, just $2 billion shy of GBTC&#8217;s, the stage is set for a potential changing of the guard within the market. This shift in dominance reflects a broader trend of institutional reallocation, as evidenced by significant outflows from Grayscale&#8217;s GBTC in recent months.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">By the end of 2024, people are going to be stunned by how many wealth management firms own a bitcoin ETF.</p>
<p>They’re smart, many extremely well informed, and increasingly share conviction on Bitcoin. Oh, and they’re long only.</p>
<p>Going to be an amazing new constituent in the…</p>
<p>— Hunter Horsley (@HHorsley) <a href="https://twitter.com/HHorsley/status/1781808283067834426?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>While Grayscale&#8217;s early-mover advantage in the Bitcoin ETF market has begun to wane, other institutional heavyweights such as Fidelity and BlackRock are stepping into the fray with notable net inflows into their respective Bitcoin ETFs. Fidelity and BlackRock Bitcoin ETFs witnessed substantial net inflows of $37.3 million and $18.7 million, respectively, in a single week, signaling a shift in investor sentiment and liquidity dynamics.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/DNQfpeJ4/" width="1835" height="883" /></p>

<h2><strong>Bitcoin ETFs: A Stepping Stone For Institutional Adoption</strong></h2>
<p>Behind the scenes, registered investment advisers (RIAs) and multifamily offices are quietly embracing Bitcoin ETFs, marking a significant milestone in the broader acceptance of cryptocurrencies within traditional financial institutions. Bitwise CEO Hunter Horsley describes this phenomenon as &#8220;stealthy but material,&#8221; indicating a growing recognition of Bitcoin&#8217;s potential as a legitimate asset class.</p>



<p>In response to market demand and the impending <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-halving-stimulates-dialogue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin halving,</a> institutional behemoths are conducting extensive studies and incorporating Bitcoin into their investment portfolios. This shift represents a fundamental reevaluation of traditional investment strategies, as institutions seek to diversify their holdings and capitalize on the potential upside of Bitcoin&#8217;s meteoric rise.</p>
<p>As the cryptocurrency market continues to evolve, Bitcoin ETFs are poised to play a pivotal role in driving institutional adoption and reshaping the financial landscape.</p>
<p>With BlackRock&#8217;s IBIT on the verge of eclipsing Grayscale&#8217;s GBTC and institutional investors flocking to Bitcoin ETFs in record numbers, the stage is set for a new era of digital asset investment.</p>
<p>As Bitwise CEO Hunter Horsley aptly puts it:</p>
<blockquote>
&#8220;By the end of 2024, people are going to be stunned by how many wealth management firms own a Bitcoin ETF.&#8221;
</blockquote>
<p><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_516357.jpg?fit=630%2C420" width="630" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295752</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigerian Court Adjourns Binance Tax Evasion Trial To May 17</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/nigerian-court-adjourns-binance-tax-trial-to-may-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Semilore Faleti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FIRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Money Laundering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tax Evasion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tigran Gambaryan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Nigerian court has rescheduled the hearing of a tax evasion lawsuit against Binance and some of its executives to May 17. This adjournment represents the latest development in the ongoing regulatory saga between various agencies of the Nigerian government and the Malta-based cryptocurrency exchange. Related Reading: Impending Extradition? Nigerian Authorities Trace Fleeing Binance Exec [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Nigerian court has rescheduled the hearing of a tax evasion lawsuit against Binance and some of its executives to May 17. This adjournment represents the latest development in the ongoing regulatory saga between various agencies of the Nigerian government and the Malta-based cryptocurrency exchange.
</p>
<p>Related Reading: <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/impending-extradition-nigerian-authorities-trace-fleeing-binance-exec-to-kenya-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Impending Extradition? Nigerian Authorities Trace Fleeing Binance Exec To Kenya – Report</a></p>
<h2><strong>Tax Case Adjourned Over Legal Standstill</strong></h2>
<p>On March 22, the Nigerian Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) charged Binance and two of its executives, namely Nadeen Ahjarwalla, head of financial crime compliance, and Tigran Gambaryan, regional manager for Africa, with four counts of tax evasion.</p>
<p>These charges included “non-payment of Value-Added Tax, non-payment of Company Income Tax, failure to tax returns and complicity in aiding customers to evade taxes through its platform”, which the FIRS believed occurred from the failure of Binance to initially undergo a registration process before offering its services to Nigerians. </p>
<p>According to l<a href="https://businessday.ng/news/article/nigerian-court-adjourns-binance-and-executives-tax-evasion-trial-to-may-17/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ocal news media BusinessDay</a>, the case was presented for hearing on April 19, with only Tigran Gimbaryan present in court as Nadeen Ahjarwhalla has long fled the West African nation. Gimbaryan is reported to have refused to take a plea as the FIRS had failed to serve Binance any tax evasion charges.</p>
<p>However, the prosecution argued that the US citizen should defend the interests of himself and the crypto exchange against the charges being presented. In response, Gambaryan’s lawyer stated that since all parties were jointly charged, Binance, being the primary defendant, must be served by the IRS before his client could plead his case in accordance with the Nigerian constitution. </p>
<p>Following the legal impasse, Justice Emeka Nwite of the Federal High Court Abuja ruled the case be adjourned to May 17, when he will provide a definite judgment. This represents the second time the FIRS’s tax evasion case against Binance has been adjourned following an <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-executive-case-in-nigeria-postponed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">initial postponement</a> on April 4 due to the failure of the Nigerian tax regulator to serve Gambaryan ahead of a stipulated court trial.
</p>


<h2><strong>Binance Troubles In Nigeria Continue</strong></h2>
<p>The Binance exchange is currently stuck in a hostile regulatory situation with the Nigerian government. Aside from tax evasion charges, the Nigerian Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC) has also accused the prominent crypto exchange of laundering over $35 million. </p>
<p>The Nigerian government has increased regulatory scrutiny of Binance after accusing the exchange of <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-executive-case-in-nigeria-postponed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">playing a major role in the massive devaluation</a> of the Nigerian naira via speculation and rate fixing. These allegations were followed by the arrest of Gimbaryan and Ahjarwhalla, who had visited the West African nation on February 26 after reports of the government banning certain access to Binance and other crypto exchanges.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Binance has disabled all naira services on its platform and appears committed to resolving all legal issues around the detention of its employees after the exchange’s CEO, Richard Teng, recently <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/binance-ceo-cooperation-with-nigerian-authorities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">confirmed</a> a willingness to cooperate with the Nigerian government. </p>


<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/QwcFISPv/" alt="Binance" width="1479" height="893" />BTC trading at $64,927.40 on that daily chart | Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/xg17RJqK/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">BTCUSDT chart on Tradingview.com</a>

<p style="text-align: left;"> <em>Featured image from The Flag Shop, chart from Tradingview</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/nigeria-flag-std_1.jpg?fit=420%2C420" width="420" height="420" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295735</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grayscale Proposes 0.15% Fee For Its Bitcoin Mini Trust Fund: Details</title>
		<link>https://bitcoinist.com/grayscale-proposes-fee-for-its-bitcoin-mini-trust/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Opeyemi Sule]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 07:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Balchunas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grayscale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bitcoinist.com/?p=295734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Asset management firm Grayscale has disclosed new details about its new Bitcoin Mini Trust fund, a “spin-off” of the GBTC exchange-traded fund (ETF). The new fund, which was first announced in March, is expected to operate independently and offer a cost-effective investment option to GBTC shareholders. Grayscale Offers Industry-Low Fee With New Fund According to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Asset management firm Grayscale has disclosed new details about its new Bitcoin Mini Trust fund, a “spin-off” of the GBTC exchange-traded fund (ETF). The new fund, which was <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-etf-grayscale-spin-off-vaneck-slashes-fees/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">first announced</a> in March, is expected to operate independently and offer a cost-effective investment option to GBTC shareholders.</p>
<h2><strong>Grayscale Offers Industry-Low Fee With New Fund</strong></h2>
<p>According to a recent <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1588489/000119312524094896/d807233dprer14c.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">filing</a> with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), asset manager Grayscale plans to set the fees for its new Bitcoin Mini Trust at one-tenth of the current 1.5% fee for GBTC. </p>
<p>The 0.15% fee would make the fund the cheapest amongst the 11 Bitcoin ETFs approved in early January, followed by Franklin Templeton’s fund at 0.19%.</p>

<p>The filing revealed that Grayscale intends to disburse 63,620 bitcoins, or 10% of the Bitcoin held by GBTC at the beginning of the year (equivalent to roughly $4 billion), towards the Mini Trust’s initial distribution. </p>
<p>This $4 billion distribution would make the fund the fourth-largest Bitcoin spot ETF by asset under management (AUM), behind BlackRock’s IBIT, Fidelity FBTC, and Grayscale’s GBTC itself.</p>
<p>As earlier <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-etf-grayscale-spin-off-vaneck-slashes-fees/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">reported by Bitcoinist</a>, existing GBTC shareholders will receive stock in Grayscale Mini Trust. The asset manager plans to list the fund on the New York Stock Exchange Arca under the ticker “BTC” and expects the product to begin trading on the exchange immediately after the initial distribution.</p>
<h2><strong>The Numbers Are Still Hypothetical: Bloomberg Analyst</strong></h2>
<p>Bloomberg ETF analyst Eric Balchunas <a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1781762745773281702" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">took to the X</a> platform to share his opinion on the latest update on Grayscale’s new Mini Trust. “This is pro-forma financials and, as such, hypothetical,” Balchunas wrote in a post on X.</p>

<p>For context, pro forma financials refer to a collection of financial statements that use hypothetical assumptions to support investment proposals. This means that there might still be some changes before the fund starts trading.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">UPDATE: so this is pro-forma financials and as such hypothetical. It doesn&#8217;t nec mean <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$BTC</a> will be 15bps. But the good news is they had to pick a number for this and knew ppl would be watching and they decided on 15bps. Anyway, do with that what you will. Updates as I get them!…</p>
<p>— Eric Balchunas (@EricBalchunas) <a href="https://twitter.com/EricBalchunas/status/1781762745773281702?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Balchunas noted in his post:</p>
<blockquote><p>It doesn&#8217;t nec mean BTC will be 15bps. But the good news is they had to pick a number for this and knew [people] would be watching, and they decided on 15bps.</p></blockquote>
<p>This development comes while investors continue to withdraw funds from the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust since its debut at the beginning of the year. According to SoSo Value, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/grayscale-ceo-gbtc-fees/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">GBTC recorded a net outflow</a> of $45.82 million in the past week.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/5ySHWhP1/" alt="Grayscale" width="2174" height="1434" /></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Grayscale-GBTC.jpeg?fit=640%2C384" width="640" height="384" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295734</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
