<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://blockworks.co</id>
    <title>Blockworks: News and insights about digital assets.</title>
    <updated>2024-03-16T03:34:32.956Z</updated>
    <generator>Blockworks</generator>
    <author>
        <name>Blockworks</name>
        <email>info@blockworks.co</email>
        <uri>https://twitter.com/Blockworks_</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blockworks.co"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://blockworks.co/feed"/>
    <subtitle>Blockworks is a financial media brand that delivers breaking news and premium insights about digital
        assets to millions of investors. Our editorial content, newsletters, podcasts and events provide investors with
        the critical analysis and information they need to make smarter decisions about digital assets.
    </subtitle>
    <logo>https://blockworks.co/images/meta-logo.png</logo>
    <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    <category term="Markets"/>
    <category term="Finance"/>
    <category term="Policy"/>
    <category term="DeFi"/>
    <category term="Business"/>
    <category term="Web3"/>
    <category term="Op-Ed"/>
    <category term="People"/>
    <category term="Podcast"/>
    <category term="Sponsored"/>
    <category term="Education"/>
    <category term="Analysis"/>
    <category term="Announcements"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US prosecutors seek decades in prison for Sam Bankman-Fried]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/prosecutors-want-50-yrs-sam-bankman-fried</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/prosecutors-want-50-yrs-sam-bankman-fried"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T18:35:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The former FTX boss will attend a sentencing hearing slated for late March]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>US prosecutors want former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried to face 40 to 50 years in prison, a new court filing revealed Friday.</p>



<p>The former executive is set to face sentencing by Judge Lewis Kaplan of the Southern District of New York later this month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The government, in its <a href="https://cms.blockworks.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/f6c7af17-95ed-445a-83d1-e2a565e6d383.pdf">sentencing memorandum</a>, wrote that Bankman-Fried “was convicted of orchestrating one of the largest financial frauds in history.” Because of his “willful” role, the government’s lawyers said he deserves a “severe sanction, proportionate to his role in this historic fraud.”</p>



<p>However, prosecutors don’t believe that <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/sam-bankman-fried">Bankman-Fried</a> should face the guidelines sentence, which would put him behind bars for over 100 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The Government urges the Court to impose a sentence that underscores the remarkably serious nature of the harm to thousands of victims; prevents the defendant from ever again committing fraud; and sends a powerful signal to others who might be tempted to engage in financial misconduct that the consequences will be severe. A sentence of 40 to 50 years is necessary to serve such purposes,” the filing continues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prosecutors, in the 116-page document, cited several victims who described the severity of losses they faced following the collapse of FTX. They also brought up the institutions that were impacted by the implosion of the former crypto exchange, including BlockFi. Former CEO Zac Prince also <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sam-bankman-fried-trial-day-8">testified in front of the court</a> at Bankman-Fried’s November trial.</p>



<p>The filing looks at a few financial crimes convictions, including Bernie Madoffs. Prosecutors argued that a shorter sentence could allow Bankman-Fried to commit fraud again once he’s released.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“And a shorter sentence because of his age also undermines general deterrence, as it could signal to would be young fraudsters that it is worthwhile to attempt a massive fraud, because either they will get away with it, or the prison sentence will allow them a second chance to make money,” the filing said.</p>



<p>Prosecutors also argued for a money judgment of more than $11 billion, claiming that the sum was “conservative.” The government “has already seized over a billion dollars in assets,” the filing said.</p>



<p>Bankman-Fried’s lawyers, friends and family <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sam-banmkan-fried-fraud-sentencing">argued for a shorter sentence</a>, proposing instead that he be sentenced to between 63 and 78 months in prison.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sam-banmkan-fried-fraud-sentencing">Bankman-Fried’s legal team argues for leniency, citing philanthropy and character</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Sam is not the ‘evil genius’ depicted in the media or the greedy villain described at trial. He is a 31-year-old son, brother, friend, humanitarian and philanthropist,” the defense’s memo argued.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="People" term="People"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T18:35:57.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A memecoin might get the Vegas treatment, but crypto ads rarely age well]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/memecoin-dogwifhat-shibainu-lasvegas-sphere</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/memecoin-dogwifhat-shibainu-lasvegas-sphere"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T18:06:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Just because your memecoin can raise almost a million dollars to put a Shiba Inu wearing a hat on the Las Vegas Sphere doesn’t mean you should ]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=1024 1024w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=300 300w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=768 768w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=428 428w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=470 470w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=389 389w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=80 80w" class="wp-image-60166" alt="" src="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=1024&amp;h=1024" height="256" width="1024" decoding="async" loading="lazy"></figure>



<p>Crypto is apparently “so back” this week that a memecoin called dogwifhat managed to crowdfund more than $700,000 to display their logo on the Las Vegas Sphere.</p>



<p>This is far from the first time that a crypto project has raised a lot of money in a very short period of time to do something unexpected. More than a few past fundraisers have proposed wacky projects with an uneven success rate, to both fanfare and groans from the community.</p>



<p>Way back in 2014, the community around the original memecoin, dogecoin, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/jan/20/jamaican-bobsled-team-raises-dogecoin-winter-olympics">gathered</a> over $25,000 to send the Jamaican bobsleigh team to the Olympics. I’d argue that this type of random crypto fundraising falls into the category of gimmicky, but with a good message.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dogwifhat’s fundraise, on the other hand, lands more firmly in the second category of crypto crowdsourcing: gimmicky, with a bad taste left in your mouth.</p>



<p>This is not a commentary on dogwifhat itself, nor am I suggesting that WIF would steal the money (their use of a five-party multi-sig wallet is a good preventative measure). Neither is my intent to say that the memecoin itself is in danger of rugging, like so many memecoins do. Its <a href="https://solana.fm/address/EKpQGSJtjMFqKZ9KQanSqYXRcF8fBopzLHYxdM65zcjm">contract</a> has no mint authority and the original LP liquidity token was <a href="https://twitter.com/WifonSol/status/1763749674899661139">burned</a>.</p>



<p>Instead, I’d merely like to point out the fact that these types of far-flung crypto advertising and fundraising boondoggles have rarely aged well. FTX’s since-discarded arena ads in Florida come to mind.</p>



<p>A better comparison might be ConstitutionDAO. The grassroots movement managed to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/18/constitutiondao-crypto-investors-lose-bid-to-buy-constitution-copy.html">raise enough money</a> to bid on the auction for a first-edition of that rare US document&nbsp; —&nbsp;a whopping $47 million in a week — only to be thwarted at the finish line.</p>



<p>The difficulties in a DAO actually entering the auction were manifold, as they had to use a non-profit to conduct the bidding and go through the necessary know-your-customer process, as well as convert the money into US dollars — all to end up not having enough to cover the expected maintenance costs of such a fragile historical document. Everyone who participated in Constitution DAO was able to get their money back, minus a transaction fee.</p>



<p><strong>Read more from our opinion section:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/crypto-must-advertise-airports">Crypto must advertise</a></p>



<p>A more successful example of a crypto fundraise that did what it set out to do is LinksDAO, which actually <a href="https://www.grampianonline.co.uk/news/historic-spey-bay-golf-course-sold-to-us-based-online-golf-c-314589/">purchased a golf course in Scotland</a> with its crowdfunding and apparently maintains a robust membership model for golf enthusiasts. But this type of funding success is the exception, not the norm.</p>



<p>The process of actually getting your advertisement on the Sphere is a bit murky, given the slew of articles on the multimillion-dollar price range for Sphere advertising during the Super Bowl. According to an <a href="https://twitter.com/BetterPitchGuy/status/1708858263469531340">unofficial pitch deck from 2023</a>, one day is priced at $450,000 and one week at $650,000.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A marketing company, unaffiliated with the Sphere, also <a href="https://americanguerillamarketing.com/f/advertising-on-the-las-vegas-sphere-a-new-era-of-engagement">advertises</a> a Sphere residency package that seems to confirm those numbers —&nbsp;an investment of $450,000-$650,000 will get you 414 minutes of exposure on the Sphere over the course of a week, with plenty of specifics on what the Sphere’s in-house design team is able to provide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although, if dogwifhat’s website is anything to go by, the in-house team will have almost nothing to do, as the design is already complete.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt="" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/a0n6kbhItBItiK6r6TkjGYcm_FvN0J1sfvpzaM2DKvDURZIcp8khg8E7SMMngXZo46KG2RHRBMcSEBpCVDJje56Pv7dQtDn6Pp7gepWhrQmZGSwNKZeCCypqunPLfvF7MyWEDra-zaZg0NvZIHZ2X7E" decoding="async"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Source: </em><a href="https://wif-sphere.vercel.app/"><em>Dogwifhat fundraising page</em></a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Dogwifhat’s <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dogwifhat/comments/1be6lcz/vegas_calling/">sub-Reddit seems to think</a> that the hatted Shiba Inu will be up on the Sphere as soon as April 19, and while dogwifhat’s multisig signer Mihir told me that the memecoin is already in touch with the Sphere, they “can’t disclose the timeline for getting dogwifhat on the Sphere.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>In response to a question about how the initiative would actually issue a payment, given the hurdles faced by ConstitutionDAO, Mihir said the team would convert their USDC donations to USD and will use leftover funds for either another marketing campaign or donate them.</p>



<p>The Sphere didn’t return my request for comment by press time, although they did <a href="https://gizmodo.com/dogwifhat-memecoin-vegas-sphere-fundraiser-1851336709">decline to comment to Gizmodo</a> about pricing or when the dogwifhat picture would appear..</p>



<p>What will happen if the knit-hatted Shiba Inu does make it onto the big stage? Incredibly, we actually have another specifically Shiba Inu-themed crypto ad campaign to compare WIF to.</p>



<p>Memecoin Floki Inu’s “Missed DOGE? Get $FLOKI” London transport campaign was <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2022/mar/02/watchdog-bans-floki-inu-cryptocurrency-campaign-on-london-tube-elon-musk">banned</a> in 2022 by the country’s advertising watchdog for “irresponsibly exploit[ing] consumers’ fear of missing out and triviali[zing] investment in cryptocurrency.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s not to say that a similar fate awaits WIF for their purported campaign. As far as we know, there’s no actual text involved, just a picture.</p>



<p>The idea that this amount of money was raised with — quite literally —&nbsp;only an image as the goal is remarkable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it doesn’t mean that just because you can do something, you should do it. As I <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/crypto-marketing-pr-circus">wrote last week</a>, there’s no reason to make crypto into more of a circus than it already is.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><em>I don’t care much about tech, I don’t care a whole lot about finance, either. I care about writing stories and watching weird things unfold. And that’s why I’ve ended up in crypto. <br><br>But because I’m missing that passion for what crypto and blockchain are all about — finance, tech, privacy, yadda yadda — I’m going to write instead about what I am actually interested in. Everything about crypto that has very little to do with crypto.<br><br>That’s what this column will be about. All the tangential stories that come out of the blockchain and crypto space, what I think about them, and how I navigate it all as a skeptical former Russian literature major.<br><br>It’s precisely my perch as an outsider that lets me do what I do: Opine on all sides of any crypto issue, no strings attached, no skin in the game.<br><br>If you want to talk crypto with me, let’s go off topic.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Molly Jane Zuckerman</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/molly-jane-zuckerman</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Op-Ed" term="Op-Ed"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T18:06:50.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s cheaper to swap on layer-2s than on Ethereum, Uniswap research finds]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/swapping-on-layer-2s-ethereum-uniswap</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/swapping-on-layer-2s-ethereum-uniswap"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T17:13:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[97.5% of swappers with trades under $125,000 did better on layer-2s than on Ethereum mainnet]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>A recent paper <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.09494">by</a> Austin Adams, a researcher at Uniswap Labs, contends that swapping and liquidity provisions on layer-2 networks are significantly cheaper than on Ethereum’s mainnet.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to the paper, chains like Arbitrum created over three times more liquidity positions this past year than Ethereum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report further shows that, when looking at USDC/ETH pools, 97.5% of swappers with trades under $125,000 did better on layer-2s than on <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/ethereum">Ethereum</a> mainnet.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/uniswap-new-swapping-tools">Uniswap releases new tools for swappers</a></p>



<p>This is likely because retail swappers, with trades under $125,000, are much more likely to benefit from the lower gas costs and higher liquidity concentration on <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/layer-2-2">layer-2s</a> than the mainnet.</p>



<p>It is worth noting that Ethereum is responsible for only around 25% of the total transaction count but over 60% of the volume — demonstrating that, despite boasting higher transaction volumes, network activity is still predominantly on layer-2s.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, layer-2s often offer shorter block times, or the time it takes the network to produce a new block. On Ethereum today, the average block time is roughly 12 seconds. On Arbitrum, on the other hand, the average block time is around 0.26 seconds.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-ethereum-burning-almost-10b">Cheatsheet: Ethereum on track to burn $10B ETH over next year</a></p>



<p>The shorter the block time, the less opportunity there would be for the market price of an asset to move, meaning that arbitrage attempts will likely not be as profitable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Less successful arbitrage attempts are a good thing for liquidity providers, who are making 20% more in returns from arbitrage on layer-2s than they are on mainnet, the paper <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.09494">shows</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although there are significant benefits for users to trade on layer-2s, the paper does note drawbacks. One primary concern is the centralized sequencer.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/shared-sequencing-blockchain-rollups">‘Shared Sequencing’ could help unite blockchain rollups</a></p>



<p>The paper notes that many existing <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/rollups">rollups</a> today still operate under one centralized sequencer. This sequencer could take advantage of the situation by reordering transactions to maximize <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/mev">MEV</a> profits for themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, optimistic rollups today do not have decentralized fraud proofs, which are necessary to correct sequencer errors.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/layer-2-secured-by-ethereum">So your layer-2 is ‘secured by Ethereum’ — what does that mean?</a></p>



<p>Finally, there are <a href="https://l2beat.com/scaling/summary">over</a> 40 layer-2 ecosystems present today. The proliferation of these networks means further liquidity fragmentation, as they cannot trustlessly speak to one another in real time. This means that they will need to rely on bridging infrastructure, which is both costly and time-consuming.</p>



<p>The developers of layer-2 networks are working to address these concerns. Optimism recently revealed a <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/op-labs-developers-fault-proofs-testnet-launch">permissionless fault-proof system</a>, while shared sequencer networks like Espresso have explored ways to <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/espresso-systems-decentralized-sequencer-testnet">diversify sequencers for rollups</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“For decentralized markets to fulfill their full potential, aggregate trading costs must continue to decline and user experience must continue to improve,” Adams wrote. “We believe that the studied generalized layer-2s still have many benefits that users can utilize today, and any future improvements will only continue to benefit the trading experience.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bessie Liu</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/bessieliu</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T17:13:22.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Binance says it’s working ‘collaboratively’ with Nigerian authorities ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/binance-employees-detained-nigeria</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-employees-detained-nigeria"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T16:44:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Nigeria and Binance continue to face off, even after Binance pulled support for the naira]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Binance’s problems in Nigeria continue as two employees remain detained in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Authorities in Nigeria asked a court in the capital of Abuja to extend the detention of two executives who have been held since Feb. 26.</p>



<p>Officials sought to extend the court order allowing the executives to be held, which lasted 14 days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Binance’s head of financial crime compliance, Tigran Gambrayan, and Nadeem Anjarwalla, the regional manager for Africa, are being detained in the country. They have not been charged with any crimes.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/nigeria-binance-warning">Nigeria’s SEC issues second ‘Binance’ investor warning, cites exchange website</a></p>



<p>Earlier this week, in a joint statement, the wives of the two executives said, “We don’t understand how keeping [Gambrayan and Anjarwalla] — and us — in this nightmare is going to help resolve whatever issues the Nigerian government has with <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/binance">Binance</a>. We just want our husbands home and we are pleading with the Nigerian authorities to release them immediately and for Tigran and Nadeem’s respective governments to do more to get their citizens home.”</p>



<p>A hearing is set for March 20 after lawyers for the executives argued that they shouldn’t be detained. Nigerian officials were given three days to respond to the arguments from the lawyers, according to a representative for the families.</p>



<p>“While it is inappropriate for us to comment on the substance of the claims at this time, we can say that we are working collaboratively with Nigerian authorities to bring Nadeem and Tigran back home safely to their families. They are professionals with the highest integrity and we will provide them all the support we can. We trust there will be a swift resolution to this matter,” a Binance spokesperson told Blockworks.</p>



<p>The dispute between Binance and Nigeria <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/nigerian-government-binance-fine">started in late February</a> after the country’s central bank governor, Olayemi Cardoso, named Binance in a press conference and said that $26 billion passed through Binance Nigeria.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then, another official said that the country was looking to impose a fine. Following the reports around the back and forth between the two, Binance <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-ends-support-nigeria-naira">announced that it was ending support for the naira</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T16:44:28.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin holds below $70k on disappointing inflation reads this week ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-below-70k-on-inflation-reads</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-below-70k-on-inflation-reads"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T14:19:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Stocks and cryptocurrencies have been on the decline since Thursday, although analysts say this week’s bad economic reads should have caused a bigger selloff ]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Cryptocurrencies and equities slid Friday, erasing gains from earlier this week as traders digested yet another hotter-than-expected inflation gauge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bitcoin and ether extended a decline that started Thursday morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>) was trading 6% lower, continuing to hover below $70,000, at time of publication, according to Coinbase. Ether (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/eth">ETH</a>) was also on the decline, losing about 7% in 24 hours to trade around $3,700.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The cumulative effect of the week’s bad news on inflation jolted BTC out of its confident climb,” Noelle Acheson, author of the Crypto is Macro Now newsletter, said. “Yesterday’s reminder of the gravity of the rates expectations adjustment understandably did more damage, pushing BTC back below $69,000, with the continued hit to sentiment continuing today.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/banking-sector-uncertainty-crypto">What banking sector uncertainty could mean for crypto markets</a></p>



<p>The S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq Composite indexes also slipped early in Friday’s trading session, losing 0.6% and 1%, respectively. Equities have largely pared gains made earlier in the week, although analysts say given recent economic data, the decline is not as significant as expected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Economic data this week has not been positive for stocks and while it hasn’t invalidated any of that bullish mantra, it has weakened it,” Tom Essaye, founder of Sevens Report Research, said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to data released Thursday, the producer price index (PPI), which measures selling prices for domestic manufacturers, showed a 0.6% month-over-month increase in February. Economists had expected a 0.3% monthly rise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Core PPI for February rose by 0.3% month-over-month, higher than the 0.2% expected but less than the January read of 0.5%.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/us-voters-holding-crypto">A fifth of US voters have bought crypto, Paradigm survey finds</a></p>



<p>The figures were not positive for those hoping for rate cuts in the coming months — markets are now calling for a 91% chance that the Federal Reserve holds rates through May, <a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/markets/interest-rates/cme-fedwatch-tool.html?redirect=/trading/interest-rates/countdown-to-fomc.html">according</a> to data from CME Group.</p>



<p>The Fed will release its rate decision and updated economic projections next week after the conclusion of the Federal Open Market Committee meeting on Wednesday.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Markets" term="Markets"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T14:19:28.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">
            <![CDATA[Mining giant Marathon set to buy another site just weeks ahead of bitcoin halving ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/marathon-digital-aquisition-bitcoin-halving</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/marathon-digital-aquisition-bitcoin-halving"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T13:58:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The planned $87 million deal follows Marathon’s purchase of two mining facilities in January ]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Crypto miner growth initiatives ahead of the bitcoin halving are not slowing down, as one of the space’s biggest players continues its string of acquisitions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Marathon Digital is set to buy a Texas bitcoin mining facility owned by Applied Digital for roughly $87 million in cash, the company said in a Friday news release.</p>



<p>The data center — located next to a wind farm — has a capacity of 200 megawatts (MW).</p>



<p>In addition to taking direct ownership of its current operations at the site, the firm added, Marathon intends to grow its presence at the facility by 100 MW by the end of the year.</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/marathon-digital">Marathon Digital</a> is already a titan in the <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/mining">mining</a> space, with 28.7 exahashes per second (EH/s) of energized self-mining hash rate at the end of February.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The planned buy is consistent with Florida-based Marathon’s intention to scale up before <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-markets-explainer">the next bitcoin halving</a> — slated for around April 20. During this event, which occurs roughly every four years, per-block rewards will drop from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC.</p>



<p>This is set to put <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-miners-hashrate-offline">financial stress on companies in the sector</a> — particularly smaller, less-efficient miners with less access to capital and high energy costs.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-crypto-miner-consolidation">Bitcoin miner consolidation appears imminent as halving looms</a></p>



<p>Marathon executives said during the company’s earnings call last month that they would look to use its balance sheet — comprising roughly $1 billion worth of unrestricted cash and bitcoin combined, as of Jan. 31 — to <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/marathon-digital-2023-q4-earnings">nearly double its hash rate to 50 EH/s by the end of 2025</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Bitcoin mining is a zero-sum game,” Marathon CEO Thiel said at the time. “There are only so many bitcoins available per day. And if you’re not out there growing our hash rate, you’re falling backwards.”</p>



<p>Marathon closed its <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-mining-giant-gets-bigger">acquisition of two mining facilities in Texas and Nebraska</a> in January. It paid about $179 million for 390 MW of mining capacity in that deal and <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/marathon-digital-terminates-competitor-involvement">terminated competitor Hut 8’s involvement</a> in overseeing the facilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The latest announced purchase is set to boost the amount of Marathon mining capacity housed on sites it owns and operates to 54%, the company added.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Marathon Digital is not the only mining company <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/crypto-miners-hash-rate-bitcoin-halving">making moves ahead of the halving</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Riot Platforms bought 31,500 more miners from MicroBT for $97.4 million last month — at which point competitor CleanSpark closed its <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/cleanspark-site-acquisition-bitcoin-halving">acquisition of three data centers in Mississippi</a>.</p>



<p>Hut 8 CEO Asher Genoot told Blockworks that while growth is also on his company’s mind, it would <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hut-8-growth-bitcoin-halving">look to be cost-conscious in its scaling initiatives</a>.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T13:58:41.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheatsheet: 1 Telegram bot still burns more ETH than Arbitrum]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-telegram-burning-more-eth</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-telegram-burning-more-eth"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T12:40:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[There’s not quite blood in the streets, but things are looking mighty red for crypto]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is Cheatsheet, a primer on what’s happening in crypto today.</em></p>



<p>Ethereum’s fancy new blobs, while a gamechanger on many levels, have done little to prop up its price amid a healthy correction this morning.</p>



<p>Bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>) and ether (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/eth">ETH</a>) are both down 7% over the past day, now at their lowest points since the end of March’s first week.</p>



<p>Only four cryptocurrencies in the top-100 are still ahead since this time yesterday: China-focused layer-1 conflux (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/cfx">CFX</a>) and AI-styled fetch (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/fet">FET</a>) are up 6.5% and 2.1%.</p>



<p>Bitfinex’s <a href="https://blockworks.co/price/leo">LEO</a> and trading-focused blockchain Sei (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/sei">SEI</a>) follow closely behind and could fall into the red if bitcoin and ether continue to slip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bitcoin SV (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/bsv">BSV</a>) performed the worst, losing more than 20% on the back of a London court verdict, which found its spokesperson Craig Wright is, in fact, <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/craig-wright-is-not-satoshi-nakamoto">not Bitcoin creator Satoshi Nakamoto</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Solana memecoin bonk (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/bonk">BONK</a>) is doing only marginally better, having lost 16.2%.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On-chain mail</h2>



<p>The Bitcoin Ordinals craze has officially died down — at least for now — turning the network back into a venue primarily for financial transactions.</p>



<ul>
<li>88% of Bitcoin blockspace over the <a href="https://dune.com/dataalways/ordinals">week</a> to date was used for traditional BTC transfers.</li>



<li>38% in the second-last week of November was either inscriptions or BRC-20s.</li>



<li>Fees spent on inscriptions is on track for its lowest week since October: $1 million in the past five days compared to $4 million in the previous seven.</li>
</ul>



<p>There were moments over the past few months where Bitcoin was the number-one blockchain for trading digital collectibles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A 50% drop in weekly sales <a href="https://www.cryptoslam.io/blockchains">volume</a> (now $89 million) has however again placed Bitcoin second behind Ethereum’s $137 million, with Pepe the Frog creator Matt Furie’s generative NFT collection Peplicator leading. Solana is in third place with about $62 million.</p>



<p>Are Ordinals over? Almost certainly not. Inscriptions may benefit immensely from a continued bull market. But at least for now, user attention appears laser-focused on bitcoin, the currency.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/craig-wright-is-not-satoshi-nakamoto">Craig Wright is not Bitcoin creator Satoshi Nakamoto, UK judge says</a></p>



<ul>
<li>Meanwhile, BananaGun, the Telegram bot built for sniping new token launches, is still <a href="https://ultrasound.money/">burning</a> more ETH than layer-2 Arbitrum: 1,021 ETH to 836.5 ETH over the past week.</li>



<li>BananaGun also operates on Solana, where it hit a new daily trading volume <a href="https://twitter.com/BananaGunBot/status/1768251349387317742">record</a> near $7.4 million.</li>



<li>One set of Telegram bots were responsible for nearly $80 million in DEX trading volumes last week, a near record high and the most since last July, per a Dune <a href="https://dune.com/web3academypro/telegram-bots">dashboard</a>.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt="" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/hpsHUyfilAzYdD5wW0_dxyN_Lpv99lLqqQrnfXtTcIIzxIZdEzoYYJGoVdhS6x0F8Z4U_RHB_IlAmnBXoBHHGs_I1VmT4b3xv-MoFLFWBoRRAGVGvY4kYEU5qjTUAjLkZ-J7uYkSyU_sVJUZMajyKgk" decoding="async"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>The brown area represents the data used by BTC-only transfers in each block. Green and blue are Ordinals-related (</em><a href="https://dune.com/dataalways/ordinals"><em>source</em></a><em>)</em></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crypto business</h2>



<p>Bitcoin’s current correction has pulled crypto stocks into a sea of red, with only one gaining ground across both yesterday’s day session and pre-market trade as of 7:30 am ET: Griid.</p>



<ul>
<li>Bitcoin miner Griid is set to open Friday 3% higher after slipping 0.75% yesterday.</li>



<li>Argo, Coinbase, Marathon and CleanSpark are the worst off, all falling a combined 12% before and after the bell.</li>



<li>MicroStrategy and Coinbase are now the only crypto stocks in the green over the past month — still up 129% and 56%, respectively.</li>
</ul>



<p>Those two aside, crypto stocks are on average down by 26% over the past month, which seems counterintuitive considering bitcoin has gone almost 30% in the opposite direction.</p>



<p>Bitcoin’s halving next month is the culprit, analysts say, with markets apparently skittish about the cost of BTC production immediately doubling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s despite the price of bitcoin still sitting quite a way above the post-halving production cost, which some suggest could be just over $50,000 per coin for most outfits (vertically-integrated miners with their own power sources may have lower costs).</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-mining-stocks-crypto-rally">Why most bitcoin mining stocks are down amid a persistent crypto rally</a></p>



<ul>
<li>Coinbase short <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/stocks/coin/short-interest">interest</a> was down 18.5% as of the end of February: 12.92 million shares or 7.63% of the float, the lowest over the last year at least.</li>



<li>MicroStrategy’s was also <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/stocks/mstr/short-interest">down</a> slightly but still above where it was in November.</li>



<li>Grayscale’s Ethereum Trust is trading at its worst <a href="https://ycharts.com/companies/ETHE/discount_or_premium_to_nav">discount</a> since October as ETF hopes dwindle: now 18.2% below NAV.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On the ground</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">It’s true. Edgar is down too. <a href="https://t.co/5TmBtfXgxD">https://t.co/5TmBtfXgxD</a> <a href="https://t.co/o8dyHXWnk6">pic.twitter.com/o8dyHXWnk6</a></p>— Justin Slaughter (@JBSDC) <a href="https://twitter.com/JBSDC/status/1768474130158850114?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Don’t say it, don’t say it, don’t say it (bitcoin fixes this)</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">“Ya we chose this location so that we could co-locate near the Telegram servers, really reduces latency between Banana Gun and both Uniswap and Raydium. Wall Street is going to offer me a fortune for this condo in 10 years time when they realize this is the future of finance.” <a href="https://t.co/HfRx9H58dI">pic.twitter.com/HfRx9H58dI</a></p>— Gwart (@GwartyGwart) <a href="https://twitter.com/GwartyGwart/status/1768585190467584122?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Are your Web3 startup offices optimized for BananaGun?</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">blob gas price and blob burn live now 👀<br><br>calm before the storm <a href="https://t.co/SjuFu6nm5w">pic.twitter.com/SjuFu6nm5w</a></p>— ultra sound money 🦇🔊 (@ultrasoundmoney) <a href="https://twitter.com/ultrasoundmoney/status/1768550429279814072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 15, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Blob tracking is live on ultrasound.money</em></figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Canellis</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/david-canellis</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Web3" term="Web3"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T12:40:50.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$190B wealth manager greenlights 4 bitcoin ETFs for allocators]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/wealth-manager-bitcoin-etfs-allocators</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/wealth-manager-bitcoin-etfs-allocators"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T11:51:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Cetera to allow its financial pros to implement BTC products offered by BlackRock, Fidelity, Invesco and Franklin Templeton into client portfolios]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Wealth management firm Cetera Financial Group has approved four bitcoin ETFs for advisers choosing to implement such funds into client portfolios.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The San Diego-based firm said Thursday it would launch educational training to its financial professionals as they consider allocations to bitcoin ETFs — marking the latest asset manager to make such a move.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cetera has so far greenlit adviser allocations to four of the 10 US spot bitcoin ETFs: BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT); the Fidelity Wise Origin Bitcoin Fund (FBTC); the Franklin Bitcoin ETF (EZBC); and the Invesco Galaxy Bitcoin ETF (BTCO).&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The company had $190 billion in assets under management, as of December 2023.</p>



<p>“We will continue to proactively evaluate the implications of bitcoin ETFs and related products and modify our policies accordingly, and we look forward to partnering with our financial professionals to adopt bitcoin ETFs when appropriate with their clients,” Matt Fries, Cetera’s head of investment products and partner solutions, said in a statement.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/wealth-managers-feel-pressure-bitcoin-etfs">Restricting access to growing bitcoin ETFs becoming ‘hard to justify’</a></p>



<p>Cetera appeared to lean toward the bitcoin ETFs offered by larger firms with a TradFi bent.</p>



<p>BlackRock’s iShares lineup manages more than $2.7 trillion in assets, while the assets in Invesco’s US ETFs amount to about $500 billion, according to ETF.com.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Financial services giants Fidelity Investments and Franklin Templeton have roughly $67 billion and $16 billion, respectively, in their US ETF complexes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These providers have “track records of successfully launching new product strategies, and are well positioned with established resources, tools and knowledge,” Cetera noted in its Thursday news release.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The 10 US spot bitcoin ETFs have tallied nearly $12 billion of net inflows in their first nine weeks of trading, according to BitMEX Research <a href="https://twitter.com/BitMEXResearch/status/1768556378858103064">data</a>. Despite its roughly $11.7 billion of net outflows, the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF (GBTC) leads the category with more than $26 billion in assets. IBIT and FBTC are next, with about $15.9 billion and $9.2 billion, respectively.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cetera chose not to yet approve GBTC, which carries a 1.5% fee that is substantially higher than competitors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For now, it also left out access to the Ark 21Shares Bitcoin ETF (ARKB) and the Bitwise Bitcoin ETF (BITB). Those two funds have significantly higher assets under management than EZBC and BTCO — with each above $2 billion.</p>



<p>Cetera’s guidance around bitcoin ETFs comes as industry watchers say more wealth managers and investment platforms are likely to unlock the use of such products for allocators in the coming months.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/wealth-managers-bitcoin-etfs">‘Primary market’ for bitcoin ETFs largely hasn’t yet adopted such funds</a></p>



<p>Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-02-23/ria-carson-group-greenlights-four-spot-bitcoin-etfs-for-retail-buyers">reported</a> last month that Carson Group — a Nebraska-based registered investment adviser (RIA) — greenlit the use of four bitcoin ETFs.</p>



<p>Other similarly-sized RIAs have chosen not to, such as Savant Wealth Management. The firm, which manages about $25 billion in assets, told Blockworks last month that it had no plans to approve the bitcoin ETFs — noting “we prefer to work with asset classes that can provide us with a good basis for understanding the expected return.”</p>



<p>In terms of financial giants making the bitcoin funds available, a Wells Fargo spokesperson <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/merrill-wells-fargo-offer-bitcoin-etfs">confirmed to Blockworks that the bitcoin ETFs are available</a> for “unsolicited purchases” through one of the firm’s advisers, or through its online WellsTrade platform.Vanguard, however, <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/vanguard-disallows-bitcoin-etf-trading">does not allow for such funds to trade</a> on its brokerage platform — calling the investment case for crypto “weak.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Finance" term="Finance"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T11:51:16.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ether ETFs? US senators tell SEC to just say no.]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/sec-approval-ether-etfs-us-senators</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-approval-ether-etfs-us-senators"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T11:02:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Democratic senators Jack Reed and Laphonza Butler urged the SEC to crack down on what they called “alarming deficiencies” in crypto marketing and disclosures]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Two US Senators unhappy with how spot bitcoin ETFs have been marketed are imploring the Securities and Exchange Commission to halt any future crypto fund approvals.</p>



<p>In a letter dated March 11 to Securities and Exchange Commission Gary Gensler, Sens. Jack Reed (D-R.I.) and Laphonza Butler (D-Calif.) implored the SEC to crackdown on “alarming deficiencies” they say exist in communications to investors within the asset class.</p>



<p>They also asked the US regulator to refrain from approving more exchange-traded products linked to other crypto assets.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-approves-bitcoin-etf">Ten US spot bitcoin ETFs launched on Jan. 11</a> after years of fund issuer attempts to bring such funds to market.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The SEC’s approvals have provided a green light for Wall Street to sell volatile cryptocurrency investments to ordinary Americans through their brokerage and retirement accounts,” Reed and Butler wrote in the <a href="https://twitter.com/AlexanderGrieve/status/1768373756169261076?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1768373756169261076%7Ctwgr%5Ef49173a444d943c7dcc0b04b9f2648a5a1a4cb3b%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.coindesk.com%2Fpolicy%2F2024%2F03%2F15%2Fdemocrats-ask-secs-gensler-to-block-approval-of-more-crypto-etps%2F">letter</a>. “Given the significant and unique risks posed by cryptocurrency, is it critical that Americans receive accurate, comprehensive information about bitcoin ETPs.”</p>



<p>The senators allude to a January report by the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority (FINRA), which found that 70% of the 500 analyzed crypto-related communications to retail investors from FINRA member firms had “potential substantive violations.”</p>



<p>The possible violations relate to FINRA Rule 2210, which “prohibits claims that are false, exaggerated, promissory, unwarranted or misleading.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some companies failed to differentiate between crypto assets offered through the firm and those provided through a third party, the agency’s <a href="https://www.finra.org/rules-guidance/guidance/targeted-examination-letters/crypto-asset-communications">analysis</a> concluded. Other communications implied that crypto assets functioned like cash.</p>



<p>The FINRA review of crypto-related communications did not focus on ETFs specifically.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/finra-crypto-firms-investor-protection">70% of crypto communications potentially misleading, FINRA analysis finds</a></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The fate of potential future crypto ETPs?</h2>



<p>In addition to urging the SEC to “scrutinize” such communications to investors about these products, Reed and Butler said the SEC should “strictly limit the precedential application of these approvals.”</p>



<p>“While the bitcoin market has displayed serious weaknesses, it is nonetheless far more established and scrutinized than the market for any other cryptocurrency,” the senators added. “However vulnerable bitcoin may be to fraud and manipulation, markets for other cryptocurrencies are far more exposed to misconduct.”</p>



<p>The SEC is considering a number of <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etfs-approved-ether-funds-next">applications for ETFs that would hold ether</a> directly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ether is the second-largest crypto asset with a market capitalization of roughly $440 billion, as of Friday morning. That was about one-third of bitcoin’s market cap, which was slightly above $1.3 trillion at the time.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Grayscale Investments notched a court victory against the SEC last August in <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-grayscale-spot-bitcoin-etf">a decision that ultimately helped lead to the approval</a> of US spot bitcoin ETFs.&nbsp;<br>The crypto asset manager had called the SEC’s approval of bitcoin futures ETFs — but not funds that hold BTC directly — a decision that was “arbitrary and capricious.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Judges wrote in their decision that the SEC’s “unexplained discounting of the obvious financial and mathematical relationship between the spot and futures markets falls short of the standard for reasoned decision-making.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reed and Butler said they don’t believe the futures markets for other crypto assets will show a tight correlation to spot markets that would allow for meaningful market surveillance and deter bad actors.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>They added: “The commission is under no obligation to approve such products, and given the risk, it should not do so.”</p>



<p>Still, the SEC <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ether-futures-etfs-vaneck-proshares-bitwise-offerings">allowed for ETFs that invest in ether futures contracts</a> to start trading in October.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/comments/sr-nysearca-2023-70/srnysearca202370-432799-1074283.pdf">letter</a> supporting an application by Grayscale to convert its Ethereum Trust to an ETF, Coinbase pointed to ETH’s tightness of spreads and price correlation across spot markets.</p>



<p>“The ETH market and [NYSE Arca’s] surveillance-sharing agreement with CME support the position that the exchange’s proposed rule change should be approved for virtually identical reasons articulated by the commission with respect to spot bitcoin [ETPs],” Coinbase wrote.The SEC has <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-delays-blackrock-ether-etf-proposal">delayed its ruling on several proposed ether ETFs</a>, including BlackRock’s application earlier this month. Segment observers expect the agency to decide on such offerings in May.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-15T11:02:32.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fifth of US voters have bought crypto, Paradigm survey finds]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/us-voters-holding-crypto</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/us-voters-holding-crypto"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T20:03:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Similar to figures reported by Grayscale late last year, Paradigm said they found that 19% of American voters have bought crypto]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Around one fifth of American registered voters say they have purchased cryptocurrencies, according to a new survey from crypto investment firm Paradigm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of the 19% of voters who say they have bought crypto, 19% self-identified as Democrats and 18% as Republicans, the poll <a href="https://policy.paradigm.xyz/writing/March-2024-Polling">found</a>. 24% of crypto-owning voters are independents.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The figure lines up with <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/a-quarter-of-us-investors-own-bitcoin-more-than-half-bought-this-year">a December study from Grayscale</a>, which found that 19% of voters held crypto. Of this group, 23% were men and 31% were Gen Z.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I’ve seen it suggested that saying 20% of voters own crypto is misleading because they likely nearly all only own a token amount of it, such that even if a fifth of the country owns crypto, they all don’t care about it or policy affecting it,” <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/paradigm">Paradigm</a> policy director Justin Slaughter <a href="https://x.com/JBSDC/status/1768334598071845378?s=20">wrote</a> on X Thursday.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/decentralizing-social-identity-zk-voting">Rarimo introduces ZK-based voting tool for secure, anonymous participation</a></p>



<p>But, Slaughter added, the survey found that 6% of crypto-owning voters hold values worth between $1,001 and $10,000, showing that there is a large group with vested financial interests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“As a point of comparison, 32% of voters own more than $1000 in stocks, and 57% of voters don’t own any stocks,” Slaughter said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The survey comes as crypto-focused political donors and super Political Action Committees (PACs) start to ramp up their distributions, and many of their bets have paid off.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Crypto super PAC Fairshake doled out more than $10.1 million in recent weeks on advertisements and air time against Rep. Katie Porter in California’s open primary for a US Senate seat, according to Federal Election Commission filings.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/crypto-super-pacs-election-primaries">Crypto PAC-backed candidates sweep in US election primaries&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Porter lost earlier this month&nbsp; to Rep. Adam Schiff, D-CA, who will face Republican Steve Garvey in November.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even if Paradigm’s figures show the political divide isn’t that important in crypto, the Defend American Jobs super PAC, the Republican crypto-focused effort, donated to the most candidates of the crypto super PACs. The group spent around $4 million backing four Republicans in recent weeks, filings show.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Paradigm conducted the poll via research firm Public Opinion Strategies. 1,000 registered voters were polled between Feb. 28 and March 4.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T20:03:44.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker moves to meet demand for DAI]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/maker-meeting-stablecoin-dai-demand</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/maker-meeting-stablecoin-dai-demand"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T17:38:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[SparkLend has been approved for a doubling of its debt ceiling to 2.5 billion DAI]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>MakerDAO, creator of the DAI stablecoin, has a good problem: Demand for its product is high.</p>



<p>SparkLend, a borrowing and lending platform organized as a sub-DAO within Maker, has issued so much DAI in recent weeks that it needs authorization to lend more.</p>



<p>In a governance vote <a href="https://vote.makerdao.com/polling/QmVGDsvm">approved</a> Thursday at 12:00 pm ET, Maker voted unanimously to double the D3M maximum debt ceiling to 2.5 billion DAI.</p>



<p>“D3M” stands for Decentralized Debt Markets Module, a mechanism designed to optimize the DAI liquidity across different DeFi platforms. The module automatically adjusts the DAI borrowing rates on external platforms (like Aave) to be in line with the Dai Stability Fee within the MakerDAO system.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/makerdao-crypto-backed-loans">MakerDAO balance sheet now majority crypto-backed loans</a></p>



<p>Motivating the change is the rapidly accelerating demand for loans at SparkLend in the past week, which left available <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/dai">DAI</a> falling to 250 million. Maker’s risk experts lobbied in favor of the increase, arguing there’s no need to keep it so constrained.</p>



<p>“With recent bull market conditions, it is becoming increasingly difficult to keep up with borrowing demand,” Monet-Supply, analyst with Block Analitica <a href="https://forum.makerdao.com/t/mar-6-2024-proposed-changes-to-sparklend-for-upcoming-spell/23791">wrote</a> on the Maker forum, noting that the protocol blew through its last debt ceiling increase and is <a href="https://spark.blockanalitica.com/v1/ethereum/markets/DAI/?days_ago=30">growing</a> at an average rate of around 20 million DAI per day.</p>



<p>“This poses a risk of unintentionally hitting the D3M maximum debt ceiling and artificially limiting Spark’s growth,” he wrote.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/makerdao">MakerDAO</a> recently more than doubled stability fees across the board on March 10 following an executive <a href="https://vote.makerdao.com/executive/template-executive-vote-out-of-schedule-executive-vote-increase-edsr-increase-stability-fees-decrease-gsm-delay-usdc-psm-throughput-change-trigger-spark-proxy-spell-march-8-2024#proposal-detail">vote</a>. The Dai Savings Rate (DSR) jumped from 5% to 15%.</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/stablecoins">Stablecoin</a> yield opportunities have been on the rise, leading traders to swap DAI borrowed at low rates for higher yielding USDC or other stablecoins used in DeFi.</p>



<p>For instance, in addition to promising high yields, a new entrant to the stablecoin market (<a href="https://blockworks.co/podcast/empire/4633d178-d215-11ee-9575-aba4a06687b1">Ethena’s USDe</a>) is incentivized by a points-like system called “shards.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/stablecoin-liquidity-ethena-labs">Stablecoins need to focus on liquidity, not decentralization — Ethena Labs founder</a></p>



<p>That dynamic puts downward pressure on DAI’s dollar peg and pushed Maker’s PSM module, which allows swaps between DAI and USDC, down to record lows.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt="" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/-V9Q47oGDUcjVcE8V9B1hfdGLxJ6bGr3UOFGiA7fVbmAwvDhN57ysF4FLKWN6_QHL_ov-N_WdGCw6UHc17CqzF-tVmmgplasjJmDfRfYL3Ut5-IbHL90LHkap0ZiMiJC0gYSKeN4Pl37T7vi_jloM-g" decoding="async"></figure>



<p><strong>Read Blockworks Research</strong>: <a href="https://app.blockworksresearch.com/flashnotes/maker-dao-organic-demand-doesn-t-grow-on-trees">MakerDAO: Organic demand doesn’t grow on trees</a></p>



<p>Ethena co-founder, known as Leptokurtic, <a href="https://x.com/ethena_labs/status/1767294768361738290?s=20">argued</a> on an X space this week that his protocol’s contribution to Maker’s rate increase was overstated, noting that Ethena had captured less than 1% of the total value locked (<a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/tvl">TVL</a>) in DeFi to date.</p>



<p>“I actually think the marginal impact that Ethena has had on these changes is probably less than people are giving credit for over the last few weeks,” Leptokurtic said. “These rate changes were going to happen with or without Ethena being there — it’s just now people make that connection a bit easier between rates in [centralized finance] and DeFi.”</p>



<p>Spark developer Sam MacPherson, CEO at Phoenix Labs, said during the same discussion that current rate levels are “almost certainly not sustainable” in the long run.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/spark-protocol-stablecoin-stability-mechanisms">Spark Protocol is re-thinking stablecoin stability mechanisms</a></p>



<p>“Ethena is performing a great function here in bridging this disjointed rates behavior,” MacPherson said. “Maker is at the mercy of the market just as much as everybody else, it’s just that there’s no smart contract doing it, there’s more of a slower human process that people attribute agency to the rate setting within Maker — but that’s really not the case.”</p>



<p>For stablecoin holders right now, times are good, with many options to receive relatively safe double-digit yields.</p>



<p>The question is, how long can it last?</p>



<p>“You can’t have 30,40, 50% rates on USD that is sustainable,” MacPherson said. “Eventually [traditional finance] is going to come in on size,” and push rates back down.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Macauley Peterson</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/macauleypeterson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T17:38:36.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Craig Wright is not Bitcoin creator Satoshi Nakamoto, UK judge says]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/craig-wright-is-not-satoshi-nakamoto</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/craig-wright-is-not-satoshi-nakamoto"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T16:47:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ruling comes after a month-long trial between COPA and Wright]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Craig Wright is not Bitcoin creator Satoshi Nakamoto, a judge ruled on Thursday.</p>



<p>The Crypto Open Patent Alliance notched the victory against Wright in a UK court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to a COPA spokesperson, Justice James Mellor — who oversaw the case — declared that Wright isn’t the author of the Bitcoin white paper, never operated under Nakamoto’s pseudonym, didn’t create Bitcoin, and didn’t author the original versions of the network.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Any further relief will be dealt with in my written judgment. I will extend time for filing any appellant’s notice until 21 days after the form of order hearing, which will be appointed following the hand down of my written judgment,” Mellor told the court.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/satoshi-nakamoto-last-online">13 years ago, Bitcoin’s pseudonymous creator signed off</a></p>



<p>The findings wrap up a month-long trial, which commenced initially back in February and put to rest a legal fight that COPA began in 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The organization hoped to prevent Wright from taking further legal actions against members of both the crypto and developer communities.</p>



<p>“This decision is a win for developers, for the entire open source community and for the truth. For over eight years, Dr. Wright and his financial backers have lied about his identity as Satoshi Nakamoto and used that lie to bully and intimidate developers in the Bitcoin community. That ends today with the court’s ruling that Craig Wright is not Satoshi Nakamoto,” a COPA spokesperson told Blockworks in an email.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/craig-wright-not-defamed-by-being-called-a-fraud-judge-rules">Craig Wright not defamed by being called ‘a fraud,’ Judge rules</a></p>



<p>Mellor, according to a news alert from COPA, found the evidence against Wright “overwhelming.”</p>



<p>Across crypto, industry participants and commentators weighed in on the decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“<a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/satoshi-nakamoto">Satoshi</a> understood the value of decentralization and built Bitcoin so that it could not be controlled by a single person or entity,” a Kraken spokesperson told Blockworks. “We’re pleased the court recognized the overwhelming evidence that categorically settles that Wright is not Satoshi.”</p>



<p>Block and Twitter founder Jack Dorsey simply posted “W” on X to show his support.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">W<br><br>"I will make certain declarations which I am satisfied are useful and are necessary to do justice between the parties. First, that Dr Wright is not the author of the Bitcoin White Paper. Second, Dr Wright is not the person who adopted or operated under the pseudonym Satoshi…</p>— jack (@jack) <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1768270416533917828?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Coinbase’s chief legal officer Paul Grewal <a href="https://twitter.com/iampaulgrewal/status/1768264534115209606">said</a> that the court ruled “definitively and without qualification.”</p>



<p>Grewal also called on Wright to apologize to “every developer, builder and BTC community member whom you harassed and bullied with your lies and false demands.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Enough of this— the Honorable Court has resolved this farce once and for all. Apologize Mr. Wright. To every developer, builder and BTC community member whom you harassed and bullied with your lies and false demands. Apologize now.</p>— paulgrewal.eth (@iampaulgrewal) <a href="https://twitter.com/iampaulgrewal/status/1768280990294913380?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>COPA’s members include Block, Coinbase, MicroStrategy and Kraken. Wright previously filed suits against Block, Kraken and Coinbase.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T16:47:09.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">
            <![CDATA[Story Protocol to help AI developers register and track their models with Ritual]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/story-protocol-ritual-ai-provenance</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/story-protocol-ritual-ai-provenance"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The pair are trialing a somewhat-novel angle for integrating AI with blockchain technology]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Intellectual property-focused Story Protocol is partnering with decentralized AI protocol Ritual to make AI models and outputs trackable and monetizable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The pair hope to create sprawling intellectual property graphs where developers can see how their AI models are being deployed and fine-tuned. Additionally, they want to ensure that content produced by AI models is watermarked and tracked on-chain. It’s the latest attempt at integrating blockchain technology into the lucrative world of AI development.</p>



<p>AI models, like OpenAI’s ChatGPT, have rapidly improved in their ability to draw conclusions and generate content. However, their creators often lack information as to how and by whom the models are being used. Story co-founder Jason Zhao said the protocol is in talks with some AI developers who simply want to track all of the derivative models being spun off their core model. And the distribution of off-chain AI content can be generally difficult to control.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/decentralized-artificial-intelligence-innovation">Funding Wrap: Decentralized AI is all the craze</a></p>



<p>Story Protocol makes creation and monetization involving intellectual property easier through blockchain tech, with this <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/artificial-intelligence">AI</a> project being one of its early use cases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For its part, Ritual helps inferences, or conclusions that AI models make when given new data, interact with smart contracts on-chain. It developed a software development kit (SDK) for its so-called Infernet that brings off-chain compute on-chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Through the Story-Ritual collaboration, developers will be able to set rules for how their AI models powered by Ritual’s Infernet are being utilized downstream, and also set terms for how the AI model’s outputs are used. For example, a developer could set a non-commercial license where no one can earn revenue from generative images created by a certain model, Zhao said.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/artificial-intelligence-decentralization-web3">Decentralized AI platform Ritual lands $25M in seed funding</a></p>



<p>“We’re enabling a network where models can be remixed and built on, and the rights, ideas and licensing of each developer’s model is tracked and protected on-chain,” Ritual co-founder Niraj Pant said in a direct message.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blockchain’s potential for AI model development is an ongoing subject of interest in the crypto world. The models themselves wouldn’t necessarily go on-chain, but blockchain could help around the edges. Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/vitalik-buterin-crypto-ai-integrations">enumerated some possible integrations</a> in a blog post.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Among the more popular ideas, one approach involves leveraging blockchains to authenticate the content used for training AI models or generated by them. In January, FOX Corp teamed up with Polygon in unveiling a <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/fox-authenticate-digital-media-sources">tool for tracing the origins</a> of content being used to train AI models. Now Media <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20240226113025/en/Now-Media-Deploys-on-Base-to-Build-the-Future-of-Authenticated-Media">released</a> Sovereignty, a content verification tool on Base meant to combat misinformation in the “age of AI and fake news.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blockchain-ai-misleading-narrative">What can blockchain do for AI? Not what you’ve heard.</a></p>



<p>Story is betting that as more content is created with the help of AI, a market will emerge for a protocol governing ownership of the models and outputs. Tokens are sometimes referred to as programmable money, where dollar-equivalents can be staked to secure blockchains or lent through DeFi protocols, Zhao said. According to Zhao, intellectual property is still stuck in its “dollar bill era.” Story hopes to make intellectual property similarly programmable, where content can be remixed or co-created without arduous legal processes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“With all these powerful tools, almost god-like tools, and the god-like distribution of the internet, why is Hollywood on strike? Why are creators struggling to monetize?” Zhao said. “There’s a real need in AI for value capture, [intellectual property] provenance and attribution.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jack Kubinec</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/jack-kubinec</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T16:30:00.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hut 8 eyes growth around the Bitcoin halving — but not at all costs]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/hut-8-growth-bitcoin-halving</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/hut-8-growth-bitcoin-halving"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T15:37:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[A few months after Hut 8’s merge with US Bitcoin Corp, the combined company’s new chief executive says building back shareholder trust is a key focus]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>A few months after the merger between crypto miner Hut 8 and US Bitcoin Corp, the combined company’s new CEO says building back shareholder trust remains a challenge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Leading up to, and following, the next Bitcoin halving slated for next month, the company’s focuses include growth — “but not growth at all costs,” Hut 8 CEO Asher Genoot told Blockworks.</p>



<p>Genoot, a co-founder and former chief operating officer at US Bitcoin Corp, <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hut-8-merger-ceo-switch">replaced Jaime Leverton as the miner’s CEO</a> just weeks after the deal closed. The switch was made in an effort to help the company move in “a new strategic direction,” according to Hut 8’s board of directors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Genoot’s first few weeks as CEO, the company closed its deal to buy four power generation facilities and broke ground on a 63 megawatt (MW) mining site in Texas. Hut 8 also noted at the time that it would <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hut-8-treasury-strategy">use its bitcoin reserves to finance growth initiatives</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Less than two weeks later, Hut 8 said it would cease mining operations at its Drumheller site in Alberta, Canada as part of <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hut-8-mining-ceo-strategy">a broader effort to nix inefficiencies</a>. High energy costs and voltage issues at the facility had hurt its profitability.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/miners-money-moves-bitcoin-halving">Miners continue money-conscious moves ahead of the Bitcoin halving</a></p>



<p>Genoot said Drumheller’s closure is just “one of many examples” of how the company intends to scale the business going forward.</p>



<p>“I’m going through not just every single facility, every single category of miners and every single business line, but also every single cost center,” he said. “I’m building bottom-up analyses where are we spending money, how are we spending money and what’s the return on that investment spend?”</p>



<p>Hut 8’s stock price was down 24.5% from a month ago, as of market close Wednesday. The company’s market capitalization was roughly $690 million at that time — not much higher than the roughly $650 million worth of BTC it holds on its balance sheet.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-mining-stocks-crypto-rally">Why most bitcoin mining stocks are down amid a persistent crypto rally</a></p>



<p>Genoot has been candid in noting the reasoning behind Hut 8’s merge with US Bitcoin Corp. While Hut 8 had a strong balance sheet, he has said, it was weak on operations — a category US Bitcoin Corp was equipped to help fix.<br><br>“So [Hut 8’s] biggest weakness is overcoming that public sentiment and building that trust back with our shareholder base and with the market,” he said. “It’s making a lot of these tough decisions in Q1 and then showing the fruits of that labor in Q2, and the execution of that.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Growth strategy, M&amp;A around the halving</h2>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-markets-explainer">The next bitcoin halving</a> — an event during which the per-block rewards for bitcoin miners is set to decrease from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC — is slated for late April.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Occurring roughly every four years, the halving is expected to put financial stress on sector companies. Smaller private operations and miners in areas with higher power costs are particularly at risk of ceasing operations, segment observers have said.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong><strong> </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-crypto-miner-consolidation">Bitcoin miner consolidation appears imminent as halving looms</a></p>



<p>But bitcoin’s price ascent in recent weeks means the halving might not be “as pronounced” as it could have been, Genoot argued.&nbsp;</p>



<p>BTC’s recent all-time highs have pushed up hash price — a metric that <a href="https://data.hashrateindex.com/chart/bitcoin-hashprice-index">measures</a> how much a miner can expect to earn from a specific quantity of hash rate. This might “bail out” miners that might have otherwise shuttered post-halving, the Hut 8 CEO added.</p>



<p>Still, Genoot said he expects there will still be attractive buying options for the company.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“It gives us a real opportunity to invest in things that come up and really be able to grow,” he said. “My belief is growth is extremely important, but not growth at all costs.”</p>



<p>He added: “Capital is going to flow toward the most efficient operators that return the best capital, and scale matters in that pursuit as well.”</p>



<p>Some of Hut 8’s biggest rivals in the space have laid out aggressive growth targets for its self-mining fleet.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/marathon-digital">Marathon</a> executives said the company was ready to <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/marathon-digital-2023-q4-earnings">use the roughly $1 billion of “dry powder” on its balance sheet</a> in a bid to double its hash rate to about 50 exahashes per second (EH/s) by the end of 2025. Riot Platforms also has <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/riot-plots-hash-rate-growth">big hash rate growth plans</a> to reach 100 EH/s over the long term via a deal with MicroBT.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though Hut 8 trails those competitors in terms of deployed self-mining hash rate — with 7.2 EH/s at the end of February — the company has achieved scale in a different way, with 926 MW of energy capacity under management, Genoot noted.</p>



<p>The decision to build scale or buy scale will depend, the CEO noted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hut 8’s 63 MW build-out in Texas is expected to cost $275,000 per megawatt, the company said. That is roughly 40% less than the roughly $460,000 per megawatt that <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-mining-giant-gets-bigger">Marathon spent on two mining facilities in December</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We’re very active in the M&amp;A markets, but we’re also very cost-conscious,” Genoot said. “We’re not going to overpay because we know what the cost is to develop ourselves as well, so we’re running both in parallel very aggressively.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T15:37:50.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s central bank begins new phase of its CBDC pilot]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/hong-kong-cbdc-pilot-testing</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/hong-kong-cbdc-pilot-testing"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T15:07:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first phase wrapped up in October of last year]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The Hong Kong Monetary Authority has launched phase two of its e-HKD pilot program.</p>



<p>According to a post on the central bank’s website Thursday, the next phase of the program will see where an e-HKD — Hong Kong’s potential future central bank digital currency — adds value through programmability, atomic settlement and even tokenization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second phase will also “explore new use cases that have not been covered in the previous phase.”</p>



<p>“An enhanced e-HKD sandbox, leveraged on the wholesale central bank digital currency (wCBDC) sandbox to be built under Project Ensemble, will support Phase 2 of the e-HKD Pilot Programme to accelerate the prototyping, development and testing of use cases by pilot participants, as well as facilitate the study of interoperability and interbank settlement between e-HKD and other forms of tokenised money,” the central bank <a href="https://www.hkma.gov.hk/eng/news-and-media/press-releases/2024/03/20240314-4/#:~:text=The%20HKMA%20completed%20Phase%201,tokenised%20assets%2C%20and%20offline%20payments">said</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hong-kong-stablecoin-regulation-2">Hong Kong official plots rules for stablecoins, crypto OTC services</a></p>



<p>However, it’s still unclear if the HKMA will move forward with a <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/cbdc">CBDC</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The research, the HKMA said, will continue so that the central bank can see how CBDCs would interact in a “future digital money landscape.”</p>



<p>Organizations can apply to participate in the second phase until mid-May.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The HKMA will also continue to engage local and international stakeholders regarding the latest development of CBDCs,” the release said.</p>



<p>Last week, Hong Kong <a href="https://www.hkma.gov.hk/eng/news-and-media/press-releases/2024/03/20240307-5/">unveiled</a> Project Ensemble, which seeks to utilize a sandbox to test out <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/tokenization">tokenization</a> use cases which could include testing out real-world use cases from carbon credits to treasury management.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hong-kong-regulator-tokenization">Tokenization top of mind for Hong Kong’s securities regulator</a></p>



<p>At the end of October last year, the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hong-kong-cbdc-pilot">HKMA wrapped up phase one of its CBDC pilot</a>. At the time, the project found that the CBDC could “improve customer protections and promote trust” between both businesses and consumers through smart contracts.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T15:07:45.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robinhood’s crypto trade volume rose 10% in February]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/robinhood-trading-volume-february</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/robinhood-trading-volume-february"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T14:51:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Last month’s crypto-related trade volumes via the investment app were roughly five times those seen in September 2023]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Robinhood’s crypto notional trading volumes in February rose 10% from January, matching a level seen only one other month since the middle of 2022.</p>



<p>The $6.5 billion worth of crypto volumes on the investment platform last month equaled those seen in December. That mark hadn’t been reached since May 2022, when Robinhood notched $6.6 billion worth of crypto-related trades.</p>



<p>Robinhood’s crypto trading volumes hit a low point last September, at $1.2 billion. The company’s transaction-based revenues on cryptocurrencies declined to $23 million during the third quarter — a 55% quarter-over-quarter drop.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/robinhood-earnings-q3-2023">Robinhood crypto trading revenue plummets 55% in Q3</a></p>



<p>But transaction-related crypto revenue <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/robinhood-q4-earnings-2024">jumped to $43 million during the fourth quarter</a>, Robinhood revealed last month. The spike in that segment helped its over transaction-based revenues rise 8% year-over-year to $200 million.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The higher crypto trading volumes come after the launch of US spot bitcoin ETFs in January. Trading of those funds was making up about 5% of Robinhood’s overall crypto trading volumes — with spot trading continuing to command 95% of the volumes, Chief Financial Officer Jason Warnick said on the company’s February earnings call.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The 10-fund bitcoin ETF segment has so far notched net inflows exceeding $11 billion. They collectively tallied <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-volumes-peak-amid-btc-ath">nearly $10 billion in trading volume</a> on March 5, which marked a record.</p>



<p>“We think it increases overall market interest in crypto and also brings liquidity to the market,” Warnick said of the new products. “So, net-net, we’re really pleased with the bitcoin ETFs.”</p>



<p>The improved volumes also follow <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/robinhood">Robinhood</a> expanding its crypto trading offering to the European Union. The launch was set to grow the company’s addressable market by hundreds of millions of customers, Robinhood CEO Tenev added at the time.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/robinhood-eyes-eu-expansion">Robinhood looks to jumpstart crypto trading revenue via EU expansion</a></p>



<p>Tenev said on the company’s earnings call last month that Robinhood so far had tens of thousands of international customers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It also follows Robinhood Connect, the wallet on-ramp launched in April 2023, <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/metamask-robinhood-wallet-partnership">integrating with self-custodial wallet app MetaMask</a> last month.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I think it really shows the investments that we’ve made in our platform,” Tenev said on the February earnings call. “We think we can be the leading player in bridging the worlds of traditional finance and crypto, so there’s a lot more where that came from.”</p>



<p>The latest crypto volumes don’t reflect trading within the last couple weeks, during which bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>) has <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-btc-all-time-high-70k">repeatedly hit new all-time highs</a>. BTC’s price stood at about $72,200 at 11:30 am ET — up about 45% from a month ago.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T14:51:36.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blobs, MSTR and more: This is Ethereum’s broadband moment]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-broadband-moment</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-broadband-moment"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T13:31:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Broadband rendering 56k modems obsolete was a far bigger deal than many realized — Ethereum’s “blobband” could turn out to be the same]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The internet turned 35 earlier this week, and it seems only fitting that <strong>Ethereum</strong> would undergo arguably its largest upgrade ever just one day later.</p>



<p>Ethereum’s <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-dencun-upgrade-mainnet">Dencun</a> hard fork went off <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-pauses-block-production"><em>mostly</em></a> without a hitch on Wednesday. Its arrival delivered a bevy of nine improvement proposals, with the blob-centric <strong>EIP-4844</strong> being by far the most memeable.</p>



<p>For more than a decade after <strong>Tim Bernes-Lee</strong> (himself a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557765/www-nft-tim-berners-lee-sothebys-source-code">dabbler</a> in NFTs) first conceived the World Wide Web, internet users languished inside a slow, cumbersome internet plagued by bandwidth bottlenecks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dial-up modems could only handle up to about 50 kilobytes per second. The platforms we now take for granted — YouTube, Spotify, Twitch and TikTok —&nbsp;were as unfeasible back then as high-frequency trading on many layer-1 DEXs are today.</p>



<p>The arrival of broadband in the early 2000s immediately 10x’d consumer-grade internet to 512 kb/sec. Impossible ideas could now be realized into billion-dollar dot-com powerhouses, radically overhauling the dynamics of our culture and turning us all terminally online.</p>



<p>Now, two decades later, TV is all but dead, replaced by a gamut of streaming services. AR headsets backed by hyper-fast wireless blend our physical worlds with the same digital space that Bernes-Lee laid out in his 1989 paper outlining the web.</p>



<p>What broadband did for the internet, blobs are now doing for Ethereum.</p>



<p>Blobs give the raft of layer-2s their own space through which to post transactions to the Ethereum mainnet without clogging up the blockspace intended for other users.</p>



<p>They have their own fee market, which means regular folk and their protocols of choice won’t have to compete with rollups and sidechains for blockspace — leading to lower fees for all involved.</p>



<p>Dencun and its blobs have already massively <a href="https://dune.com/Marcov/layer-2-transaction-cost">reduced</a> fees for the layer-2s that have adopted the new rules. For example, Optimism and Base fees are down to a fraction of an American penny per transaction compared to nearly $1 before the fork.</p>



<p>YouTube debuted in 2005, a half-decade after the rollout of the first consumer-grade broadband services. Justin.tv, the precursor to Twitch, came two years later.</p>



<p>It could be that layer-2 fees rise over time as more layer-2s compete for blobspace. The true impact of Ethereum’s successful push toward a cohesive and holistic multi-chain ecosystem, powered by “blobband,” probably won’t be felt for years to come.</p>



<p>But the groundwork has now been laid. Welcome to Ethereum’s blobband era.</p>



<p><em>— David Canellis</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Data Digest</h2>



<p><strong>🙃 Solana</strong> has <a href="https://defillama.com/chains">flipped</a> <strong>Ethereum</strong> layer-2 Arbitrum for total value locked (TVL) to become the fourth largest DeFi ecosystem — a first since November 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🌊 A<strong> quarter of a billion dollars</strong> was <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/LiquidationData">liquidated</a> on centralized exchanges over the past 24 hours, 60% longs.</p>



<p>🤪 <strong>Memecoin mania</strong> puts Solana number-one for DEX volume over the past day — $1.45 billion to <strong>BSC’s</strong> $1.14 billion</p>



<p>😴 All quiet on the crypto front as <strong>BTC</strong> hovers around $73,000 as ETH sits just below $4,000.&nbsp;</p>



<p>✋No budge in the benchmarks:<strong> S&amp;P</strong> and the <strong>Dow</strong> were flat during the pre-market trade. That’s no surprise, considering the VIX’s drop to 14 from its long-term average of 20.&nbsp;</p>



<p>✅ Good news: A bull market with a high <strong>VIX</strong> tends to spell “bubble trouble” — so lower volatility with higher prices may be a boon for traders.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is the SEC in the crypto market’s rear-view mirror?</h2>



<p>The crypto pump is upon us.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/price/sol"><strong>SOL</strong></a> is up 18% this week and almost 50% over the month. Binance’s <a href="https://blockworks.co/price/bnb"><strong>BNB</strong></a> and <a href="https://blockworks.co/price/fil"><strong>Filecoin</strong></a> are each up more than 80% over the past 30 days. <strong>Wormhole’s </strong>Portal Bridge has facilitated more than $113 million in transfers from <strong>Ethereum</strong> to alt chains like <strong>Solana</strong>, <strong>Sui</strong>, and <strong>Arbitrum</strong> over the past week.</p>



<p>Has the market forgotten that in the eyes of the <strong>SEC</strong>, they are all securities? Probably. Or maybe traders are just confident that <strong>Coinbase</strong> and <strong>Binance</strong> will emerge victorious in their legal battles with the regulator.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In June 2023, the SEC filed back-to-back lawsuits against Coinbase and Binance for allegedly selling unregistered securities, among other things. The regulator named <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/judge-questions-sec-limits-coinbase-hearing">13 cryptocurrencies available on Coinbase</a> and <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-sec-hearing-motion-dismiss">ten that trade on Binance securities</a> —&nbsp;despite none of these issuers being named co-defendants in the cases.</p>



<p>The SEC has also not filed any individual lawsuits against these alleged security token issuers, opting to take a different approach than it did in 2020 when it sued <strong>Ripple</strong> over its XRP token —&nbsp;a suit that ultimately did not play out in the regulator’s favor.</p>



<p>Both cases are still playing out in the legal system, and you might remember the SEC was notably absent from the<strong> Department of Justice’s</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-settlement-message-to-crypto-industry">historic $4.3 billion settlement</a> with Binance back in November.</p>



<p>But if you look at token prices, you’d think the SEC had dropped the cases.</p>



<p>Coinbase and Binance are both waiting for rulings in their <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-pushes-to-dismiss-sec-lawsuit">motions to dismiss</a> their respective cases. If the suits are not fully dismissed, the exchanges will move on to the discovery process.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>— Casey Wagner</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">MicroStrategy keeps its foot on the gas&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Can’t stop, won’t stop?</p>



<p>After offering an oversubscribed round where <strong>MicroStrategy</strong> (MSTR) raised nearly $800 million in senior convertible notes — mind you, they initially sought to raise $600 million before upsizing to $700 million last week — the company has proposed <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-second-convertible-senior-notes-offering"><em>another</em> $500 million</a> in convertible notes.</p>



<p>MSTR could, all-in-all, raise around $1.3 billion from its convertible notes offerings to fund its bitcoin purchases.</p>



<p>While this represents a new approach to the same tactic we’ve seen from MSTR in the past, Michael Saylor’s firm might have found a way to ensure that the stock remains more <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-stock-vs-bitcoin-etf">attractive than the bevy of bitcoin ETFs</a> on the market today.</p>



<p>By the numbers: MSTR has about $48 million in cash on hand as of December, but it has roughly $15 billion worth of bitcoin at current prices.</p>



<p>It’s fair to note that while the company <em>may</em> spend that cash on hand, MicroStrategy appears to largely plan to add to its BTC hoard. The stock was around before the bitcoin ETFs, and so far, it looks like it won’t only stick around, but may even outperform.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Compare IBIT and MSTR, for example. MSTR is outperforming BlackRock’s ETF even as the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-supply-rivals-blackrock-ibit">two go head-to-head over who holds the most bitcoin</a>.</p>



<p>MSTR’s bitcoin buying spree has proven to be a win-win for them: Wall Street’s happy and, more importantly, the crypto crowd goes bonkers when the company announces a new buy. And, trust me, the company is always announcing new buys. This year alone, MSTR has bought <em>nearly 16,000 </em>bitcoin.</p>



<p>Adding to that, when bitcoin’s price rockets, so does the company’s stock. The company, at the end of 2023, was trading around $680. Now, the stock is getting close to $2,000 — up 200% in the last three months alone.</p>



<p>Suffice to say, Saylor and MSTR keep hodling. The company isn’t afraid to hit the buy button — even if it means raising some debt to do so — and the most recent debt offerings show that the company’s appetite remains ravenous.</p>



<p>—&nbsp;<em>Katherine Ross</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Works</h2>



<p>Welcome to <strong>The Works</strong> 👋 Your daily slice of crypto (and not-so-crypto) from around the Web. 🕸️</p>



<p><strong>💸 Bakkt</strong> against the wall? The publicly-traded crypto company once owned by finance giant <strong>Intercontinental Exchange</strong> is facing an existential dilemma after <a href="https://markets.ft.com/data/announce/full?dockey=600-202403131740BIZWIRE_USPRX____20240313_BW401585-1">receiving a notice</a> from NYSE about its sub-$1 share price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bakkt’s been below a buck since the end of February, but it’s pledging to “cure” the problem. Stay tuned.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🧠 The crypto team at <strong>Franklin Templeton</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/FTI_DA/status/1767969299350610040/photo/1">thinks</a> “meme coins have a strong relationship with their native networks.” The top response on X? “[w]e need a memecoin ETF” —&nbsp;something we’re sure Gary Gensler would <em>love</em>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🐕Speaking of memecoins: X owner <strong>Elon Musk</strong>, visiting Tesla’s Berlin manufacturing plant, was asked when people can buy a car with dogecoin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Musk’s response, according to a video from <a href="https://twitter.com/dogeofficialceo/status/1768087572234793050">X user @dogeofficialceo</a>: “At some point, I think we should enable that.” He then talked up how people can buy merch with the dog-themed memecoin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🌱 A <strong>bitcoin ETF</strong> proposed last December would load up on 20% carbon credits, per a new <a href="https://www.nyse.com/publicdocs/nyse/markets/nyse-arca/rule-filings/filings/2024/SR-NYSEARCA-2024-27.pdf">regulatory filing</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🤬 The CEO of Palantir, Alex Karp, is a bit, uh, <a href="https://twitter.com/micsolana/status/1768014042105253902">steaming mad</a> about short sellers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>😕 Today’s <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6bba4771-a455-41f1-ba3b-2b9f43add832">why-is-this-a-crypto headline</a>: “What the <strong>Kate Middleton</strong> story tells us about bitcoin”</p>



<p>The short answer, per the FT’s Bryce Elder: “[a]bsolutely nothing.” Okie doke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🚚 BitKey, <strong>Jack Dorsey’s</strong> bitcoin hardware wallet play, is (finally?) <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1768003624330731842?s=46&amp;t=C4aoT7YJCbO_BZ2A-sRi4A">enroute</a> to people’s mailboxes. Get excited.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>⚖️ Finders keepers: Australia’s finance regulator <a href="https://www.canberratimes.com.au/story/8555694/asic-loses-case-over-comparison-sites-crypto-service/?cs=14231">lost a legal fight</a> against the <strong>Finder Wallet Pty Ltd</strong>, with a court saying the firm did not offer an unlicensed financial service.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🔬 Researchers over at the <strong>Bank of International Settlements</strong> <a href="https://www.bis.org/publ/work1171.pdf">dug into</a> DeFi borrower behavior in a new study.&nbsp;</p>



<p>🤔Summing it up: Investor and AngelList co-founder Naval Ravikant <a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/1768130605613818092">believes</a> that crypto is “adversarial venture capital.” Makes you think.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>—&nbsp;Michael McSweeney</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Morning Riff</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img sizes="(max-width: 1057px) 100vw, 1057px" srcset="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=1057 1057w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=428 428w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=470 470w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=389 389w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg?w=80 80w" class="wp-image-82500" alt="" src="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.jpeg" height="359" width="1057" decoding="async" loading="lazy"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Translation: We’re so back (<a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/1768143338929258932">source</a>)</em></figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Canellis</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/david-canellis</uri>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Web3" term="Web3"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T13:31:37.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[zkSync welcomes AI data warehouse as latest addition to hyperchain]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/space-and-time-artificial-intelligence-zksync-hyperchain</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/space-and-time-artificial-intelligence-zksync-hyperchain"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[zkSync will now have its own dedicated AI data warehouse layer]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Space and Time (SxT), a decentralized data warehouse that uses artificial intelligence to train its data models, will be launching its network on a zkSync hyperchain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blockchain networks often operate in silos, having limited interoperability with other chains. zkSync hyperchains offer a solution by providing an open-sourced framework specifically designed for zk <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/rollups">rollups</a> and layer-3 networks. This enables the creation of interconnected ecosystems through decentralized sequences that allow for more efficient transaction processing.</p>



<p>Moreover, hyperchains incorporate hyperbridges, which facilitate seamless asset and data transfers across different blockchains. By addressing interoperability challenges, zkSync hyperchains are able to streamline transactions, reduce fees and foster a more scalable blockchain ecosystem.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/zksync-launches-op-stack-rival">ZkSync launches rival to Optimism’s OP Stack</a></p>



<p>SxT is used to aggregate and analyze blockchain data, which can then be sent back to smart contracts. The data platform will deploy as a zero-knowledge proof (ZKP) verifiable compute layer (VCL), and ensure that accurate, verifiable and tamper-proof information is being funneled through to smart contracts and enterprises.</p>



<p>Vassilis Tziokas, the head of enterprise business development at Matter Labs, the infrastructure team behind zkSync, wrote in a press reviewed by Blockworks that SxT will be introducing to new novel ideas to zkSync, including “a decentralized data warehouse and the Proof of SQL protocol.”</p>



<p>This combination, Tziokas believes, will enable zero-knowledge verification queries to ensure that raw data and query results can not be manipulated.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/custom-hyperchains-ethereum-zk-stack">ZK Stack developers can now build custom ‘hyperchains’ on Ethereum</a></p>



<p>“We’re excited to partner with SxT and advance our shared vision of offering developers sophisticated, data-driven, cross-chain smart contracts,” Tziokas said.</p>



<p>As part of the launch, some new features will also be introduced. This includes providing zkSync data from both zkSyncEra and hyperchains to develop on the platform free of charge. Developers will be liable only for the compute that is used to execute queries, without needing to pay for storing and indexing data.</p>



<p>“Given our commitment to zk, we knew we wanted to leverage a <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/zkevm">zkEVM</a> as our network’s dedicated settlement layer. zkSync is best-in-class in fulfilling the vision of trustless layer-2s, offering extremely fast and low-cost zk-proven transactions,” Scott Dykstra, co-founder and chief technology officer of SxT said in a statement.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bessie Liu</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/bessieliu</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T13:00:00.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blockchain really is better than middlemen]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/blockchain-better-middlemen-swift</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/blockchain-better-middlemen-swift"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T12:40:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[SWIFT’s forays into blockchain hint that one day the tech can replace intermediaries]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The need for an organization connecting all banks is clear in today’s hyper-globalized economy where funds, goods and services are sent across every corner of the globe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So as globalization expanded, our deeply interconnected and centralized financial system triggered the development of SWIFT (Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication) in 1973, a member-owned messaging network for financial institutions to send secure communications as well as verify and settle inter-bank transactions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SWIFT connects more than 11 thousand financial institutions across 200 countries and territories — long serving as a unified and stable institution amid a complex and volatile world order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But recently, the exclusion of many sanctioned <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/idUSKCN1NA1PN/">Iranian</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/eu-excludes-seven-russian-banks-swift-official-journal-2022-03-02/">Russian</a> banks from SWIFT prompted <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/sanctions-swift-and-chinas-cross-border-interbank-payments-system">China</a> and other nations to launch competing alternative intermediaries. This has led to the wide-scale rethinking of how to structure international finance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While barring certain institutions from SWIFT due to connections with state-sponsored violence, terror or other criminal activity is appropriate, fractionalizing centralized entities into siloed, competing groups poses a long-term threat to global finance. <a href="https://apnews.com/article/bank-failures-poll-confidence-economy-5915263dd274314030eb055df2463d18">Changing attitudes</a> toward centralized finance and innovative fintech applications further undermine the current financial system and highlight its shortcomings.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the rise of blockchain-based trading solutions has led those in the traditional financial sector to question the role of intermediaries. There is a growing consideration into how this technology can enhance the speed and frequency of interbank transactions.</p>



<p>After all, the primary goal of Bitcoin and the broader crypto movement was to eliminate what seemed to be an unjust financial order. This order, dominated by large banks and financial institutions, wielded censorship and control over the world’s population, particularly in the aftermath of the 2008 financial crisis.</p>



<p>Despite being largely opposed to crypto and blockchain until only a few years ago, financial institutions are now embracing blockchain as a technology, crypto as an investment opportunity and DeFi as a sandbox for innovative financial products.</p>



<p><strong>Read more from our opinion section: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-conservative-portfolios-fidelity">Bitcoin ETFs in conservative portfolios is good for crypto —&nbsp;and Wall Street</a></p>



<p>This recognition of blockchain’s upside showcases its capability and effectiveness at removing the middleman. Further validating this were recent announcements that SWIFT, in collaboration with more than 12 major financial institutions, is experimenting with <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/swift-tests-chainlink-ccip">interoperable on-chain token transfers</a> and <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/banks-can-10x-the-blockchain-industry-says-chainlink-co-founder">tokenization</a>.</p>



<p>Together with SWIFT’s messaging technology, Chainlink’s Cross-Chain Interoperability Protocol (CCIP) and a public Ethereum testnet are <a href="https://www.swift.com/news-events/news/swift-explores-blockchain-interoperability-remove-friction-tokenised-asset-settlement">facilitating the routing of messages</a> between legacy banking systems. This alone should legitimize the idea that digital assets and blockchains are legitimate infrastructure components that banks should and will adopt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it’s not totally clear where this adoption could go from here, as SWIFT’s use of CCIP simply gives an intermediary a new capability in the form of blockchain.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What if we could remove the intermediaries?</h2>



<p>It’s widely acknowledged that blockchain technology has the potential to significantly enhance the financial industry’s efficiency by diminishing its reliance on intermediaries. But this current practicality is hindered by the intricate nature of reforming a deeply entrenched, centuries-old system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Rather than pursuing an immediate overhaul, the emphasis should instead shift towards making gradual strides in reducing dependence on these financial intermediaries. The path to replacing intermediaries with blockchain technology necessitates the development of use cases, along with achieving interoperability among various blockchains and traditional banking systems.</p>



<p>This requires not only demonstrating the blockchain’s technological benefits — notably its security and cost-effectiveness — in an enterprise setting, but also facilitating interoperability between dozens of unconnected blockchain networks. As siloes of data by design, blockchains are unable to share data or transfer assets among each other. Common mechanisms to boost blockchain interoperability including bridges, sidechains and cross-chain platforms all come with their fair share of complexities, security vulnerabilities and potential compliance challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ensuring limited interoperability and relying on susceptible smart contracts to link diverse blockchain networks pose significant barriers to embracing the technology for financial transactions. The prospect of all financial institutions unanimously adopting the same blockchain network seems unlikely, given the decades-long history of technological infrastructure adoption. Consequently, the necessity for intermediaries, exemplified by the establishment of SWIFT for facilitating cross-bank transactions, becomes evident.</p>



<p>But that means the fintech industry, which sits squarely between the finance and blockchain worlds, must develop solutions and protocols to link these isolated data silos. A <a href="https://www.ledgerinsights.com/swift-blockchain-interoperability-trial-bnp-paribas-citi-dtcc/">SWIFT report</a> from August 2023 stated that “firms prefer to leverage their existing infrastructure, manage implementations and proven business processes to connect to blockchain ledgers, where tokens are recorded in a way that is both compliant and secure.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since financial institutions, understandably, don’t want to abandon their existing infrastructure, the key is to integrate new technologies between systems that use various blockchains. Efficient, loosely coupled integrations among entities and the establishment of a “trusted network” to facilitate the secure exchange of value and data can enable institutions to engage in affordable and convenient transfers.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.igi-global.com/dictionary/grid-transaction-management-highly-reliable/1736">Atomic-swap transactions</a> play a significant role in ensuring that transactions occur smoothly and without errors, especially when dealing with different blockchains and older legacy systems. They help maintain consistency and reliability throughout the transaction lifecycle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, they also contribute to enhancing overall asset transfer security, especially against threats like unauthorized access attempts and manipulation of data. They do this by establishing a secure communication network that supports essential operations like authentication and encryption. This means that the information and transactions within the system are better protected from potential risks.</p>



<p>It’s unlikely that SWIFT’s dominance over the transfer of financial information and messages will be broken soon, but its research into interoperable blockchains and tokenization provides major hope toward reducing the inefficiencies caused by intermediaries — such as delays in transactions, additional costs and fees, dependency risks, lack of transparency and compliance challenges. Recognizing SWIFT as a legitimate and necessary financial institution while building the necessary infrastructure to do what it does but more efficiently, affordably and securely provides the best short-term path toward a future free from middlemen.</p>



<p>Regardless of what comes from SWIFT’s experiments with blockchain, institutional adoption of blockchain technology will continue to grow as <a href="https://www.securities.io/bny-mellon-believes-digital-assets-are-here-to-stay-2022-survey-results-revealed/">97%</a> of institutional investors believe tokenization will revolutionize asset management. Meeting this demand and bridging these two disconnected ecosystems can only be done through interoperability and automation, which can do what intermediaries do but cheaper and faster.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">


<div class="wp-block-post-author-biography">Eitan Katz is the CEO and Co-Founder of Kima. Prior to Kima, Eitan served as a seasoned executive with a distinguished background and leadership roles at the IDF (Intelligence/8200), HP, HPE, and BMC. His list of accomplishments includes building HP’s Global Innovation and Incubation program, leading HPE’s Enterprise Mobile platform, and being a 3X founder, as well as a founding member of Aegis, the first MPC-based bitcoin wallet. Eitan’s training in the Elite Israeli Intelligence Forces along with his experience, has instilled in him a unique perspective on deep technology, leadership, strategy, and execution.</div>


<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Eitan Katz</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/eitan-katz</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Op-Ed" term="Op-Ed"/>
        <published>2024-03-14T12:40:45.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MicroStrategy announces another senior notes offering to buy more bitcoin]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-second-convertible-senior-notes-offering</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-second-convertible-senior-notes-offering"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T21:17:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[MicroStrategy announced a senior notes offering last week, raising $800 million]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>MicroStrategy’s not done buying up bitcoin —&nbsp;or, rather, offering convertible senior notes to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The company, on Wednesday, announced that it was proposing another offering — this time for $500 million — of convertible senior notes due in 2031. The company added that it could raise an additional $75 million from the offer.</p>



<p>“<a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/microstrategy">​​MicroStrategy</a> also expects to grant to the initial purchasers of the notes an option to purchase, within a 13-day period beginning on, and including, the date on which the notes are first issued, up to an additional $75 million aggregate principal amount of the notes,” a press release <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20240313484286/en/MicroStrategy-Announces-Proposed-Private-Offering-of-500-Million-of-Convertible-Senior-Notes#:~:text=TYSONS%20CORNER%2C%20Va.%2D%2D(BUSINESS,a%20private%20offering%20to%20persons">said</a>.</p>



<p>The company said the funds from the sale will be used to “acquire additional bitcoin and for general corporate purposes.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-supply-rivals-blackrock-ibit">MicroStrategy once again holds more bitcoin than BlackRock’s IBIT — for now</a></p>



<p>The sale will only be offered to institutional investors.</p>



<p>The offering comes just after it proposed an initial offering of $600 million worth of convertible notes, which it later upsized to $700 million.</p>



<p>The previous convertible note offering closed on March 8.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The company announced on Monday that it had closed the $800 million offering of 0.625% senior convertible notes due in 2030.</p>



<p>‘The aggregate principal amount of the notes sold in the offering was $800 million,” the company <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20240311901408/en/MicroStrategy-Completes-800-Million-Offering-of-0.625-Convertible-Senior-Notes-Due-2030">said</a>.</p>



<p>Earlier this week, the company announced that it bought 12,000 more bitcoin for $821 million. The purchases were made from Feb. 26 through March 10, a filing showed. MicroStrategy holds roughly 205,000 bitcoin.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-convertible-note-sale">MicroStrategy will use proceeds from convertible note sale to add to bitcoin stash</a></p>



<p>The company’s stock was slightly down in after-hours trading Wednesday, hovering around $1,735 a share. It closed the market day up roughly, continuing an upward trend.</p>



<p>Over the past year, it’s up 676%. In the past five days alone, the stock has soared 41%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MicroStrategy’s most recent proposed note offering follows on the coattails of Coinbase, which announced a <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-convertible-notes-offering">proposed offering of $1 billion in senior convertible notes</a> Tuesday evening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The company said that it would be using the proceeds for general corporate purposes, according to a press release.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T21:17:56.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">
            <![CDATA[Terraform can retain its law firm despite SEC objections of ‘slush fund,’ court rules]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/terraform-retains-law-firm-despite-sec-objections</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/terraform-retains-law-firm-despite-sec-objections"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T21:03:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Terraform Labs and the SEC are expected to head to trial later this month]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Terraform Labs can retain its lawyers in its bankruptcy proceedings, a judge ruled Tuesday.</p>



<p>The ruling comes after the Securities and Exchange Commission challenged the bankrupt company’s retainer of $166 million for the lawyers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bankruptcy court found, thanks to two declarations in support of the company’s move, that the law firm “does not represent or hold any interest adverse to the debtor.”</p>



<p>Additionally, the law firm agreed to return $48 million — of the amount pre-paid for the firm’s work on the case — to <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/terraform-labs">Terraform</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/terraform-sec-trial-liability">Terraform faces ‘significant liability’ after SEC trial</a></p>



<p>The agency previously argued that “the timing and enormous amount of these transfers, given the ongoing litigation with the <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/sec">SEC</a>, warrant proceeding with caution to protect Debtor assets — which may ultimately belong to the investor victims the SEC alleges were defrauded by the debtor.”</p>



<p>Terraform filed to retain Dentons as its counsel in February.</p>



<p>The SEC argued on Feb. 27 that the timing was “suspicious” due to its litigation against the now-bankrupt company.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The SEC and Terraform have faced off in court ahead of an upcoming trial, arguing for and against a partial ruling on the securities sales alleged by the SEC. <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-granted-summary-judgment-in-terraform-case">Judge Jed Rakoff sided with the regulatory agency</a>, ruling that UST, LUNA, wLUNA and MIR “are securities because they are investment contracts.”</p>



<p>The regulatory agency called out the loss in its pushback against the Dentons retainer, saying that $122 million was transferred into an “opaque slush fund” for its lawyers before it filed for bankruptcy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A trial in the SEC’s case against Terraform Labs and its former CEO <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/do-kwon">Do Kwon</a> is set to take place later this month. The agency alleged that the two offered and sold cryptocurrencies that the SEC believes to be securities, as well as “orchestrating a multi-billion dollar crypto asset securities fraud” concerning its algorithmic stablecoin TerraUSD.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/one-year-since-terra">stablecoin collapsed in the spring of 2022</a>, just months before the FTX collapse. It wiped billions from the crypto market at the time, and the ripple effects led to the bankruptcies of Three Arrows Capital, Celsius and Voyager.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Terraform Labs <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/terraform-bankruptcy-protections">filed for bankruptcy earlier this year</a>, calling the move a “strategic step” that would “enable it to continue its operations and support for the Terra community and ecosystem.”</p>



<p>It also claimed that the bankruptcy would allow the company to navigate its “legal proceedings” in both Singapore and the US.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T21:03:53.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">
            <![CDATA[European Banking Authority takes next step in finalizing stablecoin policy ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/european-banking-authority-stablecoin-regulation</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/european-banking-authority-stablecoin-regulation"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T19:14:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The EBA released a final draft of regulatory technical standards outlining how issuers should respond to holder complaints ]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>As mandated by the recently-implemented Markets in Crypto-Assets Regulation (MiCA), the European Union has taken another step toward establishing regulations around stablecoins.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The European Banking Authority (EBA) on Wednesday released a final draft of regulatory technical standards in partnership with the European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA), which oversees markets in the EU. The standards establish protocols for stablecoin issuers when addressing complaints.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The standards ask issuers of asset-referenced tokens — known as <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/stablecoins">stablecoins</a> — to publish how they handle complaints and to have a standardized process for customers and users to submit them.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/stablecoins-beat-bitcoin-etf-inflows">Cheatsheet: Stablecoins mint $7.7B since bitcoin ETFs, beating inflows</a></p>



<p>“The issuer should acknowledge receipt of a complaint clearly mentioning the date of its receipt and, where an electronic complaint form is filed, provide the complainant with a copy of the complaint; assess whether the complaint is admissible and contains all relevant information necessary for the investigation and request immediately to the holders of asset-referenced tokens and other interested parties any additional information needed,” the draft standards state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/european-banking-authority">EBA</a> first released draft guidance for public comment in July 2023. Based on these comments, “the EBA decided to make a small number of targeted amendments,” the banking regulator <a href="https://www.eba.europa.eu/publications-and-media/press-releases/eba-publishes-final-draft-technical-standards-complaints">said</a> in a statement Wednesday. Changes include new provisions relating to data protection and updates to complaint forms to include a section for complainants to list legal representatives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Wednesday’s final draft also comes months after the EBA <a href="https://www.eba.europa.eu/sites/default/files/document_library/Publications/Consultations/2024/Consultation%20on%20Guidelines%20on%20recovery%20plans%20under%20MiCAR/1063477/CP%20GL%20recovery%20plans%20under%20MiCAR.pdf">released</a> draft guidelines relating to how stablecoin and other cryptocurrency issuers should structure their recovery plans.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/2024-stablecoins-crypto-volatility">2024 will be the year for stablecoins</a></p>



<p>“Issuers should include at least one recovery option that would strengthen the capital position and one recovery option aimed at improving the liquidity position of the issuer,” the EBA suggested in November.</p>



<p>This final draft for regulatory technical standards will be submitted to the European Commission for endorsement by the end of June 2024, the EBA said, before heading to the European Parliament and the Council for approval.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T19:14:56.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why most bitcoin mining stocks are down amid a persistent crypto rally]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-mining-stocks-crypto-rally</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-mining-stocks-crypto-rally"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T18:04:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The market is grappling with the impact of BTC price and hash rate on miner profitability about a month before the bitcoin halving, analyst says]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Bitcoin mining stocks have struggled in recent weeks despite BTC’s relentless price rally.</p>



<p>Market concerns related to the upcoming bitcoin halving are the main reason, segment observers noted. The halving is expected to occur in late April, at a block height of 840,000.</p>



<p>Mining behemoth Marathon Digital — with a standout energized self-mining hash rate of 28.7&nbsp; exahashes per second (EH/s) — was down 20% from a month ago, as of 12 pm ET Wednesday.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/btc-price-action-all-time-high">BTC price dips after all-time high. Where is it headed next?</a></p>



<p>The stock prices of rival companies Riot Platforms, Bitfarms and Bitdeer also hover around the 20% decline mark over that span.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/hut-8">Hut 8</a>, which <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/new-look-hut-8-eyes-ai-related-opportunities-after-merger">merged with US Bitcoin Corp in November</a> and <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/hut-8-mining-ceo-strategy">switched its CEO last month</a>, is down 11.5% from a month ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Core Scientific, which <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/core-scientific-relisting-shares-tumble">emerged out of bankruptcy in January</a>, has fared a bit better, dipping about 8% in the last 30 days. Cipher Mining’s stock is down just 2% from a month ago.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Las Vegas-based miner <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/cleanspark">CleanSpark</a> has bucked the downward trend, with its share price seeing a 10% gain over the past month.</p>



<p>The recent underperformance of most <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/mining">mining</a> stocks comes just weeks before the next bitcoin <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/bitcoin-halving">halving</a>, during which per-block rewards for miners is set to drop from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC. Such an event occurs roughly every four years.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-markets-explainer">The next bitcoin halving is coming. Here’s what you need to know</a></p>



<p>Compass Point Research &amp; Trading analyst Joe Flynn said in a Feb. 27 research note that he expected miner stock volatility to continue in the 50-day leadup to the halving, followed by “eventual short-term weakness related to hash price declines.”</p>



<p>Hash price — taking into account bitcoin price, network difficulty, block subsidy and transaction fees — <a href="https://data.hashrateindex.com/chart/bitcoin-hashprice-index">measures</a> how much a miner can expect to earn from a specific quantity of hash rate. It is positively correlated to BTC price changes and negatively linked to fluctuations in bitcoin mining difficulty.<br><br>Bitcoin’s price has risen more than 20% since Flynn’s Feb. 27 note was published.</p>



<p>“We think the market is trying to determine the equilibrium levels of BTC price and hash rates and the near-term impact on profitability as a result of the halving,” Flynn told Blockworks Tuesday.</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-btc-all-time-high-70k">Bitcoin’s price stood at about $72,800</a> on Wednesday at 12 pm ET — up about 14% from a week ago, but down from its high of more than $73,600 reached earlier in the day.</p>



<p>It remains to be seen if there will be a pre-halving correction in BTC prices similar to prior cycles, Flynn noted.</p>



<p>“But after hash prices decline post halving, we expect strength in miner stocks…with BTC price growth outpacing the rate at which new machines can be installed or come back online,” he added.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Other factors currently ‘bothering markets’</h2>



<p>The concerns for miners ahead of the halving are “warranted,” said Dan Weiskopf, a co-portfolio manager of the Amplify Transformational Data Sharing ETF (BLOK). Not every miner will survive the halving, he added.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-crypto-miner-consolidation">Bitcoin miner consolidation appears imminent as halving looms</a></p>



<p>The hash rate from a portion of certain application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC) models <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-halving-crypto-miner-consolidation">are likely to go offline</a> when the halving changes the breakeven revenues for such machines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Home retail miners, smaller private operations and miners in areas with higher power costs are particularly at risk of ceasing operations, segment observers have said.</p>



<p>“The higher BTC price has led to concerns around miners who have not upgraded their equipment staying on line longer rather than shutting, since they can afford to run less efficient equipment when BTC price is at current levels,” Weiskopf told Blockworks.</p>



<p>Another factor currently “bothering markets” is the proposed 30% excise tax on miners’ energy usage, the BLOK co-portfolio manager argued.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden administration <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-mining-tax-biden">first floated such a tax on miners</a> last year, citing environmental concerns. That possible tax appeared again in the US Department of Treasury’s 2025 revenue proposals.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/us-treasury-2025-greenbook-crypto-taxes">US Treasury once again proposes new crypto tax rules to “modernize” code</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Weiskopf said allocating to miners will continue to be a key strategy for BLOK — a fund that has CleanSpark, Marathon and Riot among its top 12 <a href="https://amplifyetfs.com/blok-holdings/">holdings</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blok-bitcoin-halving-spot-etf">BLOK ready for possible BTC rally ahead of halving, spot ETF</a></p>



<p>He added that he expects bitcoin’s price to trend higher, with dips being absorbed by institutions <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-inflows-price-rally">buying spot bitcoin ETFs</a>.</p>



<p>“A higher price from here will make the miners reach cash flow goals faster than planned and enhance [return on investment], and we would expect many of the miners we own to build out their facilities more aggressively,” Weiskopf said. “Access to capital continues to be a competitive edge for most miners.”</p>



<p>Marathon Digital recently <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/marathon-digital-terminates-competitor-involvement">bought two mining sites in Nebraska and Texas</a>, while CleanSpark has also <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/cleanspark-site-acquisition-bitcoin-halving">sought out growth via facility acquisitions</a>.<br><br><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/marathon-digital">Marathon</a> executives said the company was ready to <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/marathon-digital-2023-q4-earnings">use the roughly $1 billion of “dry powder” on its balance sheet</a> in a bid to double its hash rate by the end of 2025.</p>



<p>Riot Platforms, which too has <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/riot-plots-hash-rate-growth">aggressive hash rate growth plans</a>, had about $900 million in combined cash and bitcoin on its balance sheet at the end of 2023.</p>



<p>Flynn said: “We like miner stocks with the ability to grow [their] own hash rate, lower unit costs as a result of efficiency gains, and with clean balance sheets and already low power prices going into halving.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Finance" term="Finance"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T18:04:42.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swell launches its own layer-2 for restaking with Polygon CDK]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/swell-launches-layer-2</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/swell-launches-layer-2"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T15:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[rswETH, Swell’s liquid restaked token, will be the gas token used on this new rollup]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Swell, a liquid staking protocol, will launch its own layer-2 rollup solution for restaking using AltLayer and EigenDA.</p>



<p>Restaked rollups are a design pioneered by AltLayer. Unlike a standard rollup solution, these variants are architectured to include vertically integrated Actively Validated Services (AVS) systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In restaked rollups, Actively Validated Services are deployed as modular components which help to spread validation logic and responsibilities across the network. This significantly reduces the centralization of power and risk.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ether-fi-funding-restaking-interest">Ether.fi announces $23M Series A round as restaking interest grows</a></p>



<p>These components contribute to the system’s resilience by verifying the accuracy of <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/rollups">rollup</a> states and achieving faster transaction finality. This introduces a structured approach to <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/scaling">scaling</a>, focusing on security, efficiency and the distribution of control.</p>



<p>Swell has noted that the project’s liquid restaked token (LRT), rswETH, will be the chain’s native gas currency. The chain’s governance token will be SWELL, which will oversee not only the new Swell layer-2 but also swETH and rswETH.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blockworks research analyst Brick <a href="https://app.blockworksresearch.com/research?author=brrr">notes</a> that launching a rollup will enable Swell to expand vertically across the value chain, offering native integration for the project’s LRT.</p>



<p>“Newer rollups often struggle with bootstrapping capital. In contrast, Swell’s ~$1.1 billion TVL positions the project better than most to kickstart activity on its new layer-2,” he said.</p>



<p>He adds that it is unlikely that Swell will be the only LRT provider to launch a rollup, noting that many of these solutions will likely utilize similar plug-and-play solutions, converging from a design perspective.</p>



<p>This sentiment is shared by Blockworks research analyst Ren Yu Kong, who <a href="https://app.blockworksresearch.com/research?author=ren">notes</a> that Swell’s move is similar to that of <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/blast">Blast</a> earlier last year.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/3-years-launch-eth-staking">Blast from the past: 3 years on from the launch of ETH staking</a></p>



<p>“Just like how Blast kickstarted the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blur-blends-defi-nfts">idea of a layer-2 with yield bearing assets</a> from native staking on ETH, it was only a matter of time before a project would choose to do the same with restaking given the extra yield available,” Kong said.<br><br>He acknowledged that building a restaked rollup will enable Swell to launch more products that are feature specific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Building a restaked rollup allows the rollup to launch more ‘feature-rich’, with Swell planning services [like] decentralized sequencing and faster finality, which we expect more rollups, whether restaked or not, to include over the long term,” Kong said.</p>



<p><em>Updated March 14, 2024 at 9:43 am ET: Clarified use of rswETH and swETH.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bessie Liu</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/bessieliu</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T15:51:37.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blast stopped producing blocks following Ethereum’s Dencun upgrade]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/blast-pauses-block-production</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-pauses-block-production"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T15:35:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blast said the issue has since been resolved]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Following Ethereum’s Dencun upgrade, the Blast Mainnet stopped producing blocks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Around an hour after the last block was produced, Blast said that the issue was resolved in a post on X.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“A full analysis on the issue will be shared shortly,” the team said in the post.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Update: the issue has been resolved.<br><br>A full analysis on the issue will be shared shortly. <a href="https://t.co/Ggw05W3g3b">https://t.co/Ggw05W3g3b</a></p>— Blast (@Blast_L2) <a href="https://twitter.com/Blast_L2/status/1767933586487890427?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>“The Blast Mainnet has stopped producing blocks due to issues related to Ethereum’s Dencun upgrade,” Blast said in a post on X. “Core engineering contributors are working on a fix. We’ll share an update and post-mortem once the fix is live…”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Blast Mainnet has stopped producing blocks due to issues related to Ethereum’s Dencun upgrade. <br><br>Core engineering contributors are working on a fix. We’ll share an update and post-mortem once the fix is live (eta 30-60 min).</p>— Blast (@Blast_L2) <a href="https://twitter.com/Blast_L2/status/1767924021872455902?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Ethereum’s Dencun <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-dencun-upgrade-mainnet">upgrade went live early Tuesday</a>, marking the network’s largest upgrade to date.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blastscan.io/">According</a> to Blast Scan, blocks stopped publishing around 10 am ET.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-developers-layer-2-liquidity">Blast developers drawn by layer-2’s liquidity and founder’s success building Blur</a></p>



<p>The “[layer-2] with native yield” drew criticism for initially soliciting deposits to a multisig wallet. All told, it saw <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-optimistic-rollup-launch">$2.3 billion in deposits</a> before its layer-2 went live. The layer-2, which went to mainnet in late February, is a fork of <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/optimism">Optimism</a>. As of Wednesday morning, Blast had <a href="https://defillama.com/chains/Rollup">surpassed</a> Optimism as the second-largest Ethereum rollup by total value locked (<a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/tvl">TVL</a>), according to DeFiLlama. The 51 protocols built on Blast cumulatively <a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Blast">held</a> over $1 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Optimism itself <a href="https://optimistic.etherscan.io/">continued</a> producing blocks through the Dencun upgrade.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/blast">Blast</a> said over 3,000 projects entered its developer contest to go live upon the layer-2’s mainnet launch and receive a larger <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/airdrop">airdrop</a> allocation. Developers on Blast told Blockworks they were drawn to the rollup’s deep liquidity and its founder’s previous success building the NFT marketplace Blur.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Jack Kubinec</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/jack-kubinec</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T15:35:42.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stack ‘points chain’ layer-3 aims to bring loyalty points to Base]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/layer-3-loyalty-points-base</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/layer-3-loyalty-points-base"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T14:34:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Layer-3s are helpful for attestations but not as much for DeFi, Stack said in a blog post]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Stack went to mainnet Monday as a so-called points chain, built as a layer-3 on top of Base.</p>



<p>DeFi projects have lately been incentivizing usage on their platforms through “points,” or participation tallies that determine allocation in a future token airdrop.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Crypto is adjusting to points mania. Users are gaining leveraged exposure to points on Pendle and trading points on Whales Market. DeFi-focused hedge funds are accumulating currently-valueless points on behalf of liquidity providers.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/defi-points-farming-crypto-investments">DeFi ‘points’ farming has reshaped the crypto investment landscape</a></p>



<p>But these points tend to live off-chain. Backed by fresh funding from investors including Archetype Ventures, Balaji Srinivasan and Farcaster co-founder Dan Romero, Stack hopes to turn points systems into an on-chain primitive. The project was founded by Graeme Boy, who previously co-founded the decentralized publishing platform Mirror.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stack is intentionally limited in scope. In a Telegram message, Boy said points cannot be natively traded on Stack. In Boy’s view, this holds with Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin’s vision for soulbound tokens — <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2022/01/26/soulbound.html">essentially</a> non-transferable <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/nfts">NFTs</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stack is built as a layer-3 blockchain, meaning its points attestation data rolls up to Base’s <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/layer-2-2">layer-2</a> blockchain, which in turn rolls up to Ethereum. Layer-3s “may not necessarily provide a secure solution” for DeFi, Stack said in a blog post, but they inexpensively reap the benefits of blockchain transparency. Gas fees are low on layer-3s, since data is doubly compressed before being sent to Ethereum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As token <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/airdrop">airdrops</a> become an increasingly popular means of bootstrapping projects, Stack’s boosters hope on-chain points attestations will become table stakes in crypto.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/solana-defi-new-users">‘Blast radius’ of new users joining Solana DeFi for the points, liquidity is ‘snowballing’</a></p>



<p>“Orchestrating airdrops historically is extremely labor and cost-intensive, [but] by shifting the focus to points and putting them on a [layer-3], you drastically reduce the overhead in both cases while maintaining blockchain auditability,” Katie Chiou, principal at Stack investor Archetype Ventures, told Blockworks.</p>



<p>Points managed on Stack are not meant to be traded on open markets. However, points program managers could decide to make the points exchangeable, according to Stack’s product marketing manager Bradley Freeman. He said this could look similar to American Express’ program, where points can be converted into Delta Skymiles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blockchain’s usefulness for customer rewards programs isn’t a new idea. Singapore Airlines <a href="https://www.singaporeair.com/en_UK/es/media-centre/press-release/article/?q=en_UK/2018/January-March/ne0518-180205">began</a> using a private blockchain for frequent flier miles in 2018. Starbucks is still beta testing its NFT rewards program.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/lufthansa-polygon-nft-rewards">Lufthansa to offer NFT rewards program</a></p>



<p>So far, blockchain points programs have largely remained fringe initiatives. Not everyone is convinced of the need for a points chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I cannot fathom a reason why this is necessary. Points are [ERC-20] tokens without a transfer option,” an X user <a href="https://x.com/0xBuilderBob/status/1767333820909383945?s=20">wrote</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stack pitched its points chain idea to investors at the Coinbase Ventures Summit in Malibu in October 2023, the project said. Last week, it <a href="https://x.com/archetypevc/status/1764698380050002024?s=20">announced</a> a $3 million seed round. The project also drew plaudits from Jesse Pollak, the founder of <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/base">Base</a>.</p>



<p>“Everything is going to move [on-chain] — points included. This is because [on-chain], [developers] can build faster, reach more users and embody the open, transparent values of the [on-chain] economy,” Pollak said in a text.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jack Kubinec</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/jack-kubinec</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T14:34:21.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The biggest Ethereum upgrade ever goes live]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-dencun-upgrade-mainnet</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-dencun-upgrade-mainnet"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T14:15:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The Dencun hard fork hits Ethereum mainnet, the most significant upgrade since the Merge]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The long-awaited Dencun upgrade activated on Ethereum mainnet Wednesday at approximately 9:55 am ET — or the start of epoch 269568 if you’re following on-chain.</p>



<p>A scalability-focused upgrade, Dencun features EIP-4844 or Proto-Danksharding which carves out a dedicated data channel on Ethereum for layer-2 data, dramatically reducing the transaction fees on rollups.</p>



<p>But that’s not all. Dencun ships a <a href="https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-7569">total of 9</a> Ethereum Improvement Proposals (EIPs) in all, making it <a href="https://x.com/TimBeiko/status/1767925688001241515?s=20">tied</a> for the largest single hard fork in terms of improvements shipped, according to Tim Beiko, who coordinates the Ethereum core developer calls, on the Ethereum Foundation <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iL0cZRkyrV0">livestream</a> commemorating the event.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-improvement-proposals-2024">Ethereum Improvement Proposals to watch in 2024</a></p>



<p>Post-Dencun, most rollups and their users will see benefits within hours to days, as the availability of data blobs on Ethereum — introduced by EIP-4844 — should slash transaction fees by 5-10x.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" srcset="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-5.png?w=680 680w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-5.png?w=300 300w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-5.png?w=414 414w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-5.png?w=421 421w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-5.png?w=353 353w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-5.png?w=80 80w" class="wp-image-82416" alt="" src="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-5.png" height="422" width="680" decoding="async" loading="lazy"></figure>



<p>This real-world benefit to users is primarily driving anticipation for the upgrade, according to Hannes Graah, a builder of crypto wallet Zeal.</p>



<p>“The Dencun upgrade brings us closer to a future where fees are an afterthought, not a dealbreaker,” Graah told Blockworks. “Just as we generally don’t worry about the cost of traditional domestic bank transfers, Web3 users should be able to transact without worrying about fees.”</p>



<p>Aki Balogh, co-founder and CEO of DLC.Link, likens EIP-4844 to the “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NoSQL">NoSQL</a> movement of the 2010s,” which removed constraints of structured SQL data, through developments like MongoDB.</p>



<p>“Giving developers large blobs of temporary data (deleted after 30 days) provides them the opportunity to innovate while not increasing load on the network,” Balogh told Blockworks, removing a major Ethereum bottleneck. “Similar to Mongo’s effect, this proposal will help innovation as dApps and chains find new ways to use the temp storage space,” he said.</p>



<p>In contrast to scaling in Web2, this new data storage channel for Ethereum doesn’t sacrifice decentralization, notes Philippe Schommers, head of infrastructure at Gnosis, which implemented Dencun already on Monday.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/gnosis-chain-ethereum-dencun-hard-fork">Gnosis Chain premieres Ethereum’s Dencun hard fork</a></p>



<p>“When working towards scalability solutions on the blockchain, there are choices that developers have to make to prioritize decentralization,” Schommers told Blockworks. “When you look at Web2 infrastructure, it’s easy to see how centralized scalability can be done, but that’s not the path we’re trying to follow.”</p>



<p>While “less glamorous” Schommers said, it was part of Ethereum’s “big ambition,” calling Dencun “one piece of the puzzle that gets us a little bit closer to building a larger scale, fully decentralized network.”</p>



<p>Others are more effusive.</p>



<p>Lucas Henning, chief technology officer of Suku, says it’s still early days and the upgrade “will guide the Ethereum ecosystem towards a more sustainable future.”</p>



<p>“It’s an exciting time for Ethereum, and I am keen to see the effects of these changes on the decentralized world landscape,” Henning said.</p>



<p>“It’s the moment we’ve been waiting for,” said Eli Ben-Sasson, president of StarkWare. “Today will go down as the date of birth for a dapp-for-everything culture.”</p>



<p><em>Updated March 13, 2024 at 11:30 am ET, clarifying Dencun is equal to one earlier fork for the most number of EIPs included.</em></p>



<p><em>Correction March 13, 2024 at 1:40 pm ET: Misattribution of one quote.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Macauley Peterson</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/macauleypeterson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T14:15:48.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">
            <![CDATA[Judge orders former Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao to ‘surrender’ Canadian passport]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/binance-changpeng-zhao-surrenders-passport</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-changpeng-zhao-surrenders-passport"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T14:02:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[A judge in Washington modified the former Binance CEO’s bond on Monday]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>US District Judge Richard Jones modified former Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao’s bond ahead of sentencing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Zhao — a Canadian citizen — was ordered to surrender his Canadian passport to a third-party custodian employed by his lawyers. He isn’t able to apply for new passports or travel documents either.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The third-party custodian must retain control over that Canadian passport and must accompany Defendant on any travel that requires identification documents,” the Monday filing said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, Zhao must also remain in the continental US and must inform “Pretrial Services” before any travel.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-changpeng-zhao-deal-unpacked">Here are the details of Binance and Changpeng Zhao’s plea deal</a></p>



<p>The US government <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/changpeng-zhao-bond-sentencing">sought to modify the bond earlier this year</a>, arguing that the original bond expectations were set when the prosecutors believed that Zhao would be returning to the United Arab Emirates, which is his primary residence with his family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Late last year, Zhao <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-cz-in-usa-until-sentencing">pushed to be allowed to go back to the UAE</a>. However, a judge ordered him to stay in the US. This decision was made in part because the US does not have an extradition treaty with the UAE.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The former executive’s legal team initially objected to the government’s request, but prosecutors further argued that the requests were “commonsense” requirements.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/changpeng-zhao">Zhao</a> is set to be <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/binance-changpeng-zhao-sentencing-delay">sentenced on April 30</a> after the initial sentencing date was delayed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Late last year, a handful of US government agencies <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/doj-announcing-crypto-actions">announced that they had taken action</a> against <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/binance">Binance</a> and its former CEO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As part of the Department of Justice settlement, Zhao agreed to a plea deal and resigned as the chief executive. Binance agreed to pay a multi-billion dollar fine as well.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T14:02:39.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TRON Network integrated with Token Terminal]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/tron-network-integrated-with-token-terminal</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/tron-network-integrated-with-token-terminal"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T13:34:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Token Terminal’s Data Partnership is a comprehensive on-chain data analytics service for L1s, L2s, and app-chains]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>TRON DAO has collaborated with Token Terminal, integrating the TRON network’s data into Token Terminal’s sophisticated suite of data analytics tools. This collaboration promises to transform the way investors and analysts access and leverage TRON’s data.</p>



<p>Token Terminal’s <a href="https://tokenterminal.com/data-partnership">Data Partnership</a> is a comprehensive on-chain data analytics service for L1s, L2s, and app-chains. It involves running nodes for a partner’s chain, making its data available in raw, decoded, and standardized formats across Token Terminal’s platforms and products, including the <a href="https://tokenterminal.com/product/pro">Terminal Pro</a>, <a href="https://tokenterminal.com/product/api">API</a>, and <a href="https://tokenterminal.com/product/data-room">Data Room</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, the partnership extends to cover qualitative aspects of the TRON network, including detailed research articles and regular podcast updates, enriching the data with deeper, contextual insights into the network.</p>



<p>Oskari Tempakka, Head of Growth at Token Terminal, commented on the increasing demand for TRON network data: “At Token Terminal, we’ve observed a growing interest towards TRON among our institutional clients. The TRON network consistently ranks at the top for on-chain user activity, and holds a dominant lead in stablecoin transactions across all of crypto. We’re excited to offer our users the ability to delve deeper into the on-chain activity that’s driving TRON network’s growth and adoption.”</p>



<p>With the integration of TRON network’s data into Token Terminal, users gain access to a wide array of powerful data analytics tools. Key features include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Standardized financial and alternative metrics: </strong>Conduct in-depth due diligence through the analysis of key financial and alternative metrics on the TRON network.</li>



<li><strong>Comparative performance analysis: </strong>Compare TRON’s performance against other blockchain projects, to gain valuable insights about the network’s positioning.</li>



<li><strong>Trending contracts</strong>: Analyze the top 1,000 trending contracts on TRON to uncover insights about the most dominant market sectors, projects, and smart contracts in the ecosystem.</li>



<li><strong>Trending wallets: </strong>Track trending wallets on TRON to better understand the type of accounts that drive usage on the network.</li>



<li><strong>User retention</strong>: Easily assess TRON network’s user retention rates and benchmark them against other major blockchains.</li>



<li><strong>Stablecoins: </strong>Analyze<strong> </strong>key stablecoin statistics across the TRON network and compare it among other major blockchains.</li>
</ul>



<p>Dave Uhryniak, Ecosystem Lead at TRON DAO, commented on the integration, “This collaboration with Token Terminal marks a significant step in elevating TRON’s visibility and accessibility. The comprehensive data analytics provided by Token Terminal will enable a deeper understanding of TRON’s network and its strategic position in the blockchain industry. We are excited to see how this integration will enhance TRON’s engagement with the broader crypto community and contribute to our network’s growth.”</p>



<p>With this partnership, TRON network’s data is now also accessible through Token Terminal’s ‘<a href="https://tokenterminal.com/resources/articles/crypto-fundamentals-bloomberg-launch">Crypto Fundamentals</a>’ application on the Bloomberg Terminal App Portal.</p>



<p>In addition, Tronix (TRX), the native utility token of the TRON network, is eligible to be included in the <a href="https://www.marketvector.com/indexes/digital-assets/MarketVector-Token-Terminal-Fundamental">MarketVector™ Token Terminal Fundamental Index Suite</a> – a first-of-its-kind fundamentally-weighted basket of crypto assets that offers investors exposure to multi-token baskets, weighted based on economic traction.</p>



<p>For additional details on this partnership, and to explore the range of data products offered by Token Terminal, please visit tokenterminal.com.</p>



<p><em>This content is sponsored by TRON and does not serve as an endorsement by Blockworks. The veracity of this content has not been verified and should not serve as financial advice. We encourage readers to conduct their own research before making financial decisions. &nbsp;</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <category label="Sponsored" term="Sponsored"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T13:34:52.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blockchain has lost its decentralized spirit]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/blockchain-lost-decentralized-spirit</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/blockchain-lost-decentralized-spirit"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T13:19:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Decentralization must be the cornerstone, not a mere aspiration, of blockchain’s journey]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>A narrative has taken root in the realm of blockchain technology, one that champions the gradual transition from centralized control to a decentralized future. Yet this story, often recited by those at the helm, overlooks a fundamental truth about power: <em>Once seized, it is rarely surrendered without a struggle.</em>&nbsp;</p>



<p>This belief that a centralized beginning can smoothly transition to a decentralized ethos is more myth than reality, akin to convincing a child to relinquish their tight grasp on a coveted sweet. The intention here isn’t to cast venture capitalists or early stakeholders as adversaries — it’s to advocate for a balance, for fairness that underpins the very foundation of blockchain.</p>



<p>I often hear, “We will start out centralized, and we will become more decentralized later.” But I believe this is nonsense!&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the hardest things to give up is power. This notion is vividly illustrated by the French Revolution, a historical event that epitomizes the struggle to redistribute power from an entrenched monarchy to a democratic governance structure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite the promise of liberty, equality and fraternity, the revolution faced immense resistance from those unwilling to cede control, leading to a turbulent period of conflict and transformation. This historical episode serves as a poignant reminder that once power is acquired, relinquishing it is a far more formidable challenge than many anticipate.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The illusion of control</h2>



<p>As blockchain ventures flourish, the grip of those in control tightens, with early investors and builders basking in the success their influence has wrought.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Conversely, during tumultuous times, these same figures embark on campaigns of reassurance, painting over cracks while strategically planning their exits. This stark duality reveals a profound flaw in the prevalent “centralize now, decentralize later” mantra, significantly underestimating the seductive allure of power and the inherent challenges in relinquishing it once established.</p>



<p>The promise of distributed authority is at the heart of the blockchain revolution. The reimagining of governance where innovation serves not just the circulation of capital, but empowers and amplifies a multitude of voices (not just those traditionally heard in the corridors of wealth). Yet, a troubling reality overshadows this ideal: A staggering concentration of over <a href="https://research.ark-invest.com/hubfs/1_Download_Files_ARK-Invest/Big_Ideas/ARK%20Invest_Presentation_Big%20Ideas%202023_FINAL_V2.pdf">80% of blockchain assets in the hands of a mere 1% of wallets</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Regardless of whether these assets make up projects that aim to fully decentralize or not, the fact of the matter is that early stakeholders and VCs often hold the largest piece of the pie for new blockchains simply because they come in first, when it’s riskiest.</p>



<p>This imbalance transcends mere issues of fairness, striking at the very viability of blockchains as engines of innovation and inclusivity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s a travesty that the vast majority of value creation does not come from this 1%, underscoring a critical disconnect. Those who contribute the most to the ecosystem often have the least say in its direction and the smallest share in its success — those early VCs holding all the tokens do provide impact with their initial investments, but their participation usually stops there. And because the protocol’s governance is based on the ownership of the token, the new builders don’t have the weight to make major decisions by the major token holders.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more from our opinion section: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/the-worst-kind-of-decentralization-is-none-at-all">The worst kind of decentralization is none at all</a></p>



<p>This stark discrepancy isn’t just unfair; it’s fundamentally counterproductive, eroding the incentive for innovators, developers and community members to pour their energy and creativity into the ecosystem.</p>



<p>By sidelining the very individuals who are the lifeblood of innovation, blockchain ecosystems risk stagnating, as the centralized accumulation of benefits stifles the diverse input and collaboration essential for breakthroughs and resilience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Such a structure threatens the long-term sustainability and incentive for valuable contributors to remain engaged and invested in these projects. The long-term viability of blockchain technology depends on its ability to foster a genuinely inclusive environment where contributions are recognized and rewarded appropriately, ensuring that all participants have a stake in the ecosystem’s success.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">It’s time to start again</h2>



<p>Where do we go from here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe that many of the first-generation blockchains, the foundational layers that have been the bedrock of the industry, have veered too far off course. Their structures have solidified around centralization to a point where a return to true decentralization might no longer be feasible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This isn’t to say they’re doomed for failure; far from it. The potential of blockchain technology is vast, its future inherently multichain, promising a landscape rich with diverse and interconnected networks.</p>



<p>However, we need to start afresh if we want to harness this potential fully. This proposition might seem daunting, yet considering the broader timeline of technological evolution, we’re still in the nascent stages of blockchain development.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The beauty of this space is its foundation in open source principles. Almost all blockchain technologies are open to being studied, modified and repurposed. This openness paves the way for new projects to emerge — i.e, reboots of existing chains, each carrying a distinct mission and fostering a unique culture.</p>



<p>Embarking on this path isn’t merely about technological innovation; it’s about reimagining the ethos that guides blockchain development. By initiating new projects with decentralization as a core principle, we stand a chance to correct the course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This approach doesn’t merely replicate what came before, but builds upon it, learning from past missteps to create blockchains that are truly from the people, by the people and for the people.</p>



<p>To visualize the potential paths of blockchain, consider two atomic reactions: fusion and fission. A blockchain driven by a diverse, invested community is akin to a fusion reactor. It’s efficient, sustainable and produces a continuous outflow of energy. This model represents a decentralized ecosystem where power and rewards are evenly spread, fostering innovation and participation from all stakeholders. The result is a robust and vibrant network, capable of long-term growth and adaptation.</p>



<p>In contrast, a network dominated by a few mirrors the principles of a fission bomb: initially powerful, but ultimately leading to destruction. This reflects a centralized blockchain ecosystem, where concentrated power leads to rapid gains that are not sustainable over time. Such a structure can stifle innovation and lead to a fragile system, prone to collapse.</p>



<p>This analogy underlines the crucial choice blockchain faces between sustainable growth and short-term gains, emphasizing the need for a decentralized approach to ensure the technology’s long-term viability and success.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Decentralization as a starting point, not just a distant dream</h2>



<p>Decentralization must be the cornerstone, not a mere aspiration, of blockchain’s journey. It’s about democratizing power, fostering a community where everyone’s voice matters and every contribution is valued from the outset.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At this pivotal juncture, the trajectory of blockchain hinges on our resolve to anchor it in decentralization from the very beginning. By prioritizing decentralization as our foundational principle, we chart a course toward a future where blockchain serves as a bedrock for equitable growth and democratic engagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s seize this opportunity to redefine the landscape, ensuring blockchain remains a tool for empowering the many, not just the few. In doing so, we not only realize the full potential of blockchain technology but also contribute to the creation of a fairer, more inclusive world.</p>



<p>This is not just the path to technological innovation, but a step towards a more equitable and collaborative ecosystem.</p>



<p>We are still early.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">


<div class="wp-block-post-author-biography">Chris Swenor is a seasoned entrepreneur and blockchain pioneer with a 20-year career that kicked off as a self-taught programmer at age 13. He swiftly moved from corporate roles into startups, leading several to successful acquisitions. Chris started venturing into blockchain and cryptocurrency in 2013, founding Reach in 2019, a platform that has since attracted over $13M in funding and onboarded more than 8,000 developers.

In recent years, Chris founded Humble, a decentralized exchange on Algorand, and Alloy, a blockchain gaming platform acquired in 2023. He is currently working on Voi Network, a layer 1 blockchain empowering its community with user-centric governance and economics. </div>


<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Swenor</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/chris-swenor</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Op-Ed" term="Op-Ed"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T13:19:17.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheatsheet: MicroStrategy has now outperformed Nvidia this year]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-microstrategy-outperformed-nvidia</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-microstrategy-outperformed-nvidia"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T12:19:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[DeFi users seem to suffer from itchy palms ahead of an anticipated run for ether to record highs]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is Cheatsheet, a primer on what’s happening in crypto today.</em></p>



<p>Bitcoin just set another all-time high above $73,000, but It’s looking a lot like altcoin season.</p>



<p>That’s not to be confused with memecoin season: Multiple cryptocurrencies for various layer-1 networks have finally outperformed the dog tokens across multiple days.</p>



<p>Toncoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/ton">TON</a>) has extended its rally for a third day, again the star performer of the top 100 after gaining nearly 21% — now up by nearly two-thirds over the past week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>TON is now the 13th largest cryptocurrency by market cap, ahead of polygon (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/matic">MATIC</a>), chainlink (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/link">LINK</a>) and tron (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/trx">TRX</a>). TON-powered trading bot BananaGun continues to burn more ETH than layer-2 Arbitrum and MetaMask, which signals higher on-chain activity.</p>



<p>THORChain (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/rune">RUNE</a>) has the rest beaten for weekly gains, however, after a 16.4% rally in the past day and has now more than doubled in seven days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The network is built as a liquidity network for powering cross-chain token swaps. THORChain daily volume hit an all-time high yesterday of $639.6 million.</p>



<p>Bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>) is meanwhile up 1.5% and ether (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/eth">ETH</a>) is about flat and still 17% below its own price record, changing hands for $4,050 as of 7:45 am ET.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On-chain mail</h2>



<p>Rising prices have DeFi’s total value locked (TVL) metric posturing to reclaim levels not seen since the Great Terra Implosion of 2022, now more than $104 billion. But dollar bias beware.</p>



<ul>
<li>Ethereum’s apps have felt slight net ETH <a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Ethereum">outflows</a> over the past month, losing about 80,000 ETH ($324.3 million).</li>



<li>Layer-2s Arbitrum and Optimism have lost almost 15% of their ETH over the same period (nearly 205,000 ETH worth $830.5 million).</li>



<li>Maker, the collateralized debt protocol behind DAI, has 25% less ether after losing about 770,000 ETH ($3.11 billion). Its dollar-denominated TVL is still up 15%.</li>
</ul>



<p>The Maker situation, perhaps the result of rising popularity for liquid staking and restaking, has led to rate hikes and an “accelerated proposal” to <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerDAO/status/1766177247868621229">prepare</a> the protocol to meet anticipated demand for DAI with fewer deposits. Tron, Binance Smart Chain, Polygon and Avalanche apps have also seen net outflows denominated in native tokens, per DeFiLlama.</p>



<p>But not all networks are seeing the same trend. Solana apps now have more than 27% more SOL than this time last month — the equivalent of 4.81 million SOL ($731.6 million) — even as the price of SOL swelled 45%.</p>



<p>Solana derivatives DEX Jupiter and Parcl, a platform to gain leveraged exposure to real estate assets, have pulled in much of that SOL. Tron and Sui apps have also attracted more native tokens over the past 30 days.</p>



<p><strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/jito-labs-suspends-mempool-functionality">Jito Labs ends mempool functionality citing impact on Solana users</a></p>



<ul>
<li>Ethereum’s degen-optimized layer-2 Blast is jostling to flip Optimism for TVL, both about $1.06 billion.</li>



<li>That would make <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-developers-layer-2-liquidity">Blast the second-biggest Ethereum layer-2 after Arbitrum</a>, which has more than three times the TVL.</li>



<li>Blast lending app Orbit is the fastest growing DeFi app with more than $100 million TVL over the past week, popping from $88 million to $430.9 million.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" srcset="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=1600 1600w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=300 300w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=1024 1024w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=768 768w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=1536 1536w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=428 428w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=470 470w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=389 389w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png?w=80 80w" class="wp-image-82379" alt="" src="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-4.png" height="603" width="1600" decoding="async" loading="lazy"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>MakerDAO’s ETH deposits have trended downward all year (</em><a href="https://defillama.com/protocol/maker?denomination=ETH"><em>source</em></a><em>)</em></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crypto business</h2>



<p>A rarity in recent weeks: MicroStrategy wasn’t the best performing crypto-related stock over the past day, even with its 12.65% rally spread before and after the bell as of 7 am ET.</p>



<ul>
<li>Las Vegas-based bitcoin mining stock Gryphon Digital led with almost 16% gains (13.4% in the day session and 2.25% pre-market).</li>



<li>Markets barely reacted to Coinbase’s $1 billion convertible note offering, with COIN set to open 0.5% higher.</li>



<li>Ohio-based miner Griid lost almost 7%, followed by Core Scientific, which altogether shed 5.7% between the day and pre-market sessions, dragged by lackluster earnings.</li>
</ul>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/coinbase">Coinbase</a>’s move to raise cash with convertible notes (a hybrid of debt and equity) may also raise eyebrows. The firm, by far the largest crypto stock on the market, already had more than $200 billion in <a href="https://www.macrotrends.net/stocks/charts/COIN/coinbase-global/total-liabilities">liabilities</a> as of the end of last year — up from $15 billion in 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(For scale, Apple, valued at more than 40 times Coinbase, has $279.4 billion liabilities, while Intel has $81 billion.)</p>



<p>COIN’s long-term debt has meanwhile declined 12% year on year, now around $3 billion with $5.7 billion cash on hand.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-convertible-notes-offering">Coinbase announces offering of $1B in convertible notes</a></p>



<ul>
<li>If CleanSpark loses more ground, Coinbase and <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/microstrategy">MicroStrategy</a> will be the only crypto stocks to beat the S&amp;P 500 over the past month.</li>



<li>MicroStrategy has now outperformed the buzzy Nvidia over the year to date — 133% to 91%.</li>



<li>Tesla and Block are now up more than 100% on their bitcoin <a href="https://bitcointreasuries.net/">buys</a> to date, joining MicroStrategy.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On the ground</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">So many bad Maker takes the last few days in reaction to the massive rate hike<br><br>The right one would be along the lines of<br><br>"Maker emergency yanks all lending as they run out of customer deposits"<br><br>In practice it's even worse than that since active borrowers are also affected…</p>— Hasu⚡️🤖 (@hasufl) <a href="https://twitter.com/hasufl/status/1767821908655874062?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Summer is coming</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">2/7: OEV exploits the inherent delay in blockchain oracles updating asset prices. This creates opportunities for those quick on the draw to profit from these moments before the wider market catches up</p>— IOSG Intern (@IOSG_Intern) <a href="https://twitter.com/IOSG_Intern/status/1767761203387117900?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Move over MEV, it’s oracles’ turn to be wrung out for yield</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">May you Blob cheaply, securely for eons, <a href="https://twitter.com/ethereum?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ethereum</a> <a href="https://t.co/RKzggcwDYV">pic.twitter.com/RKzggcwDYV</a></p>— Eli Ben-Sasson (@EliBenSasson) <a href="https://twitter.com/EliBenSasson/status/1767869045733306675?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Happy Dencun day for the blobs who celebrate</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><em>Macauley Peterson contributed reporting.</em></p>



<p><em>Updated Mar. 13, 2024 at 8:45 am ET: Corrected year referenced for Coinbase liabilities.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Canellis</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/david-canellis</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Web3" term="Web3"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T12:19:23.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin price rally sparks record ETF inflows of over $1B]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-inflows-price-rally</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-inflows-price-rally"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T11:36:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Assets under management within BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT) stands at about $15 billion following fund’s record day]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The 10 US spot bitcoin ETFs collectively shattered their daily net inflow record Tuesday as more than $1 billion of investor assets entered the funds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>BlackRock’s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT) was again <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blackrock-bitcoin-etf-battle">the category standout</a>, notching an all-time high daily inflow total of $849 million, according to BitMEX Research data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Ark 21Shares Bitcoin ETF (ARKB) and the VanEck Bitcoin Trust contributed above-average flows of $93 million and $83 million, respectively.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">[1/4] Bitcoin ETF Flow – 12 March 2024<br><br>All data in. Record day with over $1 billion of net inflow. Blackrock with a record $849 million of inflow <a href="https://t.co/dKFmM3Qvaa">pic.twitter.com/dKFmM3Qvaa</a></p>— BitMEX Research (@BitMEXResearch) <a href="https://twitter.com/BitMEXResearch/status/1767807895645634867?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>The boost for VanEck’s product comes after the company <a href="https://twitter.com/vaneck_us/status/1767227350108794991">said</a> it would waive its 0.20% sponsor fee on the first $1.5 billion of fund assets until March 31, 2025.</p>



<p>Grayscale Investments’ Bitcoin Trust ETF (GBTC), which has bled more than $11.1 billion in assets since converting to an ETF on Jan. 11, saw just $79 million of outflows Tuesday. That outflow total was down from $494 million the day prior.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-snapshot-inflows-near-high">Bitcoin ETF snapshot: GBTC competitors surpass Grayscale fund in AUM</a></p>



<p>The $1 billion of net inflows across the 10 bitcoin funds easily surpassed the segment’s previous daily record of $673 million, set on Feb. 28, BitMEX data shows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ETF flow spike came as bitcoin’s price has continued its climb, setting multiple new all-time highs over the past eight days.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>BTC’s price stood at about $73,300 at 7 a.m. ET on Wednesday — up about 15% from a week ago. The asset’s price had risen above $73,600 a few hours prior, marking a new record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The assets under management in BlackRock’s IBIT rose above $15 billion at market close Tuesday — behind only GBTC, which has roughly $27.7 billion of assets.</p>



<p>The Fidelity Wise Origin Bitcoin Fund (FBTC) is the group’s third-largest fund, managing about $9.2 billion in assets.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tuesday marked the second-best trading volume day for the 10 US spot bitcoin ETFs, according to Bloomberg Intelligence <a href="https://twitter.com/EricBalchunas/status/1767657812920766486">data</a> — as investors traded roughly $8.5 billion worth of the funds’ shares.&nbsp;</p>



<p>IBIT’s trading volumes on Tuesday represented nearly half of those across the segment, at about $4 billion.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Markets" term="Markets"/>
        <published>2024-03-13T11:36:24.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coinbase announces offering of $1B in convertible notes]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-convertible-notes-offering</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-convertible-notes-offering"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T21:47:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The stock jumped 18% in the past week after bitcoin notched new all-time highs and US bitcoin ETFs continued to beat records]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Coinbase announced a proposed offering of $1 billion in convertible notes on Tuesday.</p>



<p>The notes would mature in 2030, according to the company, and would be offered to institutional investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Coinbase also expects to grant the initial purchasers of the notes a 30-day option to purchase up to an additional $150 million principal amount of notes solely to cover over-allotments,” the company <a href="https://investor.coinbase.com/news/news-details/2024/Coinbase-Announces-Proposed-Private-Offering-of-1.0-Billion-of-Convertible-Senior-Notes-Due-2030/default.aspx">said</a>. The company will elect to convert the notes into cash, shares of Class A stock or a combination.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The crypto exchange will use the proceeds from the offering for “general corporate purposes” and will also use the funds to pay or repurchase 0.50% convertible senior notes due 2026, 3.375% senior notes due in 2028 and 3.625% senior notes due in 2031.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-appeals-sec-rulemaking-petition">Coinbase moves forward with appeal of SEC’s rulemaking petition denial&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>“<a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/coinbase">Coinbase</a> may also use a portion of the net proceeds to make investments in and acquisitions of other companies, products or technologies that Coinbase may identify from time to time,” the press release added.</p>



<p>The stock was down around 2.5% after hours to $249 a share or roughly $22 from its 52-week high.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Coinbase is up 308% in the past year, and up 82% in the past month alone.</p>



<p>The move follows a similar one from <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-convertible-note-sale">MicroStrategy earlier this month</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The company, co-founded by Michael Saylor, announced a $600 million private offering of convertible senior notes. Just days later, it <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-700m-convertible-note-bitcoin">upped the offering to $700 million</a>. It plans to use the proceeds for corporate purposes and will also use the funds to buy more bitcoin.</p>



<p>The stocks of both Coinbase and <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/microstrategy">MicroStrategy</a> were boosted not only by the record-breaking <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-snapshot-inflows-near-high">bitcoin ETFs</a> but also buoyed by bitcoin, which has carved out <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-sets-all-time-high-71000">new all-time highs multiple times over the past week</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T21:47:17.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is fully homomorphic encryption and how will it change blockchain?]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/what-is-fully-homomorphic-encryption</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/what-is-fully-homomorphic-encryption"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T20:43:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[FHE differs from zero-knowledge technology, as it can perform computation on top of encrypted data without revealing data points]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>In today’s digital world, the need to decrypt data for computational tasks exposes it to security risks.</p>



<p>This is a significant problem in privacy-sensitive sectors like Web3, where decentralized applications and finance at times rely on both confidentiality and integrity in data processing to maintain trust and security on chain.<br><br>Fully homomorphic encryption (FHE) offers a potential solution by enabling the processing of encrypted data without needing to decrypt it first, thus preserving confidentiality. This advancement not only enhances data <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/privacy">security and privacy</a>, but also extends the potential for secure data analysis and decentralized services.</p>



<p>Guy Itzhaki, CEO and co-founder of Fhenix, says that in the context of blockchain, FHE enables developers and users to control which assets they want to maintain privately and confidentially on-chain.</p>



<p>This means that it will enable developers to “create a new set of use cases,” and “unlock the way for true on-chain gaming, voting, and auctions,” Itzahki said.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/fhenix-homomorphic-encryption">Encryption startup Fhenix raises $7M for private computation</a></p>



<p>Although there are some similarities between FHE and zero-knowledge (zk) technology, the major difference is that FHE technology can perform computation on top of encrypted data without having to reveal or know the data points to obtain the end result.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Liam McDonald, head of growth at blockchain privacy startup Fairblock, explained that with <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/zero-knowledge-tech">zk technology</a>, a prover turns necessary data into a secure code called a polynomial commitment to show it’s accurate.</p>



<p>“In order to do this, the data itself is turned into polynomial hashes and is aggregated into a polynomial equation of the hashes that represents the encoded data,” McDonald told Blockworks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This equation is then sent to a verifier, who determines whether the function is true. If the function is proven, a proof is generated, confirming that the information inside is accurate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Peyman Momeni, co-founder of Fairblock, mentioned that while zk proofs allow users to validate ownership of data or correct computation, they fall short in supporting computations on encrypted data, especially when it involves merging private information from multiple users.</p>



<p>“Zk is more relevant for scalability with some degree of security and limited privacy applications like shielded transfers, where FHE unlocks wide range of applications coupled with higher levels of data security and privacy,” Momeni said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>FHE in practice</strong></h2>



<p>When combined with the benefits of the blockchain, FHE provides enhanced privacy, which is a core component that is missing in the existing blockchain ecosystem, said Kaal Dhairya, a Shiba Inu developer.</p>



<p>“Apart from true end-to-end encryption of data, this opens up a variety of use cases, including supply chain/food chain to blockchain, private voting for DAOs, efficient prediction markets, on-chain casino games, hidden items in on-chain games, and many more,” Dhairya said.</p>



<p>Momeni notes that in most crypto use cases, it is necessary to combine private inputs from multiple users, compute over them and decrypt the results, meaning that there would be a “shared private state.”</p>



<p>“As an example in private governance or sealed-bid auctions, all users encrypt their votes or bids, we perform on-chain computing over encrypted data, then in the end we need to decrypt the actual results,” he said. “In this case we don’t actually decrypt the individual bids/votes/trades, just the updated state or the result of computation.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/fhenix-whitepaper-fhe-rollups">Fully homomorphic encryption rollups are one step closer to reality</a></p>



<p>To ensure no single user has exclusive access, a system of multiple validators should share this decryption key, and decrypt the information collaboratively at the appropriate time.</p>



<p>According to Momeni, current FHE technologies face the technical hurdle of creating a decentralized system for managing these decryption keys. Fairblock, however, is developing a solution with a decentralized network for key generation, aiming to make FHE technology more accessible and practical for developers and various platforms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Different solutions for different privacy needs</strong></h2>



<p>It’s worth noting that FHE isn’t the only privacy solution being developed on the blockchain today; there are several other solutions that might be more beneficial for developers building different tools.</p>



<p>“There are different solutions with different trade-offs, so we’re trying to enable developers to use them correctly without passing a cryptography course,” Momeni said.</p>



<p><strong>Read more from our opinion section:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/privacy-crypto-mainstream-2024">Privacy is going mainstream</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the case of Fairblock, the company sees itself as being similar to Axelar, Eigenlayer, or Celestia, where a network facilitates and accelerates other builders.</p>



<p>“Instead of cross-chain messaging, shared security, and data availability, we’re abstracting away all of the bandwidth overhead, onboarding and maintenance costs of running the network in a secure and decentralized way,” he said.</p>



<p>The company recently rolled out its <a href="https://medium.com/@Fair_Block/fairblock-public-testnet-is-now-live-a487f97ea3e0">public testnet</a>, which is designed for developers of select layer-2 networks to tailor how they integrate encryption and decryption into applications. It currently enables users to leverage identity-based encryption (IBE), witness encryption (WE) with integration of fully homomorphic encryption still under development.</p>



<p><em>Updated March 13, 2024 at 9:52 am ET: Clarified example of sealed-bid auctions.</em></p>



<p><em>Updated March 13, 2024 at 9:13 am ET: Clarified relevance of zk for scalability</em>.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bessie Liu</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/bessieliu</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T20:43:26.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crypto mixer creator found guilty, lawyer to appeal verdict]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-fog-founder-convicted-by-jury</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-fog-founder-convicted-by-jury"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T20:25:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roman Sterlingov was originally arrested in 2021]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The founder of Bitcoin Fog, a crypto mixer, was convicted in a Washington DC court on Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The crypto mixer was operated by Sterlingov for roughly 10 years and used as a money laundering service, according to a press release from the Department of Justice. The agency further alleged that Bitcoin Fog moved 1.3 million bitcoin over the course of its operation, which was valued at around $400 million at the time. It was allegedly used by the Silk Road and Agora, amongst others.</p>



<p>Roman Sterlingov was found guilty of conspiracy, sting money laundering and operating an unlicensed money-transmitting business. His sentencing hearing is set for July 15, according to a press release from the DOJ.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-blockchain-association-fincen-mixers">Coinbase, Blockchain Association challenge FinCEN’s proposed mixer crackdown&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>“The bulk of that cryptocurrency came from darknet marketplaces and was tied to illegal narcotics, computer fraud and abuse activities, and identity theft,” the press release <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-dc/pr/jury-finds-russian-swedish-operator-bitcoin-fog-guilty-running-darknet-cryptocurrency">said</a>.</p>



<p>Sterlingov’s attorney, Tor Ekeland, <a href="https://twitter.com/TorEkelandPLLC/status/1767586997219021037">said</a> that the team will appeal the verdict.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Evidence presented at trial clearly showed that the defendant laundered hundreds of millions of illicit funds from the dark web through Bitcoin Fog in an attempt to conceal the origin of those funds,” said <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/irs">IRS</a> Criminal Investigation Chief Jim Lee.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sam-banmkan-fried-fraud-sentencing">&nbsp;Bankman-Fried’s legal team argues for leniency, citing philanthropy and character&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Sterlingov, a Russian-Swedish dual citizen, was <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/individual-arrested-and-charged-operating-notorious-darknet-cryptocurrency-mixer">arrested</a> in 2021 at a Los Angeles airport. He’s been detained since his arrest.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/doj">DOJ</a>, in the Tuesday press release, further claimed that Sterlingov made “millions in commissions from Bitcoin Fog transactions.”</p>



<p>Sterlingov’s verdict is the latest in a series of wins for the US government in crypto-related cases. The jury’s findings come just a few weeks before the co-founder of FTX, Sam Bankman-Fried, is set to appear before court for his sentencing.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/sam-bankman-fried">Bankman-Fried</a>’s sentencing is formally set to take place on March 28.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The former <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sam-bankman-fried-found-guilty">CEO was convicted following</a> a month-long trial in New York City at the end of last year. He’s currently seeking a sentence of less than seven years. He could, however, face a maximum sentence of 110 years.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T20:25:13.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After US bitcoin ETFs, the UK fights for retail to have the same freedom]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etfs-in-uk</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etfs-in-uk"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T20:06:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The success of bitcoin ETFs in the US has created pressure for the FCA to reconsider its stance, 21.co executive says]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The Financial Conduct Authority’s support for crypto products in the UK only went so far — and industry watchers are calling for retail customers to also have access to such offerings.</p>



<p>Allowing non-institutional investors to trade physically backed exchange traded notes (ETNs) would match similar strides made in the US and elsewhere, they noted.</p>



<p>The FCA updated its stance on crypto ETNs Monday, noting that it would not object to so-called recognized investment exchanges listing such offerings.</p>



<p>ETNs are debt securities that offer exposure to the underlying asset. Similar to bitcoin ETFs recently approved in the US, such products let investors trade securities that track their underlying crypto assets on-exchange during trading hours.</p>



<p>The FCA support for crypto ETNs was contingent on the products being available only to professional investors like investment firms and credit institutions, the regulator said in a Monday <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/news/statements/fca-updates-position-cryptoasset-exchange-traded-notes-professional-investors">statement</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Given the change, the London Stock Exchange said Monday it would start accepting applications for physically backed bitcoin and ether ETNs in the second quarter.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/london-stock-exchange-crypto-etn-proposals">London Stock Exchange to accept physically-backed crypto ETN proposals</a></p>



<p>While the FCA said it believes exchanges and professional investors can now better determine whether crypto ETNs meet their risk appetite, such products — and crypto derivatives — remain “ill-suited for retail consumers due to the harm they pose.”</p>



<p>An <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/fca">FCA</a> spokesperson declined to comment beyond the statement.</p>



<p>Tim Bevan, CEO of crypto product issuer ETC Group, said it is “disappointing” that retail investors would still be left out from trading crypto ETNs on regulated markets. There is no such restriction for opening a direct crypto account, he added.</p>



<p>“If UK regulations permitted retail investors to invest in crypto ETPs, via regulated markets, this would bring the UK in line with much of Europe and allow those retail investors to take advantage of the built-in security that established exchanges provide,” Bevan said in an email.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The FCA first <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/news/press-releases/fca-bans-sale-crypto-derivatives-retail-consumers#:~:text=The%20FCA%20has%20published%20final,to%20the%20harm%20they%20pose.">banned</a> the sale, marketing and distribution of crypto-focused derivatives and ETNs to retail consumers in January 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the crypto ecosystem has changed substantially since then from both a commercial and regulatory perspective, according to Laura Navaratnam, UK policy lead at the Crypto Council for Innovation (CCI).</p>



<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-approves-bitcoin-etf">approved spot bitcoin ETFs in the US</a> in January. Jacobi Asset Management <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/us-europe-spot-bitcoin-etf">launched the first bitcoin ETF in Europe</a> on the Euronext Amsterdam exchange last August — though crypto ETNs have existed around the continent for years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Given these changes, it makes sense that the ban [for] retail clients be reconsidered by the FCA,” Navaratnam told Blockworks. “CCI would welcome additional work on this as a priority given the timelines for the future broader regulatory regime for crypto assets are unknown.”</p>



<p>Mandy Chiu, head of financial product development at crypto asset manager 21.co, noted that the FCA’s cautious “phased approach” is likely a step toward retail access once the regulator can assess the impact within “a more informed participant base.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/uk-upcoming-staking-stablecoin-legislation">UK minister eyes stablecoin, staking legislation in next 6 months: Report</a></p>



<p>“We are very pleased to see the decision to accept crypto ETPs applications, but we believe retail investors are better off investing in crypto ETPs versus buying spot directly, as ETPs are regulated products subject to strict regulatory oversight by financial authorities,” she told Blockworks. “ETP investors also benefit from insurance, institutional-grade crypto custody and ease of trading via their existing brokerage accounts.”</p>



<p>The FCA is likely waiting to get a clearer picture of how the <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/sec">SEC</a>’s approval of bitcoin ETFs plays out, the 21.co executive added. So far, the 10-fund segment has seen more than $10 billion of net <a href="https://twitter.com/BitMEXResearch/status/1767451778054807797">inflows</a> — even with the largest fund in the category, the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF (GBTC), enduring net outflows of about $11 billion.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The success of bitcoin <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/etfs">ETFs</a> in the US certainly have created pressure for the FCA to reconsider, as the UK has become an outlier among its peers,” Chiu said. “However, the FCA has taken a relatively progressive approach to allow for [ether] from the get-go, which is very encouraging to see.”</p>



<p>The SEC, which has not yet approved ether ETFs, is <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etfs-approved-ether-funds-next">expected to rule on ETH products</a> proposed by various US issuers in May.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T20:06:32.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stocks recover, cryptocurrencies slip sideways on CPI data ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-falters-after-all-time-high</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-falters-after-all-time-high"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T16:39:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Bitcoin, after posting another record-high of just under $73,000 Monday, lost 0.7% Tuesday]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Bitcoin and ether faltered slightly Tuesday afternoon in New York while stocks rebounded after an initial slip on disappointing annual inflation numbers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The S&amp;P 500 was trading about 1% higher at time of publication while the tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite gained 1.3%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>), after posting another record-high of just under $73,000 Monday, lost 0.7% Tuesday. Ether (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/eth">ETH</a>) was also trading lower, dropping 1% at time of publication.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-ethereum-burning-almost-10b">Cheatsheet: Ethereum on track to burn $10B ETH over next year</a></p>



<p>The market moves come as Tuesday’s Consumer Price Index (CPI) print showed inflation rose 0.4% in February and 3.2% from a year ago, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics. Analysts had expected a 3.1% year-over-year increase, but the monthly figure came in as predicted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite coming in not too far off expectations, Tuesday’s report could lead markets to expect a delayed timeline for rate cuts from the Federal Reserve, which will announce its policy decision next week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“There’s no way the <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/federal-reserve">Fed</a> can justify a cut if <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/inflation">inflation</a> is accelerating, even if it’s only a small move,” Noelle Acheson, author of the Crypto is Macro Now newsletter said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>February’s CPI report was highly anticipated, analysts say, as the January read — which showed a 3.1% annual increase — is skewed by annual contracts.</p>



<p>“In terms of the short-term impact of today’s US CPI release, we do not expect it to end the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-btc-exceeds-60k">crypto bull market</a> yet, nor to impact prices significantly in the coming weeks,” Aurelie Barthere, principal research analyst at Nansen, said. “What will probably happen is a repricing of expected Fed rate cuts: Right now future markets have four rate cuts priced by December 2024, this should be shaved to 2-3 rate cuts.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Markets" term="Markets"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T16:39:55.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grayscale to launch a new, smaller fund under ticker BTC ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/grayscale-new-mini-fund-btc-ticker</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/grayscale-new-mini-fund-btc-ticker"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T14:25:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to a filing Tuesday, GBTC will seed BTC]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Grayscale is seeking to launch a new, smaller fund based on GBTC.</p>



<p>The Grayscale Bitcoin Mini Trust fund would trade under the ticker BTC. A person familiar with the matter told Blockworks that Grayscale had the ticker reserved for a while to build out a suite of products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission will need to approve the fund before it can officially launch.</p>



<p>While an exact fee isn’t clear, the fee for BTC will be lower than GBTC’s 1.5% fee, and would be competitive with the other bitcoin ETF fees, the person said.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/grayscale-fund-optimizing-staking-rewards">Grayscale announces fund aimed at optimizing staking rewards</a></p>



<p>GBTC will seed BTC, and a certain percentage of the bitcoins will be allocated to the new fund.</p>



<p>“At <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/grayscale">Grayscale</a>, we aim to continually provide our investors with compelling, future-forward opportunities to access Bitcoin and the crypto ecosystem. Additional information can be found in Grayscale’s public filings,” a Grayscale spokesperson told Blockworks via email.</p>



<p>Additionally, the spin-off will not be a taxable event for shareholders meaning that GBTC investors will not pay capital gains, a source close to Grayscale told Blockworks.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/investors-win-bitcoin-etf-fee-war">Investors are ‘the clear winners’ as bitcoin ETF fee battle comes into focus</a></p>



<p>“The Spin-Off is not expected to be a taxable event for GBTC or its shareholders, except to the extent that Bitcoin is (or is treated as having been) sold to fund cash payments with respect to de minimis fractional Shares, if any,” the fund’s S-1 <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/2015034/000119312524065444/d785023ds1.htm#tx785023_2">said</a>.</p>



<p>Blockworks <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/gbtc-outflows-curb-asset-advantage">previously reported that some investors</a> were caught in a tax web regarding GBTC since some investors may face large tax bills if they tried to move out of GBTC into another bitcoin <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/etfs">ETF</a>.</p>



<p>Bloomberg ETF analyst James Seyffart — who also predicted that Grayscale would use the BTC ticker to launch a “cheaper sibling” — said that he wasn’t expecting the asset manager to use a spin-off to launch the fund.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">But using the spinoff mechanism wasn’t something I expected or thought of. And definitely helps out long term <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24GBTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$GBTC</a> holders — particularly the taxable ones who were sorta stuck with potential capital gains tax hits. Not a full solution. But way more helpful than launching a…</p>— James Seyffart (@JSeyff) <a href="https://twitter.com/JSeyff/status/1767534197399335045?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>The approach “definitely helps out long-term GBTC holders — particularly the taxable ones who were sorta stuck with potential capital gains tax hits. Not a full solution. But way more helpful than launching a standalone product from scratch,” he said in a post on X.</p>



<p>Smaller fund launches aren’t uncommon in the ETF industry. In 2018, State Street launched the SPDR Gold MiniShares Trust, which was designed to reflect gold’s performance with a lower fee.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Grayscale’s approach is unique, however. The fund looks to be the first to use the spin-off mechanism on a commodities ETF, according to a person familiar.</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://twitter.com/JSeyff/status/1767537435410399602">post</a> on X, Seyffart said that the “only situation like this” was the Financial Select Sector SPDR Fund (XLF) spinning REITs into Real Estate Select Sector SPDR (XLRE.) However, the fund just moved the real estate stocks into the other fund, which Seyffart noted, is a different scenario than GBTC moving a percentage of bitcoin into BTC.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Grayscale’s bitcoin ETF has the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/grayscale-fee-higher-bitcoin-etf">highest fee of all the bitcoin ETFs</a> currently on the market. The fund has also seen the highest level of outflows of the group. Grayscale converted its bitcoin trust to a bitcoin ETF in January, putting the fund slightly ahead of the rest of the pack.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, as of last week, <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-snapshot-inflows-near-high">the other nine funds have collectively surpassed GBTC</a> in assets under management.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Ross</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/katherine-ross</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T14:25:40.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">
            <![CDATA[Blast developers drawn by layer-2’s liquidity and founder’s success building Blur]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/blast-developers-layer-2-liquidity</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-developers-layer-2-liquidity"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T14:10:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Protocols built on Blast have accrued nearly $1 billion in TVL in the two weeks since the layer-2 went to mainnet]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>When the heavily-marketed layer-2 Blast went to mainnet late last month, so did a host of protocols built atop the optimistic rollup.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blast drew over $2 billion in deposits before launching — but faced criticism for initially soliciting the funds to a multisig wallet before its layer-2 had been built. A number of protocols were willing to brush that aside, though: DeFiLlama <a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Blast">lists</a> 50 protocols deployed on Blast cumulatively holding nearly $1 billion in total value locked (<a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/tvl">TVL</a>).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blast <a href="https://twitter.com/Blast_L2/status/1761246464200826945">said</a> over 3,000 projects entered its “Big Bang” developer contest to go live on mainnet launch and receive a larger allocation of the protocol’s airdrop.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-layer2-ethereum-yield">Wannabe L2 Blast bursts onto scene promising high ETH yield — in 3 months</a></p>



<p>Among the developers Blockworks spoke to about building on Blast, a couple major draws that emerged were the protocol’s success in acquiring users and liquidity, as well as founder Tieshun Roquerre’s established track record with the NFT marketplace Blur.</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-tvl-ethereum">Blast first pitched itself</a> as a layer-2 with “native yield” — meaning holdings <a href="https://docs.blast.io/about-blast#auto-rebasing">are</a> compounded on yield-generating venues like Lido and MakerDAO. The rollup is a <a href="https://github.com/blast-io/deployment">fork</a> of the second-largest layer-2, Optimism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The metaverse-adjacent protocol Entertainm was partly motivated to build on Blast by the native yield and Blast’s pledge to <a href="https://docs.blast.io/building/guides/gas-fees">reimburse</a> some gas fees to developers. Entertainm can stake the reimbursed fees to grow its treasury, the project’s pseudonymous chief marketing officer Renata said in a direct message.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vertex, an Arbitrum-native decentralized exchange (DEX), made Blast its first cross-chain deployment. Its forked DEX, called Blitz, doesn’t even let users trade yet — but that hasn’t stopped over $15 million in TVL from being bridged to the protocol from roughly 5,000 unique wallets, Vertex co-founder Darius Tabai said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tabai said Vertex began considering deploying on Blast after seeing the user excitement surrounding the layer-2. This was particularly true in Asia, where Vertex has a strong presence. Tabai was also drawn to Blast’s founder Roquerre, known online as Pacman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Roquerre has “much more of a successful Web2 founder-type mentality than some of the more academic outlook that can exist in blockchain. And I think we’re sort of attracted to that kind of pragmatism. ‘Build things that people want to use and get them to use it’ is a way more exciting story to us than ‘be 10% better on TPS [transactions per second],’” Tabai said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently in his mid-twenties, Roquerre <a href="https://tieshunroquerre.com/">went</a> through the famous startup incubator Y Combinator as a teenager before enrolling in and dropping out of MIT. In 2022, he co-founded an NFT marketplace named Blur that <a href="https://dune.com/hildobby/NFTs">unseated</a> OpenSea as the largest NFT marketplace by trading volume.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> ​​<a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blur-blends-defi-nfts">Blur blends DeFi and NFT market with new lending platform</a></p>



<p>Blur grew partly through a “points” system where users were given IOUs <a href="https://x.com/blur_io/status/1726755896708190479?s=20">for</a> bidding, listing, or lending on the platform. Users’ points determined their allocation in Blur’s eventual token airdrop.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some of Blur’s volume spike has also been <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blur-nft-volume-crypto-airdrop">attributed to wash trading</a>, where users sell NFTs to themselves to do things like drive up prices or farm for points allocations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Much of the depositing frenzy on Blast has been driven by a points system similar to Blur’s. Blast <a href="https://blast.io/en/about?utm_source=thedecentralised.beehiiv.com&amp;utm_medium=newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=prepare-for-a-2bn-blast">says</a> on its website some sort of Airdrop will be distributed to points holders in May.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One founder deploying a project on Blast said they started building on the protocol partly as a bet that Roquerre would repeat the success he saw at Blur. Blast’s deep liquidity — it has nearly already surpassed <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/optimism">Optimism</a> as the second-<a href="https://defillama.com/chains/Rollup">largest</a> Ethereum rollup by TVL, per DeFiLlama — was also a draw.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite any qualms with the tech, demand for Blast was clearly present.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Initially I was like, ‘Oh wow, this is crazy.’ But as the number goes up, and as people still commit their funds…I mean, personally, I did not deposit on Blast. But you know, as other people do it, I’m like, ‘Okay, as a developer, if there is demand of people willing to take that risk, then I can be offering a product on that chain,’” they said.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/blast-optimistic-rollup-launch">Blast launch leaves users confused about withdrawals</a></p>



<p>The founder mentioned that the participation of <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/paradigm">Paradigm</a>, a well-regarded crypto venture capital firm, increased their confidence in the project.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Paradigm <a href="https://x.com/Blast_L2/status/1726747087906464024?s=20">participated</a> in Blast’s $20 million November seed round. Days later, Paradigm head of research Dan Robinson <a href="https://twitter.com/danrobinson/status/1728817674543862023">wrote</a> on X that Blast’s launch “crossed lines in both messaging and execution.” In December, Robinson <a href="https://twitter.com/danrobinson/status/1733187417694486541">said</a> the VC firm worked with Blast to redesign its upgrade system and “set a better precedent for future projects who may try to emulate them.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jack Kubinec</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/jack-kubinec</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T14:10:32.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin’s 21 million limit is a boomer myth]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoins-21-million-limit-myth</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoins-21-million-limit-myth"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T13:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[To genuinely appreciate the value of bitcoin, one must recognize that the perceived cap of 21 million does not accurately reflect reality]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>We’ve all heard it. There will only ever be 21 million bitcoin. With 19.6 million already mined, time is of the essence to secure one’s rights to a piece of digital sovereignty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what if the situation was even more paramount? A supply of 21 million is already not enough to go around, and anything less would raise the stakes that much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To genuinely appreciate the value of bitcoin, one must recognize that the perceived cap of 21 million does not accurately reflect reality. In doing so, not only does a clearer understanding of bitcoin’s true scarcity and value proposition come into focus, but it also instills greater confidence when navigating market cycles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By using bitcoin’s actual supply as a frame of reference, those periods of volatility suddenly become all the more insignificant. Conversely, during times of market euphoria and price appreciation, bitcoin’s true scarcity makes for a compelling case to accumulate even at the top while others begin to realize profits.</p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Reassessing bitcoin’s 21 million</h1>



<p>The largest stash of bitcoin in the world belongs to its creator, Satoshi Nakamoto. Thanks to on-chain sleuths, we know that Nakamoto was one of the only miners on the network in Bitcoin’s earliest days, allowing the pseudonymous creator to amass a whopping 1.096 million coins. To this day, the only transaction to ever occur from Nakamoto was the famous 10 BTC <a href="https://20368641.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/20368641/Cointime%20Economics%20%5BDIGITAL%20SINGLE%5D.pdf">sent</a> to cryptographer and early pioneer Hal Finney.</p>



<p>These million coins or so make up most of what are often referred to as “zombie coins,” or coins that have not moved since Bitcoin’s first official exchange traded price. Totaling <a href="https://studio.glassnode.com/metrics?a=BTC&amp;category=&amp;m=supply.ProbablyLost">1.457 million</a>, <a href="https://20368641.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/20368641/Cointime%20Economics%20%5BDIGITAL%20SINGLE%5D.pdf">heuristic analysis</a> of UTXO’s hint that it’s safe to consider these coins as gone forever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just like that, nearly 7% of Bitcoin’s supply is effectively inaccessible. That 21 million is getting smaller.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this only scratches the surface of the sheer extent of lost coins. Data suggests there are millions more that haven’t budged since Bitcoin’s earliest days. Likely associated with other early miners or poor souls who lost the keys to their archaic wallet, on-chain analytics tell a different story of Bitcoin’s actual supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In their research report, <em>Cointime Economics</em>, analysts David Puell and James Check <a href="https://20368641.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/20368641/Cointime%20Economics%20%5BDIGITAL%20SINGLE%5D.pdf">surmise </a>that anywhere from 3.89 million to 4.87 million coins could be considered lost. This estimate includes Satoshi’s holdings as well as the zombie coins.</p>



<p><strong>Read more from our opinion section:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-price-soars-poor-hodl">As bitcoin’s price soars, I’m having fun and staying poor</a></p>



<p>While they acknowledge there is some ambiguity when trying to quantify the number of lost coins, let’s take the lower bound of their estimate for the sake of brevity. If 3.89 million coins can be considered permanently lost, gone to eternity, never to be seen again, Bitcoin’s original 21 million is now down to 17.11 million, an 18% reduction.</p>



<p>Is that FOMO building up yet?</p>



<p>Making matters worse (or better depending on how much bitcoin you already have), there is a growing cohort of individuals and institutions who are set on never parting with their precious bitcoin. The actual scale of holding that is permanently removing coins from circulation can’t be accurately measured, and any estimations will have to wait for more time to pass. But rest assured, they’re out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Take the poster child of holding, Michael Saylor, as evidence. As CEO of MicroStrategy, he and his company have embarked on a <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-supply-rivals-blackrock-ibit">historic accumulation</a> of around 205,000 bitcoin, plus another 17,000 stockpiled for his personal reserves.</p>



<p>When asked if he ever had plans to sell his holdings in a recent interview, he candidly <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-millions-142143795.html">remarked</a>, “I’m gonna be buying the top forever.”</p>



<p>And just like that, another 1% of Bitcoin’s supply that will never see the light of markets again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Saylor represents just a fraction of the tens of thousands, if not millions, of investors out there with an increasing propensity to hold on, no matter how bad a bear market gets or how high a bull market goes. Consider the supply held by long-term holders steadily growing and hitting an all-time high in the midst of a brutal crypto winter as proof.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-sets-all-time-high-71000">Bitcoin sets another all-time high Monday flirting with $72,000</a></p>



<p>The harsh truth is that Bitcoin is far more scarce than we were led to believe. Accounting for the known lost coins and estimating the coins that holders won’t part ways with, it’s safe to assume that the initial supply has been reduced by somewhere around 20%. That means there are less than 16.8 million bitcoin to last us until the final block is mined.</p>



<p>So, as we approach another halving, witness the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etfs-btc-supply">unprecedented buying spree of Wall Street’s bitcoin ETF sponsors</a>, and await the influx of buyers that so often arrive during bull markets, the stage is set. Time is of the essence to grab your slice of the bitcoin pie; there are only 16.8 million left, probably even less. Act accordingly.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">


<div class="wp-block-post-author-biography">RJ Fulton is a self-taught crypto market analyst and writer. With contributions to blockchain projects like Stacks and popular financial platforms such as The Motley Fool and Yahoo! Finance, RJ is becoming a recognized voice shaping conversations in the crypto space. Driven by a belief in crypto’s power to revolutionize economic sovereignty, RJ explores decentralized technologies’ transformative potential and dissects market trends to demystify the burgeoning crypto landscape. Open to new opportunities, he envisions contributing his analytical acumen to companies and projects aligning with his passion for leveraging digital assets as the foundation of a new financial era.</div>


<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>RJ Fulton</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/rj-fulton</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Op-Ed" term="Op-Ed"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T13:30:03.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CoinShares closes buy of US bitcoin ETF issuer’s fund division]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/coinshares-buys-valkyrie-fund-business</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinshares-buys-valkyrie-fund-business"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T13:15:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Europe-focused investment firm is set to expand its US asset management business after taking over ETFs with $530 million in combined assets ]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>CoinShares completed its takeover of Valkyrie’s fund business Tuesday as part of its bid to expand its asset management footprint in the US.</p>



<p>Specifically, the Europe-focused investment company bought the Tennessee-based crypto asset manager’s actively managed ETF business. Details of the deal were not disclosed.</p>



<p>CoinShares said it <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinshares-potential-buy-valkyrie">had secured an option to buy Valkyrie</a>’s fund division in November. That option was active until March 31, 2024.</p>



<p>With the purchase, <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/coinshares">CoinShares</a> is set to gain roughly $530 million of assets under management across four funds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This includes one of the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-approves-bitcoin-etf">10 US spot bitcoin ETFs</a> — the Valkyrie Bitcoin Fund (BRRR) — as well as the firm’s Bitcoin Miners ETF (WGMI); its Bitcoin and Ether Strategy ETF (BTF); and the Valkyrie Bitcoin Futures Leveraged Strategy ETF (BTFX).&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinshares-acquires-valkyrie">CoinShares to take over Valkyrie now that spot bitcoin ETF is live</a></p>



<p>CoinShares aims to rebrand the four <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/valkyrie">Valkyrie</a> funds by the summer, the company said in a Tuesday news release.</p>



<p>CoinShares CEO Jean-Marie Mognetti said in a statement that the Valkyrie acquisition is a step toward moving deeper into the US after a decade of focusing on European markets.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“It broadens our product offerings, strengthens our innovation capacity and increases by a factor of 15 our total addressable market,” Mognetti added.</p>



<p>Valkyrie is perhaps best known for being one of the issuers to gain Securities and Exchange Commission approval in January to launch a spot bitcoin ETF.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though among the smaller funds in the segment, BRRR has notched net inflows of $308 million since launching on Jan. 11, according to BitMEX Research. The fund had eclipsed $400 million in assets at market close on Monday, the data <a href="https://twitter.com/BitMEXResearch/status/1767451778054807797">shows</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Valkyrie was second to the US market — behind ProShares — with an ETF that invested in bitcoin futures contracts, launching that offering in October 2021. That fund <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/valkyrie-etf-ether-futures-unwind">started to also give investors exposure to ether futures contracts</a> last October.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>More recently, the company <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/valkyrie-bitcoin-futures-etf">launched its Bitcoin Futures Leveraged Strategy ETF</a> last month.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T13:15:02.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheatsheet: Ethereum on track to burn $10B ETH over next year]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-ethereum-burning-almost-10b</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/cheatsheet-ethereum-burning-almost-10b"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T12:56:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Crypto is certainly heating up on exchanges — but on-chain it’s already white hot]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is Cheatsheet, a primer on what’s happening in crypto today.</em></p>



<p>Crypto has hit that point of the bull market where anything and everything is rallying without any real link between star performers.</p>



<p>Today, toncoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/ton">TON</a>) is beating the top end of the table, up 25% as of 8 am ET. While TON is its own layer-1 blockchain, the token finds utility with a web of Telegram trading bots rapidly gaining popularity over the past year.</p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/price/xrp">XRP</a> is second for the day with 12.5%, followed by flow (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/flow">FLOW</a>), the native crypto for the NFT-focused chain built by Dapper Labs, which is up 9%.</p>



<p>Bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>) and ether (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/eth">ETH</a>) have ended up flat over the same period. Crypto’s total market capitalization is now only 7% shy of its $3 trillion record high, set in late 2021.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On-chain mail</h2>



<p>After plateauing for six weeks, Ethereum is now burning supply faster than at any point in the past nine months.</p>



<ul>
<li>The ETH supply has shrunk by 74,603 ETH ($300 million) over the past month.</li>



<li>Burns were totally stagnant between Christmas and the second week of February.</li>



<li>Ethereum will burn $10 billion ETH over the next year at its current pace (and current prices), per <a href="https://ultrasound.money/">ultrasound.money</a>.</li>
</ul>



<p>As of August 2021, the Ethereum network burns a small amount of ETH with every transaction — specifically the base fee paid by users.</p>



<p>The ETH supply has shrunk by 0.31% over the past year and is currently on track to reduce by 1.42% over the next if on-chain activity keeps up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The network still issues fresh ETH with every block: without burns, the circulating ETH supply would increase by 0.5% every year.</p>



<ul>
<li>Top DEX Uniswap still burns more ETH than any other platform — more than 22,000 ETH ($87.9 million) over the past month.</li>



<li>Telegram trading bot Banana Gun is burning more ETH than layer-2s Arbitrum and Optimism.</li>



<li>ETH supply is tipped to dip below 120 million sometime in May, which would return it to Aug. 2022 levels.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" srcset="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=1600 1600w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=300 300w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=1024 1024w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=768 768w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=1536 1536w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=428 428w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=470 470w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=389 389w, https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png?w=80 80w" class="wp-image-82296" alt="" src="https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-3.png" height="597" width="1600" decoding="async" loading="lazy"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Ethereum supply may have peaked in September 2022 (</em><a href="https://ultrasound.money/"><em>source</em></a><em>)</em></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crypto business</h2>



<p>Bitcoin’s strength still hasn’t converted to gains for crypto stocks, with only two set to open Tuesday higher: MicroStrategy and Coinbase.</p>



<ul>
<li>MicroStrategy gained 4.11% on Monday and added another 5% after hours as of 7 am, ET.</li>



<li>Coinbase slipped nearly 1% but regained 1.5% post-bell.</li>



<li>CleanSpark and Marathon took a beating, down 17.24% and 13.2%, respectively.</li>
</ul>



<p>Still, CleanSpark is the only miner to beat S&amp;P 500 over the past month, now up 20% to the S&amp;P’s 2%. The Las Vegas-headquartered firm announced plans to double its hashrate in February.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the year-to-date, CleanSpark’s 52% gains are second only to MicroStrategy, now up 147%. Coinbase trails slightly with 48.3%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>CleanSpark, now the second-largest mining stock by market value, flipped Colorado-headquartered Riot earlier this month, worth $3.34 billion to $2.98 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Former MicroStrategy CEO Michael Saylor has sold $167.4 million in MSTR shares this year, per OpenInsider.</li>



<li>Saylor sold those shares for $688.29 on average, MSTR currently trades for more than double that price.</li>



<li>He announced a plan to sell 315,000 shares in January — he’s more than three-quarters of the way through that stack.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On the ground</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">from the creators of orb salute (<a href="https://twitter.com/0xPenryn?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@0xPenryn</a>), we bring you: orb wif hat <a href="https://t.co/acYTZkBn2a">pic.twitter.com/acYTZkBn2a</a></p>— dcbuilder.eth 🕯4844🕯.oO (@DCbuild3r) <a href="https://twitter.com/DCbuild3r/status/1767505442215792976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>We never stood a chance</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">New Prometheum just dropped. The SEC's posture child for "regulatory compliance" is on thin ice. <br><br>On Friday PM the company buried a filing for their Ember ATS entity that shows an increasingly precarious financial state. <br><br>$468k cash despite a $5.1m injection from the parent co. <a href="https://t.co/HwUv3D9oZT">https://t.co/HwUv3D9oZT</a> <a href="https://t.co/FFXNPO3ACO">pic.twitter.com/FFXNPO3ACO</a></p>— Matt Walsh (@MattWalshInBos) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattWalshInBos/status/1767374300590293168?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Prometheum is bleeding cash</em></figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">fun fact. in q2 2020 when microstrategy first announced their bitcoin buy strategy, not a SINGLE question on the earnings call was about bitcoin. every wall street analyst completely ignored it <br><br>the stock is up 12x since then<a href="https://t.co/D69j5IEIhQ">https://t.co/D69j5IEIhQ</a></p>— nic 🌠 carter (@nic__carter) <a href="https://twitter.com/nic__carter/status/1767386297348293070?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Analysts in disbelief</em></figcaption></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Canellis</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/david-canellis</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Web3" term="Web3"/>
        <published>2024-03-12T12:56:06.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coinbase moves forward with appeal of SEC’s rulemaking petition denial ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-appeals-sec-rulemaking-petition</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-appeals-sec-rulemaking-petition"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T21:28:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The exchange argues that SEC acted arbitrarily in denying the petition for rulemaking, which Coinbase filed in June 2022]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Coinbase on Monday continued its effort to nail down concrete industry rules from the US Securities and Exchange Commission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Attorneys for the American exchange giant filed their opening brief in their case against the SEC in the Third Circuit Court of Appeals. Coinbase is asking the court to grant their petition for review, overturn the SEC’s denial and order the securities regulator to begin the rulemaking process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The [SEC] is asserting sweeping new authority over a vibrant, rapidly expanding industry — digital assets,” Coinbase’s team wrote in the brief. “But the SEC is pursuing this power grab <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-2023-crypto-enforcement-actions">through enforcement actions</a>, and it has refused to set forth its new interpretation of its enabling statutes in a rulemaking, where the lack of legal basis for its self-aggrandizement would be laid bare.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-commissioners-disagree-with-coinbase-decision">Peirce, Uyeda ‘disagree’ with SEC decision to deny Coinbase petition</a></p>



<p>The exchange argues that the <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/sec">SEC</a> acted arbitrarily in denying the petition for rulemaking, which <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/coinbase">Coinbase</a> filed in June 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Digital asset firms are therefore in a Catch-22 of the SEC’s own making: The agency insists they comply with its regulations, but it refuses to conduct the rulemaking needed to establish regulations by which firms feasibly could do so,” Monday’s filing read.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The SEC denied Coinbase’s petition for rulemaking in December 2023 in a 3-2 Commissioner vote. In his supporting statement, SEC Chairman Gary Gensler <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/statement/gensler-coinbase-petition-121523">said</a> the petition was denied because digital assets already fall under existing rules and regulations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a joint dissenting opinion, Commissioners Hester <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/hester-peirce">Peirce</a> and Mark Uyeda <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/statement/peirce-uyeda-petition-121523">said</a> Coinbase’s petition highlights “issues presented by new technologies and other innovations, and addressing these important issues is a core part of being a responsible regulator.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/permissionless-regulatory-panel-peirce">SEC’s Peirce: The US government needs to remember who it represents</a></p>



<p>Coinbase <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-files-rulemaking-petition-review">promptly appealed the decision</a>, arguing that the SEC’s denial is an “abuse of discretion and contrary to law, in violation of the Administrative Procedure Act.”</p>



<p>Monday’s filing comes as a separate case between Coinbase and the securities regulator continues in New York. The SEC in June sued Coinbase for <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-sues-coinbase">allegedly operating as an unregistered broker</a>, exchange and clearing agency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Both parties in January <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/judge-questions-sec-limits-coinbase-hearing">presented oral arguments</a> relating to Coinbase’s motion to dismiss the suit. Presiding Judge Katherine Polk Failla has not yet ruled on the motion.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T21:28:06.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies extend rally while stocks falter ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-monday-all-time-high</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-monday-all-time-high"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T20:16:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Bitcoin started another record-setting week Monday, hitting a price of $72,846.65 according to Coinbase]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Bitcoin and ether continued their historic price run Monday while equities posted a mild correction ahead of next week’s interest rate decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bitcoin broke yet another record Monday afternoon in New York, hitting a price of $72,846.65, according to Coinbase. The largest cryptocurrency is up close to 5% today and more than 8% over the past week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>), <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-correction-all-time-high">which lost 11% last week</a> after clocking an all-time high, managed to hold steady Monday, trading just under $72,300 at time of publication, per Coinbase.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-sets-all-time-high-71000">Bitcoin sets another all-time high Monday flirting with $72,000</a></p>



<p>Bitcoin’s rally has spurred a number of liquidations in the derivatives market that exacerbated the volatility, analysts from Kaiko said in a Monday note. Bitcoin perpetual futures open interest hit a multi-year high last week of $15 billion while market depth surpassed $600 million, according to Kaiko.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“However, looking at the breakdown between bid and ask depth, we observe a strong mismatch,” Kaiko analysts wrote. “The quantity of asks far surpasses bids within 2% of the mid price for the longest period since early 2021. This suggests that traders have been taking profit as BTC hits new highs.”</p>



<p>Ether (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/eth">ETH</a>) was also on the rise Monday, rallying 4% over 24 hours to trade around $4,000. While bitcoin has been breaking records in recent days, ether has yet to post a new all-time high. Its last record price of $4,721 was set in 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-eth-tops-4k">Ethereum hits $4K for first time since December 2021</a></p>



<p>The Federal Reserve’s Open Market Committee convenes next week for their policy-setting meeting. Markets overwhelmingly expect central bankers to hold interest rates, according to <a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/markets/interest-rates/cme-fedwatch-tool.html?redirect=/trading/interest-rates/countdown-to-fomc.html">data</a> from CME Group.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stocks pared gains from last week, with the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq Composite indexes closing Monday’s session 0.1% and 0.4% lower, respectively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investors are still parsing through the “mixed bag” jobs report released on Friday, which showed the US economy added 275,000 jobs in February, more than the 200,000 new positions expected, Nicholas Colas, co-founder of DataTrek Research said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Since unemployment is exceptionally low, it makes it harder to know whether rising joblessness is truly worrisome or simply the return to a more-sustainable long run average,” Colas said. “This is a potential problem for the <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/federal-reserve">Fed</a>’s ability to read the US labor market/economy, and Chair <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/jerome-powell">Powell</a> has discussed it at past post-FOMC press conferences.”&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Markets" term="Markets"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T20:16:59.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html">
            <![CDATA[MicroStrategy once again holds more bitcoin than BlackRock’s IBIT — for now]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-supply-rivals-blackrock-ibit</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-supply-rivals-blackrock-ibit"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T19:56:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[A big portion of the company’s value comes from its ability to purchase bitcoin with convertible debt and equity, founder Michael Saylor says]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>MicroStrategy now holds 205,000 bitcoin after revealing the latest addition to its stockpile amid a crypto price rally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The total is slightly more bitcoin than what BlackRock’s spot bitcoin ETF held, as of market close on Friday.</p>



<p>The largest publicly traded holder of bitcoin (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/btc">BTC</a>) said Monday it used proceeds from convertible notes as well as excess cash to buy 12,000 more bitcoins for about $820 million.</p>



<p>The buy comes a week after MicroStrategy said it intended to <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-convertible-note-sale">utilize a $600 million private offering of convertible notes</a> to do just that. The unsecured senior obligations of MicroStrategy were set to bear interest payable semi-annually, beginning on Sept. 15, 2024.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-bitcoin-buying">Will MicroStrategy ever stop buying bitcoin?</a></p>



<p>The business intelligence firm’s announcement came on a day during which <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-sets-all-time-high-71000">bitcoin reached another all-time high price</a> of more than $72,000.</p>



<p>BTC’s price was at about $72,600 at 2:30 pm ET — bringing the value of <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/microstrategy">MicroStrategy</a>’s bitcoin to about $14.9 billion. That value is more than double the roughly $6.9 billion the BTC stockpile was purchased for.</p>



<p>While MicroStrategy’s most recent stack of BTC was purchased at an average price of $68,477, the average price per bitcoin of its 205,000 BTC stands at about $33,700.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MicroStrategy founder Michael Saylor called bitcoin “digital property” that “is going to eat gold” during a Monday <a href="https://twitter.com/saylor/status/1767178599390458285">interview</a> with CNBC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The killer application is capital preservation for everybody,” he added. “The store of value is the killer use case.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-defi-future">Bitcoin is DeFi’s future</a></p>



<p>The latest rise in price is validating — for now — a bitcoin buy-and-hold strategy that <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/michael-saylor">Saylor</a>’s firm has held in all market conditions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We’re buying it to hold it [for] 100 years; so that being the case, that $66,000 to $16,000 crash shook out the tourists [and] shook out the non-believers,” the executive told CNBC. “We were all ready to ride it to zero…Now we’re riding it the other direction.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">MicroStrategy stock versus ETFs</h2>



<p>MicroStrategy’s stock was up about 12.5% on the day at 2:30 pm ET. It is up about 123% from a month ago — outpacing BTC’s price rise of about 50% over that span.</p>



<p>Historically a proxy for bitcoin, MicroStrategy stock now competes with the spot bitcoin <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/etfs">ETFs</a> that the <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-approves-bitcoin-etf">Securities and Exchange Commission approved in January</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Analysts have noted, however, that shareholders of MicroStrategy don’t pay a management fee. Stockholders can also benefit from the company’s use of leverage, while also getting downside protection, some industry watchers argue.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/microstrategy-stock-vs-bitcoin-etf">Is MicroStrategy stock better than a spot bitcoin ETF?</a></p>



<p>The 205,000 BTC MicroStrategy holds is slightly more than the nearly 198,000 BTC held by <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/blackrock">BlackRock</a>’s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT) at market close Friday, according to BitMEX Research <a href="https://twitter.com/BitMEXResearch/status/1766359950970786251">data</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>IBIT’s assets under management stood at about $13.6 billion on Friday — roughly half of the assets within the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust ETF (<a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/gbtc">GBTC</a>). The latter fund ported over $28 billion when converting to an ETF in January and remains the biggest fund in the category.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>While MicroStrategy previously functioned primarily as a software business, Saylor said it has rebranded to a “bitcoin development company.”</p>



<p>“Certainly the substantial amount of our enterprise value is based on our unique ability to issue securities and to purchase bitcoin with convertible debt, with equity and the like,” Saylor said Monday. “The only reason we could make this transition was because the software business was healthy.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Business" term="Business"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T19:56:03.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gnosis Chain premieres Ethereum’s Dencun hard fork]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/gnosis-chain-ethereum-dencun-hard-fork</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/gnosis-chain-ethereum-dencun-hard-fork"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T19:15:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[For the first time, a major Ethereum hard fork launches on another chain first]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Gnosis Chain, originally known as xDai Chain, is a proof-of-stake blockchain designed to maintain full Ethereum compatibility, including the ability to directly implement all hard-forks.</p>



<p>At approximately 2:30 pm ET, Gnosis activated the Dencun hard fork, which is set to go live on Ethereum in less than two days. That is made possible as Gnosis’ design mirrors that of Ethereum, with a “Beacon” chain and an execution layer.</p>



<p>Gnosis can be thought of as kind of like a research network to test things in the real world, according to infrastructure director Phillippe Schommers.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-devs-debate-account-abstraction">Ethereum devs debate future of account abstraction</a></p>



<p>“We really want to stay exactly like Ethereum, so that an application developed for Ethereum can come to Gnosis Chain seamlessly,” Schommers told Blockworks.</p>



<p>The Dencun upgrade is focused on scaling Ethereum through layer-2 networks with the introduction of a new dedicated data storage channel — dubbed blobs — that will dramatically <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-improvement-proposal-4844">decrease transaction costs on Ethereum rollups</a> which use Ethereum for data availability.</p>



<p>No errors were reported on Gnosis Chain after the fork, and the chain is now finalizing with blobs, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eeYESXzzmEw">said</a> Ethereum core developers on a livestream commemorating the hard fork.</p>



<p><strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/ethereum-dencun-upgrade-march-13">Ethereum Foundation gives Dencun upgrade an activation time on March 13</a></p>



<p>Exactly how cheap transactions can get is still a matter of debate. Martin Koeppelmann, Gnosis co-founder, predicted on the Gnosis livestream that <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/rollups">rollups</a> will not reach sub-cent transaction fees.</p>



<p>“We still think we need more, so we have Gnosis Chain as our horizontal <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/scaling">scaling</a> — very similar to Ethereum — and now we also do <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/layer-2-2">layer-2s</a> on top of Gnosis Chain,” Koeppelmann said.</p>



<p>With the Dencun hard fork, tech stacks that work for <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/ethereum">Ethereum</a> to launch rollups will also work on Gnosis Chain out of the box.</p>



<p>Even on the Gnosis layer-1, gas costs, paid in xDAI — a derivative of the DAI stablecoin — are well under $0.01.</p>



<p>One of the first applications of layer-2s on Gnosis Chain will be for Gnosis Pay, the payments network that is now rolling out. Gnosis Pay currently operates on the base layer, but will migrate to layer-2s, perhaps segregated by jurisdiction, to facilitate regulatory compliance — with data protection laws, for example.</p>



<p><strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/non-custodial-crypto-cards-ftx-industry-trend">Non-custodial crypto cards proliferate as part of wider industry trend</a></p>



<p>Once the infrastructure is in place, the goal is to provide abundant blockspace and focus can shift to productive uses in the form of apps that can appeal to non-technical users.</p>



<p>“Moving from Ethereum to layer-2, or to another chain with bridges, or with sequencers or whatever, is always going to be complicated for the average user,” Schommers said.</p>



<p>“We should work a lot more on the application part and make it seamless.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Macauley Peterson</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/macauleypeterson</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T19:15:34.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jito Labs ends mempool functionality citing impact on Solana users]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/jito-labs-suspends-mempool-functionality</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/jito-labs-suspends-mempool-functionality"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T18:21:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Telegram bot users may come out as the latest winners for Jito’s mempool suspension]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Solana MEV startup Jito Labs said on Friday that it will suspend mempool functionality offered by the Jito Block Engine following an increased amount of sandwich attacks on the Solana blockchain.</p>



<p>MEV sandwich attacks occur when MEV searchers profit from an asset’s price volatility. The searcher jumps ahead of a large purchase order that they know will raise the asset’s price and then sells it immediately following a victim’s purchase, profiting from the user’s swap.</p>



<p>Jito Labs’ decision to pause was made after “deliberate conversations with the Jito Labs team and key Solana ecosystem stakeholders.” The move was met with mixed responses from industry participants.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/mev-who-should-profit">MEV: Who should profit from a protocol’s economic activity?</a></p>



<p>On Ethereum, validators create blocks by collecting transactions from a mempool — a staging area before a block is constructed and confirmed on-chain. Based on how these transactions are ordered in the block, validators can earn additional revenue, referred to as maximum extractable value, or <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/mev">MEV</a> for short, <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/chorus-one-to-capture-solana-mev">often at the expense of retail traders</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mempools are built into <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/ethereum">Ethereum</a> by design, but this is not the case for <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/solana">Solana</a>, where the block processor is known ahead of time. To allow <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/validator">validators</a> to capture MEV on Solana, startups like Jito Labs created infrastructure to introduce mempool functionalities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blockworks research analyst Dan Smith <a href="https://twitter.com/smyyguy/status/1766234020076011865">noted</a> in a post on X that MEV had been the “entire growth story for JTO,” implying that by suspending mempool functionality, it could struggle to drive value to JTO token holders.</p>



<p>Jito’s native token (<a href="https://blockworks.co/price/jto">JTO</a>) serves two main functions. One is for community members to participate in governance and the second is for holders to earn MEV rewards. These rewards are earned through MEV generated and redistributed by the Jito protocol.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/jito">According</a> to CoinGecko, JTO is trading at $2.72 at the time of this writing, down 1.6% over the past week.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">As a JTO holder, I can’t help but wonder if it’s a breach of fiduciary duty for the team to decide to stop beating poor people over the head with sticks 🤔</p>— Gwart (@GwartyGwart) <a href="https://twitter.com/GwartyGwart/status/1766287555949949231?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>“One party that this decision potentially benefits is Telegram bot users, who frequently set a high slippage amount to get their swap through but then experience the maximum slippage due to them getting sandwiched,” Blockworks research analyst Ren Yu Kong said. “With the removal of Jito’s mempool, this is much less likely to occur.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/solana-spam-problem">Solana has a spam problem. Can it be fixed?</a></p>



<p>However, Kong notes that without Jito’s mempool, searchers and arbitragers are likely to be incentivized to spam the network, resulting in failed transactions and wasted validator resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“With better execution, users get worse transaction inclusion guarantees as searchers and participants are once again incentivized to spam transactions for the maximum probability of fastest transaction inclusion,” Kong said.</p>



<p>Jito did not respond to Blockworks request for comment before publish time.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bessie Liu</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/bessieliu</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi" term="DeFi"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T18:21:56.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US Treasury once again proposes new crypto tax rules to “modernize” code ]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/us-treasury-2025-greenbook-crypto-taxes</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/us-treasury-2025-greenbook-crypto-taxes"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T18:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[Treasury on Monday released its 2025 revenue proposals, known as the “Greenbook,” detailing many of the same plans it unveiled last year]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>In line with President Joe Biden’s plans, the US Department of Treasury is once again suggesting a plethora of tax rules relating to digital assets, including outlawing wash-trading and imposing an excise tax on electricity costs for miners.</p>



<p>The Treasury on Monday released its 2025 revenue proposals, known as the “Greenbook,” outlining the tax recommendations in Biden’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/03/11/fact-sheet-the-presidents-budget-protects-and-strengthens-social-security-and-medicare/">budget</a>, also published Monday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The crypto-related proposals are largely a repeat from what the President asked for in 2023, which ultimately did not become law.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/biden-crypto-tax-lummis">Biden won’t tax crypto out of existence: Lummis</a></p>



<p>The Department wants to add an excise tax on “any firm using computing resources…to mine digital assets” of 30% of electricity costs used for <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/mining">mining</a>. If the proposal is adopted, miners would be required to report the amount and type of electricity used and the cost, when purchased externally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Miners that lease equipment would also be responsible for reporting electricity values and firms that use off-grid power would have to pay 30% of estimated costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden Administration first proposed excise taxes on miners last year, citing environmental concerns.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“While crypto assets are virtual, the energy consumption tied to their computationally intensive production is very real and imposes very real costs,” the White House <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cea/written-materials/2023/05/02/cost-of-cryptomining-dame-tax/">said</a> in a May 2023 statement.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/eia-drops-bitcoin-miner-survey">EIA to drop emergency bitcoin miner survey following court battle</a></p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/treasury">Treasury</a> officials also want to see wash-trading rules applied to crypto, nixing <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/crackdown-crypto-wash-trading">a long-standing loophole</a> Democrats have been trying to close for some time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“A taxpayer may sell a digital asset that is not considered a stock or security for wash sale purposes at a loss on one day and repurchase the same digital asset the next day,” Monday’s Greenbook read. “The same loss recognition rules should apply to digital assets held as investments or for trading as would apply for stocks and securities.”</p>



<p>The Treasury suggests adding all “digital assets,” not just crypto securities, to the current wash trading rules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Department defines “digital asset” as “any digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger or any similar technology as specified by the Secretary,” per the Greenbook.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Policy" term="Policy"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T18:00:39.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump cites merchandise sales in apparent bitcoin U-turn]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/donald-trump-talks-bitcoin</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/donald-trump-talks-bitcoin"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T17:31:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[This represents a change in course for Trump, who previously told the BBC that bitcoin “seems like a scam.”]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Former President Donald Trump says he is “not sure” if he would crack down on bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies after alleging that digital assets were a popular form of payment for his recently-launched sneaker collection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I noticed that so many of them were paid for with this, with the new currency,” Trump <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/squawk-box-us/">said</a> of accepting crypto as payment for his new footwear launch during an interview Monday on CNBC’s “Squawk Box.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“People were going crazy for these sneakers. You probably were, too. Everybody was. Every friend I have had called me for a pair of sneakers. And I noticed that so many of them were paid for with the new currency. It’s a new cryptocurrency. I couldn’t believe the amount,” he added.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/donald-trumps-nft-gala">I attended Trump’s NFT gala. Here’s why it matters</a></p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/donald-trump">Trump</a> claimed Monday that the “last pair” in the sneaker collection sold for $450,000, not specifying whether the transaction was completed in fiat or crypto. Each sneaker in the collection was originally sold for $399 a pair, and Blockworks was unable to verify a $450,000 shoe sale amount on any secondary markets at press time.</p>



<p>It was previously <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/trumps-limited-edition-sneakers-are-already-being-listed-for-up-to-45-000-on-ebay-but-can-they-hold-their-value-620c3bbc">reported</a> that someone listed a pair of the shoes for $45,000 — not $450,000 — on eBay. However, it is unclear whether or not they sold for that amount. At time of publication, a pair of the shoes recently <a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/326040246922?itmmeta=01HRQ4D8AQHDB4DCTBSD4EEGNF&amp;hash=item4be9835a8a:g:UkkAAOSwN-dl5e9C&amp;itmprp=enc%3AAQAIAAAA8DTP4EJj09NpDwvtC90FupDyA0%2FmUJlgqGk0JOwNqHG%2B9BfNBs55nu0xj%2B4t4PouYBhPkG06njbjIRzV90HAM%2BdH%2BEdeEKwx51sm0zgLitKgqFq3fgbFROBS6fjx8tXf6DVQi6dWXfk%2FnNRMGWRJvBt8062qkQANMe9rWflDPzFYmdCLON3YYyb2OogP8w0wAygCEIZj7niQXXHiTxKWT0%2BR0TemQc2F6mUbowpZypMxhXwNTTYd5U6q6bMHypvqNxMo2VBtq3soaLmOL--PX33aLnuxjUVu2qqBfUJHVHzxwZJk5YdfkW5Nul0yHAoTig%3D%3D%7Ctkp%3ABk9SR86FteTFYw">sold</a> for $5,100 on eBay.</p>



<p>“If you think of it, it’s an additional form of currency and I used to say, ‘I want one currency, I want the dollar, I don’t want people leaving the dollar,’” Trump said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“But I will tell you, it has taken on a life,” the former President added. “And I’m not sure that I’d want to take it away at this point.”</p>



<p>It’s not the first time the presumed Republican nominee has cashed in on the public’s growing interest in digital assets. His <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/cash-grab-trump-nfts-political-cultism">NFT collection last year</a> earned at least six figures of income, <a href="https://www.citizensforethics.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Disclosure-Report-Part-1-4-14-23.pdf">according</a> to 2023 financial disclosures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even so, Trump maintained that dollar dominance is still essential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I hate when countries go off the dollar. I would not allow countries to go off the dollar because when we lose that standard, that will be like losing a revolutionary war,” Trump said. “That will be a hit to our country just like losing a war, and we can’t let that happen.”&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/america-financial-alternative-crypto">America deserves a financial alternative — and it’s crypto</a></p>



<p>Trump’s comments come after Anthony Scaramucci, founder of alternative investment firm SkyBridge, said in an X Space last week that another Trump presidency would likely not be good for bitcoin.<br><br>“I did read the Constitution and I did go to law school,” said Scaramucci, who briefly worked as the White House communications director for ten days in 2017 under Trump. “[Trump’s] people are absolutely nuts, and you don’t want him to return to the presidency.”</p>



<p>Trump has previously tweeted negatively about bitcoin. In 2019, for example, the then-president said bitcoin and other crypto assets “are not money” — adding that their values are “highly volatile and based on thin air.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote data-dnt="true" data-width="550" class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am not a fan of Bitcoin and other Cryptocurrencies, which are not money, and whose value is highly volatile and based on thin air. Unregulated Crypto Assets can facilitate unlawful behavior, including drug trade and other illegal activity….</p>— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1149472282584072192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 12, 2019</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>In 2021, Trump <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-57392734#">told</a> the BBC that bitcoin “seems like a scam.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I don’t like it because it’s another currency competing against the dollar,” he added.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Scaramucci noted that while many voters tend to think Republicans are more favorable toward crypto, Trump is the exception.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“He really doesn’t have an opinion one way or another, but there are people who in general think [a] Republican [means] less regulation,” Scaramucci said. “But this is not a garden-variety Republican; this is a dangerous man with a very, very smart, well-disciplined team.”</p>



<p>Trump is currently leading in the Republican Presidential primary as the only candidate from the party still in the race. The former president currently faces four criminal indictments, totaling 91 felony counts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the civil front, Trump was found liable for sexual abuse and defamation against writer E. Jean Carol in 2023. In a separate proceeding, a federal jury awarded Carroll $83.3 million.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The former president also owes $454 million in civil penalties after being found liable for fraudulent financial reporting. Trump is appealing the case but is required to pay the full amount or purchase a bond to cover it by March 25.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump’s next legal hurdle comes this week in his classified documents case, in which prosecutors allege he mishandled confidential information at his Florida estate. Judge Aileen M. Cannon is scheduled to hear arguments related to two of Trump’s dismissal motions on Thursday in a hearing that is expected to take several days.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>Ben Strack contributed reporting.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Casey Wagner</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/casey-wagner</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="People" term="People"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T17:31:09.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[London Stock Exchange to accept physically-backed crypto ETN proposals]]></title>
        <id>https://blockworks.co/news/london-stock-exchange-crypto-etn-proposals</id>
        <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/london-stock-exchange-crypto-etn-proposals"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T15:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">
            <![CDATA[The FCA said Monday it would not object to such products being offered to professional investors]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>The London Stock Exchange is willing to soon consider proposals for certain crypto investment products given new guidance from the UK’s Financial Conduct Authority.</p>



<p>But such applications will need to meet a range of criteria.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The exchange giant said Monday in a “market notice” that it would start accepting applications for bitcoin and ether exchange traded notes (ETNs) in this year’s second quarter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ETNs are debt securities that, in this case, would offer exposure to BTC and ETH. Similar to crypto ETFs in the US and elsewhere, such products let investors trade securities that track their underlying crypto assets on-exchange during London trading hours.</p>



<p><strong>Following bitcoin ETFs? Stay up to date with our </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/bitcoin-etf"><strong>bitcoin ETF tracker</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>



<p>This comes as the <a href="https://blockworks.co/tag/fca">FCA</a> said in a statement Monday that it would not object to so-called recognized investment exchanges creating a market segment for such ETNs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“These products would be available for professional investors, such as investment firms and credit institutions authorized or regulated to operate in financial markets only,” the FCA <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/news/statements/fca-updates-position-cryptoasset-exchange-traded-notes-professional-investors">said</a> Monday.</p>



<p>The UK regulator had <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/news/press-releases/fca-bans-sale-crypto-derivatives-retail-consumers#:~:text=The%20FCA%20has%20published%20final,to%20the%20harm%20they%20pose.">banned</a> the sale, marketing and distribution of crypto-focused derivatives and ETNs to retail consumers in January 2021. The ban for that segment of investors remains in place, the FCA noted.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/uk-fca-crypto-firm-warnings">FCA issued 450 warnings to crypto firms in the final months of 2023</a><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The London Stock Exchange <a href="https://docs.londonstockexchange.com/sites/default/files/documents/crypto_etn_admission_factsheet.pdf">acknowledged</a> in a crypto ETN admission factsheet that, in light of the FCA’s guidance about crypto assets, admitting such products to trade “may be detrimental” to the exchange’s reputation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Therefore, proposed bitcoin and ether ETNs must be physically backed, it noted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The underlying crypto assets must be “wholly or principally held in cold storage,” the exchange added. In cases no such storage exists, the issuer will have to obtain third-party audit reports and secure regulated custodians.</p>



<p>“Given the nature of the product, and the admission guidance set out in this factsheet, standard admission timelines do not apply to crypto ETNs,” the London Stock Exchange said. “Issuers and their advisers should therefore liaise with the Exchange at the earliest opportunity to discuss their proposed admission.”</p>



<p>While the Securities and Exchange Commission <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/sec-approves-bitcoin-etf">approved physically backed bitcoin ETFs</a> in the US in January, the regulator has not yet greenlit spot ether funds.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etf-snapshot-inflows-near-high">Bitcoin ETF snapshot: GBTC competitors surpass Grayscale fund in AUM</a></p>



<p><a href="https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-sec-ethereum-etf-meeting">Coinbase met with the SEC about ether ETFs</a> last week. The US regulator is <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/bitcoin-etfs-approved-ether-funds-next">expected to rule on ETH products</a> proposed by Ark Invest, BlackRock, Fidelity and others in May.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">



<p><strong>Don’t miss the next big story – join our&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blockworks.co/newsletter?source=end">free daily newsletter</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Strack</name>
            <uri>https://blockworks.co/benstrack</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Finance" term="Finance"/>
        <published>2024-03-11T15:16:24.000Z</published>
        <rights>2024, Blockworks</rights>
    </entry>
</feed>