<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<atom:link href="https://coinjournal.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<description><![CDATA[Keep your finger on the pulse of the fast-moving cryptocurrency sector with all the latest crypto news, analysis and reviews from CoinJournal]]></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/apple-touch-icon.png</url>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Figure Markets CEO confirms FTX&#8217;s auction of remaining locked Solana (SOL)</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/figure-markets-ceo-confirms-ftxs-auction-of-remaining-locked-solana-sol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Thuo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>FTX to auction the remaining locked Solana (SOL) tokens. The last SOL token sale by FTX attracted significant buyer interest. Figure Markets confirms it will participate in the auction. The embattled FTX cryptocurrency exchange is set to auction the remaining locked Solana (SOL) tokens from its estate. The decision follows the success of the previous [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/figure-markets-ceo-confirms-ftxs-auction-of-remaining-locked-solana-sol/">Figure Markets CEO confirms FTX&#8217;s auction of remaining locked Solana (SOL)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FTX to auction the remaining locked Solana (SOL) tokens.</li>
<li>The last SOL token sale by FTX attracted significant buyer interest.</li>
<li>Figure Markets confirms it will participate in the auction.</li>
</ul>
<p>The embattled FTX cryptocurrency exchange is set to auction the remaining locked Solana (SOL) tokens from its estate. The decision follows the success of the previous sale, which generated significant interest from buyers.</p>
<p>The upcoming auction has been <a href="https://x.com/mcagney/status/1781804464028139848">confirmed by Mike Cagney</a>, the CEO of Figure Markets and board chair of Figure, who disclosed that the decentralized exchange will take part in the auction.</p>
<h2>Figure Markets introduces SPV investment opportunity</h2>
<p>To facilitate Figure Markets&rsquo; participation in the upcoming SOL auctions from the FTX estate, Figure Markets has unveiled a Special Purpose Vehicle (SPV) open to non-US investors (subject to KYC) and accredited US investors.</p>
<p>The SPV will operate based on community consensus, where each dollar invested equals one vote in determining bid prices and subsequent management decisions.</p>
<p>Investors interested in participating in the SPV can do so using USD, USDC, BTC, or ETH. Figure Markets will charge a 50 bps annual management fee to cover the costs of setting up the SPV and ongoing management. Additionally, while there&rsquo;s no confirmed timeline yet, Figure Markets intends to integrate the SPV into their exchange, allowing investors to use their investment as collateral for borrowing and margining.</p>
<p>By offering this investment opportunity, Figure Markets aims to provide investors with a streamlined way to participate in the auction of locked Solana tokens from the FTX estate. With the SPV structure, investors can have a say in bid prices and subsequent management decisions, creating a community-driven approach to investment in the cryptocurrency space.</p>
<h2>FTX&rsquo;s previous Solana (SOL) token sale</h2>
<p>The success of FTX&rsquo;s previous SOL token sale to industry giants like Pantera and Galaxy Digital&nbsp;cannot be understated.</p>
<p>With approximately $2.6 billion generated from selling two-thirds of its locked Solana tokens at around $60 per token, the FTX estate made significant gains from the sale.</p>
<p>For the investors, considering <a href="https://coinjournal.net/solana/">Solana&rsquo;s current price</a> hovering around $153, the decision to buy in previous Solana sales appears to have been a prudent one.</p>
<p>However, the volatile nature of cryptocurrencies calls for careful consideration and risk management especially seeing that the unlocking of huge amounts of tokens could create a surplus in supply and unless the demand goes through the roof, the token price could plummet.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/figure-markets-ceo-confirms-ftxs-auction-of-remaining-locked-solana-sol/">Figure Markets CEO confirms FTX&#8217;s auction of remaining locked Solana (SOL)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitbot gains as Ape Terminal cancels ZKasino IDO</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitbot-gains-as-ape-terminal-cancels-zkasino-ido/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 12:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ape Terminal, one of the top IDO platform&#8217;s in the market, has cancelled crypto betting platform ZKasino&#8217;s IDO. This unfolds as the broader crypto community is showing greater resilience amid Bitcoin&#8217;s halving. A few projects are however attracting as much attention as new crypto trading solution Bitbot. As Bitbot matches towards a highly successful presale, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/bitbot-gains-as-ape-terminal-cancels-zkasino-ido/">Bitbot gains as Ape Terminal cancels ZKasino IDO</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Ape Terminal, one of the top IDO platform&rsquo;s in the market, has cancelled crypto betting platform ZKasino&rsquo;s IDO.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">This unfolds as the broader crypto community is showing greater resilience amid Bitcoin&rsquo;s halving.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">A few projects are however attracting as much attention as new crypto trading solution Bitbot.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=current_news" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitbot</a> matches towards a highly successful presale, investors flocking to it are likely buoyed by what the project promises in the wake of events surrounding ZKasino, a decentralized betting network.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While the ZKasino team says the project will still launch as expected, it&rsquo;s likely to face challenges with regard to community trust after the rug pull allegations and <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/exchanges/">exchange</a> listing delays.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot brings non-custodial trading and anti-rug pull features to crypto</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot is one of the few emerging crypto projects that are pushing for market dominance. In particular, <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/game-changing-telegram-trading-bot-bitbot-reaches-2m-mark-in-presale/">Bitbot&rsquo;s eyes are on the Telegram bot space</a>, which analysts have predicted could explode as crypto prepares for the bull market proper.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">What makes Bitbot stand out in the market is its pioneering non-custodial trading feature. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">PAAL AI, Banana Gun, PaLM AI and Unibot have seen significant success since their launch. However, none of these solutions offer the industry-leading security that Bitbot pioneers with its non-custodial Telegram bot.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">When the bot launches in coming months, users will not only have the peace of mind of retaining full control of their assets as they trade, but also tap into additional security layers provided by anti-rug pull and anti-MEV tools.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">So it&rsquo;s not just Bitbot&rsquo;s non-custodial solution or its AI-powered trading tools, but also the protection users can get with the anti-rug pull feature. Bitbot team&rsquo;s transparency also adds to this positive outlook for the project, likely the reason the presale has raced to over $2.7 million.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Ape Terminal cancels IDO for ZKasino (ZKAS)</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Following concerns around a potential rug pull, IDO platform Ape Terminal announced it had cancelled ZKasino&rsquo;s initial DEX offering.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Ape Terminal&rsquo;s <a href="https://twitter.com/apeterminal/status/1781836764958830658" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> comes after ZigZag, a decentralised P2P orderbook exchange, published concerns about ZKasino and a potential $32 million rug pull.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Meanwhile, ZKasino participants have reportedly been unable to withdraw their money as the platform&rsquo;s team has moved all 10,515 ETH from the deposit contract to Lido.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Amid these allegations, some exchanges have announced paused listing plans of the ZKasino token ZKAS. Crypto exchange MEXC <a href="https://twitter.com/MEXC_Official/status/1781685207286079515" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> it would cancel ZKAS listing on Saturday.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">A lot of FUD going around.</p>
<p>The ZKasino network will still go live, it has been delayed due to exchange listings.</p>
<p>&mdash; ZKasino (@ZKasino_io) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZKasino_io/status/1781670189118976450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Ape Terminal said on April 21 that participants who opted into the crypto betting platform&rsquo;s DEX offering will receive a refund of their assets. Stablecoin claims are open, the platform posted on X.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot presale could be key opportunity</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The Bitbot native token BITBOT will power the new trading bot, providing users with another investment opportunity. Top of this is the chance to earn a share of platform revenue. Other perks are outlined via the project&rsquo;s whitepaper.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Currently, BITBOT token is priced at just $0.0163 in stage 11. As highlighted in the project&rsquo;s whitepaper, the presale price is scheduled to rise to $0.020 in stage 15, the final presale stage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot&rsquo;s launch will see it stand out as the only non-custodial Telegram trading bot in the market. Already, there&rsquo;s a strong community building around the project as its presale moves towards an end and the next few weeks could be an early opportunity for investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">To learn more about Bitbot, go to the <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=current_news" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website</a>.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/bitbot-gains-as-ape-terminal-cancels-zkasino-ido/">Bitbot gains as Ape Terminal cancels ZKasino IDO</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 crypto underdogs that could be ready to shine in the bull run</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/4-crypto-underdogs-that-could-be-ready-to-shine-in-the-bull-run/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 16:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR The Ethena (ENA) price is predicted to bounce back above $1.50. The Celestia (TIA) token is predicted to rise again and trade above $15. Experts predict that the SUI price will rise above $1.50. Rebel Satoshi ($RBLZ) surpasses 357 million $RECQ tokens sold during its skyrocketing presale. With the recent dip in the market, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/4-crypto-underdogs-that-could-be-ready-to-shine-in-the-bull-run/">4 crypto underdogs that could be ready to shine in the bull run</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">TLDR</span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400">The Ethena (ENA) price is predicted to bounce back above $1.50.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400">The Celestia (TIA) token is predicted to rise again and trade above $15.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400">Experts predict that the SUI price will rise above $1.50.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400">Rebel Satoshi ($RBLZ) surpasses 357 million $RECQ tokens sold during its skyrocketing presale.</li>
</ul>
<p>With the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/">recent dip in the market</a>, investors are on the lookout for the best cryptos to buy right now, and many are reaching the conclusion that Ethena (ENA), Celestia (TIA), and SUI could be the top crypto coins that are ready to shine. Meanwhile, <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4844&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rebel Satoshi</a>&rsquo;s ($RBLZ) new token, $RECQ, has continued to draw investors in hordes to its presale. Let&rsquo;s understand what makes ENA, TIA, SUI, and $RECQ some of the best altcoins to buy, according to experts.</p>
<h2>Ethena shows strength to bounce back from the dump</h2>
<p>The Ethena (ENA) token has performed tremendously ever since its launch in April. The Ethena (ENA) token rose to an all-time high of $1.50 on April 11. However, as the market soon dumped due to global factors and conflicts, Ethena (ENA) also dumped. The Ethena (ENA) token was down by nearly 38% to $0.93 on April 14.</p>
<p>Since then, the Ethena (ENA) price has recovered by nearly 14% to $1.06 on April 16. Amid the tumultuous price action, Ethena (ENA) announced <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/binance-adds-ethena-ena-as-50th-launchpool-project/">integration with Web3 wallets like Binance</a>, Bybit, OKX, and Bitget on April 10.</p>
<p>These developments have led to a bullish outlook on the Ethena (ENA) token. Some experts predict that the Ethena (ENA) token will rise above $1.50 in the coming months.</p>
<h2>Celestia reclaims $10 support amid fresh surge</h2>
<p>As the market dropped on April 12, the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/celestia-price-declines-as-okb-and-rebel-satoshi-arcade-soar/">Celestia (TIA) token</a> also witnessed a massive drop. The Celestia (TIA) token was trading at $11.19 on April 12 and dumped by 24.3% to $8.46 on April 14. As a result, the Celestia (TIA) token lost its $10 support for the first time in months as a result.</p>
<p>Since then, the Celestia (TIA) token has risen by 20.4% to $10.19 on April 16. While the Celestia (TIA) price dropped, NodeKit announced its integration with Celestia on April 12. Celestia&rsquo;s (TIA) Infinite Space Bazaar hackathon surpassed 1000 entries on April 15.</p>
<p>These developments have resulted in many experts having a bullish outlook on Celestia (TIA). They predict that the Celestia (TIA) token will rise above $15 going forward.</p>
<h2>SUI rises above $1 again after a brief drop below</h2>
<p>Just like the other tokens, the SUI price also turned bearish as the market dropped on April 12. The SUI token was trading at $1.51 on April 12 before facing a drop. The SUI token was down by 37.7% to $0.94 on April 14 before <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/sui-spikes-11-as-btc-eth-slide-heres-why-sui-price-is-surging/">bouncing back again</a>. The SUI price has since risen by 23.4% to $1.16 on April 16.</p>
<p>While its price suffered, SUI announced the first handheld gaming device, SuiPlayOX1, with native Web3 capabilities on April 10. On the same day, Blocktrade announced its groundbreaking partnership with the SUI Network.</p>
<p>Due to the constant growth, the outlook for SUI is bullish, and some experts predict a surge above $1.50.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=MCAP&amp;utm_medium=Banner&amp;utm_id=Bird" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-199551 aligncenter" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/rebel-satoshi.png" alt="" width="728" height="90"></a></p>
<h2>Rebel Satoshi soars past 360 million milestone in the $RECQ presale</h2>
<p>The innovative and groundbreaking project, Rebel Satoshi, is built on the Ethereum network. Drawing inspiration from Guy Fawkes and Satoshi Nakamoto, Rebel Satoshi aims to bring a decentralized revolution to the market. The Rebel Satoshi rebellion is led by its Recusant community members as they rise against the elites to take back control.</p>
<p>Rebel Satoshi has a vast ecosystem comprising an NFT vault, a gaming Arcade, exclusive merchandise, and staking pools. The Rebel Satoshi ecosystem is built around its dual-token system of the $RBLZ and the $RECQ tokens. Rebel Satoshi aims to grow to a market cap of $100 million and raised over $2.5 million with the $RBLZ presale.</p>
<p><a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4844&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rebel Satoshi</a> is conducting the presale of the $RECQ token in Stage 1 at $0.0037 right now. The $RECQ token has rallied by 85% already, and over 360 million tokens have been sold.</p>
<p>The $RECQ token will rise to its launch price of $0.0125 by the end of the presale. The $RECQ token should generate 237.8% returns for current investors at that stage. As a result, some analysts are suggesting that the $RECQ token could be one of the best cryptos to invest in right now.</p>
<p><b>For the latest updates and more information, be sure to visit the official </b><a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Rebel Satoshi Website</b></a><b> or contact Rebel Red via</b> <a href="https://t.me/RBLZRED" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Telegram</b></a></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/4-crypto-underdogs-that-could-be-ready-to-shine-in-the-bull-run/">4 crypto underdogs that could be ready to shine in the bull run</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hedgey Protocol loses $44.7M in dual cyber attacks</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/hedgey-protocol-loses-44-7m-in-dual-cyber-attacks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Thuo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 17:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hedgey Protocol suffers $44.7M loss in dual cyber attacks. The protocol was targeted on both Arbitrum and Ethereum chains. Hedgey advises users to cancel active claims, revoking approvals amid the ongoing investigation. Hedgey Protocol, a decentralized finance (DeFi) platform, finds itself in the throes of a cyber siege after suffering a devastating attack that resulted [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/hedgey-protocol-loses-44-7m-in-dual-cyber-attacks/">Hedgey Protocol loses $44.7M in dual cyber attacks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hedgey Protocol suffers $44.7M loss in dual cyber attacks.</li>
<li>The protocol was targeted on both Arbitrum and Ethereum chains.</li>
<li>Hedgey advises users to cancel active claims, revoking approvals amid the ongoing investigation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hedgey Protocol, a decentralized finance (DeFi) platform, finds itself in the throes of a cyber siege after suffering a devastating attack that resulted in a staggering loss of $44.7 million across the Arbitrum and <a href="https://coinjournal.net/ethereum/what-is-ethereum/">Ethereum</a> blockchains.</p>
<p>Cyvers Alerts, a leading cybersecurity watchdog, uncovered the vulnerabilities exploited in the attack, raising urgent concerns about the security landscape within the DeFi ecosystem.</p>
<h2>Hedgey Protocol hacked on Arbitrum and Ethereum chains</h2>
<p>Cyvers Alerts revealed that the attack targeted Hedgey Protocol on both the Arbitrum and Ethereum chains, with $42.8 million and $1.9 million stolen, respectively.</p>
<p><a href="https://x.com/CyversAlerts/status/1781271050073841735">According to Cyners Alerts</a>, the attackers swiftly converted the stolen funds into DAI, complicating recovery efforts. Furthermore, additional transactions on the Arbitrum chain signalled potential vulnerabilities within the ecosystem, necessitating prompt action.</p>
<p>In response, <a href="https://x.com/hedgeyfinance/status/1781257581488418862">Hedgey Protocol acknowledged the attack</a> and they have said that they have launched a comprehensive investigation into the breach, working closely with security experts and auditors to understand the attack&rsquo;s root cause.</p>
<p>As the investigation unfolds, Hedgey Protocol issued urgent advisories to its users, urging them to cancel active claims and revoke all approvals to mitigate the risk of further exploitation. They recommended an immediate review of approvals while the investigation progresses to ensure users&rsquo; security and prevent any potential loss of funds. Additionally, users were warned to remain vigilant against scammers attempting to capitalize on the situation, emphasizing the importance of cautious online behaviour.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Security Alert: We're investigating an attack on the Hedgey Token Claim Contract. If you have created active claims, please cancel them using the "End Token Claim" button at <a href="https://t.co/Tt7Aq0n2dh">https://t.co/Tt7Aq0n2dh</a>. </p>
<p>We are are actively working with our auditors and team to understand the attack&hellip;</p>
<p>&mdash; Hedgey &#129428; (@hedgeyfinance) <a href="https://twitter.com/hedgeyfinance/status/1781257581488418862?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>The Hedgey Protocol cyber attack underscores the interconnectedness of DeFi platforms and the imperative for robust security protocols in the evolving landscape of decentralized finance.</p>
<p>As stakeholders collaborate to address vulnerabilities and enhance security measures, the incident serves as a stark reminder of the ongoing challenges posed by cyber threats in the digital asset space.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/hedgey-protocol-loses-44-7m-in-dual-cyber-attacks/">Hedgey Protocol loses $44.7M in dual cyber attacks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Telegram to tokenize emojis and stickers as NFTs on TON blockchain</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/telegram-to-tokenize-emojis-and-stickers-as-nfts-on-ton-blockchain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Telegram co-founder and CEO Pavel Durov announced the plans at Token2049 Dubai. The tokenization project will use the TON blockchain. Toncoin price rose as TON Foundation and Tether partnered to bring USDT to TON blockchain. Telegram is taking a major step in its blockchain technology adoption with a new effort announced today during Token2049 Dubai. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/telegram-to-tokenize-emojis-and-stickers-as-nfts-on-ton-blockchain/">Telegram to tokenize emojis and stickers as NFTs on TON blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Telegram co-founder and CEO Pavel Durov announced the plans at Token2049 Dubai.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">The tokenization project will use the TON blockchain.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin price rose as TON Foundation and Tether partnered to bring USDT to TON blockchain.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Telegram is taking a major step in its blockchain technology adoption with a new effort announced today during</span> <a href="https://youtu.be/gBEOJRvZ-wI" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Token2049 Dubai</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The popular messaging app&rsquo;s co-founder and CEO Pavel Durov revealed this next step on Friday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">According to Durov, the company&rsquo;s tokenization journey now includes plans to tokenize Telegram stickers and emojis as non-fungible tokens (NFTs).</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Telegram plans tokenized stickers</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Telegram&rsquo;s initiative follows the notable success of tokenized usernames and anonymous numbers. Already, users can earn up to 95% of revenue that comes from the sale of the unique usernames.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Tokenization is the next step in Telegram&rsquo;s growth, Durov said, highlighting the role blockchain technology is set to play in this. The project will &ldquo;exclusively&rdquo; leverage The Open Network (TON) blockchain, the Telegram CEO noted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Commenting on the success recorded so far, Durov said:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400">&ldquo;We don&rsquo;t want to stay there. We want to go further. You see, we believe in socially-relevant NFTs. We believe in NFTs that are deeply integrated into human culture, into human interaction, into our communication. NFTs that you can see tens of billions of times and have a lot of potential to spread virally. These are the right NFTs. That&rsquo;s why the next step that we are going to undertake is tokenizing Telegram stickers.&rdquo;</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><a href="https://coinjournal.net/toncoin/">Toncoin (TON)</a>, the native token of TON blockchain, soared in recent months after Telegram rolled out its &lsquo;Ad Network&rsquo;. Users can now pay for in-platform adverts, with the initiative offering a 50% share of ad-revenue to channel owners and creators.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Earlier today, TON price rose sharply to $7.20 amid the NFT news. The token&rsquo;s value also gained after news that stablecoin issuer Tether had <a href="https://twitter.com/ton_blockchain/status/1781294469901373931" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched its USDT on the TON blockchain</a>.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/telegram-to-tokenize-emojis-and-stickers-as-nfts-on-ton-blockchain/">Telegram to tokenize emojis and stickers as NFTs on TON blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Milei Moneda presale challenges existing meme coins FLOKI and BONK: Which one has room for higher price?</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/milei-moneda-presale-challenges-existing-meme-coins-floki-and-bonk-which-one-has-room-for-higher-price/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199410</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR Milei Moneda ($MEDA) investors are forecast to gain 60% ROI at launch. FLOKI dips as the threat of war looms. BONK remains resilient despite sell pressure. Milei Moneda&#8217;s ($MEDA) presale is attracting a growing number of investors thanks to its potential profit margins. Binance extends support for Floki (FLOKI) as the cryptocurrency gains popularity. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/milei-moneda-presale-challenges-existing-meme-coins-floki-and-bonk-which-one-has-room-for-higher-price/">Milei Moneda presale challenges existing meme coins FLOKI and BONK: Which one has room for higher price?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>TLDR</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Milei Moneda ($MEDA) investors are forecast to gain 60% ROI at launch.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">FLOKI dips as the threat of war looms.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">BONK remains resilient despite sell pressure.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Milei Moneda&rsquo;s ($MEDA) presale is attracting a growing number of investors thanks to its potential profit margins. Binance extends support for Floki (FLOKI) as the cryptocurrency gains popularity. Meanwhile, a reputable fintech adopts Bonk (BONK).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">How impressive is $MEDA&rsquo;s presale gain? And is it the best cryptocurrency to buy ahead of Floki and Bonk? Let&rsquo;s dig into the data.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://mileimoneda.io/?utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_id=782" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Economize Like Milei: Invest in $MEDA</span></a></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Milei Moneda&rsquo;s presale offers 60% gains</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Milei Moneda is a new meme coin that combines humor, politics, and blockchain technology. The project has recently become popular due to its lucrative presale. The presale is currently in Stage 2, and the $MEDA token is sold for $0.0125.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Stage 1 investors have already earned a 25% profit. They&rsquo;re forecast to gain a total of 100% on their initial investment when the presale ends. Similarly, Stage 2 investors are forecast to earn a 60% profit when $MEDA becomes $0.020 at the end of the presale.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In addition, investors become a part of Milei Moneda&rsquo;s vibrant community on Reddit, Discord, and X. They can meet other members and participate in giveaways and Q&amp;A sessions. Also, Milei Moneda investors get voting rights and access to exclusive NFT collections. They also earn NFT staking rewards and discounts.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Furthermore, $MEDA is a deflationary token. Supply is fixed at 500 million, while five percent of this supply will be burned to maintain price stability.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Finally, Milei Moneda is protected through locked liquidity, smart contract audits, and zero team allocations. All these reveal why many analysts and investors are suggesting $MEDA could be the best crypto to invest in now.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://mileimoneda.io/?utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_id=782" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Economize Like Milei: Invest in $MEDA</span></a></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Binance introduces new Floki pairs</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">On March 26, 2024, Binance </span><a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/notice-on-new-trading-pairs-trading-bots-services-on-binance-spot-2024-03-27-0f3ce0f5305e47659ca47d42d0c5cd91" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">announced</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> that it would list new <a href="https://coinjournal.net/floki/">Floki</a> trading pairs. This move comes as meme coins take center stage, consequently increasing Floki&rsquo;s popularity. The new pair, FLOKI/USDC, will be added to Binance Spot on March 28. Bot services will also be available to users who want to trade the pair.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Furthermore, clients based in the USA and its territories, Canada, Japan, Iran, Cuba, North Korea, Syria, Netherlands, and any non-government-controlled areas of Ukraine won&rsquo;t be able to trade the new Floki pair.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Since the news broke, Floki has plummeted 42.7%, falling from $0.000241 to $0.000138. This significant slump has been attributed to investors seeking safety in more stable investments after tensions escalated between Iran and Israel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Analysts predict that Floki will remain around $0.000153 as long as the political situation in the Middle East remains unstable.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Bonk gets support from TradFi firm</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">On February 16, popular fintech Revolut </span><a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/revolut-list-bonk-distribute-1-191655835.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAGdyNd2GWVqwD9sPKpA3k9NjwK3vhjgariJ5hgIR_m3ojdR_A_j6K8zAL8v__tOH8yR7hr9KPdb-GvL3xZKrTWCdLNDPCucmWuH-7eehV6aXF9sruNzGY2JnCcjJcXXRTGxurxLzoLh4Ui0ps4EjIoz870tkUo3eaWx7X5AcyIpW" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">announced</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> that it was listing Bonk on its platform. Bonk is one of the Solana meme coins driving the current meme coin frenzy and will be the first from Solana. The meme coin will become accessible to Revolut&rsquo;s 30 million customers, increasing adoption.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/revolut/">Revolut</a> will also institute an education program for Bonk. Plans are in place to distribute 93 billion Bonk to users during this education campaign. Analysts say this development signals Bonk&rsquo;s increasing mainstream acceptance.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This acceptance is evident in Bonk&rsquo;s increased price. The token gained 157% in less than one month after the announcement. It increased from $0.000014 to $0.000036 in. However, a market-wide sell-off triggered by the political tensions in the Middle East has ensured that Bonk is back to $0.000014.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">However, analysts predict that Bonk could reach $0.000067 after the Bitcoin Halving. This makes the token one of the important altcoins this year.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Conclusion</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Milei Moneda&rsquo;s successful presale, which has sold over 59 million tokens to date, is challenging existing meme coins FLOKI and BONK, with early investors already experiencing 25% ROI &amp; those that invest in its current presale stage 2 projected to gain a 60% ROI. The success of Milei Moneda is causing analysts to speculate that this coin could have major upside potential.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong>Got $MEDA curiosity? <a href="https://mileimoneda.io/?utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_id=782" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Visit us</a> or chat on <a href="https://t.me/mileimoneda" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Telegram</a> for the inside scoop. Fast, fun, and informative!</strong></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/milei-moneda-presale-challenges-existing-meme-coins-floki-and-bonk-which-one-has-room-for-higher-price/">Milei Moneda presale challenges existing meme coins FLOKI and BONK: Which one has room for higher price?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celestia price declines as OKB and Rebel Satoshi Arcade soar</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/celestia-price-declines-as-okb-and-rebel-satoshi-arcade-soar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199395</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR: Celestia&#8217;s price has dropped 12.7% in the past week. OKB&#8217;s price has increased 4.9% on the 14-day price chart. OKX&#8217;s launch of the X Layer network might be responsible for the recent gains.&#160; Rebel Satoshi Arcade is on the rise, with its crypto ICO selling over 355 million tokens in stage 1. The crypto [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/celestia-price-declines-as-okb-and-rebel-satoshi-arcade-soar/">Celestia price declines as OKB and Rebel Satoshi Arcade soar</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>TLDR:</b></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Celestia&rsquo;s price has dropped 12.7% in the past week.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">OKB&rsquo;s price has increased 4.9% on the 14-day price chart. OKX&rsquo;s launch of the X Layer network might be responsible for the recent gains.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Rebel Satoshi Arcade is on the rise, with its crypto ICO selling over 355 million tokens in stage 1.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/">crypto market</a> witnessed a massive shift lately that left several top crypto coins gasping for air. The likes of Celestia were among the first to feel the heat, as it dropped 12.7% on the weekly price chart. Meanwhile, OKB and Rebel Satoshi Arcade are currently in the green, thanks to recent developments in their respective ecosystems.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Rebel Satoshi Arcade ($RECQ) presale soars due to its decentralized gaming platform&nbsp;</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Rebel Satoshi Arcade ($RECQ) is a new DeFi project that has hit a remarkable milestone, selling 80% of the tokens for stage one of its crypto ICO in a short amount of time.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4832&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Rebel Satoshi</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> is building a decentralized gaming ecosystem where members are at the top of the food chain. The gaming ecosystem does not have a centralized authority that makes the decision.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Instead, the members of the community make the decisions; they have a say in the platform&rsquo;s operations, the kind of crypto games that are released, and so many other rights. Apart from being a decentralized platform, Rebel Satoshi Arcade operates on a play-to-earn model &ndash; gamers are rewarded for playing games, giving them a source of passive income.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Finally, Rebel Satoshi Arcade has a marketplace where players can buy several assets like new gaming tools, upgrade their weapons, and even add the best NFTs to their collections. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The token used for these transactions is the $RECQ token. In addition to its use as a transaction token, the $RECQ token gives its holders access to top NFTs and new games that are yet to hit the market, you can join before that for only $0.0037 per RECQ token.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Celestia (TIA) price continues to consolidate</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Since reaching an all-time high of $20.85 on February 10, 2024, Celestia (TIA) has been on a downtrend. The alt coin is now trading between $8.52 and $11.88 in April after falling 12.7% in the past week.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">There has been a relentless battle between bulls and bears, with neither showing dominance. As a result, TIA continues to consolidate at the range of $8-11. Nonetheless, Celestia stayed in the top 50 cryptocurrencies, trading at $10.5 with a market cap of $1.88 billion.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">OKB (OKB) price surges as OKX launches its own L2 network&nbsp;</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The native token of the OKX crypto exchange, <a href="https://coinjournal.net/okb/">OKB (OKB)</a>, has been bullish, defying the bearish trend in the crypto market. The price of OKB recently recorded a new all-time high at $73.80 in mid-March but couldn&rsquo;t retain the bullish momentum above $70.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Retracing with the rest of the crypto market, OKB has dropped back to the $50.61 &ndash; $61.16 price zone. However, following the announcement from OKX about the release of the l<a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/okx-launches-public-mainnet-for-its-zk-powered-l2-network-x-layer/">ayer-2 (L2 network) called X layer</a>, OKB has regained bullish momentum. The altcoin is up by 9% since April 13, forcing a retest of the $60 resistance.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">In summary</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Celestia is still among the top 50 cryptocurrencies in the market despite its poor price movement. Meanwhile, OKB and </span><a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4832&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Rebel Satoshi</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> Arcade are two top altcoins that are in the green. While the recent development around OKX is responsible for OKB&rsquo;s latest surge, that of Rebel Satoshi Arcade is its gaming platform.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><b>For the latest updates and more information, be sure to visit the official </b><a href="http://www.rebelsatoshi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Rebel Satoshi Website</b></a><b> or contact Rebel Red via </b><a href="https://t.me/rebelsatoshi_news" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Telegram</b></a><b>, </b><a href="https://twitter.com/rebel_satoshi" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Twitter</b></a><b>, or </b><a href="https://discord.gg/f8fNQnN9WH" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Discord</b></a><b>.</b></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/celestia-price-declines-as-okb-and-rebel-satoshi-arcade-soar/">Celestia price declines as OKB and Rebel Satoshi Arcade soar</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TRON investors considering TON and Bitbot amid SEC lawsuit against Justin Sun</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/tron-investors-considering-ton-and-bitbot-amid-sec-lawsuit-against-justin-sun/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Thuo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 12:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TRON News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SEC lawsuit against Justin Sun casts doubt on TRON&#8217;s future. TON Network&#8217;s integration of USDT boosts Toncoin price by 12%. Bitbot&#8217;s AI-powered trading platform and $BITBOT token offer innovative solutions. As the cryptocurrency market navigates through turbulent waters, TRON investors are exploring alternative options amidst a legal battle involving Justin Sun, the founder of TRON [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tron-investors-considering-ton-and-bitbot-amid-sec-lawsuit-against-justin-sun/">TRON investors considering TON and Bitbot amid SEC lawsuit against Justin Sun</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SEC lawsuit against Justin Sun casts doubt on TRON&rsquo;s future.</li>
<li>TON Network&rsquo;s integration of USDT boosts Toncoin price by 12%.</li>
<li>Bitbot&rsquo;s AI-powered trading platform and $BITBOT token offer innovative solutions.</li>
</ul>
<p>As the cryptocurrency market navigates through turbulent waters, TRON investors are exploring alternative options amidst a legal battle involving Justin Sun, the founder of TRON (TRX).</p>
<p>The recent lawsuit filed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) against Sun has prompted investors to seek refuge in projects such as the TON Network and <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=investment_opportunity">Bitbot</a>.</p>
<h2>SEC&rsquo;s lawsuit casts a shadow over TRON (TRX)</h2>
<p>The SEC&rsquo;s legal action against Justin Sun has sent shockwaves through the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/tron/what-is-tron/">TRON</a> community.</p>
<p>The accusations of selling unregistered securities through TRON&rsquo;s native token (TRX) and BitTorrent&rsquo;s token (BTT) have cast doubt on the future of these assets.</p>
<p>Sun&rsquo;s alleged involvement in deceptive practices, including wash trading and undisclosed paid celebrity endorsements, has further exacerbated concerns among investors.</p>
<p>As the legal battle unfolds, investors are grappling with the uncertainty surrounding TRON&rsquo;s regulatory status and the potential ramifications for its market value.</p>
<p>The outcome of this lawsuit could redefine the regulatory landscape for TRON and other cryptocurrencies, potentially leading to increased scrutiny and tighter controls on their operations.</p>
<h2>USDT support added to TON Network boosting Toncoin price</h2>
<p>Amidst the regulatory turmoil facing TRON, the recent announcement of <a href="https://coinjournal.net/tether/what-is-tether/">Tether (USDT)</a> support on the TON Network has injected a sense of optimism into the cryptocurrency market.</p>
<p>Tether&rsquo;s decision to integrate its stablecoin with TON expands its presence across the crypto sphere, providing users with a seamless experience for peer-to-peer payments and value transfers.</p>
<p>In response to this development, Toncoin has experienced a surge in price, reaching $7.09 and marking a 12% daily increase. This bullish momentum reflects investors&rsquo; confidence in the potential of TON Network and the broader ecosystem it encompasses.</p>
<p>The integration of USDT on TON not only enhances liquidity but also opens up new avenues for decentralized applications across various verticals.</p>
<h2>Bitbot: revolutionizing cryptocurrency trading</h2>
<p>Just like Toncoin, Bitbot, a sophisticated Telegram-based AI-powered trading bot designed to enhance the trading experience, is also attracting investors&rsquo; attention.</p>
<p>Bitbot&rsquo;s platform provides users with real-time data, technical analysis, and seamless execution, levelling the playing field for both novice and experienced traders.</p>
<p>At the heart of Bitbot&rsquo;s ecosystem is its native token, $BITBOT, which offers holders exclusive benefits such as revenue sharing and governance rights. The token is currently in its <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=investment_opportunity">presale stage</a> which has already raised $2,603,234 out of its $2,844,000 target, reflecting growing demand for Bitbot&rsquo;s innovative solutions.</p>
<p>The current presale price is $0.0163 per token giving early investors an investment opportunity seeing that the price is set to increase to $0.0171 in the next presale stage.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>As TRON investors navigate through uncertain waters, TON Network and new projects like Bitbot offer promising alternatives for those seeking stability and growth opportunities in the ever-evolving cryptocurrency market.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, as with any cryptocurrency investment, investors should conduct thorough research before investing owing to the extremely volatile nature of cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tron-investors-considering-ton-and-bitbot-amid-sec-lawsuit-against-justin-sun/">TRON investors considering TON and Bitbot amid SEC lawsuit against Justin Sun</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain Expo North America 2024 set to showcase latest developments in crypto innovation</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/blockchain-expo-north-america-2024-set-to-showcase-latest-developments-in-crypto-innovation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Hoey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 11:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain developers, influencers, leaders, investors, entrepreneurs, and business owners from around the world are gearing up for this year&#8217;s Blockchain Expo North America 2024, one of North America&#8217;s premier blockchain and cryptocurrency events, which will&#160;take place on 5th and 6th June 2024 at the Santa Clara Convention Center, in California. The event will generate opportunities [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/blockchain-expo-north-america-2024-set-to-showcase-latest-developments-in-crypto-innovation/">Blockchain Expo North America 2024 set to showcase latest developments in crypto innovation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain developers, influencers, leaders, investors, entrepreneurs, and business owners from around the world are gearing up for this year&rsquo;s <a href="https://blockchain-expo.com/northamerica/">Blockchain Expo North America 2024</a>, one of North America&rsquo;s premier blockchain and cryptocurrency events, which will</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;take place on 5</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and 6</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> June 2024 at the Santa Clara Convention Center, in California. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The event will generate opportunities for collaboration, networking and exploration, while keeping participants at the forefront of the rapidly evolving blockchain and crypto landscape.</span></p>
<p>Announcing this year&rsquo;s Expo, Megan Davis, Director of Techforge, said:</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;The Blockchain Expo North America 2024 will serve as a hub for those wanting to learn about the latest</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> tools, platforms, and technologies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Our visitors will leave inspired &amp; equipped with the insights needed to shape the future of their blockchain projects.&rdquo;</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attendees can expect a dynamic environment with opportunities for networking and knowledge-sharing. Engage with local and global developers, connect with potential clients, talent, and partners, and learn the latest blockchain technology updates. Meet CEOs of international companies to forge new partnerships and explore trends for the next bull run.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Delve into the industry&rsquo;s most promising projects, discovering those with the highest ROI potential in 2024. Meet valuable startups, potentially identifying the next unicorn to invest in, and gain access to startup pitch decks. This event is a platform for industry professionals to collaborate, innovate, and share knowledge.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the two days, attendees can expect intensive knowledge-sharing sessions, technical workshops, fire-side chats, and insightful panel discussions, all aimed at keeping participants up to date on the latest trends and advancements in blockchain technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Industry leaders who have confirmed their participation, include:&nbsp;</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bob Ejodame, VP Capital Markets, at&nbsp;</span><b>INX</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Autumn Moss Penaloza, Head of Global Community at&nbsp;</span><b>Algorand Foundation</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Miguel Guillen, Director Of Data Architecture at&nbsp;</span><b>PepsiCo</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cody Carbone, Chief Policy Officer at </span><b>The Digital Chamber</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ettore Rossetti, Head Advisor, Technology/Marketing and Innovation Partnerships at </span><b>Save the Children</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">..and more!&nbsp;</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to keynote presentations and panel discussions, attendees will have the chance to engage with leading </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">exchanges, coins, trading platforms and big brand names who will showcase their latest blockchain technology</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From blockchain-powered applications to decentralized finance platforms, the exhibition promises a glimpse into the future of technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you&rsquo;re a seasoned blockchain expert or a newcomer to the industry, the Blockchain Expo North America 2024 offers something for everyone. Don&rsquo;t miss this opportunity to meet with crypto leaders, learn the latest industry trends and explore potential partnership or investment opportunities.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><a href="https://blockchain-expo.com/northamerica/"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-199369 size-full" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/expo.jpg" alt="" width="1800" height="900"></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more information and to secure your spot, visit </span><a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/northamerica/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.blockchain-expo.com/northamerica/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/blockchain-expo-north-america-2024-set-to-showcase-latest-developments-in-crypto-innovation/">Blockchain Expo North America 2024 set to showcase latest developments in crypto innovation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
