<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<atom:link href="https://coinjournal.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<description><![CDATA[Keep your finger on the pulse of the fast-moving cryptocurrency sector with all the latest crypto news, analysis and reviews from CoinJournal]]></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:14:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/apple-touch-icon.png</url>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Injective and Jambo partner to bring mobile-based DeFi to millions in emerging markets</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/injective-and-jambo-partner-to-bring-mobile-based-defi-to-millions-in-emerging-markets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto adoption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Injective and Web3 mobile firm Jambo will partner to promote DeFi in Africa, Latin America and Southeast Asia. The collaboration seeks to make it easy for millions to access dApps via the Jambophone. Injective and Web3 mobile infrastructure platform Jambo have announced a partnership that will see the two companies collaborate to bring blockchain-powered financial [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/injective-and-jambo-partner-to-bring-mobile-based-defi-to-millions-in-emerging-markets/">Injective and Jambo partner to bring mobile-based DeFi to millions in emerging markets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Injective and Web3 mobile firm Jambo will partner to promote DeFi in Africa, Latin America and Southeast Asia.</li>
<li>The collaboration seeks to make it easy for millions to access dApps via the Jambophone.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><a href="https://coinjournal.net/injective/">Injective</a> and Web3 mobile infrastructure platform Jambo have announced a partnership that will see the two companies collaborate to bring blockchain-powered financial solutions to millions of users in emerging markets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The partnership will tap into JamboPhone, a Web3 Android 13 smartphone, to introduce users across Africa, Latin America and Southeast Asia to Injective&rsquo;s DeFi ecosystem.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><em>&ldquo;Combining Injective&rsquo;s robust infrastructure stack with Jambo&rsquo;s mature Web3 mobile technology will enable us to efficiently scale DeFi to the point where it can tangibly help billions of people overcome socioeconomic hurdles,</em>&rdquo; Mirza Uddin, head of business at Injective Labs said in an <a href="https://blog.injective.com/en/injective-and-jambo-bring-mobile-based-defi-to-millions-in-emerging-markets/">announcement</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As part of the collaboration, users in these emerging markets will access multiple decentralised applications (dApps) in the Injective ecosystem via JamboPlay dApp store. One of the first platforms to be available will be Ninji, a native Injective wallet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">&ldquo;We want to bring emerging markets on-chain,&rdquo; James Zhang, co-founder of Jambo, noted.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Web3 phone for DeFi adoption</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">JamboPhone is currently priced at $99 and has been sold in more than 100 countries. The Web3 phone features preloaded applications that include DeFi, gaming, and Web3 infrastructure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The partnership continues Jambo&rsquo;s commitment to promoting the crypto adoption space in Africa and other emerging markets. It&rsquo;s also part of Injective&rsquo;s mission, with the blockchain platform offering an interoperable layer 1 network optimised for Web3.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Injective, incubated by Binance, counts Pantera, Jump Crypto and Mark Cuban among its backers. The native token INJ is currently the 45</span><span style="font-weight: 400">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400">-largest cryptocurrency by market cap.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Following today&rsquo;s partnership announcement, INJ price has surged more than 12% in 24 hours to reach highs of $28.47.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/injective-and-jambo-partner-to-bring-mobile-based-defi-to-millions-in-emerging-markets/">Injective and Jambo partner to bring mobile-based DeFi to millions in emerging markets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shiba Inu burns 774M SHIB, Solana bearish despite congestion fix, NuggetRush introduces NFTs</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/shiba-inu-burns-774m-shib-solana-bearish-despite-congestion-fix-nuggetrush-introduces-nfts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Solana&#8217;s price has plunged 21.8% in the last seven days despite fixing its recent network congestion issues. The Shiba Inu community has burnt over 774 million tokens in the past week. NuggetRush&#8217;s crypto mining game integrates NFTs with blockchain gaming. Despite a 21.8% price drop over the last week, investors remain hopeful that the new [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/shiba-inu-burns-774m-shib-solana-bearish-despite-congestion-fix-nuggetrush-introduces-nfts/">Shiba Inu burns 774M SHIB, Solana bearish despite congestion fix, NuggetRush introduces NFTs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Solana&rsquo;s price has plunged 21.8% in the last seven days despite fixing its recent network congestion issues.</li>
<li>The Shiba Inu community has burnt over 774 million tokens in the past week.</li>
<li>NuggetRush&rsquo;s crypto mining game integrates NFTs with blockchain gaming.</li>
</ul>
<p>Despite a 21.8% price drop over the last week, investors remain hopeful that the new update will resolve network congestion on the Solana network. The update is expected to bring a positive turnaround in the market for SOL.</p>
<p>At the same time, the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/shiba-inu/what-is-shiba-inu/">Shiba Inu</a> community has burned over 774 million tokens in just one week. <a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=78">NuggetRush</a>, meanwhile, has integrated some of the best NFTs into their new crypto mining game. The target is to offer its users a real-world gaming experience.</p>
<h2>NuggetRush (NUGX) raises excitement in the gaming space with NFTs</h2>
<p><a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=78">NuggetRush (NUGX)</a> is building a platform where players can assemble the best mining team to explore and mine precious minerals like gold, silver, and diamond. The platform has trending NFTs, which have different users on its gaming platform.</p>
<p>Firstly, these NFTs serve as the characters of players and give them unique abilities. These unique abilities &ndash; speed, mining knowledge, and lots more add fun to the game, making it interesting. In addition to the NFTs acting as characters, there are some rare NFTs called RUSHGEMs.</p>
<p>Fans have described them as the coolest NFTs, as they can be exchanged for real gold, making them one of the most searched NFTs in the game. Lastly, NFTs can be staked to receive a passive income of up to 20% APY. The amount earned as passive income will depend on the amount of stake and the duration of the stake.</p>
<p>Whichever is the case, NuggetRush&rsquo;s NFTs are being hailed by some as the best NFTs to invest in. The NuggetRush airdrop for its NUGX token is less than a week from now, and investors are excited. The NUGX token, which will be listed at $0.020, could rise 50x after its listing this quarter, according to some chartists.</p>
<h2>Solana (SOL) price drops to lows at $120</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/solana/">Solana (SOL) price</a> has been on a steep decline in the past week, dropping 21.8% to $124.69. The &ldquo;Ethereum killer&rdquo; was greatly affected by the latest bear market and issues of failed transactions on its network. Meanwhile, Anza, the development team behind Solana, has launched a new update, v1.17.31, to solve the issue of network congestion.</p>
<p>While this is not a major fix, the team said it would release other updates to complete the issue. With this update, we should see positive momentum returning to the Solana ecosystem in the coming days. If this happens, bulls could take SOL to the long-awaited $250 mark.</p>
<h2>Shiba Inu (SHIB) community burns 774M SHIB</h2>
<p>Shiba Inu (SHIB) has seen a rapid increase in its token burn rates. Data from Shibburn shows that over 774 million SHIB tokens were burnt in the last week. This is an increase of nearly 200%. Despite this uptick in burn rates, the circulating supply of the meme coin still stands at 582.80 trillion SHIB.</p>
<p>Additionally, Shiba Inu, like many other top altcoins, is still trading in losses. The coin&rsquo;s price has gone down 24.0% in the past week. Its price could increase in the coming days if positive momentum returns to the market.</p>
<h2>Final thoughts</h2>
<p>Solana investors are expecting the new update to bring a positive wave to the SOL token. On the other hand, Shiba Inu&rsquo;s massive token burn did not affect its price.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, NuggetRush&rsquo;s introduction of NFTs to its game makes its native token one of the best altcoins to watch.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/shiba-inu-burns-774m-shib-solana-bearish-despite-congestion-fix-nuggetrush-introduces-nfts/">Shiba Inu burns 774M SHIB, Solana bearish despite congestion fix, NuggetRush introduces NFTs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Over 1,000 Builders, Partners, Investors and Enthusiasts Gather at Inaugural Global Event to Celebrate Sui</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/over-1000-builders-partners-investors-and-enthusiasts-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/over-1000-builders-partners-investors-and-enthusiasts-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Grand Cayman, Cayman Islands, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire The annual event is a culmination of Sui&#8217;s exceptional debut Over 1,000 projects, partners, investors, and enthusiasts from 65 countries around the world gathered last week in Paris to celebrate Sui at the vaunted Layer 1&#8217;s inaugural global Sui Basecamp conference. At its first-ever annual event held [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/over-1000-builders-partners-investors-and-enthusiasts-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui/">Over 1,000 Builders, Partners, Investors and Enthusiasts Gather at Inaugural Global Event to Celebrate Sui</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Grand Cayman, Cayman Islands, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<h2>The annual event is a culmination of Sui&rsquo;s exceptional debut</h2>
<p>Over 1,000 projects, partners, investors, and enthusiasts from 65 countries around the world gathered last week in Paris to celebrate <a href="https://sui.io/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Sui</a> at the vaunted Layer 1&rsquo;s inaugural global Sui Basecamp conference.</p>
<p>At its first-ever annual event held during Paris Blockchain Week, Sui was feted by developers and builders from around the world during a two-day event. Speakers at Sui Basecamp spanned all aspects of the industry from payments to gaming to e-commerce to major league sports, offering commentary in keynotes, panels, and fireside chats.</p>
<p>The event was punctuated by three major announcements. In partnership with Playtron, the Sui team announced the SuiPlay0x1, the world&rsquo;s first lightweight handheld gaming device designed with native Web3 capabilities, and promising new gaming experiences. Additionally, First Digital Labs, joined an announcement that FDUSD, the fastest-growing stablecoin in crypto, will be the first native dollar-backed stablecoin on Sui, a boon to Sui&rsquo;s DeFi ecosystem, which is already the fastest-growing in the industry. Finally, Sui announced Enoki, a suite of Web3 utilities that will make it very simple for enterprises to leverage decentralized solutions inside their applications, products and services.</p>
<h6><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image3_1713441290AoB5zziFvA.jpg">Sui Basecamp attendees from 65 countries had the opportunity to meet each other face-to-face.</h6>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;In building Sui, we began with a blank canvas, aiming to create the preeminent platform for decentralized applications without the structural limitations we saw in other blockchains,&rdquo; said Evan Cheng, Co-founder and CEO of Mysten Labs, originator of the Sui Network. &ldquo;Less than a year after launching Sui&rsquo;s mainnet, the remarkable strength of Sui&rsquo;s performance has confirmed the approach. From nearly limitless horizontal scalability to industry leading speed of execution to achieving the most transactions in a single day of any blockchain ever, Sui&rsquo;s performance has been exceptional and the network has only scratched the surface.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>The industry veterans who founded Sui launched its mainnet nearly a year ago to great expectations, and the network has performed exceptionally well. Rather than cloning an existing network, the Sui team started from scratch to build an entirely new infrastructure layer that addressed the shortcomings of existing blockchains. They started by creating Move, a novel smart contract language, and on top of it created a new architecture centered around objects that enables performance and functionality that is simply not available on existing blockchains. The result is a blockchain that is singular in the industry &mdash; the universal coordination layer for intelligent assets.</p>
<p>Sui is a industry leader with lightning-fast transactions, with time to finality clocked at just 400 milliseconds. Likewise, Sui&rsquo;s scalability is also at the pinnacle, reaching 297,000 TPS in a controlled environment. But the Sui team is also constantly improving its technology. At the conference, members of the Sui team unveiled the next advancement in speed and scalability in the form of Mysticeti, which significantly accelerates Sui&rsquo;s time to finality, and Pilotfish, which enables nearly unlimited horizontal scaling by validators.</p>
<p>And beyond performing in test environments, at just four months old, Sui broke the record for transactions executed in a single day, achieving a higher figure than any existing blockchain while fees remained low and stable. Notably, in nearly a year of its mainnet, Sui has not experienced a single minute of downtime.</p>
<p>Gradually, after a series of community events around the world, media stories highlighting Sui&rsquo;s remarkable early milestones, sustained ecosystem growth and multiple stories of builders eschewing other blockchains to leverage the Sui network, builders, developers, investors and the broader community have begun to understand the potential for Sui&rsquo;s groundbreaking blockchain technology. The crowds that gathered for Sui Basecamp 2024 represented the culmination of Sui&rsquo;s arrival.</p>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The overwhelming turnout and the vibrant enthusiasm at the inaugural Sui Basecamp event reflects a Sui community that is captivated by Sui&rsquo;s potential to make people&rsquo;s lives better,&rdquo; said Greg Siourounis, Managing Director of the Sui Foundation. &ldquo;In the coming months, the Sui Foundation will continue to focus on expanding the ecosystem of projects leveraging Sui and the number of users benefiting from those applications as we work to make Sui one of the blockchains most widely adopted to solve real world challenges. With cutting edge technology and the most dedicated and professional community in web3 behind it, Sui&rsquo;s progress so far is just a glimpse of what this network will achieve.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Users can read more on the event on the <a href="https://blog.sui.io/sui-basecamp-2024-recap/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Sui Blog</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Sui Foundation<br>
media@sui.io</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/over-1000-builders-partners-investors-and-enthusiasts-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui/">Over 1,000 Builders, Partners, Investors and Enthusiasts Gather at Inaugural Global Event to Celebrate Sui</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/over-1000-builders-partners-investors-and-enthusiasts-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rebel Satoshi momentum hits overdrive; SUI and BONK holders scramble for a piece of the pie</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/rebel-satoshi-momentum-hits-overdrive-sui-and-bonk-holders-scramble-for-a-piece-of-the-pie/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SUI plunges 33% in a week, but experts believe bulls will take over soon. BONK slumps 32% in a week, but analysts foresee a resurgence by month&#8217;s end. Rebel Satoshi&#8217;s $RECQ attracts more investors after surging 85% during its presale. Top crypto coins like Sui (SUI) and Bonk (BONK) have recorded double-digit losses over the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/rebel-satoshi-momentum-hits-overdrive-sui-and-bonk-holders-scramble-for-a-piece-of-the-pie/">Rebel Satoshi momentum hits overdrive; SUI and BONK holders scramble for a piece of the pie</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SUI plunges 33% in a week, but experts believe bulls will take over soon.</li>
<li>BONK slumps 32% in a week, but analysts foresee a resurgence by month&rsquo;s end.</li>
<li>Rebel Satoshi&rsquo;s $RECQ attracts more investors after surging 85% during its presale.</li>
</ul>
<p>Top crypto coins like Sui (SUI) and Bonk (BONK) have recorded double-digit losses over the second week of April as the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/cryptocurrency/">crypto market</a> continues bleeding.</p>
<p>As a result, a growing number of investors are migrating to <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4793&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel Satoshi&rsquo;s</a> $RECQ token, which has surged 85% so far during its ongoing public presale.</p>
<p>Why is $RECQ outpacing popular cryptos like SUI and BONK? Continue reading to find out.</p>
<h2>SUI plummets 33% in a week: will bulls resurface soon?</h2>
<p>SUI has performed deplorably over the past seven days. On April 7, SUI was changing hands at around $1.65. After a day of range-bound trading, the token rose slightly on April 8 following the <a href="https://twitter.com/SuiNetwork/status/1777369064303657318">announcement</a> of Suilend completing its beta phase, becoming publicly available. Notably, Suilend hit a $30 million TVL during its beta phase, which started on March 11.</p>
<p>This news saw SUI jump to as high as $1.72 on April 9. However, the excitement about this news cooled off, and the price began correcting downward. By April 14, the token had stabilized at around $1.10.</p>
<p>This price means SUI has shed 33.33% in a week and the subpar performance explains why many investors are abandoning the token.</p>
<p>Still, some experts believe SUI will overcome the current bearish trend and climb to $1.91 by the end of April. This forecast could make SUI a good crypto to buy now. Experts base this prediction on SUI gaining more adoption as more Web3 gamers line up to purchase the SuiPlay0X1 handheld gaming device, which SUI introduced on April 10.</p>
<h2>BONK wipes off 32% in a week: will bears persist?</h2>
<p>BONK has performed abysmally over the past seven days. On April 7, BONK was hovering around $0.00002317. After a day of sideways trading, BONK gained traction on April 8 after AllDomains announced the number of registered .LetsBONK domain names had exceeded 10,000.</p>
<p>This milestone saw BONK jump as high as $0.00002452 on April 8. BONK held this level for a day before the excitement about AllDomain news faded. Consequently, BONK began retracing its growth. By April 14, BONK had leveled off at around $0.00001561. This price means SUI has plunged 32.63% in a week.</p>
<p>This lackluster performance has left investors asking, is BONK a top crypto to invest in? According to some experts, BONK could reverse course and jump to $0.00001800 by the end of April. Experts base this prediction on BONK gaining more adoption after the BONK team announced that BONK adopters had locked over 3 trillion BONK on ArmadaFi as of April 12.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=MCAP&amp;utm_medium=Banner&amp;utm_id=Bird"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-198347" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Market-cap.png" alt="" width="587" height="73"></a></p>
<h2>Rebel Satoshi&rsquo;s $RECQ steals the show after jumping 85%</h2>
<p>Rebel Satoshi, an upcoming meme coin project, has emerged as the latest sensation in the crypto industry due to its mission to fight centralization. Investors are buzzing about Rebel Satoshi because its mission entails uniting the silent majority and building a vibrant community that champions decentralization.</p>
<p>A number of analysts have suggested Rebel Satoshi might be the best ICO to invest in right now because it boasts two tokens, namely $RBLZ and $RECQ. $RBLZ is <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4793&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel SatoshI&rsquo;s</a> governance and membership token, while $RECQ is its base currency. Interestingly, $RBLZ rewarded Early Bird Round investors of its presale with a 150% ROI.</p>
<p>As of April, $RBLZ was available on Coinstore, CoinGecko, <a href="https://coinjournal.net/uniswap/what-is-uniswap/">Uniswap</a>, and DEXTools. On the other hand, $RECQ had kickstarted Stage 1 of its ongoing public presale. During this round, investors can purchase $RECQ at $0.0037. This price denotes an 85% surge from the Early Bird Round $RECQ price of $0.0020.</p>
<p>It is worth pointing out that Rebel Satoshi has set $RECQ&rsquo;s launch price at $0.0125. When $RECQ attains this price, Early Bird Round investors will get a 525% ROI, while Stage 1 investors will enjoy an ROI of 237.84%.</p>
<p>For the latest updates and more information on $RECQ, visit the official <a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/">Rebel Satoshi Website</a> or contact Rebel Red via <a href="https://t.me/RBLZRED">Telegram</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/rebel-satoshi-momentum-hits-overdrive-sui-and-bonk-holders-scramble-for-a-piece-of-the-pie/">Rebel Satoshi momentum hits overdrive; SUI and BONK holders scramble for a piece of the pie</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aptos Labs collaborates with Microsoft, Brevan Howard and SK Telecom to bring global institutional finance on-chain with Aptos Ascend</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom-to-bring-global-institutional-finance-on-chain-with-aptos-ascend/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom-to-bring-global-institutional-finance-on-chain-with-aptos-ascend/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Washington, United States, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire Aptos Ascend, powered by Microsoft Azure OpenAI and implemented in consultation with Boston Consulting Group, to enable regulatory-compliant digital asset management at scale for financial institutions with global reach. Aptos Labs today announced a collaboration with Microsoft, Brevan Howard, and SK Telecom (SKT) to deliver to the global [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom-to-bring-global-institutional-finance-on-chain-with-aptos-ascend/">Aptos Labs collaborates with Microsoft, Brevan Howard and SK Telecom to bring global institutional finance on-chain with Aptos Ascend</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Washington, United States, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p class="ql-align-center">Aptos Ascend, powered by Microsoft Azure OpenAI and implemented in consultation with Boston Consulting Group, to enable regulatory-compliant digital asset management at scale for financial institutions with global reach.</p>
<p><a href="https://aptosascend.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Aptos Labs</a> today announced a collaboration with Microsoft, Brevan Howard, and SK Telecom (SKT) to deliver to the global financial market Aptos Ascend, a suite of end-to-end institutional solutions including a permissioned network and Digital Asset Controls powered by SKT&rsquo;s Wallet-as-a-Service product and the scalable, secure Aptos blockchain. Aptos Ascend will also tap Brevan Howard&rsquo;s industry leadership and expertise to develop a seamless path for any major bank or financial institution to begin offering digital currency and asset management to their clients responsibly and at scale.</p>
<p>Boston Consulting Group (BCG) will be Aptos&rsquo; Labs preferred consulting partner, leveraging its global expertise in decentralized finance, digital assets, and AI to work with companies to implement the solutions. As one of the world&rsquo;s leading management consulting firms, BCG has a strong track record in delivering and implementing large-scale digital transformations for major financial institutions.</p>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Global institutions require superior levels of compliance, security, trust, and innovation to service customers, operate across borders, and adhere to regulations at every level,&rdquo; said Mo Shaikh, Co-Founder &amp; CEO of Aptos Labs. &ldquo;In collaboration with SKT, Brevan Howard and Microsoft, Aptos Ascend will provide the world&rsquo;s financial institutions, banks, and tech-forward money markets with a performant, compliant, secure, and scalable gateway to decentralized finance on Aptos that will evolve for years to come.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We see a tremendous opportunity at the intersection of AI and distributed ledger technologies and are pleased to support Aptos&nbsp;and the Ascend Project as they apply these technologies in financial services,&rdquo;&nbsp;says Adrian Crockett, GM &amp; Head of Product, Microsoft Cloud for Financial Services.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We continue to have high conviction in the positive impact that the application of Web3 and blockchain technology will have on the financial services industry,&rdquo; said Gautam Sharma, CEO &amp; CIO of Brevan Howard Digital. &ldquo;It is still early days, and we are pleased to support initiatives like Ascend that may help propel the industry forward.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;With a growing trend of tokenization in traditional finance, we expect the partnership to create a strong model for innovation in the future financial market,&rdquo; said Oh Se-hyeon,&nbsp;Vice President and Head of Web3 CO at SKT. &ldquo;Built upon SKT&rsquo;s trusted KYC/authentication business experience, T wallet (Wallet as a Service) aims to provide a stable platform for various crypto services to be provided with high reliability and security.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>In addition to bringing traditional finance giants, innovative fintech partners, money market platforms, and global investment firms into the Web3 fold, Aptos Ascend will enable organizations to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unlock unparalleled transaction efficiency with the Aptos blockchain thanks to an industry-leading sub-second latency&mdash;built for scale to achieve more than 30,000 transactions per second (TPS).</li>
<li>Use the Move smart contract language and Digital Asset Controls, which provide secure asset management, privacy options, and formal verification of smart contracts, greatly reducing the risk of hacks.</li>
<li>Collaborate with like-minded partners to build an extended ecosystem from the start to deliver scale from day one to encourage adoption.</li>
<li>Further explore financial services solutions with dedicated support from the Aptos Labs&rsquo; engineering team to develop additional functions and features as required.</li>
</ul>
<p>The institution-ready, end-to-end financial suite will use Microsoft Azure and Azure OpenAI Service<strong>, </strong>along with Brevan Howard&rsquo;s international and market-specific investment expertise, and SKT&rsquo;s regulatory-compliant Web3 technology, to pair innovative trade finance offerings with a decentralized, scalable, data-rich, and accessible network. Adding BCG&rsquo;s strategic consulting expertise will enable Aptos Labs clients to implement the technology solutions seamlessly within their institutions. While the Aptos Ascend solutions will continue to evolve, immediate value at a global scale will take the form of:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expanding decentralized finance to institutional capital.</li>
<li>Unlocking the uncollateralized lending market for Web3.</li>
<li>Releasing the liquidity of tokenized assets on a global scale.</li>
</ul>
<p>Aptos Ascend is designed to help regulated institutions around the world meet their obligations to customers, regulators, and other stakeholders. Further, Aptos Ascend includes unparalleled customizable configurations to meet specific business and regulatory requirements, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Access controls to help institutions meet regulatory requirements.</li>
<li>Controls over the types of transactions allowed and which entities can control transaction types.</li>
<li>Tools to maintain account and transaction privacy.</li>
<li>Embedded features for Know Your Customer (KYC) and anti-money laundering (AML) checks and other regulatory considerations.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information and to explore Aptos Ascend, visit <a href="https://aptosascend.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://aptosascend.com/</a>.</p>
<p class="ql-align-center">###</p>
<p>For media inquiries, email: <a href="mailto:aptos@hirschleatherwood.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">aptos@hirschleatherwood.com</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Comms<br>
Brian Principato<br>
Aptos Labs<br>
briannprincipato@gmail.com<br>
7033891211</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom-to-bring-global-institutional-finance-on-chain-with-aptos-ascend/">Aptos Labs collaborates with Microsoft, Brevan Howard and SK Telecom to bring global institutional finance on-chain with Aptos Ascend</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom-to-bring-global-institutional-finance-on-chain-with-aptos-ascend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Powered by Qualcomm, Aethir Unveils Game-Changing Aethir Edge Device to Unlock the Decentralized Edge Computing Future</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/powered-by-qualcomm-aethir-unveils-game-changing-aethir-edge-device-to-unlock-the-decentralized-edge-computing-future/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/powered-by-qualcomm-aethir-unveils-game-changing-aethir-edge-device-to-unlock-the-decentralized-edge-computing-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Singapore, Singapore, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire At the Dubai Press Conference, Aethir Edge debuted as the pioneering edge computing device and the first authorized mining machine of Aethir, one of the industry-leading decentralized cloud computing infrastructure providers, alongside Qualcomm. It enables users to mine 23% of Aethir&#8217;s native token $ATH supply. Integrated with a distributed [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/powered-by-qualcomm-aethir-unveils-game-changing-aethir-edge-device-to-unlock-the-decentralized-edge-computing-future/">Powered by Qualcomm, Aethir Unveils Game-Changing Aethir Edge Device to Unlock the Decentralized Edge Computing Future</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Singapore, Singapore, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>At the Dubai Press Conference, Aethir Edge debuted as the pioneering edge computing device and the first authorized mining machine of Aethir, one of the industry-leading decentralized cloud computing infrastructure providers, alongside Qualcomm. It enables users to mine 23% of Aethir&rsquo;s native token $ATH supply. Integrated with a distributed cloud network to overcome centralized barriers, Aethir Edge combines unmatched edge computing capability, decentralized access, and exclusive rewards.</li>
</ul>
<p>The future of decentralized edge computing is here. <a href="https://www.aethir.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Aethir</a> debuts <a href="https://www.myedge.io/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Aethir Edge</a>, supported by Qualcomm technology, at its official press conference in Token 2049 Dubai. As the first-ever authorized mining device integrated with distributed cloud infrastructure, Aethir Edge spearheads the evolution to decentralized edge computing &ndash; unlocking elite GPU performance, 23% of Aethir&rsquo;s native token $ATH supply, and equitable access all in one device.</p>
<h2>Edge into The Multi-Trillion Computing Market</h2>
<p>While the edge computing sector rapidly evolving into a multi-trillion-dollar industry, edge capacity has been siloed in centralized data centers for too long. Aethir Edge shatters these barriers with groundbreaking architecture interconnecting high-performance edge AI devices into a distributed cloud network. By pooling localized resources, Aethir Edge brings elite computing power home and makes it accessible to all.</p>
<p>Computing power holds immense potential as the energy of the digital realm. Aethir Edge taps into this power and takes it to the next level, with support from Aethir and Qualcomm. Aethir Edge&rsquo;s vision is to fundamentally transform how users access, contribute to, and own a future where edge AI technology&rsquo;s full potential is collectively unleashed beyond the constraints of centralized networks. Aethir Edge represents the beginning of this user-powered decentralized evolution.</p>
<h2>The First and Only Authorized Mining Device by Aethir</h2>
<p>As the sole whitelisted mining product from Aethir, Aethir Edge enables users worldwide to tap into exclusive rewards &ndash;&nbsp;and earn income by sharing spare bandwidth, IP addresses, and computing power. With its authorized status, Aethir Edge reserves up to 23% of the total native token $ATH supply for mining potential.</p>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re thrilled to support the innovative convergence of decentralized cloud, edge infrastructure and equitable incentives,&rdquo; said Aethir&rsquo;s Co-Founder, Mark Rydon. &ldquo;Aethir Edge pioneers community-powered edge computing technology through robust hardware, exclusive mining and Aethir&rsquo;s decentralized cloud network.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<h2>When Unrivaled Edge Computing Power Meets Open Accessibility</h2>
<p>Powered by the Qualcomm&reg; SnapdragonTM 865 chip, Aethir Edge achieves elite performance for data-intensive workloads. The 12GB LPDDR5 memory and 256GB UFS 3.1 storage ensure ample resources for smooth parallel processing. The decentralized architecture guarantees reliability and uptime by distributing capacity across peer nodes &ndash;&nbsp;overcoming centralized network vulnerabilities.</p>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;It is my great pleasure to congratulate the Aethir team on their next-generation product announcement, targeting distributed edge computing use cases, and more importantly, powered by Qualcomm Technologies and Qualcomm processors,&rdquo; said Qualcomm&rsquo;s Vice President and Head of Building, Enterprise, and Industrial Automation. &ldquo;We are very proud to be working with partners like Aethir, to advance the edge capabilities.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Aethir Edge interoperates seamlessly with diverse applications while enabling ultra-low latency through localized processing. Users worldwide can access optimized experiences unconfined by location.</p>
<h2>The Backbone for Innovations In The Decentralized Cloud Ecosystem</h2>
<p>As a core component in Aethir&rsquo;s decentralized cloud, Aethir Edge powers transformative new products like APhone, the first decentralized cloud smartphone. Its localized edge capacity enables implementations and operations across Gaming, AI, VR/AR, real-time streaming, and many more applications.</p>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Aethir Edge perfectly complements APhone&rsquo;s mission to make Web3 accessible to all. As APhone brings next-generation mobile experiences like high-performance gaming, AI, and graphics rendering to every smartphone user globally through our virtual OS, Aethir Edge will help us further our vision of reinventing the future of digital connectivity.&rdquo; &ndash; William Peckham, APhone&rsquo;s Chief Business Officer.</p></blockquote>
<h2>Democratizing Access to the Edge Computing Future</h2>
<p>Aethir Edge spearheads decentralized infrastructure owned and governed by users, not centralized entities. It makes high-powered computing accessible as a sleek, easy-to-use product integrated with earning potential. With its superior enterprise-grade hardware and distributed cloud infrastructure, Aethir Edge leads the shift away from centralized data monopolies and into the equitable edge landscape of the future.</p>
<p>Aethir Edge is now actively building partnerships with distributors worldwide, including crypto mining companies, hardware vendors, and distributors. Interested parties can fill out Aethir Edge&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.myedge.io/distributor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><strong>distributor application form</strong></a> so the team can explore win-win opportunities to distribute the product together, and shape the community-powered landscape of tomorrow.</p>
<p>Users can visit <a href="http://www.myedge.io" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><strong>www.myedge.io</strong></a> and be one of the first to unlock decentralized edge computing power.</p>
<h3>About Aethir Edge</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.myedge.io/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Aethir Edge</a> is an enterprise-grade edge computing device integrated with Aethir&rsquo;s distributed GPU cloud infrastructure to spearhead a new era of edge computing. As the first and only authorized mining device from Aethir, we combine powerful computing, exclusive earning, and decentralized access in one device &ndash; unlocking the true potential of DePIN.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.myedge.io" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docsend.com/view/s/8jvxpnnjyc6pnhp7" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Documentation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/AethirEdge" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Twitter</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>About Aethir</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.aethir.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Aethir</a> is a cloud computing infrastructure platform that revolutionizes the ownership, distribution, and utilization paradigms of enterprise-grade graphical processing units (GPUs). By moving away from traditional centralized models, Aethir has deployed a scalable and competitive framework for sharing distributed computational resources, catering to enterprise applications and clientele across various industries and regions.</p>
<p>Aethir is revolutionizing DePIN with its advanced, distributed enterprise-grade GPU-based compute infrastructure tailored for AI and gaming. Backed by leading Web3 investors like Framework Ventures, Merit Circle, Hashkey, Animoca Brands, Sanctor Capital, Infinity Ventures Crypto (IVC), and others, with over $130 M in funds raised for the ecosystem, Aethir is paving the way for the future of decentralized computing.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.aethir.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.aethir.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Documentation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/AethirCloud" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://t.co/JvxSy9X0Ji" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Discord</a></li>
<li><a href="https://t.co/9TF9m3AbIc" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Telegram</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/aethir-limited" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">LinkedIn</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Marketing lead<br>
Diksha<br>
Aethir<br>
diksha@aethir.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/powered-by-qualcomm-aethir-unveils-game-changing-aethir-edge-device-to-unlock-the-decentralized-edge-computing-future/">Powered by Qualcomm, Aethir Unveils Game-Changing Aethir Edge Device to Unlock the Decentralized Edge Computing Future</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/powered-by-qualcomm-aethir-unveils-game-changing-aethir-edge-device-to-unlock-the-decentralized-edge-computing-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SeedHunter Marketing Module is live &#8211; Web3 Influencer Campaigns with payment in Stable Coins</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/seedhunter-marketing-module-is-live-web3-influencer-campaigns-with-payment-in-stable-coins/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/seedhunter-marketing-module-is-live-web3-influencer-campaigns-with-payment-in-stable-coins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai, UAE, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire SeedHunter is a dedicated platform that facilitates and fosters collaborations between influencers and crypto projects to gain traction in the web3 community. The company has a new and fresh perspective on how to match high-potential influencers and KOLs with respective crypto projects and investors in a lucrative, scalable, and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/seedhunter-marketing-module-is-live-web3-influencer-campaigns-with-payment-in-stable-coins/">SeedHunter Marketing Module is live &#8211; Web3 Influencer Campaigns with payment in Stable Coins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dubai, UAE, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.seedhunter.com?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=launch" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">SeedHunter</a> is a dedicated platform that facilitates and fosters collaborations between <strong>influencers and crypto projects</strong> to gain traction in the<strong> web3 community</strong>. The company has a new and fresh perspective on how to match high-potential influencers and KOLs with respective crypto projects and investors in a lucrative, scalable, and secure way.</p>
<p>SeedHunter <strong>launched on April 18th 2024</strong>, its debut service: <strong>The Marketing Module</strong>. This is a platform that allows crypto projects to manage and maintain their influencer marketing campaigns more efficiently, securely, and effectively. The marketing campaigns launched can be uniquely customized to the crypto project&rsquo;s needs in terms of content, deliverables, and more.</p>
<p>The platform then uses an <strong>AI-based data model</strong> to evaluate, rate, and <strong>match reliable KOLs to crypto projects</strong>. SeedHunter will also assess influencer performance and define pricing directly using an advanced algorithm based on metrics of engagement, impression rates, number of followers, and the compatibility of the KOL with the campaign they manage &ndash; all of these standards will ensure that the right influencer is matched to the user&rsquo;s target audience needs. This <strong>ensures a fully transparent, fair, and lucrative</strong> influencer marketing position for influencers of all kinds.</p>
<p>Crypto <strong>projects can also benefit</strong> from several built-in marketing campaign tools to drive engagement &ndash; including consultancy and account management as needed. SeedHunter takes care of all the tedious admin to provide a <strong>simplified, insightful, and efficient platform</strong> to view potential influencer and KOL partnerships. Dariusz Kowalczyk, the co-founder and CTO of SeedHunter, has stated that the platform &ldquo;does the due diligence to find reliable and relevant KOLs that match your target audience&rsquo;s interests. This saves time and energy while pulling the focus onto the customer.&rdquo;</p>
<p>SeedHunter also makes cryptocurrency projects a lot more accessible by <strong>simplifying processes</strong>. Influencer campaigns can be created in a matter of minutes through a centralized platform &ndash; giving the community <strong>automated contracts, KOL reviews, and delivery checks</strong>. Payments will also be based on deliveries to ensure cost-effective marketing. The web3 community can easily use SeedHunter to curate the ideal influencer campaign for their project and push growth.</p>
<p>To celebrate its official launch, SeedHunter is diving right in with a platform campaign open to all interested KOLs. This provides <strong>an opportunity for influencers to get involved from the get-go</strong>. SeedHunter has also three additional, high-profile projects waiting to be launched. These span the exciting realms of blockchain, entertainment, and gaming, offering KOLs a chance to contribute to cutting-edge initiatives and propel their marketing efforts.</p>
<p>The crypto industry is uniquely disruptive and as such, it needs platforms like SeedHunter that <strong>offer scalable solutions from the very beginning for a lasting chance of success</strong>. With automated, simplified, and user-friendly interfaces, SeedHunter provides a seamless experience for influencers and crypto projects alike.</p>
<blockquote><p>Co-founder and CEO, Junaid Dar has said, &ldquo;The SeedHunter platform will act as a canvas for prospective reliable influencers and KOLs to connect to crypto projects that are looking to gain traction in the market in a way that will simplify, secure, and inspire the industry.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>SeedHunter is built on the values of <strong>trust, efficiency, collaboration, dynamics, and prosperity</strong>. This has helped the company establish a clear, guided vision for the future of the crypto influencer market. The platform&rsquo;s ultimate mission is to <strong>ensure an easier, scalable, and more secure channel through which innovative crypto projects can be matched to specific influencers and investors</strong> in a way that adds value and clarity to a dynamic cryptocurrency market.</p>
<p>SeedHunter invites crypto project managers and influencers of all sizes to take advantage of the Marketing Module that simplifies collaborations in a mutually beneficial, fair, and secure way. SeedHunter is also open to partnerships in the cryptocurrency industry that would help to expand and establish the vision of efficient, secure, and reliable collaborations across the web3 community.</p>
<p>Moving forward, SeedHunter will also be launching its <strong>Funding Module in June 2024</strong> which will allow crypto projects to find the necessary seed capital needed to gain traction. In this project, SeedHunter will <strong>act as a broker between the community and crypto projects</strong> that need funding. This project ensures the involvement of smaller influencers as well and allows the project to engage with communities and participate in projects for only $50. This ensures safety, transparency, and safety for start-up crypto projects looking to change the industry.</p>
<h3>About SeedHunter</h3>
<p>SeedHunter was founded recently and allows crypto projects to connect to reliable and trusted influencers and KOLs to drive engagement and improve marketability. The centralized platform establishes a mutually beneficial link between influencers and crypto investors that is mutually beneficial and transparent. The company uses advanced technology to match ideal influencer candidates to crypto projects and helps to source seed funding for start-up crypto projects.</p>
<p><strong>Contact Information&nbsp;</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Website: <a href="https://www.seedhunter.com?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=launch" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">www.seedhunter.com</a></li>
<li>Email: <a href="mailto:contact@seedhunter.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">contact@seedhunter.com</a></li>
<li>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/SeedHunterHQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">@SeedHunterHQ</a></li>
<li>LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/seedhunter-platform/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">SeedHunter</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Chief Operating Officer<br>
Alexandre Barros<br>
SeedHunter<br>
contact@seedhunter.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/seedhunter-marketing-module-is-live-web3-influencer-campaigns-with-payment-in-stable-coins/">SeedHunter Marketing Module is live &#8211; Web3 Influencer Campaigns with payment in Stable Coins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/seedhunter-marketing-module-is-live-web3-influencer-campaigns-with-payment-in-stable-coins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitgets COO Leads Discussion on Cryptocurrencys Future at Blockchain Life Week 2024</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitgets-coo-leads-discussion-on-cryptocurrencys-future-at-blockchain-life-week-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitgets-coo-leads-discussion-on-cryptocurrencys-future-at-blockchain-life-week-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Victoria, Seychelles, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire Bitget&#8217;s Chief Operating Officer, Vugar Usi Zade, shared the stage during the recent Blockchain Life Week 2024, with other distinguished leaders from top crypto exchanges in a panel titled &#8220;Conductors in the World of Cryptocurrencies: What Top Exchanges Think About 2024&#8221;. The discussion provided an in-depth look at the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/bitgets-coo-leads-discussion-on-cryptocurrencys-future-at-blockchain-life-week-2024/">Bitgets COO Leads Discussion on Cryptocurrencys Future at Blockchain Life Week 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Victoria, Seychelles, April 18th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.bitget.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Bitget&rsquo;s</a> Chief Operating Officer, Vugar Usi Zade, shared the stage during the recent <a href="https://blockchain-life.com/asia/en/?spring2024" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Blockchain Life Week 2024</a>, with other distinguished leaders from top crypto exchanges in a <a href="https://twitter.com/usithetalk/status/1779973977080770608" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">panel</a> titled &ldquo;Conductors in the World of Cryptocurrencies: What Top Exchanges Think About 2024&rdquo;. The discussion provided an in-depth look at the anticipated developments and strategic directions for the crypto industry in the upcoming year.</p>
<p>Vugar Usi Zade highlighted the critical importance of prioritizing end-user experiences and privacy, drawing lessons from historical challenges such as the Facebook and Cambridge Analytica data scandal. He stressed the necessity for industry leaders to work closely with regulators to enhance user protection without stifling innovation.</p>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Our goal is to ensure that legislation supports the growth of blockchain technologies rather than hindering it,&rdquo; Usi Zade noted. &ldquo;As key players, centralized exchanges should work with legislators and educate them on how blockchain technology works and how introducing legislation should help the end user.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Addressing the infrastructure of the gig economy and energy sectors, Usi Zade shared insights about Bitget&rsquo;s initiatives to support the integration of blockchain technologies in various industries. &ldquo;We are particularly excited about our projects that give NFTs a second chance and promote sustainable energy practices among communities,&rdquo; he added.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>A significant focus for Bitget in the coming years, as outlined by Usi Zade, will be on developing and nurturing talent within the blockchain sector. He emphasized the company&rsquo;s commitment to invest in entrepreneurial innovation on its platform. &ldquo;We believe in empowering new talent to build and develop rather than trying to do everything ourselves,&rdquo; he explained. &ldquo;There are so many opportunities, and we need so much talent, for the entire economy and industry. In the next two years, we will invest as many resources as possible to develop talent.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>With an exemplary track record of safety, Bitget underscores its pledge to user security through substantial financial safeguards, including a robust protection fund. &ldquo;We maintain a 200% <a href="https://www.bitget.com/proof-of-reserves" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">proof of reserve</a>, ensuring that funds remain secure even if all users withdraw their assets simultaneously.&rdquo; Usi Zade asserted. &ldquo;We have security measures in place, but in case something goes wrong, we have an insured Protection Fund to make sure that there are no customers suffering at the other end.&rdquo; The Bitget COO emphasized that its Protection Fund is one of the largest in the industry, providing an additional layer of security against potential breaches.</p></blockquote>
<h1><strong><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BuivzSy73mQi1jetm55ZsabSK7OR0lCaDbta8bDucXdp3pIUi4_1713438832bt5PKLfy9B.jpeg"></strong></h1>
<p>Usi Zade also discussed the role of centralized exchanges in facilitating access to the crypto market. He described how Bitget has simplified the transition for users from traditional finance to cryptocurrencies through user-friendly services like social logins and comprehensive customer support.</p>
<blockquote><p>The COO concluded his talk by touching upon the regulatory challenges and the potential of decentralized exchanges to evolve further. &ldquo;As legislation in Europe begins to affect how users can transact with non-KYC wallets, centralized exchanges will need to adapt. However, this also presents an opportunity to redefine our roles, potentially acting as intermediaries in large B2B transactions,&rdquo; he speculated.</p></blockquote>
<p>The panel discussion at Blockchain Life Week 2024 provided much-needed insights into the crypto industry&rsquo;s expected trajectory. It also reinforced Bitget&rsquo;s position as a leader prepared to navigate and shape the future landscape of digital currencies.</p>
<h3>About Bitget</h3>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Established in 2018, <a href="https://www.bitget.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Bitget</a> is the world&rsquo;s leading <a href="https://www.bitget.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">cryptocurrency exchange</a> that offers Copy Trading services as one of its key features. Serving over 8 million users in more than 100 countries and regions, the exchange is committed to helping users trade smarter by providing a secure, one-stop trading solution. Bitget inspires individuals to embrace crypto through collaborations with credible partners, including legendary Argentinian footballer Lionel Messi and official eSports events organizer PGL.</p>
<p>For more information, visit:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.bitget.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/bitgetglobal" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://t.me/BitgetENOfficial" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Telegram</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/bitget-global/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">LinkedIn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://discord.com/invite/bitget" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Discord</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>PR team<br>
media@bitget.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/bitgets-coo-leads-discussion-on-cryptocurrencys-future-at-blockchain-life-week-2024/">Bitgets COO Leads Discussion on Cryptocurrencys Future at Blockchain Life Week 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitgets-coo-leads-discussion-on-cryptocurrencys-future-at-blockchain-life-week-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Release date confirmed for new augmented reality move-to-earn game, SpaceCatch</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/release-date-confirmed-for-new-augmented-reality-move-to-earn-game-spacecatch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 09:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=199200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SpaceCatch, a brand new AR M2E (Move-to-Earn) game, has confirmed the release date for its public beta version. The game, which will come packed with impressive features and multiple benefits after an extensive development period, is scheduled for release on April 22 2024.&#160; Set in a futuristic world similar to our own, where Earth has [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/release-date-confirmed-for-new-augmented-reality-move-to-earn-game-spacecatch/">Release date confirmed for new augmented reality move-to-earn game, SpaceCatch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://spacecatch.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SpaceCatch</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a brand new AR M2E (Move-to-Earn) game, has confirmed the release date for its public beta version. The game, which will come packed with impressive features and multiple benefits after an extensive development period, is scheduled for release on April 22 2024.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Set in a futuristic world similar to our own, where Earth has been overtaken by AI-driven aliens, SpaceCatch challenges players, known as Catchers, to restore peace on Earth by defeating these aliens.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The game offers a captivating narrative that engages players, making it difficult to put their phones down.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scheduled for release on April 22, SpaceCatch is inviting players to reserve their spot early, with only 22,000 entries available.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite being pre-launch, SpaceCatch has already won over early adopters thanks to its rich feature set and engaging plot. The growing community and successful fundraising efforts are living proof of its appeal and potential.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">And how does it work?</span></h2>
<p><a href="https://spacecatch.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SpaceCatch</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> leverages several cutting-edge technologies to deliver its exciting gameplay. The game operates on two models: M2E (Move to Earn) and P2E (Play to Earn). The P2E model is straightforward: players engage in combat with AI-driven aliens to restore peace on Earth.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The M2E model, on the other hand, is powered by Augmented Reality (AR). This integration allows players to interact with the SpaceCatch universe as it blends seamlessly with the real world. Imagine spotting an alien while in the park, relaxing in your living room, or getting in your car.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furthermore, SpaceCatch employs artificial intelligence (AI) to develop a unique gaming experience for each player. Your game experience will differ from that of others, molded by your decisions, preferences, and behavior.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than just a game</span></h2>
<p><a href="https://spacecatch.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SpaceCatch</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has also developed a native token, CATCH, which is valuable both within and outside the game&rsquo;s ecosystem.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CATCH has been distributed to users during various fundraising events, CATCH can be earned through specific actions in the game and is available for purchase on multiple exchanges, including Gate.io, Bitget, MEXC, BitMart, XT.com, and Bingx.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And if you were not around when SpaceCatch organized the fundraising rounds, or you prefer not to perform certain actions in the game to earn CATCH, don&rsquo;t worry; you can still get some tokens. CATCH can be bought, sold, or traded on various platforms, and this will help several new players get a better start in the SpaceCatch world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CATCH helps SpaceCatch players improve their characters and tools, and this can highly contribute to their evolution in the game and how much they manage to help with their main common goal: restoring peace on Earth.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Discover More</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SpaceCatch is just getting started in the industry, and has big plans up its sleeve. But with just 22,000 beta entries up for grabs, gamers should check out its </span><a href="https://spacecatch.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">official website</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> asap and follow its activity on </span><a href="https://t.me/spacecatch_io"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Telegram</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://discord.gg/spacecatchers"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Discord</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://twitter.com/spacecatch_io"><span style="font-weight: 400;">X (Twitter)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@spacecatch_io"><span style="font-weight: 400;">YouTube</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://instagram.com/spacecatch_io"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instagram</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://medium.com/@spacecatch"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Medium</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/spacecatch/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CoinMarketCap</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/release-date-confirmed-for-new-augmented-reality-move-to-earn-game-spacecatch/">Release date confirmed for new augmented reality move-to-earn game, SpaceCatch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
