<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<atom:link href="https://coinjournal.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<description><![CDATA[Keep your finger on the pulse of the fast-moving cryptocurrency sector with all the latest crypto news, analysis and reviews from CoinJournal]]></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:34:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/apple-touch-icon.png</url>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Research Reveals Mobile Devices as Catalysts for Efficient Decentralized Infrastructure Networks (DePINs)</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/research-reveals-mobile-devices-as-catalysts-for-efficient-decentralized-infrastructure-networks-depins/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/research-reveals-mobile-devices-as-catalysts-for-efficient-decentralized-infrastructure-networks-depins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Zug, Switzerland, April 24th, 2024, Chainwire Researchers from the University of Z&#252;rich&#8217;s Communication Systems Group, in collaboration with the Acurast Association building on Polkadot and other ecosystems, have unveiled groundbreaking results in their latest study, &#8220;Performance Analysis of Decentralized Physical Infrastructure Networks and Centralized Clouds.&#8221; This work demonstrates the viability of Decentralized Physical Infrastructure Networks [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/research-reveals-mobile-devices-as-catalysts-for-efficient-decentralized-infrastructure-networks-depins/">Research Reveals Mobile Devices as Catalysts for Efficient Decentralized Infrastructure Networks (DePINs)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Zug, Switzerland, April 24th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p>Researchers from the University of Z&uuml;rich&rsquo;s Communication Systems Group, in collaboration with the Acurast Association building on Polkadot and other ecosystems, have unveiled groundbreaking results in their latest study, &ldquo;Performance Analysis of Decentralized Physical Infrastructure Networks and Centralized Clouds.&rdquo; This work demonstrates the viability of Decentralized Physical Infrastructure Networks (DePIN) as a robust alternative to traditional centralized cloud computing platforms.</p>
<p>DePINs, leveraging blockchain technology and the Internet of Things (IoT), aim to enhance data sovereignty, reduce dependency on centralized models, and improve system resilience against potential failures. The research specifically highlights and evaluates <a href="https://acurast.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Acurast</a>, a new decentralized serverless cloud network that capitalizes on underutilized resources of smartphones to perform complex computing tasks with enhanced security and efficiency.</p>
<h2>Key Findings</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Enhanced Efficiency:</strong> Acurast has shown potential to perform computationally intensive tasks more efficiently than traditional cloud services like Google Cloud Platform and Amazon AWS.</li>
<li><strong>Power Efficiency:</strong> Acurast significantly reduce power consumption, compared to existing centralized server infrastructure, making it an environmentally friendly alternative to existing solutions.</li>
<li><strong>Empirical Evidence:</strong> The study provides empirical evidence supporting the theoretical benefits of DePINs, demonstrating Acurast&rsquo;s ability to handle computationally intensive applications with reliability and cost-effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The advent of decentralized technologies presents a unique opportunity to rethink how we manage and operate digital infrastructures,&rdquo; said Jan von der Assen, PhD student and Junior Researcher of the Communication Systems Group (CSG) at the University of Zurich (UZH) on the project. &ldquo;Acurast not only challenges the status quo but may also present a scalable, secure, and sustainable model for future computing needs.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>This research marks a significant step toward understanding and harnessing the power of DePINs for computing. It opens up a real alternative to existing cloud providers for applications in all industries, especially where confidentiality is paramount.</p>
<p>The full <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.08306" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">research paper</a> is publicly available and has been accepted at the upcoming DePIN Workshop of the International Conference on Blockchain Technology (ICBC) 2024.</p>
<h3>About University of Z&uuml;rich&rsquo;s Communication Systems Group</h3>
<p>The <a href="https://www.csg.uzh.ch/csg/en/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Communication Systems Group (CSG)</a> at the University of Zurich focuses on research and development in networked systems and communication mechanisms. The group is dedicated to advancing the state of the art in communication systems, network security, and infrastructure development.</p>
<h3>About Acurast Association</h3>
<p>The Acurast Association is dedicated to breaking up the cloud monopoly with <a href="https://acurast.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Acurast</a> using mobile hardware, thereby democratizing and decentralizing the cloud. Allowing everyone to become a part of the cloud through their mobile devices. Providing developers with unrestricted, permissionless access to computing resources that are secure, cost-effective, and confidential.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Co-Founder<br>
Pascal Brun<br>
Acurast<br>
hi@acurast.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/research-reveals-mobile-devices-as-catalysts-for-efficient-decentralized-infrastructure-networks-depins/">Research Reveals Mobile Devices as Catalysts for Efficient Decentralized Infrastructure Networks (DePINs)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/research-reveals-mobile-devices-as-catalysts-for-efficient-decentralized-infrastructure-networks-depins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Worldcoin update: What’s going on with the WLD token?</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/worldcoin-update-whats-going-on-with-the-wld-token/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Worldcoin subsidiary plans to sell up to 36 million WLD tokens over next six months WLD supply could increase by as much as 19%. Worldcoin price hovered around $5.48 on Wednesday, flat on the day after paring earlier gains. The scenario that the supply of Worldcoin increases by up to the above number of coins [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/worldcoin-update-whats-going-on-with-the-wld-token/">Worldcoin update: What’s going on with the WLD token?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Worldcoin subsidiary plans to sell up to 36 million WLD tokens over next six months</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">WLD supply could increase by as much as 19%.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Worldcoin price hovered around $5.48 on Wednesday, flat on the day after paring earlier gains.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The scenario that the supply of Worldcoin increases by up to the above number of coins stems from plans outlined in a <a href="https://worldcoin.org/blog/announcements/circulating-supply-update-sales-trading-firms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a> published on April 23.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">&ldquo;<em>To meet the increasing demand for orb-verified World IDs around the world and support the growth of the Worldcoin network, World Assets Ltd. (a subsidiary of the Worldcoin Foundation) expects to sell WLD tokens from the World Assets treasury in the coming months</em>,&rdquo; Worldcoin Foundation said in the announcement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In particular, World Assets is looking to sell between 500,000 to 1.5 million WLD tokens every week for six months. The tokens will account for about 0.1% to 0.4% of Worldcoin&rsquo;s weekly trading volume.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">According to the blog post, the tokens are from the World Assets treasury and will be sold via private sales to non-US institutional trading firms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">&ldquo;<em>These private placements of WLD will take place for up to 6 months and will include certain measures designed to prevent WLD sold outside the US from flowing back into the US</em>,&rdquo; Worldcoin Foundation team noted.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Worldcoin (WLD) token price</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">If World Assets sells the expected weekly total of up to 1.5 million WLD tokens (worth about $8.2 million) the total sales for the six months could reach 36 million tokens. The value of the new WLD supply hitting the market could be up to $197 million, given current WLD token price of $5.48.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Per CoinGecko data, Worldcoin&rsquo;s 24-hour trading volume stands at $216 million while circulating supply is just over 194 million.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Worldcoin (WLD) price today is up about 9.7% in the past week and down by about 36% in the past 30 days. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/portugal-orders-worldcoin-to-halt-data-collection/">Regulatory headwinds</a> and slowdown in AI tokens is likely behind the decline this past month. However, WLD price is more than 456% up since its all-time low of $0.9731 reached in September last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The token launched in July 2023, co-founded by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman. In March, Worldcoin surged to its all-time high of $11.74, getting tailwinds from the broader AI narrative. Worldcoin&rsquo;s plans for <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/worldcoin-to-launch-a-new-ethereum-l2-network-dubbed-world-chain/">a new Ethereum layer-2 called World Chain</a> also buoyed prices.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/worldcoin-update-whats-going-on-with-the-wld-token/">Worldcoin update: What’s going on with the WLD token?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Poker Site CoinPoker Launches CSOP Tournament Series with $1M Pot and Removes Cashout Fees</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-poker-site-coinpoker-launches-csop-tournament-series-with-1m-pot-and-removes-cashout-fees/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-poker-site-coinpoker-launches-csop-tournament-series-with-1m-pot-and-removes-cashout-fees/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Willemstad, Curacao, April 24th, 2024, Chainwire CoinPoker, the world&#8217;s largest cryptocurrency poker platform, has launched its annual Crypto Series of Online Poker (CSOP) Spring tournament series while also removing all Cashout Fees as announced by the team on X: After kicking off on Friday April 19, the ongoing tournament series will end on April 28, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-poker-site-coinpoker-launches-csop-tournament-series-with-1m-pot-and-removes-cashout-fees/">Crypto Poker Site CoinPoker Launches CSOP Tournament Series with $1M Pot and Removes Cashout Fees</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Willemstad, Curacao, April 24th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p class="ql-align-justify"><a href="https://coinpoker.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CoinPoker</a>, the world&rsquo;s largest cryptocurrency poker platform, has launched its annual Crypto Series of Online Poker (CSOP) Spring tournament series while also removing all Cashout Fees as announced by the <a href="https://twitter.com/CoinPoker_OFF/status/1782807509528420829" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">team on X</a>:</p>
<p class="ql-align-center"><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/xApln2jl5Uq-xzPv8Tck9VD-eHx8tlxC_iz2uJu3SoKoHRlVet_1713954692J3sTTM8Ebx.jpeg"></p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">After kicking off on Friday April 19, the ongoing tournament series will end on April 28, featuring 41 events with a combined $1 million in guaranteed prize pools.</p>
<h2>CSOP spring tournament spans 41 events over 10 days</h2>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Drawing comparisons to the prestigious World Series of Poker (WSOP), the <a href="https://coinpoker.com/tournament/csop/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CSOP</a> is one of the biggest online poker tournament series to use cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">CoinPoker&rsquo;s flagship CSOP series has grown in stature each year, attracting players globally to compete for seven-figure prize pools paid out in crypto.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">This year&rsquo;s CSOP Spring edition has also attracted high stakes cash game action, with 1000/2000 games running on Sunday and some <a href="https://www.rakeback.com/news/tony-g-wins-304575-usdt-pot-in-nosebleeds-coinpoker-action/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">poker pots over $300k</a>.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify"><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL3WY12XwAAjjPLformatjpgnamemedium_1713955307vMPzegZw01.jpeg"></p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">The ten days of the CSOP and 41 tournaments encompass a range of buy-in levels, from $20 openers to the $500 CSOP Grand Finale main event on April 28, all with freeroll qualifier events to satellite in at a discount.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Players can also expect a diverse slate of formats, including progressive knockout (PKO), Pot Limit Omaha (PLO), &ldquo;MonsterStack&rdquo; big blind events, and more mixed throughout the series.</p>
<h2>CoinPoker&rsquo;s CHP Token offers Ethereum-based utility for platform rewards</h2>
<p class="ql-align-justify">The CSOP Spring event is also shining the spotlight on CoinPoker&rsquo;s ecosystem.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">CoinPoker is the original cryptocurrency poker site, launched in 2017 with a vision of bringing blockchain technology to the poker world.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">The lifeblood of CoinPoker&rsquo;s ecosystem is <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/coinpoker/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CHP</a>, a utility token built on the Ethereum network.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Though poker games are played using the USDT stablecoin, CHP serves as a &ldquo;bonusing fuel&rdquo; that provides rewards and incentives for token holders.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Players can also earn CHP through the platform&rsquo;s various promotions, rake races, and referral programs.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">The token is currently available to trade through the QuickSwap DEX on the Polygon network.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">At the time of writing, CHP is valued at $0.059 and is up 5% in the past seven days.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">CHP&rsquo;s market cap is just over $15 million, with over 98% of the 278,237,314 supply in circulation.</p>
<h2>Poker pro Tony G serves as CoinPoker ambassador</h2>
<p class="ql-align-justify">A key part of CoinPoker&rsquo;s credibility in the poker world comes from its association with renowned pro <a href="https://twitter.com/TonyGuoga" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Tony G</a> (Antanas Guoga).</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">The Lithuanian-Australian poker legend serves as an ambassador and representative for the platform.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Tony G has an illustrious poker resume, with 15 World Series of Poker money finishes and two final table appearances at the World Poker Tour.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Tony G took part in the largest ever online poker pot worth <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4p5jXD28nk8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">over $7.7 million</a>, played on CoinPoker&rsquo;s platform. Tony&rsquo;s decades of experience have helped steer CoinPoker into becoming one of the most popular crypto poker rooms.</p>
<h3 class="ql-align-justify">About CoinPoker</h3>
<p class="ql-align-justify">CoinPoker is the world&rsquo;s premier online crypto poker room and has been operating since 2017.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Using blockchain technology and cryptocurrencies, CoinPoker provides a secure, transparent, and provably fair poker experience.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">With high-profile ambassadors like Tony G representing the platform, CoinPoker hosts regular tournaments, attracting thousands of players globally to compete for crypto prizes.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">Players can register a free anonymous <a href="https://coinpoker.com/register/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CoinPoker account here</a> to get started playing in the CSOP &ndash; all that&rsquo;s needed is a crypto wallet, email and phone number.</p>
<p class="ql-align-justify">CoinPoker is the source of this content. This Press Release is for informational purposes only. The information does not constitute investment advice or an offer to invest.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>CoinPoker<br>
contact@coinpoker.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-poker-site-coinpoker-launches-csop-tournament-series-with-1m-pot-and-removes-cashout-fees/">Crypto Poker Site CoinPoker Launches CSOP Tournament Series with $1M Pot and Removes Cashout Fees</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-poker-site-coinpoker-launches-csop-tournament-series-with-1m-pot-and-removes-cashout-fees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arthur Hayes says macro setup favours Bitcoin bulls as KangaMoon attracts investors</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/arthur-hayes-says-macro-setup-favours-bitcoin-bulls-as-kangamoon-attracts-investors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Arthur Hayes is bullish on crypto amid the macro setup that he says could present a golden opportnity He says altcoins as well as presale tokens may be worth a look at as crypto exits latest window of weakness KangaMoon (KANG) is one of the new projects attracting huge attention as its presale noves towards [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/arthur-hayes-says-macro-setup-favours-bitcoin-bulls-as-kangamoon-attracts-investors/">Arthur Hayes says macro setup favours Bitcoin bulls as KangaMoon attracts investors</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Arthur Hayes is bullish on crypto amid the macro setup that he says could present a golden opportnity</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">He says altcoins as well as presale tokens may be worth a look at as crypto exits latest window of weakness</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">KangaMoon (KANG) is one of the new projects attracting huge attention as its presale noves towards a close</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Arthur Hayes believes the crypto market is set to continue on the upside, pointing to the macro setup and the sovereign debt bubble. The Maelstrom family office head, is also bullish on altcoins and new token launches that he says present a &ldquo;golden opportunity&rdquo; after the recent crypto weakness.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">With the market likely to flip bullish in coming months, could this be the time to take advantage of the <a href="https://pr.kangamoon.com/1ditvb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KangaMoon (KANG) presale</a>?</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Arthur Hays explains bull market setup and potential opportunities</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BitMEX exchange co-founder and former CEO Arthur Hayes is bullish on crypto rebounding after the recent dip, noting that prices could &ldquo;get sillier on the upside.&rdquo; This, he argued in his <a href="https://cryptohayes.medium.com/left-curve-ef2e1e187027" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&ldquo;Left Curve&rdquo; blog post</a>, could be a &lsquo;golden opportunity&rdquo; for investors to add to their positions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In his opinion, the market is currently exiting &ldquo;the window of weakness&rdquo; that likely followed the April 15 US tax payments and the recent Bitcoin halving event.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While the factors that drove <a href="https://coinjournal.net/bitcoin/">Bitcoin price</a> from zero to $70k over the past decade may not be the same ones at play in the future, Hayes says the macro setup and the fiat liquidity surge that fueled BTC&rsquo;s staggering gains can only get more pronounced, particularly as &ldquo;the sovereign debt bubble begins to burst.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">&ldquo;<em>As we enter the northern hemispheric summer and decision-makers enjoy a respite from reality, crypto volatility will decline. This is the perfect time to take advantage of the recent crypto dip to slowly add to positions</em>,&rdquo; the BitMEX co-founder noted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Altcoins pounded during the latest dump, new token launches and presales are all likely to offer great entry points. These opportunities could materialise over the next few months.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">KangaMoon brings GameFi and SocialFi to meme world</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">KangaMoon (KANG) is a new SocialFi and play-to-earn gaming project currently in presale.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The project, which also taps into meme culture to spice up the epic game battles, has a strong pull due to what the native $KANG token offers to holders. With KangaMoon, the opportunities to earn more $KANG and other exclusive rewards are available right from the presale stage.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Kangaverse is the GameFi platform&rsquo;s ecosystem for contests and tournaments. $KANG holders can access these chances to earn more tokens through weekly, monthly and quarterly competitions and game challenges.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">What makes KangaMoon a potentially great opportunity?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">What makes KangaMoon a potentially great investment opportunity is its current presale price. $KANG&rsquo;s value during the five stages of the token sale has increased from $0.005 to $0.0196, meaning early birds are looking at about 280% upside on the price.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">However, the current price is also likely to be a great entry point given market predictions for Bitcoin and the altcoin sector. Analysts are also bullish on play-to-earn, while meme coins may see a new leg of interest.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">A look at KangaMoon&rsquo;s performance as stage 5 of the presale nears a close shows a great deal of confidence in the project from early investors. KangaMoon has raised more than $5.2 million so far, with the final stage 48% sold out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Investors can take advantage of the 20% bonus available on all purchases to load up on what could be the next top big thing in SocialFi and P2E.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">To learn more or buy $KANG, visit the <a href="https://pr.kangamoon.com/1ditvb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official KangaMoon website</a>.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/arthur-hayes-says-macro-setup-favours-bitcoin-bulls-as-kangamoon-attracts-investors/">Arthur Hayes says macro setup favours Bitcoin bulls as KangaMoon attracts investors</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto price predictions: BitBot, Pepe, Algorand (ALGO)</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-price-predictions-bitbot-pepe-algorand-algo/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-price-predictions-bitbot-pepe-algorand-algo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Crispus Nyaga]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Algorand News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-price-predictions-bitbot-pepe-algorand-algo/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cryptocurrency prices drifted upwards this week as investors reacted to the risk-on sentiment in the market. That view is supported by the performance of US equities like the Dow Jones, Nasdaq 100, and S&#38;P 500. The US dollar index (DXY) has also pulled back as geopolitical risks have faded. Bitcoin price has remained above $66,000 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-price-predictions-bitbot-pepe-algorand-algo/">Crypto price predictions: BitBot, Pepe, Algorand (ALGO)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Cryptocurrency prices drifted upwards this week as investors reacted to the risk-on sentiment in the market. That view is supported by the performance of US equities like the Dow Jones, Nasdaq 100, and S&amp;P 500. The US dollar index (DXY) has also pulled back as geopolitical risks have faded.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Bitcoin price has remained above $66,000 while altcoins like Pepe, Algorand, and&nbsp;<a href="https://coinjournal.net/hedera/"><u>Hedera Hashgraph</u></a> (HBAR) have continued rising.&nbsp;<a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=price_prediction"><u>BitBot</u></a> ($BITBOT), on the other hand, has continued thriving as it raised over $2.8 million.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Pepe price forecast</h2>
<p dir="ltr">The price of Pepe token bottomed at $0.0000039 earlier this month and then bounced back to a high of $0.0000080, its highest point since April 1st. It has soared by more than 100% from its lowest point this month.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The token has remained above the 50-day and 100-day Exponential Moving Averages (EMA). It has also risen in the past seven straight days, the longest winning streak in months. Pepe has also jumped above the strong pivot reverse point of the Murrey Math Lines.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, the Relative Strength Index (RSI) and the Stochastic Oscillator have all pointed upwards, meaning that it has momentum. The Average Directional Index (ADX) has remained above 20. Therefore, the outlook for the token is bullish, with the next point to watch being at $0.00010, which is about 26% above the current level.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://media.igms.io/2024/03/24/1713942909831-291f89bc-b204-408e-b93a-3f104d7a89ee.jpg" style="width: 706px;height: 369.473px" class="fr-fic fr-dib" width="706" height="369.473"></p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Algorand price prediction</h2>
<p dir="ltr">The&nbsp;<a href="http://coinjournal.net/algorand"><u>Algorand</u></a> price bottomed at $0.1490 this month and then bounced back as the crypto rally resumed. It has rebounded to $0.2616, its highest swing since April 1st of this year. The token has now pulled back and retreated to the key point at $0.2400. It has remained above the 50-day and 100-day moving averages and the Ichimoku cloud indicator.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The Relative Strength Index (RSI) index has also pointed upwards. Therefore, the pair will likely now move to a consolidation phase in the coming days and then resume the bull run. If this happens, the token will likely rise to the key resistance point at $0.30, which is about 30% above the current level.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://media.igms.io/2024/03/24/1713942810999-487cf737-de5b-4ac6-b8cb-7e25886eac66.png" style="width: 696px;height: 385.12px" class="fr-fic fr-dib" width="696" height="385.12"></p>
<h2 dir="ltr">BitBot analysis</h2>
<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, BitBot, an upcoming cryptocurrency, is doing remarkably well as demand for the token rises ahead of the eventual token listing. The developers have raised over $2.8 million from investors in its current stage.</p>
<p dir="ltr">For starters, BitBot is a project that is aiming to transform the financial trading industry by creating a decentralized trading bot. The bot will be distributed using Telegram, an application used by more than 900 million users around the world.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The network will have features like revenue sharing, exclusive access to $BITBOT holders, and governance.</p>
<p>Therefore, the BitBot token is doing well as investors cheer its potential growth in the artificial intelligence (AI) and the financial services industry. &nbsp;You can buy the BitBot token&nbsp;<a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=price_prediction"><u>here</u></a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-price-predictions-bitbot-pepe-algorand-algo/">Crypto price predictions: BitBot, Pepe, Algorand (ALGO)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/crypto-price-predictions-bitbot-pepe-algorand-algo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Me3 Launches Private Sale on Yield App: Revolutionising Fan Engagement and Digital Asset Ownership</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/me3-launches-private-sale-on-yield-app-revolutionising-fan-engagement-and-digital-asset-ownership/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/me3-launches-private-sale-on-yield-app-revolutionising-fan-engagement-and-digital-asset-ownership/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 06:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dubai, United Arab Emirates, April 24th, 2024, Chainwire Me3, a prediction platform that integrates digital asset ownership with live events, Web 2.5 gaming &#38; eSports interaction, announces its private sale on the Yield App Angel Launchpad. Yield App, a well-known crypto platform&#160;that bridges the gap between traditional finance and the innovative world of Web3, making [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/me3-launches-private-sale-on-yield-app-revolutionising-fan-engagement-and-digital-asset-ownership/">Me3 Launches Private Sale on Yield App: Revolutionising Fan Engagement and Digital Asset Ownership</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dubai, United Arab Emirates, April 24th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p>Me3, a prediction platform that integrates digital asset ownership with live events, Web 2.5 gaming &amp; eSports interaction, announces its private sale on the <a href="https://yield.app/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Yield App</a> Angel Launchpad. Yield App, a well-known crypto platform&nbsp;that bridges the gap between traditional finance and the innovative world of Web3, making crypto accessible and rewarding for everyone, teams up with Me3 for an opportunity to revolutionise the way fans interact with their favourite events.</p>
<h2>Key highlights</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stake to Win Rewards:</strong> Unlock exclusive rewards and incentives with Me3&rsquo;s &lsquo;Stake to Win&rsquo; feature, incentivizing active participation and fostering a vibrant and rewarding ecosystem for all stakeholders.</li>
<li><strong>Flexible Staking and Prediction Pools:</strong> Users can engage in prediction pools with flexible staking options, allowing them to amplify their participation and earn rewards for their insights into various events and outcomes.</li>
<li><strong>Yield Battle Feature:</strong> Me3 introduces the innovative &lsquo;Yield Battle&rsquo; feature, enabling users to potentially earn yields while blending decentralized finance (DeFi) with the excitement of competitive gaming, further enhancing their earning potential and entertainment experience.</li>
<li><strong>Staking Rewards and Fee Discounts:</strong> $ME3 token holders stand to benefit from staking rewards and fee discounts, aligning their interests with the long-term success of the platform.</li>
<li><strong>Support from Established VCs and KOLs: </strong>With investments from renowned venture capital firms such as&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/playkakaogames?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Kakao Games</a> (BORA Ecosystem Fund), <a href="https://twitter.com/OVioHQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Outlier Ventures</a>, <a href="https://mvglobal.io/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Master Ventures</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/mavencapitalio?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Maven Capital</a>, <a href="https://www.tokocrypto.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Tokocrypto</a> (acquired by Binance), and more, with support from major KOLs like Jett Chang, Brian D Evans, Mario Nawful, and many others.</li>
<li><strong>Successful Offering on Top Launchpads: </strong>Having previously completed successful offerings on top launchpads such as Trustswap &amp; Ferrum DAO, Me3 is primed for further growth and success in the digital asset space.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;At Me3, we are leading a revolution in the Web3 space by launching innovative products that reinvent the relationship between digital assets and esports. We increase user engagement by combining competitive predictions with the strategic depth of yield-based markets and fan-driven activities through unique features like Hype Pool, Yield Battle, and FANatic. Furthermore, we are growing our reach through strategic alliances with leading Web 2.5 platforms and Asean gaming communities.&rdquo; said Matthew Ainscow, Founder of Me3.</p></blockquote>
<h2>Launch on Yield App</h2>
<p>Me3 through Yield Apps launchpad is offering a private sale to it&rsquo;s users&nbsp;of up to $400,000 at a token sale price of @ 0.007 per ME3 token at a&nbsp;$7 million fully diluted valuation (FDV).</p>
<h2>Tokenomics</h2>
<p>$ME3 represents the wide range of features that it brings to the ecosystem. $ME3 token users can engage with Prediction Pools, enjoy safe and transparent transactions, enjoy staking incentives (with up to 50% of platform fees flowing back to them), enjoy fee discounts, and a lot more.</p>
<h3>About Me3</h3>
<p>Introducing Me3, a pioneering platform that integrates Live Events, Gaming, Sports, and Esports engagement with the dynamic world of digital asset owners.</p>
<h3>About Yield.app</h3>
<p>Introducing Yield.app, The next generation of personal finance. Built with the user in mind, Yield App offers all the tools needed to grow the user&rsquo;s crypto portfolio</p>
<p>More details about Yield App&nbsp;can be found on Yield App&rsquo;s <a href="https://yield.app/launchpad" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">website</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/yieldapp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>For in-depth information can be found here on Yield App&rsquo;s <a href="https://yield.app/launchpad/me3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">launchpad sale</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Chief Marketing Officer<br>
Grigory Prelovskiy<br>
grigory@yield.app</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/me3-launches-private-sale-on-yield-app-revolutionising-fan-engagement-and-digital-asset-ownership/">Me3 Launches Private Sale on Yield App: Revolutionising Fan Engagement and Digital Asset Ownership</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/me3-launches-private-sale-on-yield-app-revolutionising-fan-engagement-and-digital-asset-ownership/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>K33 Research cautions Mt. Gox&#8217;s imminent $9B payout could impact Bitcoin (BTC)</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/k33-research-cautions-mt-goxs-imminent-9b-payout-could-impact-bitcoin-btc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Thuo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 20:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Cash News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200012</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gox to distribute 142,000 BTC and 143,000 BCH, valued at over $9 billion, to creditors. The payout process could commence as early as next month. All eyes are on the impact of the payout on Bitcoin and Bitcoin Cash price especially after the bitcoin halving event. Mt. Gox, once a major player in the cryptocurrency [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/k33-research-cautions-mt-goxs-imminent-9b-payout-could-impact-bitcoin-btc/">K33 Research cautions Mt. Gox&#8217;s imminent $9B payout could impact Bitcoin (BTC)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gox to distribute 142,000 BTC and 143,000 BCH, valued at over $9 billion, to creditors.</li>
<li>The payout process could commence as early as next month.</li>
<li>All eyes are on the impact of the payout on Bitcoin and Bitcoin Cash price especially after the bitcoin halving event.</li>
</ul>
<p>Mt. Gox, once a major player in the cryptocurrency exchange scene, faced a devastating hack in 2014, leading to its collapse. Now, nearly a decade later, the defunct exchange is preparing to distribute a significant sum of digital assets including approximately 142,000 <a href="https://coinjournal.net/bitcoin/what-is-bitcoin/">Bitcoin (BTC)</a> and 143,000 <a href="https://coinjournal.net/bitcoin-cash/what-is-bitcoin-cash/">Bitcoin Cash (BCH)</a>, amounting to over $9 billion in total, to creditors.</p>
<p>This impending payout has prompted concerns among market observers, with K33 Research highlighting the possibility of a negative impact on the price of Bitcoin in a <a href="https://k33.com/research/articles/the-froth-is-over">report</a> released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>According to the analysts, the influx of Mt. Gox coins into the market could create downward pressure on BTC valuation in the coming weeks.</p>
<h2>Possible implications for Bitcoin (BTC) price</h2>
<p>K33 Research analysts have highlighted concerns that the influx of Mt. Gox&rsquo;s digital assets into the market could exert downward pressure on Bitcoin&rsquo;s price in the coming weeks. While creditors may not immediately liquidate their assets, the anticipation surrounding the payout could instil caution among investors, potentially dampening market sentiment.</p>
<p>Creditors recently received updates on their BTC and BCH claims, indicating that payments could commence sooner than initially anticipated. This development, coupled with the looming deadline set by Mt. Gox trustees for reimbursements, has intensified speculation within the crypto community.</p>
<p>Market observers remain divided on the potential impact of Mt. Gox&rsquo;s payout on Bitcoin&rsquo;s price. While some believe that creditors may opt to hold onto their funds, others fear that the sheer volume of digital assets entering the market could trigger a sell-off, leading to a temporary downturn in prices.</p>
<p>Despite the uncertainty surrounding Mt. Gox&rsquo;s payout, the crypto market continues to show resilience in the face of external pressures. However, investors are advised to exercise caution and closely monitor developments related to the distribution process to mitigate any adverse effects on their portfolios especially according to the K33 Research analysts warning.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/k33-research-cautions-mt-goxs-imminent-9b-payout-could-impact-bitcoin-btc/">K33 Research cautions Mt. Gox&#8217;s imminent $9B payout could impact Bitcoin (BTC)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Archax, Ownera and Hedera collaborate to tokenize BlackRock money market fund</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/archax-ownera-hedera-collaborate-tokenize-blackrock-mmf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 18:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Archax, Ownera and The HBAR Foundation have enabled the first tokenization of BlackRock&#8217;s money market fund (MMF) on Hedera. This is a major development in the real-world assets (RWAs) industry and comes after abrdn plc tokenized its MMFs on Hedera last year. The crypto world has witnessed a historic moment in the real-world assets (RWAs) [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/archax-ownera-hedera-collaborate-tokenize-blackrock-mmf/">Archax, Ownera and Hedera collaborate to tokenize BlackRock money market fund</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Archax, Ownera and The HBAR Foundation have enabled the first tokenization of BlackRock&rsquo;s money market fund (MMF) on Hedera.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a major development in the real-world assets (RWAs) industry and comes after abrdn plc tokenized its MMFs on Hedera last year.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The crypto world has witnessed a historic moment in the real-world assets (RWAs) industry after Archax, a London-based digital asset exchange, broker and custodian, tokenized the BlackRock ICS US Treasury money market fund (MMF) on the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/hedera/">Hedera (HBAR) blockchain</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Archax collaborated with the HBAR Foundation and the institutional-grade digital assets platform Ownera to bring the MMF to Hedera. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to details in an <a href="https://blog.archax.com/resources/archax-increases-tokenised-money-market-fund-offerings" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcement</a>, the milestone follows Hedera Council member abrdn&rsquo;s successful tokenization of its MMFs on Hedera last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">abrdn is the largest active wealth manager in the UK and its flagship tokenized funds marked a major milestone in the asset management industry.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today we witness <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RWA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#RWA</a> history as <a href="https://twitter.com/BlackRock?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BlackRock</a>&rsquo;s ICS US Treasury money market fund (MMF) is tokenized on <a href="https://twitter.com/hedera?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Hedera</a> with <a href="https://twitter.com/ArchaxEx?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ArchaxEx</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/OwneraIO?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@OwneraIO</a>, marking a major milestone in asset management by bringing the world&rsquo;s largest asset manager on-chain &#127974; <a href="https://t.co/1Kye8cjAJx">pic.twitter.com/1Kye8cjAJx</a></p>
<p>&mdash; HBAR Foundation (@HBAR_foundation) <a href="https://twitter.com/HBAR_foundation/status/1782759384742813951?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hedera&rsquo;s growing RWA adoption</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The RWAs sector is getting a big boost from MMFs, which offer suitable investment vehicles for investors with institutional stability and yield.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With tokenised MMFs allows for the trading of their shares on exchanges such as Archax and provide extra benefits that include instantaneous transfer and deployment as collateral rather than just being used for traditional subscriptions and redemptions.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;The addition of MMF shares tokenized on Hedera, enabled by Archax, is a huge vote of confidence. Hedera&rsquo;s unmatched speed, security, and low-cost infrastructure is ideally suited for the institutional-grade tokenization of real-world assets made possible by Archax,&rdquo; Shayne Higdon, CEO of The HBAR Foundation, said in a statement.</span></p></blockquote>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">HBAR price soars to 4-week high</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HBAR price surged after the news, rising more than 46% to reach highs of $0.1314 on Tuesday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The token changed hands at around $0.087 before the news and is currently sitting at its highest level since March 27. Data from CoinGecko shows HBAR&rsquo;s 24-hour trading volume has spiked more than 600% to over $346 million.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/archax-ownera-hedera-collaborate-tokenize-blackrock-mmf/">Archax, Ownera and Hedera collaborate to tokenize BlackRock money market fund</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlackCard Redefines Crypto Payments With Token Launch And Key Listings</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/blackcard-redefines-crypto-payments-with-token-launch-and-key-listings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 18:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ico]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=200001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By introducing a plethora of useful features for crypto users, including the launch of the $BcCoin token (which will be featured on prominent crypto exchanges soon), BlackCard aims to be at the forefront of revolutionizing global cryptocurrency payment operations. By utilizing AI technology, the BlackCard Crypto Credit Card empowers users to easily integrate their digital [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/blackcard-redefines-crypto-payments-with-token-launch-and-key-listings/">BlackCard Redefines Crypto Payments With Token Launch And Key Listings</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By introducing a plethora of useful features for crypto users, including the launch of the $BcCoin token (which will be featured on prominent crypto exchanges soon), BlackCard aims to be at the forefront of revolutionizing global cryptocurrency payment operations. By utilizing AI technology, the BlackCard Crypto Credit Card empowers users to easily integrate their digital assets into their respective everyday transactions, thereby removing the limitations commonly associated with traditional banking systems.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What Does BlackCard Provide?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With BlackCard, users can now effortlessly convert their cryptocurrency assets into local currency at any point of sale, thereby guaranteeing optimal exchange rates and unparalleled convenience. This solution simplifies transactions, providing users the freedom to utilize their digital assets for a variety of purposes, such as everyday purchases, online shopping, ATM withdrawals, and much more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moreover, the BlackCard team has introduced the aforementioned </span><a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/community/profile/BlackCardCoin/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$BcCoin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> token. This represents a significant advancement within the digital asset sector, as not only has the token witnessed a remarkable surge in value when it skyrocketed by an impressive 900% from its initial price of 30 cents to an impressive $2.70, but the growth has also garnered widespread attention from enthusiasts and investors around the world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This highlights the intrinsic value of the token along with its disruptive potential within the global cryptocurrency market. In addition, with a target price firmly established at 100 USD, the token presents an investment opportunity for discerning investors who seek exponential growth potential.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking Toward The Future</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As interest in Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies continues to soar, the $BcCoin token looks to be a beacon of opportunity, one that offers investors continued access to the burgeoning digital economy. The BlackCard team also managed to secure several key listings on prominent cryptocurrency exchanges. On April 24th, the $BcCoin token shall be listed on MEXC, BingX, and XT, thereby expanding its reach and accessibility to a global audience of investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furthermore, the BlackCard team looks to take advantage of the ever-growing interest in cryptocurrencies, which will also undoubtedly include several additional advancements within the industry going forward. In doing so, the platform is able to enhance its position as a revolutionary platform within this space.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">About BlackCard</span></h2>
<p><a href="https://blackcardcoin.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">BlackCard</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a provider of high-quality crypto solutions, providing a useful range of services and products that are fully customized for each user to enhance their digital financial well-being. The team is poised to capitalize on a vast market opportunity with an estimated 500 million crypto wallet owners worldwide. With a keen focus on security, convenience, and sophistication, BlackCard remains committed to shaping the future of finance through meticulous transactional excellence.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BlackCard&rsquo;s other notable aspects include instant card activation, unlimited global spending, 13% instant starter cashback, the ability to earn instant 10% on all referrals, simple KYC procedures, zero fees for the credit card, and much more. In the near future, BlackCard plans to further develop its ecosystem by adding cross-chain interoperability, sharding, and a slew of strategic partnerships, according to its </span><a href="https://download.blackcardcoin.com/BCCoin_BlackCardCoin_Roadmap_v2.pdf?_gl=1*1dj61gc*_ga*OTMzNjExNzQ4LjE3MTM4NjYxMDA.*_ga_TWMNZ2FJVB*MTcxMzg2NjA5OS4xLjEuMTcxMzg2NzM1MC4wLjAuMA.."><span style="font-weight: 400;">roadmap</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be sure to check out BlackCard&rsquo;s </span><a href="https://blackcardcoin.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">official website</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for additional information, as well as its </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/BCcoin.official"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://twitter.com/BlackCardCoin"><span style="font-weight: 400;">X</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/bccoin.official/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instagram</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@bccoin.official"><span style="font-weight: 400;">YouTube</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://t.me/official_BCcoin"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Telegram</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> channels for regular updates.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/blackcard-redefines-crypto-payments-with-token-launch-and-key-listings/">BlackCard Redefines Crypto Payments With Token Launch And Key Listings</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
