<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<atom:link href="https://coinjournal.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<description><![CDATA[Keep your finger on the pulse of the fast-moving cryptocurrency sector with all the latest crypto news, analysis and reviews from CoinJournal]]></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 12:46:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/apple-touch-icon.png</url>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>RECQ records lightning-fast presale progress amid sluggish market momentum on INJ and LUNC</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/recq-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress-amid-sluggish-market-momentum-on-inj-and-lunc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 17:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="374" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/RECQ-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Rebel Satoshi ($RBLZ) draws investors with its lightning-fast presale of the $RECQ token The Injective (INJ) token is set to rise above $40 and beyond in the coming months, according to some analysts The Terra Classic (LUNC) token price is predicted to drop below $0.000120. The presale of Rebel Satoshi&#8217;s new token, $RECQ, has been [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/recq-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress-amid-sluggish-market-momentum-on-inj-and-lunc/">RECQ records lightning-fast presale progress amid sluggish market momentum on INJ and LUNC</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="374" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/RECQ-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li>Rebel Satoshi ($RBLZ) draws investors with its lightning-fast presale of the $RECQ token</li>
<li>The Injective (INJ) token is set to rise above $40 and beyond in the coming months, according to some analysts</li>
<li>The Terra Classic (LUNC) token price is predicted to drop below $0.000120.</li>
</ul>
<p>The presale of <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4641&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel Satoshi&rsquo;s</a> new token, $RECQ, has been growing at a significant rate. This growth has occurred even as many top crypto coins, such as Injective (INJ) and Terra Classic (LUNC), have been struggling.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s delve into why $RECQ has left the top altcoins like INJ and LUNC behind, and why several analysts are describing it as the best crypto to buy right now.</p>
<h2>Rebel Satoshi nears 75% completion of stage 1 of the $RECQ presale</h2>
<p>The innovative meme coin project Rebel Satoshi is built on the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/ethereum/what-is-ethereum/">Ethereum network</a>. Inspired by Guy Fawkes and Satoshi Nakamoto, Rebel Satoshi aims to bring a community-driven revolution. Rebel Satoshi aims to challenge the centralized financial institutions and take back control from the elites.</p>
<p>The Rebel Satoshi ecosystem includes an NFT Vault, staking pools, a merchandise store, and a gaming Arcade. The entire Rebel Satoshi ecosystem is built on its dual-token system of the $RBLZ and the $RECQ tokens. Rebel Satoshi aims to grow to a $100 million market cap. Also, the presale of the $RBLZ token generated 150% returns and raised over $2.5 million for its investors.</p>
<p>Right now, <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4641&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel Satoshi</a> is conducting the presale of the $RECQ tokens at $0.0037 per token in Stage 1. The $RECQ token has rallied by 85% to reach the current price, and over 74% of tokens have already been sold out. By the end of the presale, the $RECQ token is forecast to surge by 238% to $0.0125. That&rsquo;s why some analysts are describing the $RECQ token as one of the best cryptos to buy right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=MCAP&amp;utm_medium=Banner&amp;utm_id=Bird"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-198347" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Market-cap.png" alt="" width="587" height="73"></a></p>
<h2>Injective continues to trade in red after rising to an all-time high</h2>
<p>The Injective (INJ) token has been one of the best performers in the recent market surge. As a result, the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/injective/">Injective&nbsp; price</a> rose to an all-time high of $52.75 on March 13. Since then, the INJ token has been on a downtrend. As of the second week of April, the INJ price dropped by 34.6% to trade at around $34.45.</p>
<p>Amid the price drop, the Injective (INJ) ecosystem has continued to grow exponentially. For instance, the Ionic Upgrade to the Injective Bridge was announced on March 26. The first DePin platform on Injective (INJ), Aurora, was introduced on April 7.</p>
<p>These developments and others in the Injective ecosystem have led to a bullish outlook. Experts predict that the INJ token could rise above $40 again in the coming months.</p>
<h2>Terra Classic trades sideways after getting caught in market volatility</h2>
<p>The Terra Classic (LUNC) token has been caught up in volatility ever since rising in March. Initially, the LUNC token price dropped to $0.000121 on March 19 before bouncing slightly. The Terra Classic price then rose by 41.3% to $0.000171 a week later before dipping again.</p>
<p>Since then, the Terra Classic (LUNC) has entered a downtrend, dipping by 20.4% to around the $0.000136 level. This drop in LUNC price has occurred despite <a href="https://coinjournal.net/exchanges/binance/">Binanc</a>e burning 4.1 billion LUNC on April 2.</p>
<p>As the massive token burn has failed to turn the Terra Classic token bullish, experts are increasingly bearish on it. Hence, many are predicting that the Terra Classic (LUNC) will drop below $0.000120 in the coming months.</p>
<p>For the latest updates and more information, be sure to visit the official<a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/"> Rebel Satoshi Website</a> or contact Rebel Red via <a href="https://t.me/RBLZRED">Telegram</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/recq-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress-amid-sluggish-market-momentum-on-inj-and-lunc/">RECQ records lightning-fast presale progress amid sluggish market momentum on INJ and LUNC</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/ethereum-and-cardano-register-gains-analysts-focus-shifts-to-nugx-token/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="550" height="550" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" srcset="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg 550w, https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><p>Ethereum and Cardano remain stable and show growth in the crypto market downturn. NuggetRush token emerges as a promising altcoin with play-to-earn gaming features. Cardano prioritizes security and scalability for smart contracts, while Ethereum faces technical challenges but maintains its commitment to decentralization. Amidst a recent downturn in the cryptocurrency market, Ethereum (ETH) and Cardano [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ethereum-and-cardano-register-gains-analysts-focus-shifts-to-nugx-token/">Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="550" height="550" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" srcset="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg 550w, https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><ul>
<li>Ethereum and Cardano remain stable and show growth in the crypto market downturn.</li>
<li>NuggetRush token emerges as a promising altcoin with play-to-earn gaming features.</li>
<li>Cardano prioritizes security and scalability for smart contracts, while Ethereum faces technical challenges but maintains its commitment to decentralization.</li>
</ul>
<p>Amidst a recent downturn in the cryptocurrency market, Ethereum (ETH) and Cardano (ADA) have demonstrated signs of steadiness, as both assets have seen remarkable increases in value. At the same time, some analysts are shifting their attention to <a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=75">NuggetRush (NUGX)</a>, assessing its potential to become the next altcoin sensation. This digital asset offers innovative features and potential for growth in the crypto community.</p>
<p>Nugge&shy;tRush is among the bullish altcoins incorporating a play-to-earn (P2E) gaming design, allowing participants to e&shy;arn tangible assets as prizes. Its innovative&shy; offerings strive to foster an e&shy;ngaging gaming atmosphere, attracting investors and gaming e&shy;nthusiasts alike. The blockchain ICO presale&shy; is gaining momentum and piquing crypto investors&rsquo; intere&shy;st.</p>
<p>This article explores why Ethereum and Cardano show remarkable gains as analysts eye NUGX tokens as the next altcoin sensations.</p>
<h2>NuggetRush (NUGX): decentralized GameFi exploration and real-world rewards</h2>
<p><a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=75">NuggetRush</a> is a new DeFi project fostering a vibrant community within a flourishing digital ecosystem focused on GameFi exploration. Operating on the Ethereum blockchain, NuggetRush prioritizes broad user accessibility. NUGX captures atte&shy;ntion through blending exploration, strategic thinking, and tangible&shy; real-world benefits. Analysts sugge&shy;st it may be one of the bullish altcoins poise&shy;d for significant gains this year.</p>
<p>The platform pre&shy;sents diverse ave&shy;nues for gamers to accumulate re&shy;wards, including acquiring unique character NFTs, earning RUSHGEMS, and trading in-game&shy; assets. NuggetRush differe&shy;ntiates itself from typical meme&shy; coins by enabling players to trade the&shy;ir in-game earnings outside the&shy; platform&rsquo;s ecosystem. This new DeFi project has also established a playe&shy;r-driven marketplace for characte&shy;r NFTs and other exclusive ite&shy;ms. This enriches the platform&rsquo;s e&shy;conomy and empowers users to e&shy;xchange and sell virtual assets.</p>
<p>NuggetRush has already garnered immense&shy; support, with over 271 million tokens sold and more&shy; than $3.75 million raised. Some industry analysts are predicting that once NUGX is listed on major e&shy;xchanges, its price could expe&shy;rience a significant surge, pote&shy;ntially reaching $0.020. This anticipated price incre&shy;ase could position NUGX as one of the best crypto investment options right now.</p>
<p>The NuggetRush vesting system presents an appealing incentive for early adopters. Through participation in the presale phase, investors can access up to 50% of the tokens across five claim rounds based on their entry timing. This mechanism could enable early supporters to realize substantial gains as the project progresses.</p>
<h2>Cardano (ADA): scalable ecosystem for smart contracts and DApps</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/cardano/what-is-cardano/">Cardano</a> is a decentralized platform that creates a more secure and scalable infrastructure for developing smart contracts and decentralized applications (DApps). Cardano is trading at approximately $0.5877, showing stability amidst market fluctuations. As the highly anticipated Bitcoin halving eve&shy;nt approaches, alternative coins like&shy; Cardano are garnering attention. ADA showcase&shy;s resilience and growth pote&shy;ntial amid market volatility. This has piqued the inte&shy;rest of investors and traders se&shy;eking promising alternatives within the&shy; cryptocurrency landscape.</p>
<p>Cardano has see&shy;n a remarkable turnaround in investor se&shy;ntiment. After facing outflows, there&shy;&rsquo;s now a substantial $1.1 million inflow into ADA investment products. This shift highlights Cardano&rsquo;s resurge&shy;nce and growing appeal among crypto investors. The&shy; influx of funds indicates a renewe&shy;d confidence in Cardano&rsquo;s potential, marking a positive&shy; trend after a period of unce&shy;rtainty.</p>
<h2>Ethereum (ETH): empowering decentralization with smart contracts</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/ethereum/what-is-ethereum/">Ethere&shy;um</a> is a blockchain network that is decentralize&shy;d and open-source, with the ability to e&shy;xecute smart contracts. The curre&shy;nt price of Ethereum is approximate&shy;ly $3,315, which represents an incre&shy;ase of nearly 2%. After a significant upward tre&shy;nd from the $3,500 support level, ETH is now facing re&shy;sistance around $3,550 and the 100-hour Simple Moving Ave&shy;rage (SMA). The hourly ETH/USD chart reve&shy;als a notable resistance zone&shy; at $3,550.</p>
<p>Technical indicators indicate that the hourly Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD) remains bullish for ETH. However, the Relative Strength Index (RSI) sits below the 50 level, suggesting potential increased selling pressure. Despite recent challenges, Ethereum&rsquo;s repeated tests of crucial support levels hint at the possibility of a rapid price recovery.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>As Ethereum and Cardano continue demonstrating remarkable gains in the cryptocurrency market, analysts are now setting their sights on the NuggetRush token as the next potential altcoin sensation.</p>
<p>NuggetRush is an intriguing platform that combine&shy;s gaming with decentralized finance&shy; principles. Its unique approach prese&shy;nts an attractive investment prospe&shy;ct for those intereste&shy;d in the growing GameFi industry.</p>
<p>With growing excite&shy;ment surrounding NUGX&rsquo;s listing on major exchanges and the&shy; continued developme&shy;nt of its ecosystem, this token&rsquo;s future&shy; appears promising. It has the potential to cre&shy;ate ripples within the e&shy;ver-changing cryptocurrency world.</p>
<p>For more information on NUGX, <a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=75">visit NuggetRush Presale Website</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ethereum-and-cardano-register-gains-analysts-focus-shifts-to-nugx-token/">Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong’s spot ETFs report drives BTC higher; investors pile into Bitbot presale</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/hong-kongs-spot-etfs-report-drive-btc-higher-investors-pile-into-bitbot-presale/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 12:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1500" height="1000" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/hong-kong-reportedly-set-to-approve-btc-etf.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Bitcoin price has flipped above $70,000, while Ethereum is above $3,500. This is after news that Hong Kong is likely to approve its first spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs as soon as early next week. Bitbot (BITBOT) is nearing the $2.3 million mark in presale amid investor interest. Bitcoin is trading up, currently green as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/hong-kongs-spot-etfs-report-drive-btc-higher-investors-pile-into-bitbot-presale/">Hong Kong’s spot ETFs report drives BTC higher; investors pile into Bitbot presale</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1500" height="1000" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/hong-kong-reportedly-set-to-approve-btc-etf.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitcoin price has flipped above $70,000, while Ethereum is above $3,500.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">This is after news that Hong Kong is likely to approve its first spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs as soon as early next week.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot (BITBOT) is nearing the $2.3 million mark in presale amid investor interest.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> is trading up, currently green as price hovers above $70,900. The leading cryptocurrency&rsquo;s potential to break out to a new all-time high has received a new boost as reports emerge Hong Kong is set to approve its first spot Bitcoin ETFs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BTC&rsquo;s upside flip is likely to push other altcoins higher, and one of the new tokens attracting the most attention is <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=investment_opportunity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitbot (BITBOT)</a>.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Is Bitcoin (BTC) set to explode next week?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">There are <a href="https://twitter.com/BTC_Archive/status/1778741866168537315" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Hong Kong could approve the first spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs in the region as early as Monday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">A Bloomberg report on Friday quotes sources as saying that the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) is set to give it nod, just days after major Chinese funds applied to issue spot Bitcoin ETFs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While Hong Kong&rsquo;s decision is not officially communicated as of writing, there&rsquo;s growing positivity in the market already. In January 2024, when the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) approved the first spot Bitcoin ETFs, the price of BTC skyrocketed amid massive demand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BTC reached its ATH of $73,737 in March, riding halving and spot ETFs sentiment. The SEC has <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/u-s-sec-calls-for-public-input-on-spot-ethereum-etf-applications/">called for public participation on spot ETH ETFs</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Today&rsquo;s news has seen the bellwether crypto flip from lows of $69,500 to currently trade above $70,900. Ethereum has also gained slightly, currently hovering above $3,520.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Should the ETFs draw inflows as witnessed with BlackRock&rsquo;s IBIT and others, there&rsquo;s potential for BTC, ETH and other coins to rally in coming weeks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Also likely to attract investor are new tokens that could tap into the overall market strength and specific fundamentals to emerge as top performers in the market in 2024 and beyond.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot: Pioneering non-custodial trading bot on Telegram</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BitBot is the pioneering non-custodial crypto trading bot, poised to enter the crypto market at a time traders are keen on available opportunities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While competing Telegram trading bots are custodial solutions &ndash; that is they control users&rsquo; private keys and thus hold their assets &ndash; Bitbot takes the approach of &lsquo;not your keys, not your assets.&rdquo; In short, Bitbot is where a Telegram bot user has the full control of their private keys and wallet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Security is key to crypto traders, who unfortunately have had to learn the hard way given incidents involving top bots such as Unibot and Banana Gun. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">By focusing on security through its partnership with Knightsafe, Bitbot has taken an early lead against potential rival trading apps.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot app&rsquo;s AI capabilities add to the superior outlook, with users able to access all the advanced institutional-grade trading tools that make trading via bots such a huge market in the crypto space. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot offers all of these, including trade sniping, gem scanner, copy trading and automated execution, without compromising on user security and convenience.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot presale surpasses $2.2 million amid investor interest</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The native BITBOT token is in presale and users will get access to benefits such as revenue-sharing, trading discounts and airdrops. Presale participants can buy BITBOT at the still heavily discounted price of $0.0155 in stage 10.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Early bird investors have pushed the presale to near $2.3 million. Notably, there&rsquo;s just five stages to go before Bitbot hits the final stage 15 and tokens debut in the market. This could be at a time when Bitcoin and Ethereum are in parabolic mode.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">That means current presale prices could be a real bargain and opportunity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">To learn more visit the <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=investment_opportunity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitbot website</a>.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/hong-kongs-spot-etfs-report-drive-btc-higher-investors-pile-into-bitbot-presale/">Hong Kong’s spot ETFs report drives BTC higher; investors pile into Bitbot presale</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>99Bitcoins Launches Learn-To-Earn Presale and Raises $150K On First Day</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 10:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainwire_-_1800x1080_12_1712913142ZfZpzbRf70.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>New York, United States, April 12th, 2024, Chainwire 99Bitcoins, established in 2013, has recently begun its token presale in an effort to harness the current upward trend in Bitcoin&#8217;s value. The 99BTC team, seizing this opportunity, offers its learn-to-earn platform, a longstanding resource in cryptocurrency education. What is 99Bitcoins? 99Bitcoins has been breaking down technical [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/">99Bitcoins Launches Learn-To-Earn Presale and Raises $150K On First Day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainwire_-_1800x1080_12_1712913142ZfZpzbRf70.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p><strong>New York, United States, April 12th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">99Bitcoins</a>, established in 2013, has recently begun its token presale in an effort to harness the current upward trend in Bitcoin&rsquo;s value. The 99BTC team, seizing this opportunity, offers its learn-to-earn platform, a longstanding resource in cryptocurrency education.</p>
<h2>What is 99Bitcoins?</h2>
<p>99Bitcoins has been breaking down technical concepts and onboarding newcomers to the crypto world for over ten years as the team can show by the numbers on its social media accounts: over <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@99Bitcoins" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">700,000 YouTube followers</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/99BitcoinsHQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">16,000 Twitter followers</a> and 2 million registered users have confirmed its +80 hours of resources are a great entry point for those looking to learn more about crypto.</p>
<p>The $99BTC token is its latest venture. The team promotes its commitment to education by introducing the &ldquo;gamification of learning&rdquo; into the platform, providing $99BTC rewards for those who complete its courses, such as exclusive access to premium content, discounts on partner products and services, VIP communities, trading signals, and token holder events.</p>
<p>The 99Bitcoins team aims to attract all the potential new users who are expected to enter the crypto space and explore Bitcoin in light of the upcoming halving; the event, which will occur this month, is expected to increase the number of first-time crypto enthusiasts as confirmed by multiple researches and major sources like <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-halving-institutional-investors-crypto-adoption" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CoinTelegraph</a> and <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/consensus-magazine/2024/04/10/how-the-halving-will-impact-the-bitcoin-market/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CoinDesk</a>.</p>
<h2>Pioneering BRC-20: Pushing Learn-to-Earn in new directions</h2>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dnM2lZrkUsb6PZiozUftflhQimKkVi2QrUAT__eusmMRyO5g-k_1712912300JYsiGkZO9d.jpeg"></p>
<p>99Bitcoins is also trying to set itself as a pioneer of the BRC-20 movement: a new token standard that allows developers to deploy smart contracts on the Bitcoin blockchain. Security and transparency are also key to this project, a <a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/assets/docs/audit.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Solidproof audit</a> confirms that 99Bitcoins contract does have no potential issues or warnings.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s worth noting $99BTC is originally deployed as an ERC-20 token and that it will be bridged to BRC-20 only in Q4 2024, transferring the security of the project to the Bitcoin network.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/wRavhnrTYwyazd5brgtgKMP8XHvPWUAB6PegDIOTaV2wemttN3_1712912300nOKAR4dtXe.jpeg"></p>
<p>When it comes to the tokenomics (renamed to Token Metrics by its team), 99Bitcoins is distributing its 99 billion $99BTC total supply with the goal of helping it remain competitive and provide lasting sustainability:</p>
<ul>
<li>15% is allocated to the presale, which is currently selling $99BTC for $0.001</li>
<li>14% for staking rewards, providing $99BTC stakers with rewards for two years</li>
<li>23% is allocated to project funds</li>
<li>17% for community rewards</li>
<li>8% to provide liquidity to exchanges</li>
<li>23% for marketing</li>
</ul>
<p>This tokenomics structure is then paired with an ambitious roadmap which would target the beta release of the platform to last quarter this year, followed by the full release next year.</p>
<h3>About 99Bitcoins</h3>
<p><a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">99Bitcoins</a> is a vital educational resource for Bitcoin. It focuses on providing information about cryptocurrency to onboard new users to the industry. The website was established in 2013 and has since expanded its knowledge base to popular blockchains and cryptocurrencies such as Litecoin, Ethereum, Cardano, and Solana.</p>
<p>The platform now brings a gamification element to its product, allowing students to receive $99BTC rewards in a L2E economy. The $99BTC token is also pioneering the BRC-20 movement, a new token standard that enables smart contracts to be deployed on the Bitcoin network.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/en#home" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/99BitcoinsHQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">X</a></li>
<li><a href="https://t.me/Official_99_Bitcoins" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Telegram</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>99Bitcoins<br>
contact@99bitcoins.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/">99Bitcoins Launches Learn-To-Earn Presale and Raises $150K On First Day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Omni Network lands on Binance Launchpool as Algotech picks presale momentum</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/omni-network-lands-on-binance-launchpool-as-algotech-picks-presale-momentum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 09:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="500" height="333" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/1688987659644-b2863938-988a-423c-9374-7ab81e3d5bf4.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Binance has announced Omni Network (OMNI) as the 52nd project on the Binance Launchpool. Algotech (ALGT) is a new crypto project set to redefine crypto trading. OMNI and ALGT could be altcoins to watch in 2024. Omni Network (OMNI) is the 52nd project on the Binance Launchpool, and excitement is high among crypto investors. Meanwhile, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/omni-network-lands-on-binance-launchpool-as-algotech-picks-presale-momentum/">Omni Network lands on Binance Launchpool as Algotech picks presale momentum</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="500" height="333" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/1688987659644-b2863938-988a-423c-9374-7ab81e3d5bf4.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Binance has announced Omni Network (OMNI) as the 52nd project on the Binance Launchpool.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">Algotech (ALGT) is a new crypto project set to redefine crypto trading.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400"><span style="font-weight: 400">OMNI and ALGT could be altcoins to watch in 2024.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Omni Network (OMNI) is the 52nd project on the Binance Launchpool, and excitement is high among crypto investors. Meanwhile, new crypto project </span><a href="https://algotechtrade.com?utm_source=coinjournal&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=1204" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Algotech (ALGT)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> is generating huge interest as traders look forward to its launch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Is OMNI worth a look after the Binance announcement and could ALGT emerge as the top crypto trading related token? Find out more.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Algotech, the new decentralised algorithmic trading platform</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As traders look to tap into opportunities in the crypto market, the need for cutting-edge trading tools and advanced artificial intelligent solutions is rising.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Algotech is a new decentralized algorithmic trading platform that could redefine the crypto trading space.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Not only does it offer innovative algorithms it combines the best of </span><a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/ai/"><span style="font-weight: 400">AI</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> and machine learning capabilities. Algotech&rsquo;s design means traders can leverage machine learning capabilities to profit from efficiency and accuracy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The automated strategies that Algotech brings to the market and which traders can leverage to make profitable trades trend following, mean reversion and breakout trading. The strategies are a result of expert insights, machine learning techniques and quantitative analysis.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This is a project entering a market rife with opportunities and the native token ALGT could be one of the top altcoins to watch in 2024.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Omni Network (OMNI): Binance introduces 52nd Launchpool project</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Omni Network (OMNI) is the latest project to </span><a href="https://twitter.com/binance/status/1778664044704178201" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">feature in the Binance Launchpool</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> ahead of its mainnet launch and trading debut. Omni is the 52nd project to bring airdrop benefits to the community via the Launchpool.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/binance/"><span style="font-weight: 400">Binance</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> users can farm OMNI over the next four days, starting on April 13, 2024 at 00:00 (UTC). Omni has a total supply of 100 million tokens, 3.5% or 3.5 million of which will be available to Launchpool participants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">At the end of the farming period, Binance will list the OMNI token and open trading on April 17, 2024, at 12:00 (UTC). Trading pairs to be added will include OMNI/BTC, OMNI/USDT, OMNI/BNB, OMNI/FDUSD, and OMNI/TRY.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">What is Omni Network?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Omni Network, is an interoperability protocol that provides for low latency communications across Ethereum rollups.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The Cosmos SDK powered protocol facilitates seamless interoperability between Ethereum rollups, empowering developers and users with a unified system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The protocol&rsquo;s team </span><a href="https://twitter.com/OmniFDN/status/1778432401594790072" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">announced</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> its Genesis airdrop on Thursday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">According to a recent update, the project&rsquo;s launch will initially see users have access to simple cross-rollup messaging functionality. However, as the protocol matures, OMNI holders will participate in governance decisions, including network upgrades and launch of new developer features.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Binance&rsquo;s listing of projects has often seen native tokens explode in value amid listing excitement. OMNI could be the next one to see a significant price surge.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Algotech presale accelerates in stage 3</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">With the project set to launch in coming months, the crypto community has poured into the Algotech presale.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The native ALGT token is currently priced at $0.08 in stage 3, with over $3.7 million raised from early bird investors keen to take advantage of Algotech&rsquo;s potential market dominance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In the next stage, the ALGT price will increase to $0.10.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">ALGT holders will benefit from features such as trading fee discounts, exclusive rewards and participation in future airdrop campaigns among others. Joining the presale is an early backing of a project likely to take the crypto trading by storm, particularly amid the anticipated bull market explosion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">To learn more about Algotech or to join the presale, visit their </span><a href="https://algotechtrade.com?utm_source=coinjournal&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=1204" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">website</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/omni-network-lands-on-binance-launchpool-as-algotech-picks-presale-momentum/">Omni Network lands on Binance Launchpool as Algotech picks presale momentum</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitget Launches Pre-market with Merlin Chain (MERL) as the First Supported Asset</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitget-launches-pre-market-with-merlin-chain-merl-as-the-first-supported-asset/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitget-launches-pre-market-with-merlin-chain-merl-as-the-first-supported-asset/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 07:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198266</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainwire-1200_720_1712891086I0YDdd4oAu.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Victoria, Seychelles, April 12th, 2024, Chainwire Bitget, a world-leading cryptocurrency exchange and Web3 platform, is excited to announce the launch of its latest feature, Pre-market. This new feature aims to meet the demand for pre-listing trading of the latest tokens and enhance the liquidity and trading experience for users. The first supported token on the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/bitget-launches-pre-market-with-merlin-chain-merl-as-the-first-supported-asset/">Bitget Launches Pre-market with Merlin Chain (MERL) as the First Supported Asset</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainwire-1200_720_1712891086I0YDdd4oAu.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p><strong>Victoria, Seychelles, April 12th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p>Bitget, a world-leading cryptocurrency exchange and Web3 platform, is excited to announce the launch of its latest feature, Pre-market. This new feature aims to meet the demand for pre-listing trading of the latest tokens and enhance the liquidity and trading experience for users. The first supported token on the Pre-market will be Merlin Chain (MERL), and trading will commence at 04:00 (UTC) on April 12th.</p>
<p>Pre-market is designed to facilitate trading for tokens that have not yet been officially listed on the spot market of major centralized exchanges like Bitget. It allows users to activate community trading interests and attract early adopters. By enabling pre-listing trading, users can gain early pricing power over the asset, making it easier to become the primary trading market for the asset once it is listed on various exchanges.</p>
<p>The Pre-market will debut with Merlin Chain (MERL) as its first supported project. Merlin Chain is a Bitcoin Layer 2 solution that integrates the ZK-rollup network, decentralized oracles, and on-chain BTC fraud prevention modules. Merlin Chain supports popular Bitcoin protocols such as BRC20, BRC420, Bitmap, Atomicals, Pipe, Stamp, and more, enabling a broader user base to interact on Bitcoin Layer 2. As an EVM-compatible chain, it offers low fees and high scalability, ensuring rapid transaction processing and improved transaction liquidity.</p>
<p>Bitget&rsquo;s Pre-market trading offers an OTC market platform, facilitating peer-to-peer trading and enabling buyers and sellers to set prices and match trades directly. This ensures that they can secure their desired prices and liquidity in advance for the assets supported. Users engaging in pre-listing trading must ensure they have sufficient assets before trading and can complete delivery within the specified timeframe.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Gracy Chen, Managing Director of Bitget</strong>, expressed, &ldquo;Bitget&rsquo;s introduction of the Pre-market marks a significant advancement in our commitment to providing cutting-edge solutions for our users. This innovative feature underscores our dedication to fostering a dynamic and inclusive trading environment, empowering users to seize opportunities and stay ahead in the fast-paced crypto market.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Bitget is now one of the top 10 crypto spot trading platforms with over 700 coins and 800 pairs. With the introduction of Pre-market, Bitget continues to innovate and provide solutions to meet the evolving needs of cryptocurrency traders and investors.</p>
<p>For more information about Bitget Pre-market, please visit: https://www.bitget.com/support/articles/12560603808074</p>
<h3>About Bitget</h3>
<p>Established in 2018, <a href="https://www.bitget.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><u>Bitget</u></a> is the world&rsquo;s leading <a href="https://www.bitget.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><u>cryptocurrency exchange</u></a> and Web3 company. Serving over 25 million users in 100+ countries and regions, the Bitget exchange is committed to helping users trade smarter with its pioneering copy trading feature and other trading solutions. Formerly known as BitKeep, <a href="https://web3.bitget.com/en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Bitget Wallet</a> is a world-class multi-chain crypto wallet that offers an array of comprehensive Web3 solutions and features including wallet functionality, swap, NFT Marketplace, DApp browser, and more. Bitget inspires individuals to embrace crypto through collaborations with credible partners, including legendary Argentinian footballer Lionel Messi and official eSports events organizer PGL.</p>
<p>For more information, visit:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.bitget.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/bitgetglobal" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://t.me/BitgetENOfficial" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Telegram</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/bitget-global/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">LinkedIn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://discord.com/invite/bitget" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Discord</a></li>
<li><a href="https://web3.bitget.com/en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Bitget Wallet</a></li>
</ul>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact: <a href="mailto:media@bitget.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">media@bitget.com</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>PR TEAM<br>
Bitget<br>
media@bitget.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/bitget-launches-pre-market-with-merlin-chain-merl-as-the-first-supported-asset/">Bitget Launches Pre-market with Merlin Chain (MERL) as the First Supported Asset</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitget-launches-pre-market-with-merlin-chain-merl-as-the-first-supported-asset/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Metacade Unchains Web3 Gaming: Multi-Chain Integration Unites the Industry</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/metacade-unchains-web3-gaming-multi-chain-integration-unites-the-industry/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/metacade-unchains-web3-gaming-multi-chain-integration-unites-the-industry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 21:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Metacade_-_Multi-Chain_Gaming_v2_17127631137TQq68teik.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>London, United Kingdom, April 11th, 2024, Chainwire Metacade, the leading blockchain gaming platform, takes a monumental leap forward with the integration of multi-chains into its ecosystem. This Omni-layer development provides universal application reach, resolving blockchain fragmentation and empowering builders across diverse chains. The rapid integration of the Metacade Tournament Platform with the Base Layer 2 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/metacade-unchains-web3-gaming-multi-chain-integration-unites-the-industry/">Metacade Unchains Web3 Gaming: Multi-Chain Integration Unites the Industry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Metacade_-_Multi-Chain_Gaming_v2_17127631137TQq68teik.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p><strong>London, United Kingdom, April 11th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://metacade.co" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><strong>Metacade</strong></a>, the leading blockchain gaming platform, takes a monumental leap forward with the integration of multi-chains into its ecosystem.</p>
<p>This Omni-layer development provides universal application reach, resolving blockchain fragmentation and empowering builders across diverse chains.</p>
<p>The rapid integration of the Metacade Tournament Platform with the <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/blog/introducing-base" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><strong>Base</strong></a> Layer 2 Rollup within 12 hours showcases Metacade&rsquo;s technical prowess and underscores a commitment to delivering best-in-class solutions for partners and players.</p>
<p>The decision to introduce multi-chain functionality highlights Metacade&rsquo;s vision to create the largest Web3 gaming platform, grounded in open market principles.</p>
<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We recognize that speed and low transaction costs are crucial for builders. However, game development hinges on intricate blockchain solutions,&rdquo; states CEO Russell Bennett. &ldquo;For Metacade to achieve genuine inclusivity, our success depends on an adaptable infrastructure, regardless of the blockchain utilized.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>The multi-chain approach considers scalability for partner road maps, allowing existing projects to remain on their native chain while maintaining platform security through an optimistic-based rollup.</p>
<p>What began as a vision to connect Web3 game developers with seasoned players has become an omni-layer movement to unify games across chains and provide fluid liquidity, expanding economic opportunities for builders and players alike.</p>
<p>A multi-chain infrastructure will optimize liquidity access, mitigate inefficiencies, and simplify asset trading processes. It offers an efficient on-ramp for gaming partners to facilitate the use of their tokens regardless of where the core of their liquidity is situated.</p>
<p>This pivotal development future proofs Metacade&rsquo;s robust, diverse, and accessible ecosystem. For more information on Metacade and its multi-chain expansion, users can visit the new website: <a href="https://metacade.co" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">metacade.co</a>.</p>
<h3>About METACADE</h3>
<p><a href="https://metacade.co" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Metacade</a>&nbsp;is a seamless Web3 Gaming platform connecting developers and players through plug-and-play community initiatives. Providing an unfair advantage through early access, dev-player collaborations, and financial rewards.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Elly Bradbury<br>
Metacade<br>
marketing@metacade.co</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/metacade-unchains-web3-gaming-multi-chain-integration-unites-the-industry/">Metacade Unchains Web3 Gaming: Multi-Chain Integration Unites the Industry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/metacade-unchains-web3-gaming-multi-chain-integration-unites-the-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlackRock&#8217;s BUIDL fund now convertible to USD Coin (USDC) after Circle integration</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/blackrocks-buidl-fund-now-convertible-to-usd-coin-usdc-after-circle-integration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Thuo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 18:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="946" height="538" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/1644463622883-8854b2dd-6bdf-4e8e-ac9e-8ce963b4c3a4.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="BlackRock&#039;s BUIDL fund now convertible to USD Coin (USDC) after Circle integration" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Circle enables BUIDL share conversion to USDC with new smart contract functionality. BlackRock&#8217;s BUIDL investors can convert their shares to USDC 24/7. BlackRock&#8217;s BUIDL fund saw $240 million in first-week investments. Circle, the issuer of USD Coin (USDC) stablecoin, has unveiled a new smart contract functionality, enabling BlackRock&#8217;s USD Institutional Digital Liquidity Fund (BUIDL) investors [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/blackrocks-buidl-fund-now-convertible-to-usd-coin-usdc-after-circle-integration/">BlackRock&#8217;s BUIDL fund now convertible to USD Coin (USDC) after Circle integration</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="946" height="538" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/1644463622883-8854b2dd-6bdf-4e8e-ac9e-8ce963b4c3a4.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="BlackRock&#039;s BUIDL fund now convertible to USD Coin (USDC) after Circle integration" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li>Circle enables BUIDL share conversion to USDC with new smart contract functionality.</li>
<li>BlackRock&rsquo;s BUIDL investors can convert their shares to USDC 24/7.</li>
<li>BlackRock&rsquo;s BUIDL fund saw $240 million in first-week investments.</li>
</ul>
<p>Circle, the issuer of USD Coin (USDC) stablecoin, has unveiled a new smart contract functionality, enabling BlackRock&rsquo;s USD Institutional Digital Liquidity Fund (BUIDL) investors to convert their shares into USDC.</p>
<p>The groundbreaking smart contract functionality enables BUIDL investors to convert their shares into USDC at any time, 24/7.</p>
<h2>BlackRock&rsquo;s foray into tokenized funds</h2>
<p>BlackRock&rsquo;s foray into the world of blockchain and digital assets took a significant leap with the launch of its BlackRock USD Institutional Digital Liquidity Fund (BUIDL). In collaboration with <a href="https://coinjournal.net/exchanges/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>, the fund operates on the Ethereum blockchain, aiming to provide US dollar yields through tokenization.</p>
<p>Launched on March 19, BUIDL represents a pivotal step in integrating traditional finance with blockchain technology, backed by a consortium of industry-leading firms including Anchorage Digital Bank NA, BitGo, Fireblocks, and Coinbase.</p>
<p>The fund attracted a staggering $240 million in its inaugural week, signalling strong market interest in tokenized assets.</p>
<h2>BlackRock&rsquo;s BUIDL and Circle&rsquo;s USD Coin (USDC) integration</h2>
<p>With the integration of BlackRock&rsquo;s BUIDL with Circle, BlackRock BUIDL investors&rsquo; pain points have been addressed by offering a near-instant off-ramp, leveraging Circle&rsquo;s speed, transparency, and efficiency inherent in tokenized assets. The integration marks a significant milestone in the tokenization of financial markets, providing investors with a secure and compliant means to engage with digital assets.</p>
<p>Jeremy Allaire, the Co-founder and CEO of Circle, in a <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20240411966052/en/Circle-Announces-USDC-Smart-Contract-for-Transfers-by-BlackRock%E2%80%99s-BUIDL-Fund-Investors">press release</a> underscored the importance of tokenizing real-world assets and the role of USDC in facilitating seamless transactions. He emphasized that USDC enables investors to exit tokenized assets swiftly, thereby reducing costs and friction from the process.</p>
<p>Allaire expressed enthusiasm about delivering the core benefits of blockchain transactions to BUIDL investors through USDC availability, highlighting the growing significance of tokenized assets in the evolving financial landscape.</p>
<h2>Future implications on financial markets</h2>
<p>The integration between BlackRock&rsquo;s BUIDL fund and Circle&rsquo;s USD Coin (USDC) not only enhances liquidity and efficiency but also sets a precedent for the tokenization of financial markets.</p>
<p>As institutional investors increasingly embrace digital assets, innovations like these are poised to reshape the future of global finance.</p>
<p>With regulatory clarity and technological advancements driving the adoption of tokenized assets, the collaboration between BlackRock and Circle signifies a step towards democratizing access to digital financial products.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/blackrocks-buidl-fund-now-convertible-to-usd-coin-usdc-after-circle-integration/">BlackRock&#8217;s BUIDL fund now convertible to USD Coin (USDC) after Circle integration</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favourite altcoins in Q2 2024: FLOKI (FLOKI), Cardano (ADA) and Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ)</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/favourite-altcoins-in-q2-2024-floki-floki-cardano-ada-and-rebel-satoshi-arcade-recq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="375" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Favourite-altcoins-among-savvy-investors-in-Q2-2024.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Favourite altcoins in Q2 2024: FLOKI (FLOKI), Cardano (ADA) and Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ)" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>FLOKI, Cardano and Rebel Satoshi Arcade are altcoins that investors have been massively accumulating this quarter. Their bullish outlooks and unique concepts make them promising altcoins to hold. As a new token, Rebel Satoshi Arcade has significant upside potential, fueling investor interest. Investors have waited years for this moment &#8212; a new bull market. The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/favourite-altcoins-in-q2-2024-floki-floki-cardano-ada-and-rebel-satoshi-arcade-recq/">Favourite altcoins in Q2 2024: FLOKI (FLOKI), Cardano (ADA) and Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="375" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Favourite-altcoins-among-savvy-investors-in-Q2-2024.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Favourite altcoins in Q2 2024: FLOKI (FLOKI), Cardano (ADA) and Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ)" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li>FLOKI, Cardano and Rebel Satoshi Arcade are altcoins that investors have been massively accumulating this quarter.</li>
<li>Their bullish outlooks and unique concepts make them promising altcoins to hold.</li>
<li>As a new token, Rebel Satoshi Arcade has significant upside potential, fueling investor interest.</li>
</ul>
<p>Investors have waited years for this moment &mdash; a new bull market. The market has been retesting levels last seen during the 2021 bull market, signalling the start of a new cycle. To determine the most compelling investments, we have been following what savvy investors are buying&mdash; following the money trail.</p>
<p>Some of the altcoins favoured by savvy investors this quarter include FLOKI (FLOKI), Cardano (ADA) and Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ). These altcoins could have significant upside potential and all three have unique concepts. If bullish forecasts are right, these could be some of the best cryptos to buy now.</p>
<h2>Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ): the rave of the moment</h2>
<p>Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ) is a new and emerging crypto, stirring up quite a buzz. Its presale was met with huge excitement in light of the explosive success of <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4612&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel Satoshi</a> (RBLZ), the governance token within its dual-token ecosystem. For those who missed out on RBLZ, it represents a second chance at significant gains.</p>
<p>It is more than just a meme; it is on a mission to reshape the crypto landscape, particularly the meme and GameFi sectors. In the spirit of unity and defiance, it aims to tilt the balance towards decentralization and individual empowerment, evident in its community-driven approach.</p>
<p>Representing the best of the gaming and meme worlds, investors have been showing quite a keen interest. Within its gaming ecosystem will be a selection of free-to-play (F2P), pay-to-play (P2P) and play-to-earn (P2E) arcade games &mdash; all gaming needs will be catered for. The game will be as much fun as it is rewarding, making the ecosystem a place to be, with participation rewards being the icing on the cake.</p>
<p>The presale recently kicked off but has been selling out fast. In the first stage of the ICO, a token is priced at just $0.0037. Its significant upside potential &mdash; one of its biggest appeals &mdash; contributes to the massive presale turnout, tipped for a 70x surge post-launch.</p>
<h2>FLOKI (FLOKI): a promising memecoin</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/floki/">FLOKI (FLOKI)</a> is among the best meme coins on the market. However, it is more than just a meme; it is evolving to be more than just fun. The ecosystem offers DeFi utilities, an NFT metaverse and NFTs, among others. Hence, it is positioned as one of the best coins to invest in &mdash; a blend of memes and utility.</p>
<p>It had an impressive first quarter and with further upsides anticipated, savvy investors have been doubling down on it this quarter. It was at the forefront of the latest meme crazy, hot on the heels of the trending Solana memecoins like dogwifhat (WIF) and Bonk (BONK).</p>
<p>Analysts are confident in its surge past the current all-time high (ATH) in the coming months. To make the most of this bull market, FLOKI is among the best cryptos to invest in &mdash; don&rsquo;t miss out.</p>
<h2>Cardano (ADA): an investor favorite</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/cardano/what-is-cardano/">Cardano (ADA)</a> is a utility-backed cryptocurrency that plays a vital role in the crypto landscape. Its value is primarily driven by its real-world applications as a smart contract and blockchain platform. Its rise to the status of one of the top altcoins is thanks to its growing adoption and institutional interest.</p>
<p>While it had a sub-par performance in the year&rsquo;s first quarter, Cardano has been showing remarkable potential, capturing investors&rsquo; attention. Its solid fundamentals, coupled with its significant upside potential, considering it is ridiculously undervalued, have been fueling investor interest.</p>
<p>As it races towards $1 and hopes to flip its all-time high (ATH), Cardano is a top crypto to invest in. You can ride this promising wave by adding ADA to your crypto portfolio &mdash; WAGMI.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The altcoins that investors have been showing a keen interest in this quarter are FLOKI, Cardano and <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4612&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel Satoshi</a> Arcade, which some analysts are pointing to as a top ICO.</p>
<p>Their promising outlooks this year make them compelling investments, especially RECQ. You can become an early adopter of this promising altcoin by participating in the presale now.</p>
<p>For the latest updates and more information on $RECQ, visit the official <a href="http://www.rebelsatoshi.com">Rebel Satoshi Website</a> or contact Rebel Red via <a href="https://t.me/rebelsatoshi_news">Telegram</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/favourite-altcoins-in-q2-2024-floki-floki-cardano-ada-and-rebel-satoshi-arcade-recq/">Favourite altcoins in Q2 2024: FLOKI (FLOKI), Cardano (ADA) and Rebel Satoshi Arcade (RECQ)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
