<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<atom:link href="https://coinjournal.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<description><![CDATA[Keep your finger on the pulse of the fast-moving cryptocurrency sector with all the latest crypto news, analysis and reviews from CoinJournal]]></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 19:17:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/apple-touch-icon.png</url>
	<title><![CDATA[CoinJournal: Latest Crypto News, Alt Coin News and Cryptocurrency Comparison]]></title>
	<link>https://coinjournal.net/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>ORDI, Fantom, Aave prices lead losses as BitBot defies gravity</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/ordi-fantom-aave-prices-lead-losses-as-bitbot-defies-gravity/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/ordi-fantom-aave-prices-lead-losses-as-bitbot-defies-gravity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Crispus Nyaga]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 19:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/news/ordi-fantom-aave-prices-lead-losses-as-bitbot-defies-gravity/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="500" height="281" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/1970/01/1675102415183-91b252f2-201e-42e7-aecd-b49f6886206f.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>ORDI,&#160;Fantom (FTM), and&#160;Aave were among the worst performers in the crypto industry during the weekend as the crypto sell-off intensified. The ORDI token crashed by over 15% in the past 24 hours and has retreated by over 50% from its highest point this year. Fantom, on the other hand, crashed by over 8% in the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ordi-fantom-aave-prices-lead-losses-as-bitbot-defies-gravity/">ORDI, Fantom, Aave prices lead losses as BitBot defies gravity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="500" height="281" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/1970/01/1675102415183-91b252f2-201e-42e7-aecd-b49f6886206f.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p dir="ltr">ORDI,&nbsp;<a href="https://coinjournal.net/fantom/"><u>Fantom</u></a> (FTM), and&nbsp;<a href="https://coinjournal.net/aave/"><u>Aave</u></a> were among the worst performers in the crypto industry during the weekend as the crypto sell-off intensified. The ORDI token crashed by over 15% in the past 24 hours and has retreated by over 50% from its highest point this year.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Fantom, on the other hand, crashed by over 8% in the past 24 hours and has retreated by more than 45% from the year-to-date high. Similarly, the AAVE token plunged to a low of $72.76, which is much lower than the year-to-date high of $153.90. The other most popular laggards were coins like KuCoin Token (KCS), XRP, and Ethereum Classic.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Not all cryptocurrencies were in the red. Bittensor (TAO) token rose by over 20% in the past 24 hours while Celestia (TIA), Dogwifhat (WIF), and Wormhole (W) soared by more than 10%.&nbsp;<a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=current_news"><u>BitBot</u></a><strong>&nbsp;</strong>too continued its token sale, raising over $2 million.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Why cryptocurrencies plunged</h2>
<p dir="ltr">There are three main reasons why cryptocurrencies crashed during the weekend. First, crypto investors are likely selling the news as the Bitcoin halving event is set to happen in less than two weeks.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">This situation is known as&nbsp;<em>buying the rumour and selling the news.&nbsp;</em>They have already bought the rumour as the coin has surged from below $20,000 to a high of over $73,000.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Second, they crashed because of the geopolitical risks that accelerated during the weekend. Iran retaliated against Israel by firing over 300 drones and rockets. Most of these strikes were unsuccessful, helped by the country&rsquo;s iron dome.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">These tensions mean that the price of crude oil could continue rising in the coming weeks. Brent, the global benchmark, has already jumped to a multi-month high of $92.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Third, there are signs that the Federal Reserve will not cut interest rates in the coming months as was widely expected. That explains why the US dollar index has jumped while US equities and bonds have retreated.&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Still, in the long term, analysts believe that cryptocurrencies will continue doing well because of Bitcoin. Besides, the coin is still getting rare because of halving while institutional investors are moving to the coin.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">BitBot token sale intensifies</h2>
<p dir="ltr">BitBot is thriving even as the crypto sell-off continues. The developers have already raised over $2.3 million from investors and are slowly nearing stage ten&rsquo;s target of $2.5 million.</p>
<p dir="ltr">For starters, BitBot is one of the most ambitious companies in the blockchain industry. The developers are aiming to disrupt the fast-growing Telegram bot market that has been rife with fraud for years.</p>
<p dir="ltr">BitBot will be a Telegram bot with some of the most advanced features in the industry. In addition to technical indicators, the platform will have advanced artificial intelligence (AI) features that will help give near-accurate signals.</p>
<p>Further, BitBot will be powered by blockchain technology, which will help to reduce or prevent fraud. This technology will also help to decentralize the network, making it possible for all token holders to take advantage of its governance. You can buy the BitBot token&nbsp;<a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=current_news"><u>here</u></a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ordi-fantom-aave-prices-lead-losses-as-bitbot-defies-gravity/">ORDI, Fantom, Aave prices lead losses as BitBot defies gravity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/ordi-fantom-aave-prices-lead-losses-as-bitbot-defies-gravity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple CEO sees crypto market hitting $5T by year-end: here are the top 3 picks</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/ripple-ceo-sees-crypto-market-hitting-5t-by-year-end-here-are-the-top-3-picks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="309" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ripple-CEO-sees-crypto-market-hitting-5T-by-year-end.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Ripple CEO sees crypto market hitting $5T by year-end: here are the top 3 picks" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Ripple CEO is claiming the crypto market could reach $5 trillion by the end of 2024. Investors are looking for better opportunities to invest and gain lucrative profits if that happens. According to some analysts, Solana (SOL), Sui (SUI), and Borroe Finance ($ROE) could be some of the best altcoins to include in investment portfolios. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ripple-ceo-sees-crypto-market-hitting-5t-by-year-end-here-are-the-top-3-picks/">Ripple CEO sees crypto market hitting $5T by year-end: here are the top 3 picks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="309" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ripple-CEO-sees-crypto-market-hitting-5T-by-year-end.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Ripple CEO sees crypto market hitting $5T by year-end: here are the top 3 picks" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li>Ripple CEO is claiming the crypto market could reach $5 trillion by the end of 2024.</li>
<li>Investors are looking for better opportunities to invest and gain lucrative profits if that happens.</li>
<li>According to some analysts, Solana (SOL), Sui (SUI), and <a href="https://borroe.co/cjl26">Borroe Finance ($ROE)</a> could be some of the best altcoins to include in investment portfolios.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/ripple/what-is-ripple/">Ripple</a> CEO, Brad Garlinghouse, is bullish on the crypto market, predicting that the crypto market cap could double and reach around $5 trillion by the end of 2024.</p>
<p>Garlinghouse believes spot ETF approval and the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/halvening-explained-infographic/">Bitcoin halving</a> event will fuel this prediction. But he also emphasized the crucial impact of favourable U.S. regulatory changes on the crypto market&rsquo;s growth.</p>
<p>The crypto community is understandably excited about this market prediction, with investors and analysts digging into the numbers to determine which tokens could be the best bets to capitalize on this growth.</p>
<p>Many experts believe SOL, SUI and <a href="https://borroe.co/cjl26">Borroe Finance ($ROE)</a> could be some of the top crypto coins to consider adding to your portfolio ahead of this market expansion. Let&rsquo;s take a look at their reasoning.</p>
<h2>Solana validators approve &lsquo;Timely Vote Credits&rsquo;</h2>
<p>Solana validators have agreed on a &ldquo;Timely Vote Credits&rdquo; plan, which speeds up transactions. It does so by modifying the consensus vote latency. The proposal was passed on April 8 with 98% votes.</p>
<p>Besides, SOL was trading around $172 in the second week of April with minor fluctuations. Experts say it is near the crucial support level of $170. If it breaks down from here then, SOL might trade around $160 by mid-2024.</p>
<p>However, if <a href="https://coinjournal.net/solana/">Solana (SOL) price</a> manages to stay above $172, then it could head towards $190 and eventually to $200. If the bullish momentum persists then SOL could trade around $250 by the end of 2024.</p>
<h2>Is SUI ready to take off?</h2>
<p>SUI has risen by 290% in the past year, from a low of $0.37 in October to its current price of $1.46. In mid-April, Sui was trading around $1.57 with the crypto market cap of $2 billion. SUI has been fluctuating between $1.35 and $2.15 in the past month.</p>
<p>Experts say SUI is in a downtrend now, with the support at $1.55. If it breaks below this support zone, then SUI could trade around $1.30 by mid-2024.</p>
<p>Still, many analysts are optimistic about SUI&rsquo;s growth potential, with some indicating that if it breaks above the resistance level of $1.70, then it will move towards $1.80. By the end of 2024, SUI has the potential to trade around $2.50, according to a number of forecasts.</p>
<h2>Borroe Finance presale on fire</h2>
<p><a href="https://borroe.co/cjl26">Borroe Finance</a> is attracting investors in its final stage of the presale. They raised over $3.66 million by selling over 282 million $ROE tokens. In Stage 5, $ROE is priced at $0.02 per token, and it will be listed at a price of $0.025 across several exchanges.</p>
<p>This will generate 25% profit for new investors. In addition, current investors are also enjoying a 15% bonus when they use a promo code (&ldquo;WELCOME&rdquo;), but data suggests there are now only 153 million $ROE tokens left to be sold.</p>
<p>Borroe Finance aims to revolutionize Web3 business funding through blockchain, AI-powered risk assessments, and smart contracts. It offers quicker access to capital by allowing businesses to mint and sell NFTs. These NFTs represent their future revenue.</p>
<p>ROE utilizes the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/polygon/what-is-polygon/">Polygon blockchain</a> for its efficiency and low fees. The team is experienced and always brings their best to the table. Some crypto analysts are predicting that Borroe Finance could be one of the best blockchain ICOs in the market today, which is why many investors are to HODLing $ROE tokens.</p>
<p>To learn more about Borroe Finance ($ROE), <a href="https://borroe.co/cjl26">visit Borroe Finance presale</a> or <a href="https://t.me/Borroe">join their Telegram Group</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/Borroe_Finance">follow Borroe Finance on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ripple-ceo-sees-crypto-market-hitting-5t-by-year-end-here-are-the-top-3-picks/">Ripple CEO sees crypto market hitting $5T by year-end: here are the top 3 picks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New MEDA investors spot strong potential while AVAX and FIL look to stabilize</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/new-meda-investors-spot-strong-potential-while-avax-and-fil-look-to-stabilize/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 18:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avalanche News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Filecoin News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="452" height="253" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/New-MEDA-investors-spot-strong-potential.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="New MEDA investors spot strong potential while AVAX and FIL look to stabilize" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Milei Moneda ($MEDA) targets 60% ROI for early investors. Avalanche (AVAX) forms cross-chain asset settlements with ANZ and Chainlink, sparking bullish predictions after its recent price decline. Filecoin (FIL) sees a 12% surge with its Swan Chain integration. In recent weeks, Milei Moneda ($MEDA) has emerged among top contenders in crypto presales, capturing the attention [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/new-meda-investors-spot-strong-potential-while-avax-and-fil-look-to-stabilize/">New MEDA investors spot strong potential while AVAX and FIL look to stabilize</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="452" height="253" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/New-MEDA-investors-spot-strong-potential.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="New MEDA investors spot strong potential while AVAX and FIL look to stabilize" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li>Milei Moneda ($MEDA) targets 60% ROI for early investors.</li>
<li>Avalanche (AVAX) forms cross-chain asset settlements with ANZ and Chainlink, sparking bullish predictions after its recent price decline.</li>
<li>Filecoin (FIL) sees a 12% surge with its Swan Chain integration.</li>
</ul>
<p>In recent weeks, Milei Moneda ($MEDA) has emerged among top contenders in crypto presales, capturing the attention of new investors eager to capitalize on its strong presale potential.</p>
<p>Alongside the bullish potential of $MEDA, the crypto market is witnessing notable developments with Avalanche (AVAX) and Filecoin (FIL).</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s explore these bullish crypto stories.</p>
<h2>Milei Moneda eyes 60% ROI for early investors</h2>
<p>As digital investors seek the best coins to invest in for substantial returns, one name that keeps popping up is <a href="https://mileimoneda.io/?utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_id=657">Milei Moneda ($MEDA)</a>. The DeFi meme coin has been making waves with its unique blend of humor, politics, and blockchain technology infused with Anarcho-capitalism.</p>
<p>Milei Moneda ($MEDA) is an Ethereum Network-based deflationary token boasting locked liquidity and a total supply of 500,000,000 tokens. Its deflationary feature and strategic distribution system have made Milei Moneda ($MEDA) one of the top sorted altcoins, with the meme coin recording a sale of over 56 million tokens in just weeks since its presale debut.</p>
<p>Currently selling at $0.0125 in Stage 2 of its <a href="https://mileimoneda.io/?utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_id=657">presale</a>, $MEDA is getting close to its highly anticipated launch on Uniswap. Scheduled for May 21, Milei Moneda&rsquo;s DeFi coin price is set to launch at $0.020, translating to a 60% ROI for Stage 2 investors. This promising outlook has added to the excitement surrounding the price recovery of top altcoins Avalanche (AVAX) and Filecoin (FIL).</p>
<h2>Avalanche teams up with ANZ for cross-chain asset settlements</h2>
<p>Avalanche (AVAX) recently <a href="https://www.avax.network/blog/anz-leverages-avalanche-and-chainlink-in-tokenized-asset-settlement-project">announced</a> a partnership with Australia and New Zealand Banking Group (ANZ) and <a href="https://coinjournal.net/chainlink/what-is-chainlink/">Chainlink (LINK)</a> Labs. This collaboration aims to leverage Chainlink&rsquo;s Cross-Chain Interoperability Protocol (CCIP) to connect Avalanche and <a href="https://coinjournal.net/ethereum/what-is-ethereum/">Ethereum (ETH)</a> blockchains, enabling seamless delivery versus payment (DvP) settlement of tokenized assets across networks in multiple currencies.</p>
<p>News of the collaboration ignited significant interest in Avalanche, boosting bullish price predictions for AVAX&rsquo;s price. Since the beginning of April, Avalanche (AVAX) has seen its bears in control, recording a 5% decline in its altcoin price. However, with this recent collaboration, market analysts anticipate a price recovery in the coming weeks.</p>
<h2>Filecoin rebounds after ATH dip: Swan Chain integration fuels price surge</h2>
<p>Like Avalanche (AVAX), Filecoin (FIL) has been quite volatile for the past few weeks. In March, Filecoin dropped for the year&rsquo;s ATH, plummeting by over 20%. However, the altcoin made a 12% price recovery recently, fueled by the network&rsquo;s integration with Swan Chain, a Layer 2 network compatible with the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM).</p>
<p>Filecoin&rsquo;s integration with Swan Chain not only enhances storage capabilities but also offers users the ability to seamlessly integrate decentralized computing, bandwidth, and payments within a single suite.</p>
<p>The integration has generated enthusiasm within the crypto community, reflecting positively on FIL&rsquo;s price. As Filecoin&rsquo;s utility expands through innovative integrations like Swan Chain, analysts predict continued growth and price appreciation for FIL in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/new-meda-investors-spot-strong-potential-while-avax-and-fil-look-to-stabilize/">New MEDA investors spot strong potential while AVAX and FIL look to stabilize</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple CEO believes crypto market could reach $5 trillion by year end &#8211; Here are top 3 picks that might help position you for gains</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/ripple-ceo-believes-crypto-market-could-reach-5-trillion-by-year-end-here-are-top-3-picks-that-might-help-position-you-for-gains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1600" height="826" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ripple-cryptocurrency-symbol.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Ripple CEO is claiming the crypto market could reach $5 trillion by the end of 2024. Investors are looking for better opportunities to invest and gain lucrative profits if that happens. According to some analysts, Solana (SOL), Sui (SUI), and Borroe Finance ($ROE) could be some of the best altcoins to include in investment portfolios. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ripple-ceo-believes-crypto-market-could-reach-5-trillion-by-year-end-here-are-top-3-picks-that-might-help-position-you-for-gains/">Ripple CEO believes crypto market could reach $5 trillion by year end &#8211; Here are top 3 picks that might help position you for gains</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1600" height="826" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ripple-cryptocurrency-symbol.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400">Ripple CEO is claiming the crypto market could reach $5 trillion by the end of 2024.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400">Investors are looking for better opportunities to invest and gain lucrative profits if that happens.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400">According to some analysts, Solana (SOL), Sui (SUI), and <a href="https://borroe.co/cjl26" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Borroe Finance ($ROE)</a> could be some of the best altcoins to include in investment portfolios.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/ripple/">Ripple</a> CEO, Brad Garlinghouse, is bullish on the crypto market, predicting that the crypto market cap could double and reach around $5 trillion by the end of 2024.</p>
<p>Garlinghouse believes spot ETF approval and the Bitcoin halving event will fuel this prediction. But he also emphasized the crucial impact of favorable U.S. regulatory changes on the crypto market&rsquo;s growth.</p>
<p>The crypto community is understandably excited about this market prediction, with investors and analysts digging into the numbers to determine which tokens could be the best bets to capitalize on this growth. A growing number of experts believe SOL, SUI and $ROE could be some of the top crypto coins to consider adding to your portfolio ahead of this market expansion. Let&rsquo;s take a look at their reasoning.</p>
<h2>Solana validators approve &lsquo;Timely Vote Credits&rsquo;</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/solana/" rel="">Solana</a> validators have agreed on a &ldquo;Timely Vote Credits&rdquo; plan, which speeds up transactions. It does so by modifying the consensus vote latency. The proposal was passed on April 8 with 98% votes.</p>
<p>Besides, SOL was trading around $172 in the second week of April with minor fluctuations. Experts say it is near the crucial support level of $170. If it breaks down from here then, SOL might trade around $160 by mid-2024.</p>
<p>However, if SOL manages to stay above $172, then it could head towards $190 and eventually to $200. If the bullish momentum persists then SOL could trade around $250 by the end of 2024.</p>
<h2>Is SUI ready to take off?</h2>
<p>SUI has risen by 290% in the past year, from a low of $0.37 in October to its current price of $1.46. In mid-April, Sui was trading around $1.57 with the crypto market cap of $2 billion. SUI has been fluctuating between $1.35 and $2.15 in the past month.</p>
<p>Experts say SUI is in a downtrend now, with the support at $1.55. If it breaks below this support zone, then SUI could trade around $1.30 by mid-2024.</p>
<p>Still, many analysts are optimistic about SUI&rsquo;s growth potential, with some indicating that if it breaks above the resistance level of $1.70, then it will move towards $1.80. By the end of 2024, SUI has the potential to trade around $2.50, according to a number of forecasts.</p>
<h2>Borroe Finance presale is on fire</h2>
<p><a href="https://borroe.co/cjl26" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Borroe Finance</a> is attracting investors in its final stage of the presale. They raised over $3.66 million by selling over 282 million $ROE tokens. In Stage 5, $ROE is priced at $0.02 per token, and it will be listed at a price of $0.025 across several exchanges.</p>
<p>This will generate 25% profit for new investors. In addition, current investors are also enjoying a 15% bonus when they use a promo code (&ldquo;WELCOME&rdquo;), but data suggests there are now only 153 million $ROE tokens left to be sold.</p>
<p>Borroe Finance aims to revolutionize Web3 business funding through blockchain, AI-powered risk assessments, and smart contracts. It offers quicker access to capital by allowing businesses to mint and sell <a href="https://coinjournal.net/nfts/">NFTs</a>. These NFTs represent their future revenue.</p>
<p>$ROE utilizes the Polygon blockchain for its efficiency and low fees. The team is experienced and always brings their best to the table. Some crypto analysts are predicting that Borroe Finance could be the best blockchain ICO in the market right now, which is why many investors are deciding to HODL $ROE tokens.</p>
<p>Learn more about Borroe Finance ($ROE) here:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://borroe.co/cjl26" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Visit Borroe Finance Presale</a></li>
<li><a href="https://t.me/Borroe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Join The Telegram Group</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/Borroe_Finance" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Follow Borroe Finance on Twitter</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ripple-ceo-believes-crypto-market-could-reach-5-trillion-by-year-end-here-are-top-3-picks-that-might-help-position-you-for-gains/">Ripple CEO believes crypto market could reach $5 trillion by year end &#8211; Here are top 3 picks that might help position you for gains</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogecoin eyes $1 mark, Monero and Chainlink&#8217;s competitor attracts top-tier investors</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/dogecoin-eyes-1-mark-monero-and-chainlinks-competitor-attracts-top-tier-investors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1024" height="1024" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dogecoin-doge.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" srcset="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dogecoin-doge.jpg 1024w, https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dogecoin-doge-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p>We have seen all sorts of events happening in the crypto world, where some of the best meme coins can capture a huge chunk of the market while fundamentally strong projects remain in the shadows.&#160; DOGE, with massive community backing, is an example of how hype can impact the price of a token. Some traders [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/dogecoin-eyes-1-mark-monero-and-chainlinks-competitor-attracts-top-tier-investors/">Dogecoin eyes $1 mark, Monero and Chainlink&#8217;s competitor attracts top-tier investors</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1024" height="1024" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dogecoin-doge.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" srcset="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dogecoin-doge.jpg 1024w, https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dogecoin-doge-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p><span style="font-weight: 400">We have seen all sorts of events happening in the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/">crypto world</a>, where some of the best meme coins can capture a huge chunk of the market while fundamentally strong projects remain in the shadows.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">DOGE, with massive community backing, is an example of how hype can impact the price of a token. Some traders are already seeing it touch the $1 mark sooner than later, but that will depend on multiple factors. While we see how it goes, a new ICO, </span><a href="https://inqubeta.ai/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=57" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">InQubeta,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> is competing with the likes of Chainlink and Monero.</span></p>
<h2>Will Dogecoin touch the $1 mark?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/dogecoin/">Dogecoin</a> has made quite the splash recently, riding the wave of meme culture straight into the hearts of a diverse crowd. It&rsquo;s not just the seasoned crypto heads getting in on the action but also those looking for a fun entry point into the world of digital money. Dogecoin stands out, not so much for its tech or financial chops, but for its vibe: it&rsquo;s all about community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Yet, hitting that $1 dream is tricky. Detractors often say Dogecoin&rsquo;s more about hype than substance, lacking the solid foundation other top crypto coins have. But DOGE believers see a different picture: its acceptance by more and more merchants and its die-hard community could mean Dogecoin&rsquo;s joke could have the last laugh, making it a serious player in the crypto game.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As Dogecoin starts popping up more in everyday transactions and online shops start accepting it, it&rsquo;s beginning to shake off its meme coin image, hinting that its cultural clout could indeed cement its place in the crypto world with real, lasting value.</span></p>
<h2>InQubeta: A new vanguard in AI crypto investment</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While Dogecoin captures headlines with its rollercoaster market antics, a new name, </span><a href="https://inqubeta.ai/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=57" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">InQubeta</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">, is quietly turning heads among savvy investors. Positioned as a serious rival to crypto veterans like Monero and Chainlink, InQubeta stands out by weaving the untapped potential of AI into the fabric of crypto investments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">InQubeta is on a mission to simplify access to the once-gated world of AI startups, offering a golden ticket to the average investor through its innovative QUBE tokens. This platform is changing the game by allowing anyone to grab a piece of the AI pie, previously a feast for the Silicon Valley bigwigs only. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">By making fractional investment a thing of reality, InQubeta is breaking open the door that has always kept retail on the sidelines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The real kicker? InQubeta utilizes <a href="https://coinjournal.net/nfts/">NFTs</a> to offer shares in these AI companies, making investment outcomes transparent and directly related to their success. This not only enriches the investment landscape but also weaves a closer bond between investors and the tech pioneers driving these projects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">InQubeta&rsquo;s vision doesn&rsquo;t stop there. With a roadmap that dreams big &ndash; launching an NFT marketplace, rolling out the InQubeta swap, and firing up a decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) &ndash; it&rsquo;s clear they&rsquo;re leading the march towards a future where AI and blockchain not just meet but meld in exciting ways.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Backed by a thorough audit and a presale buzz that&rsquo;s already drawing in the millions, InQubeta&rsquo;s journey towards cross-chain expansion in 2024 is not just promising; it&rsquo;s practically in motion.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://inqubeta.ai/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=57" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-194243 aligncenter" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/inqubeta-qube-buy.png" alt="" width="400" height="156"></a></p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As Dogecoin dances its way towards the coveted $1 mark, fueled by a lively community and its irresistible meme magic, InQubeta is carving out its own place in the crypto world with something totally different. Very few initiatives are targeted towards making the investment game easy for average investors with small capital. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">However, with InQubeta, one can expect to be a part of a circle where the big investors take a chance. But as always, doing your homework is essential before deciding on the best crypto investments.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="https://inqubeta.ai/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=57" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Visit InQubeta Presale&nbsp;</span></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><span style="font-weight: 400">&nbsp;</span><a href="https://linktr.ee/inqubeta" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400">Join The InQubeta Communities</span></a></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/dogecoin-eyes-1-mark-monero-and-chainlinks-competitor-attracts-top-tier-investors/">Dogecoin eyes $1 mark, Monero and Chainlink&#8217;s competitor attracts top-tier investors</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>RECQ records lightning-fast presale progress amid sluggish market momentum on INJ and LUNC</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/recq-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress-amid-sluggish-market-momentum-on-inj-and-lunc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 17:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="374" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/RECQ-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Rebel Satoshi ($RBLZ) draws investors with its lightning-fast presale of the $RECQ token The Injective (INJ) token is set to rise above $40 and beyond in the coming months, according to some analysts The Terra Classic (LUNC) token price is predicted to drop below $0.000120. The presale of Rebel Satoshi&#8217;s new token, $RECQ, has been [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/recq-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress-amid-sluggish-market-momentum-on-inj-and-lunc/">RECQ records lightning-fast presale progress amid sluggish market momentum on INJ and LUNC</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="600" height="374" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/RECQ-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li>Rebel Satoshi ($RBLZ) draws investors with its lightning-fast presale of the $RECQ token</li>
<li>The Injective (INJ) token is set to rise above $40 and beyond in the coming months, according to some analysts</li>
<li>The Terra Classic (LUNC) token price is predicted to drop below $0.000120.</li>
</ul>
<p>The presale of <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4641&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel Satoshi&rsquo;s</a> new token, $RECQ, has been growing at a significant rate. This growth has occurred even as many top crypto coins, such as Injective (INJ) and Terra Classic (LUNC), have been struggling.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s delve into why $RECQ has left the top altcoins like INJ and LUNC behind, and why several analysts are describing it as the best crypto to buy right now.</p>
<h2>Rebel Satoshi nears 75% completion of stage 1 of the $RECQ presale</h2>
<p>The innovative meme coin project Rebel Satoshi is built on the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/ethereum/what-is-ethereum/">Ethereum network</a>. Inspired by Guy Fawkes and Satoshi Nakamoto, Rebel Satoshi aims to bring a community-driven revolution. Rebel Satoshi aims to challenge the centralized financial institutions and take back control from the elites.</p>
<p>The Rebel Satoshi ecosystem includes an NFT Vault, staking pools, a merchandise store, and a gaming Arcade. The entire Rebel Satoshi ecosystem is built on its dual-token system of the $RBLZ and the $RECQ tokens. Rebel Satoshi aims to grow to a $100 million market cap. Also, the presale of the $RBLZ token generated 150% returns and raised over $2.5 million for its investors.</p>
<p>Right now, <a href="https://recq.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=4641&amp;utm_medium=News&amp;utm_id=Fox">Rebel Satoshi</a> is conducting the presale of the $RECQ tokens at $0.0037 per token in Stage 1. The $RECQ token has rallied by 85% to reach the current price, and over 74% of tokens have already been sold out. By the end of the presale, the $RECQ token is forecast to surge by 238% to $0.0125. That&rsquo;s why some analysts are describing the $RECQ token as one of the best cryptos to buy right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/?utm_source=MCAP&amp;utm_medium=Banner&amp;utm_id=Bird"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-198347" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Market-cap.png" alt="" width="587" height="73"></a></p>
<h2>Injective continues to trade in red after rising to an all-time high</h2>
<p>The Injective (INJ) token has been one of the best performers in the recent market surge. As a result, the <a href="https://coinjournal.net/injective/">Injective&nbsp; price</a> rose to an all-time high of $52.75 on March 13. Since then, the INJ token has been on a downtrend. As of the second week of April, the INJ price dropped by 34.6% to trade at around $34.45.</p>
<p>Amid the price drop, the Injective (INJ) ecosystem has continued to grow exponentially. For instance, the Ionic Upgrade to the Injective Bridge was announced on March 26. The first DePin platform on Injective (INJ), Aurora, was introduced on April 7.</p>
<p>These developments and others in the Injective ecosystem have led to a bullish outlook. Experts predict that the INJ token could rise above $40 again in the coming months.</p>
<h2>Terra Classic trades sideways after getting caught in market volatility</h2>
<p>The Terra Classic (LUNC) token has been caught up in volatility ever since rising in March. Initially, the LUNC token price dropped to $0.000121 on March 19 before bouncing slightly. The Terra Classic price then rose by 41.3% to $0.000171 a week later before dipping again.</p>
<p>Since then, the Terra Classic (LUNC) has entered a downtrend, dipping by 20.4% to around the $0.000136 level. This drop in LUNC price has occurred despite <a href="https://coinjournal.net/exchanges/binance/">Binanc</a>e burning 4.1 billion LUNC on April 2.</p>
<p>As the massive token burn has failed to turn the Terra Classic token bullish, experts are increasingly bearish on it. Hence, many are predicting that the Terra Classic (LUNC) will drop below $0.000120 in the coming months.</p>
<p>For the latest updates and more information, be sure to visit the official<a href="https://www.rebelsatoshi.com/"> Rebel Satoshi Website</a> or contact Rebel Red via <a href="https://t.me/RBLZRED">Telegram</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/recq-records-lightning-fast-presale-progress-amid-sluggish-market-momentum-on-inj-and-lunc/">RECQ records lightning-fast presale progress amid sluggish market momentum on INJ and LUNC</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/ethereum-and-cardano-register-gains-analysts-focus-shifts-to-nugx-token/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="550" height="550" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" srcset="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg 550w, https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><p>Ethereum and Cardano remain stable and show growth in the crypto market downturn. NuggetRush token emerges as a promising altcoin with play-to-earn gaming features. Cardano prioritizes security and scalability for smart contracts, while Ethereum faces technical challenges but maintains its commitment to decentralization. Amidst a recent downturn in the cryptocurrency market, Ethereum (ETH) and Cardano [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ethereum-and-cardano-register-gains-analysts-focus-shifts-to-nugx-token/">Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="550" height="550" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" srcset="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains.jpg 550w, https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum-and-Cardano-register-gains-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><ul>
<li>Ethereum and Cardano remain stable and show growth in the crypto market downturn.</li>
<li>NuggetRush token emerges as a promising altcoin with play-to-earn gaming features.</li>
<li>Cardano prioritizes security and scalability for smart contracts, while Ethereum faces technical challenges but maintains its commitment to decentralization.</li>
</ul>
<p>Amidst a recent downturn in the cryptocurrency market, Ethereum (ETH) and Cardano (ADA) have demonstrated signs of steadiness, as both assets have seen remarkable increases in value. At the same time, some analysts are shifting their attention to <a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=75">NuggetRush (NUGX)</a>, assessing its potential to become the next altcoin sensation. This digital asset offers innovative features and potential for growth in the crypto community.</p>
<p>Nugge&shy;tRush is among the bullish altcoins incorporating a play-to-earn (P2E) gaming design, allowing participants to e&shy;arn tangible assets as prizes. Its innovative&shy; offerings strive to foster an e&shy;ngaging gaming atmosphere, attracting investors and gaming e&shy;nthusiasts alike. The blockchain ICO presale&shy; is gaining momentum and piquing crypto investors&rsquo; intere&shy;st.</p>
<p>This article explores why Ethereum and Cardano show remarkable gains as analysts eye NUGX tokens as the next altcoin sensations.</p>
<h2>NuggetRush (NUGX): decentralized GameFi exploration and real-world rewards</h2>
<p><a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=75">NuggetRush</a> is a new DeFi project fostering a vibrant community within a flourishing digital ecosystem focused on GameFi exploration. Operating on the Ethereum blockchain, NuggetRush prioritizes broad user accessibility. NUGX captures atte&shy;ntion through blending exploration, strategic thinking, and tangible&shy; real-world benefits. Analysts sugge&shy;st it may be one of the bullish altcoins poise&shy;d for significant gains this year.</p>
<p>The platform pre&shy;sents diverse ave&shy;nues for gamers to accumulate re&shy;wards, including acquiring unique character NFTs, earning RUSHGEMS, and trading in-game&shy; assets. NuggetRush differe&shy;ntiates itself from typical meme&shy; coins by enabling players to trade the&shy;ir in-game earnings outside the&shy; platform&rsquo;s ecosystem. This new DeFi project has also established a playe&shy;r-driven marketplace for characte&shy;r NFTs and other exclusive ite&shy;ms. This enriches the platform&rsquo;s e&shy;conomy and empowers users to e&shy;xchange and sell virtual assets.</p>
<p>NuggetRush has already garnered immense&shy; support, with over 271 million tokens sold and more&shy; than $3.75 million raised. Some industry analysts are predicting that once NUGX is listed on major e&shy;xchanges, its price could expe&shy;rience a significant surge, pote&shy;ntially reaching $0.020. This anticipated price incre&shy;ase could position NUGX as one of the best crypto investment options right now.</p>
<p>The NuggetRush vesting system presents an appealing incentive for early adopters. Through participation in the presale phase, investors can access up to 50% of the tokens across five claim rounds based on their entry timing. This mechanism could enable early supporters to realize substantial gains as the project progresses.</p>
<h2>Cardano (ADA): scalable ecosystem for smart contracts and DApps</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/cardano/what-is-cardano/">Cardano</a> is a decentralized platform that creates a more secure and scalable infrastructure for developing smart contracts and decentralized applications (DApps). Cardano is trading at approximately $0.5877, showing stability amidst market fluctuations. As the highly anticipated Bitcoin halving eve&shy;nt approaches, alternative coins like&shy; Cardano are garnering attention. ADA showcase&shy;s resilience and growth pote&shy;ntial amid market volatility. This has piqued the inte&shy;rest of investors and traders se&shy;eking promising alternatives within the&shy; cryptocurrency landscape.</p>
<p>Cardano has see&shy;n a remarkable turnaround in investor se&shy;ntiment. After facing outflows, there&shy;&rsquo;s now a substantial $1.1 million inflow into ADA investment products. This shift highlights Cardano&rsquo;s resurge&shy;nce and growing appeal among crypto investors. The&shy; influx of funds indicates a renewe&shy;d confidence in Cardano&rsquo;s potential, marking a positive&shy; trend after a period of unce&shy;rtainty.</p>
<h2>Ethereum (ETH): empowering decentralization with smart contracts</h2>
<p><a href="https://coinjournal.net/ethereum/what-is-ethereum/">Ethere&shy;um</a> is a blockchain network that is decentralize&shy;d and open-source, with the ability to e&shy;xecute smart contracts. The curre&shy;nt price of Ethereum is approximate&shy;ly $3,315, which represents an incre&shy;ase of nearly 2%. After a significant upward tre&shy;nd from the $3,500 support level, ETH is now facing re&shy;sistance around $3,550 and the 100-hour Simple Moving Ave&shy;rage (SMA). The hourly ETH/USD chart reve&shy;als a notable resistance zone&shy; at $3,550.</p>
<p>Technical indicators indicate that the hourly Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD) remains bullish for ETH. However, the Relative Strength Index (RSI) sits below the 50 level, suggesting potential increased selling pressure. Despite recent challenges, Ethereum&rsquo;s repeated tests of crucial support levels hint at the possibility of a rapid price recovery.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>As Ethereum and Cardano continue demonstrating remarkable gains in the cryptocurrency market, analysts are now setting their sights on the NuggetRush token as the next potential altcoin sensation.</p>
<p>NuggetRush is an intriguing platform that combine&shy;s gaming with decentralized finance&shy; principles. Its unique approach prese&shy;nts an attractive investment prospe&shy;ct for those intereste&shy;d in the growing GameFi industry.</p>
<p>With growing excite&shy;ment surrounding NUGX&rsquo;s listing on major exchanges and the&shy; continued developme&shy;nt of its ecosystem, this token&rsquo;s future&shy; appears promising. It has the potential to cre&shy;ate ripples within the e&shy;ver-changing cryptocurrency world.</p>
<p>For more information on NUGX, <a href="https://nuggetrush.io/?utm_source=PR&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=cjl&amp;utm_content=75">visit NuggetRush Presale Website</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/ethereum-and-cardano-register-gains-analysts-focus-shifts-to-nugx-token/">Ethereum and Cardano register gains; analysts’ focus shifts to NUGX token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong’s spot ETFs report drives BTC higher; investors pile into Bitbot presale</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/hong-kongs-spot-etfs-report-drive-btc-higher-investors-pile-into-bitbot-presale/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Toti]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 12:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1500" height="1000" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/hong-kong-reportedly-set-to-approve-btc-etf.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>Bitcoin price has flipped above $70,000, while Ethereum is above $3,500. This is after news that Hong Kong is likely to approve its first spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs as soon as early next week. Bitbot (BITBOT) is nearing the $2.3 million mark in presale amid investor interest. Bitcoin is trading up, currently green as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/hong-kongs-spot-etfs-report-drive-btc-higher-investors-pile-into-bitbot-presale/">Hong Kong’s spot ETFs report drives BTC higher; investors pile into Bitbot presale</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1500" height="1000" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/hong-kong-reportedly-set-to-approve-btc-etf.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitcoin price has flipped above $70,000, while Ethereum is above $3,500.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">This is after news that Hong Kong is likely to approve its first spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs as soon as early next week.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot (BITBOT) is nearing the $2.3 million mark in presale amid investor interest.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/tag/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> is trading up, currently green as price hovers above $70,900. The leading cryptocurrency&rsquo;s potential to break out to a new all-time high has received a new boost as reports emerge Hong Kong is set to approve its first spot Bitcoin ETFs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BTC&rsquo;s upside flip is likely to push other altcoins higher, and one of the new tokens attracting the most attention is <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=investment_opportunity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitbot (BITBOT)</a>.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Is Bitcoin (BTC) set to explode next week?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">There are <a href="https://twitter.com/BTC_Archive/status/1778741866168537315" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Hong Kong could approve the first spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs in the region as early as Monday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">A Bloomberg report on Friday quotes sources as saying that the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) is set to give it nod, just days after major Chinese funds applied to issue spot Bitcoin ETFs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While Hong Kong&rsquo;s decision is not officially communicated as of writing, there&rsquo;s growing positivity in the market already. In January 2024, when the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) approved the first spot Bitcoin ETFs, the price of BTC skyrocketed amid massive demand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BTC reached its ATH of $73,737 in March, riding halving and spot ETFs sentiment. The SEC has <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/u-s-sec-calls-for-public-input-on-spot-ethereum-etf-applications/">called for public participation on spot ETH ETFs</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Today&rsquo;s news has seen the bellwether crypto flip from lows of $69,500 to currently trade above $70,900. Ethereum has also gained slightly, currently hovering above $3,520.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Should the ETFs draw inflows as witnessed with BlackRock&rsquo;s IBIT and others, there&rsquo;s potential for BTC, ETH and other coins to rally in coming weeks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Also likely to attract investor are new tokens that could tap into the overall market strength and specific fundamentals to emerge as top performers in the market in 2024 and beyond.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot: Pioneering non-custodial trading bot on Telegram</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BitBot is the pioneering non-custodial crypto trading bot, poised to enter the crypto market at a time traders are keen on available opportunities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While competing Telegram trading bots are custodial solutions &ndash; that is they control users&rsquo; private keys and thus hold their assets &ndash; Bitbot takes the approach of &lsquo;not your keys, not your assets.&rdquo; In short, Bitbot is where a Telegram bot user has the full control of their private keys and wallet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Security is key to crypto traders, who unfortunately have had to learn the hard way given incidents involving top bots such as Unibot and Banana Gun. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">By focusing on security through its partnership with Knightsafe, Bitbot has taken an early lead against potential rival trading apps.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot app&rsquo;s AI capabilities add to the superior outlook, with users able to access all the advanced institutional-grade trading tools that make trading via bots such a huge market in the crypto space. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot offers all of these, including trade sniping, gem scanner, copy trading and automated execution, without compromising on user security and convenience.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitbot presale surpasses $2.2 million amid investor interest</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The native BITBOT token is in presale and users will get access to benefits such as revenue-sharing, trading discounts and airdrops. Presale participants can buy BITBOT at the still heavily discounted price of $0.0155 in stage 10.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Early bird investors have pushed the presale to near $2.3 million. Notably, there&rsquo;s just five stages to go before Bitbot hits the final stage 15 and tokens debut in the market. This could be at a time when Bitcoin and Ethereum are in parabolic mode.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">That means current presale prices could be a real bargain and opportunity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">To learn more visit the <a href="https://bitbot.tg/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=artc&amp;utm_campaign=coinjournal&amp;utm_term=internal&amp;utm_content=investment_opportunity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitbot website</a>.</span></p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/hong-kongs-spot-etfs-report-drive-btc-higher-investors-pile-into-bitbot-presale/">Hong Kong’s spot ETFs report drives BTC higher; investors pile into Bitbot presale</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>99Bitcoins Launches Learn-To-Earn Presale and Raises $150K On First Day</title>
		<link>https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/</link>
					<comments>https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chainwire &#160;]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 10:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://coinjournal.net/?p=198309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainwire_-_1800x1080_12_1712913142ZfZpzbRf70.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p>New York, United States, April 12th, 2024, Chainwire 99Bitcoins, established in 2013, has recently begun its token presale in an effort to harness the current upward trend in Bitcoin&#8217;s value. The 99BTC team, seizing this opportunity, offers its learn-to-earn platform, a longstanding resource in cryptocurrency education. What is 99Bitcoins? 99Bitcoins has been breaking down technical [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/">99Bitcoins Launches Learn-To-Earn Presale and Raises $150K On First Day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1200" height="720" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainwire_-_1800x1080_12_1712913142ZfZpzbRf70.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" /><p><strong>New York, United States, April 12th, 2024, Chainwire</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">99Bitcoins</a>, established in 2013, has recently begun its token presale in an effort to harness the current upward trend in Bitcoin&rsquo;s value. The 99BTC team, seizing this opportunity, offers its learn-to-earn platform, a longstanding resource in cryptocurrency education.</p>
<h2>What is 99Bitcoins?</h2>
<p>99Bitcoins has been breaking down technical concepts and onboarding newcomers to the crypto world for over ten years as the team can show by the numbers on its social media accounts: over <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@99Bitcoins" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">700,000 YouTube followers</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/99BitcoinsHQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">16,000 Twitter followers</a> and 2 million registered users have confirmed its +80 hours of resources are a great entry point for those looking to learn more about crypto.</p>
<p>The $99BTC token is its latest venture. The team promotes its commitment to education by introducing the &ldquo;gamification of learning&rdquo; into the platform, providing $99BTC rewards for those who complete its courses, such as exclusive access to premium content, discounts on partner products and services, VIP communities, trading signals, and token holder events.</p>
<p>The 99Bitcoins team aims to attract all the potential new users who are expected to enter the crypto space and explore Bitcoin in light of the upcoming halving; the event, which will occur this month, is expected to increase the number of first-time crypto enthusiasts as confirmed by multiple researches and major sources like <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-halving-institutional-investors-crypto-adoption" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CoinTelegraph</a> and <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/consensus-magazine/2024/04/10/how-the-halving-will-impact-the-bitcoin-market/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CoinDesk</a>.</p>
<h2>Pioneering BRC-20: Pushing Learn-to-Earn in new directions</h2>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/dnM2lZrkUsb6PZiozUftflhQimKkVi2QrUAT__eusmMRyO5g-k_1712912300JYsiGkZO9d.jpeg"></p>
<p>99Bitcoins is also trying to set itself as a pioneer of the BRC-20 movement: a new token standard that allows developers to deploy smart contracts on the Bitcoin blockchain. Security and transparency are also key to this project, a <a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/assets/docs/audit.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Solidproof audit</a> confirms that 99Bitcoins contract does have no potential issues or warnings.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s worth noting $99BTC is originally deployed as an ERC-20 token and that it will be bridged to BRC-20 only in Q4 2024, transferring the security of the project to the Bitcoin network.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/wRavhnrTYwyazd5brgtgKMP8XHvPWUAB6PegDIOTaV2wemttN3_1712912300nOKAR4dtXe.jpeg"></p>
<p>When it comes to the tokenomics (renamed to Token Metrics by its team), 99Bitcoins is distributing its 99 billion $99BTC total supply with the goal of helping it remain competitive and provide lasting sustainability:</p>
<ul>
<li>15% is allocated to the presale, which is currently selling $99BTC for $0.001</li>
<li>14% for staking rewards, providing $99BTC stakers with rewards for two years</li>
<li>23% is allocated to project funds</li>
<li>17% for community rewards</li>
<li>8% to provide liquidity to exchanges</li>
<li>23% for marketing</li>
</ul>
<p>This tokenomics structure is then paired with an ambitious roadmap which would target the beta release of the platform to last quarter this year, followed by the full release next year.</p>
<h3>About 99Bitcoins</h3>
<p><a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">99Bitcoins</a> is a vital educational resource for Bitcoin. It focuses on providing information about cryptocurrency to onboard new users to the industry. The website was established in 2013 and has since expanded its knowledge base to popular blockchains and cryptocurrencies such as Litecoin, Ethereum, Cardano, and Solana.</p>
<p>The platform now brings a gamification element to its product, allowing students to receive $99BTC rewards in a L2E economy. The $99BTC token is also pioneering the BRC-20 movement, a new token standard that enables smart contracts to be deployed on the Bitcoin network.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://presale.99bitcoins.com/en#home" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/99BitcoinsHQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">X</a></li>
<li><a href="https://t.me/Official_99_Bitcoins" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Telegram</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>99Bitcoins<br>
contact@99bitcoins.com</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/">99Bitcoins Launches Learn-To-Earn Presale and Raises $150K On First Day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://coinjournal.net">CoinJournal</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://coinjournal.net/news/99bitcoins-launches-learn-to-earn-presale-and-raises-150k-on-first-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
