<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:38:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bitwise Head of Alpha Strategies explains how US Bitcoin ETFs outperformed expectations</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/bitwise-head-of-alpha-strategies-explains-how-us-bitcoin-etfs-outperformed-expectations/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/bitwise-head-of-alpha-strategies-explains-how-us-bitcoin-etfs-outperformed-expectations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nate Whitehill]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_video&#038;p=413843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a recent episode of the SlateCast, Liam &#8220;Akiba&#8221; Wright and CryptoSlate Lead Analyst James Van Straten welcomed Jeff Park, Head of Alpha Strategies at Bitwise, to discuss the groundbreaking launch of Bitcoin ETFs in the United States. Park shared valuable insights into the ETF approval process, the industry&#8217;s response, and the broader implications for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/bitwise-head-of-alpha-strategies-explains-how-us-bitcoin-etfs-outperformed-expectations/">Bitwise Head of Alpha Strategies explains how US Bitcoin ETFs outperformed expectations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a recent episode of the SlateCast, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/author/liam-akiba-wright">Liam &#8220;Akiba&#8221; Wright</a> and CryptoSlate Lead Analyst <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/author/james-van-straten">James Van Straten</a> welcomed Jeff Park, Head of Alpha Strategies at <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitwise">Bitwise</a>, to discuss the groundbreaking launch of <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/etfs">Bitcoin ETFs</a> in the United States. Park shared valuable insights into the ETF approval process, the industry&#8217;s response, and the broader implications for Bitcoin adoption.</p>
<h2>The Long Road to Approval</h2>
<p>The journey to the approval of Bitcoin ETFs in the US has been a marathon, spanning over a decade since the Winklevoss twins filed the first application. Park acknowledged the persistence and determination required to achieve this milestone:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;It&#8217;s been close to plus 10 plus years of the timing of the application since its first inception with the Winklevoss twins. And so some of, I think, the growth that we&#8217;ve seen was because there was a lot of capital on the sideline anticipating this for almost a decade.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Exceeding Expectations</h2>
<p>Despite the lengthy approval process, the inflows into the newly launched Bitcoin ETFs have surpassed industry expectations. Park attributed this to the pent-up demand from investors who had been eagerly awaiting this opportunity:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Honestly, it&#8217;s gone beyond our expectations as well. We try to be conservative in our estimations of what inflows could be, but the truth is that this has been a long marathon here in the U.S.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Changing Perceptions</h2>
<p>One of the key impacts of the Bitcoin ETF launch has been the shift in perception surrounding the asset class. Park highlighted the newfound confidence among investors, citing a recent family office conference where questions about the legitimacy of crypto were no longer raised:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Anecdotally, I was at a family office conference last week and it was the first time in a while where nobody asked the question, &#8216;is crypto here to stay?&#8217; It&#8217;s just out of the purview and, and that&#8217;s an incredible feeling.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Is Bitcoin Safer at Higher Prices?</h2>
<p>In a counterintuitive observation, Park suggested that Bitcoin might be perceived as a safer investment at higher price points due to the increasing acceptance and adoption of the asset class:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;[Bitcoin] is safer to buy it at $70k versus when it was at $10k because of all the ways that it&#8217;s become accepted in the psyche of people to think of this asset class.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>The Overton Window and Bitcoin&#8217;s Supply</h2>
<p>Park also touched on the U.S. government&#8217;s daily interest burden, which he compared to the daily issuance of new Bitcoin. This perspective challenges the traditional notion of Bitcoin&#8217;s limited supply:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The Overton window is actually incorrect. It&#8217;s not even about the issuance of new Bitcoin. It&#8217;s where the other fiat-based currency is finding inflation, and this is counterbalancing.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>As the crypto industry continues to evolve, the launch of Bitcoin ETFs in the US marks a significant milestone, signaling growing acceptance and mainstream adoption. Jeff Park&#8217;s insights from Bitwise provide a unique perspective on this historic event and its potential implications for the future of Bitcoin and the broader crypto ecosystem.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f399.png" alt="🎙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />New SlateCast: Inside Bitcoin ETFs alpha strategies</p>
<p>&#8220;Is Bitcoin riskier to buy at $10k or at $70k? [&#8230;] It&#8217;s safer to buy at $70k&#8221;</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f3a4.png" alt="🎤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />: Guest &#8211; <a href="https://twitter.com/BitwiseInvest?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BitwiseInvest</a> Head of Alpha Strategy <a href="https://twitter.com/dgt10011?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dgt10011</a></p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f5e3.png" alt="🗣" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />: Hosts: <a href="https://twitter.com/jvs_btc?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@jvs_btc</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/akibablade?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@akibablade</a> <a href="https://t.co/L3JK1gGU1O">pic.twitter.com/L3JK1gGU1O</a></p>
<p>— CryptoSlate (@CryptoSlate) <a href="https://twitter.com/CryptoSlate/status/1781354740191838232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/bitwise-head-of-alpha-strategies-explains-how-us-bitcoin-etfs-outperformed-expectations/">Bitwise Head of Alpha Strategies explains how US Bitcoin ETFs outperformed expectations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/bitwise-head-of-alpha-strategies-explains-how-us-bitcoin-etfs-outperformed-expectations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SlateCast-Bitwise.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SlateCast-Bitwise.jpg" length="1280" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>100k signatures can trigger Swiss national referendum on adding Bitcoin to country reserves</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/100k-signatures-can-trigger-swiss-national-referendum-on-adding-bitcoin-to-country-reserves/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/100k-signatures-can-trigger-swiss-national-referendum-on-adding-bitcoin-to-country-reserves/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Switzerland]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin advocates in Switzerland have initiated a campaign to trigger a National Referendum urging the Swiss National Bank (SNB) to include the flagship digital asset in its asset reserves. The campaign is spearheaded by Yves Bennaïm, the founder and chairman of 2B4CH, a nonprofit think tank, and enjoys support from Luzius Meisser, the chairman of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/100k-signatures-can-trigger-swiss-national-referendum-on-adding-bitcoin-to-country-reserves/">100k signatures can trigger Swiss national referendum on adding Bitcoin to country reserves</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> advocates in Switzerland have initiated a campaign to trigger a National Referendum urging the Swiss National Bank (SNB) to include the flagship digital asset in its asset reserves.</p>
<p>The campaign is spearheaded by Yves Bennaïm, the founder and chairman of 2B4CH, a nonprofit think tank, and enjoys support from Luzius Meisser, the chairman of asset manager Bitcoin Suisse.</p>
<p>Bennaïm <a href="https://twitter.com/initiativeBTC/status/1781932788976931024">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We are in the process of completing the organizational preparations for the committee and preparing the documents that must be submitted to the State Chancellery in order to start the process.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>What next?</h2>
<p>The referendum&#8217;s launch hinges on securing 100,000 valid signatures from Swiss citizens. Subsequently, all Swiss nationals will vote on the proposed constitutional amendment.</p>
<p>All of these processes could take as much as five years.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Meisser will <a href="https://www-nzz-ch.translate.goog/wirtschaft/nun-kommt-die-volksinitiative-welche-die-nationalbank-zum-kauf-von-bitcoin-verpflichten-will-ld.1827256?_x_tr_sl=auto&amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;_x_tr_hl=en-US&amp;_x_tr_pto=wapp&amp;_x_tr_hist=true">champion</a> Bitcoin at the upcoming Swiss National Bank&#8217;s general assembly.</p>
<p>Notably, this isn&#8217;t Meisser&#8217;s first foray into advocating for Bitcoin. Previously, he proposed a similar action at the 2022 General Meeting, urging the bank to prioritize Bitcoin investments over German government bonds.</p>
<p>He estimated that had the bank heeded his advice, Switzerland would now possess an additional 30 billion francs.</p>
<p>In 2021, 2B4CH initiated the Bitcoin Initiative, intending to enshrine BTC as a reserve currency in the Swiss Constitution.</p>
<p>However, the process suffered some hiccups, which Bennaïm explained were caused by the timing and need for discussion. He <a href="https://twitter.com/ZLOK/status/1782308310235918631">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The reason why it took some time since the original 2021 announcement was not the 100,000 signatures&#8230;we wanted to first discuss openly with the SNB and give them the opportunity to start adopting Bitcoin before moving forward with the official procedure.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>If the Bitcoin advocates&#8217; plan succeeds, Switzerland could become the first country in the West to embrace the flagship crypto asset. However, it would trail behind El Salvador, a Central American country that has made <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/el-salvador-and-pro-bitcoin-businesses-reaping-rewards-after-years-of-skepticism/">substantial investments i</a>n BTC and adopted it as a legal tender.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/100k-signatures-can-trigger-swiss-national-referendum-on-adding-bitcoin-to-country-reserves/">100k signatures can trigger Swiss national referendum on adding Bitcoin to country reserves</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/100k-signatures-can-trigger-swiss-national-referendum-on-adding-bitcoin-to-country-reserves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-switzerland.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-switzerland.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kenya to extradite Binance executive involved in tax evasion and escape drama to Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/kenya-to-extradite-binance-executive-involved-in-tax-evasion-and-escape-drama-to-nigeria/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/kenya-to-extradite-binance-executive-involved-in-tax-evasion-and-escape-drama-to-nigeria/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan authorities are gearing up to extradite Nadeem Anjarwalla, a Binance executive sought by the Nigerian government. Over the weekend, a joint operation involving various agencies—such as the Economics and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC), Nigeria Police Force, Kenya Police Service, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and International Criminal Police Organization (INTERPOL)—successfully captured him in Kenya [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kenya-to-extradite-binance-executive-involved-in-tax-evasion-and-escape-drama-to-nigeria/">Kenya to extradite Binance executive involved in tax evasion and escape drama to Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan authorities are gearing up to extradite Nadeem Anjarwalla, a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a> executive sought by the Nigerian government.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, a joint <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nigeria-and-interpol-collaborate-to-extradite-binance-executive-amid-money-laundering-charges/">operation</a> involving various agencies—such as the Economics and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC), Nigeria Police Force, Kenya Police Service, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and International Criminal Police Organization (INTERPOL)—successfully captured him in Kenya after weeks of search.</p>
<p>Following his arrest, local media outlet Punch, citing an undisclosed government source, <a href="https://punchng.com/exclusive-kenya-to-extradite-binance-executive-who-escaped-from-nigeria/">revealed</a> that Anjarwalla is slated for extradition to Nigeria within the week. There, he faces trial on charges related to tax evasion.</p>
<p>Moreover, the Nigerian law enforcement agencies might pursue additional charges regarding his use of illegal passports and escape from custody.</p>
<p>Anjarwalla, Binance Africa&#8217;s regional manager, and another executive, Tigran Gambrayan, found themselves in legal trouble in Nigeria in February after the authorities <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/former-us-irs-agent-among-binance-staff-detained-in-nigeria/">detained</a> them over their connections to the crypto exchange.</p>
<p>However, Anjarwalla managed to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/detained-binance-executive-escapes-from-nigerian-custody-amid-tax-evasion-charges/">slip away</a> from legal custody in March using a Kenyan passport and has been on the run since.</p>
<h2>Updates on Binance situation in Nigeria</h2>
<p>This development further exacerbates the ongoing <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-accused-of-manipulating-nigerian-naira-as-glitch-impacts-p2p-traders/">conflict</a> between Binance and the Nigerian authorities.</p>
<p>Gambrayan, a key Binance executive detained since February, is on trial for alleged tax evasion.</p>
<p>Notably, the tax evasion proceedings have faced challenges. A Nigerian court has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-executive-remains-detained-as-nigerian-court-postpones-case/">adjourned the case</a> twice because the exchange was not formally served with the charges. The judge is expected to rule on the matter by May 17.</p>
<p>Binance CEO Richard Teng has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/binance-working-closely-with-nigeria-authorities-resolve-execs-detention-ceo-2024-04-18/">pledged</a> cooperation with Nigerian authorities to resolve the issue. However, specific efforts to secure the release of the detained executives remain undisclosed.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Gambrayan&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/detained-binance-exec-sues-nigeria-over-human-rights-violations/">effort to secure his relea</a>se has also faced setbacks. A federal high court at the nation&#8217;s capital, Abuja, postponed his bail application hearing, and he is currently being <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nigerian-court-orders-binance-executive-to-remain-in-prison-despite-not-guilty-plea/">held at the Kuje correctional center.</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kenya-to-extradite-binance-executive-involved-in-tax-evasion-and-escape-drama-to-nigeria/">Kenya to extradite Binance executive involved in tax evasion and escape drama to Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/kenya-to-extradite-binance-executive-involved-in-tax-evasion-and-escape-drama-to-nigeria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/binance-nigeria-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/binance-nigeria-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halving sees transaction fees hit new record momentarily as Bitcoin climbs back above $66k</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/insights/halving-sees-transaction-fees-hit-new-record-momentarily-as-bitcoin-climbs-back-above-66k/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_insight&#038;p=413792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Following the Bitcoin halving on Saturday, April 20, transaction fees surged to the highest level on record as users competed to mint new Runes inscriptions. According to RunesMarketCap, Runes have a market cap of around $430 million as of press time, with the top project being SATOSHI•NAKAMOTO at $130 million. Bitcoin Runes is a new [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/halving-sees-transaction-fees-hit-new-record-momentarily-as-bitcoin-climbs-back-above-66k/">Halving sees transaction fees hit new record momentarily as Bitcoin climbs back above $66k</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following the Bitcoin halving on Saturday, April 20, transaction fees surged to the highest level on record as users competed to mint new <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/runes-liquid-fund-launches-with-3-million-investment-as-halving-nears/">Runes</a> inscriptions. According to RunesMarketCap, Runes have a market cap of around <a href="https://runesmarketcap.com/">$430 million</a> as of press time, with the top project being SATOSHI•NAKAMOTO at $130 million.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413800" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413800" style="width: 2826px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-413800" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-09.04.09.png" alt="Historic Bitcoin transaction fees (mempool.space)" width="2826" height="1202" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-09.04.09.png 2826w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-09.04.09-300x128.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-09.04.09-1024x436.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-09.04.09-768x327.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-09.04.09-1536x653.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-09.04.09-2048x871.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2826px) 100vw, 2826px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413800" class="wp-caption-text">Historic Bitcoin transaction fees (mempool.space)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700">Bitcoin Runes is</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> a new protocol</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> on the Bitcoin</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> blockchain, designed</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> to create fung</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700">ible tokens using</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> the UTXO (Unspent Transaction</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> Output) model</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700">. This protocol</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700">, proposed by</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> Casey Rodarmor, aims</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> to address ineff</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700">iciencies in existing</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> token standards</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> like BRC-20 by</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> minimizing the</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> creation of &#8220;</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700">junk&#8221; UTXOs and</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> promoting more</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> responsible management</span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700"> of blockchain </span><span class="animate-in fade-in-25 duration-700">resources. </span>The protocol launched in conjunction with the halving, leading to a scramble to mint Runes and the subsequent fee spike as users competed to be included in a block.</p>
<p>However, fees subsided early on Sunday, April 21, and as of this morning, April 22, fees are close to pre-halving levels.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413796" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413796" style="width: 2838px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-413796" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-08.57.37.png" alt="Bitcoin fees (mempool.space)" width="2838" height="1146" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-08.57.37.png 2838w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-08.57.37-300x121.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-08.57.37-1024x413.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-08.57.37-768x310.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-08.57.37-1536x620.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-08.57.37-2048x827.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2838px) 100vw, 2838px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413796" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin fees (mempool.space)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s price has rallied through the halving event, reaching as high as $66,500 and currently sitting around $66,000 as of press time.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/halving-sees-transaction-fees-hit-new-record-momentarily-as-bitcoin-climbs-back-above-66k/">Halving sees transaction fees hit new record momentarily as Bitcoin climbs back above $66k</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/coinbase-legal-copy.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/coinbase-legal-copy.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto regulation redefined: How MiCA affects your company</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-regulation-redefined-how-mica-affects-your-company/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-regulation-redefined-how-mica-affects-your-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Gofaizen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest post by Mark Gofaizen, Senior Partner at Gofaizen &#38; Sherle. As the MiCA regulation that will reshape the crypto industry approaches, crypto companies need to ensure compliance for a smooth transition. Crypto-asset market regulation (MiCA), which represents an important step by the European Union (EU) towards regulating the crypto-asset market, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-regulation-redefined-how-mica-affects-your-company/">Crypto regulation redefined: How MiCA affects your company</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is a guest post by Mark Gofaizen, Senior Partner at Gofaizen &amp; Sherle.<br />
</em></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the MiCA regulation that will reshape the crypto industry approaches, crypto companies need to ensure compliance for a smooth transition.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crypto-asset market regulation (MiCA), which represents an important step by the European Union (EU) towards regulating the crypto-asset market, is one of the hot topics of 2024. MiCA seeks to infuse the market with clarity and security, addressing the needs of crypto-asset service providers (CASPs) and issuers while safeguarding investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For companies operating in the crypto space, MiCA clearly calls for changes to their processes in order to adapt to the new regulatory environment. Covering topics ranging from operational flexibility to consumer protection, MiCA ensures that the crypto asset market is sustainable and compliant with wider financial market regulations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Industry stakeholders and companies need support and guidance during this transition period. This article will cover how MiCA can impact companies, focusing on processes that need attention, potential cost increases, and staffing needs.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Core Requirements Under MiCA</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The crypto industry is on the verge of a regulatory evolution, with the draft Regulatory Technical Standards (RTS) outlined by the European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA). These forthcoming standards, anticipated to be presented to the European Commission by June 30, 2024, are crucial for CASPs aiming to secure a MiCA license.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Essential aspects of MiCA include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Anti-Money Laundering (AML): </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">CASPs must adhere to a comprehensive suite of laws and procedures to prevent the disguise of illicit funds as legitimate.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Combating the Financing of Terrorism (CFT):</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Crypto-asset service providers are responsible for measures to prevent the flow of funds to terrorist organizations.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Authorized Capital: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">CASPs are required to define the maximum capital they can issue, as stated in their charter.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Customer Due Diligence (CDD): </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crypto-asset service providers must verify customer identities and assess transactional risks.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Suspicious Transaction Reporting (STR): </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">CASPs must have procedures for detecting and reporting suspicious transactions to competent authorities.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Cooperation and Information Sharing: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cooperating with competent authorities and sharing necessary information is another obligation for CASPs.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These foundational requirements align CASPs with broader fiscal and regulatory expectations, tailoring to their unique operational frameworks.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Aligning with Wider Financial Regulations</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MiCA&#8217;s introduction necessitates comprehensive adjustments across CASP operations, underscoring the necessity for a holistic strategy to foster a transparent, secure, and consumer-centric crypto market in sync with broader financial regulations.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Key business process areas for review include:</strong></h3>
<h4><strong>Personnel Training and Recruitment</strong></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To comply with MiCA, companies need to create a team specializing in regulatory compliance specific to financial services or crypto assets. Acquiring risk management experts and legal advisors is crucial to tackling the complexities of MiCA. These professionals will be instrumental in identifying, assessing, and mitigating risks and ensuring all company operations fully comply with the new regulation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CASPs should have at least one person from senior management (director) located in the country of establishment and organize activity through the place of business in the EU.</span></p>
<h4><strong>Collection and Use of Personal Data</strong></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MiCA mandates the protection of consumer information and the segregation of customer assets. Companies must ensure compliance with privacy and data protection by developing secure systems for collecting and using personal data. Additionally, the regulation requires implementing customer separation systems to protect customer assets, a measure aimed at improving consumer protection in the crypto market.</span></p>
<h4><strong>Reporting and Accounting</strong></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Companies must improve their reporting and accounting practices to meet MiCA&#8217;s transparency and accountability standards. These standards include accurately reporting financial transactions and keeping company records compliant with regulatory requirements.</span></p>
<h4><strong>Advisory Services for Crypto Assets Users</strong></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MiCA significantly emphasizes the quality of advisory services provided to crypto asset users. Companies offering advisory services must ensure that advice is personalized, transparent, fair, and not misleading, considering the client&#8217;s personal circumstances, investment objectives, and risk appetite.</span></p>
<h4><strong>Crypto Exchange Services and Related Policies</strong></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For companies providing crypto exchange services, MiCA seeks to ensure fair and orderly trading, set rules for order execution, and provide clear information on the exchange of crypto assets. The regulation aims to improve the integrity and stability of crypto exchange services by promoting a safer trading environment for consumers.</span></p>
<h2><strong>MiCA: An Opportunity, Not a Challenge</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The launch of MiCA is a milestone for the cryptoasset market in the European Union and sets a precedent for regulatory frameworks worldwide. As we approach a new era of compliance and regulation, companies in the crypto sector are being given a transition period until June 2025. With the proposed changes being submitted to institutions for coordination and feedback by March 28, the regulatory changes are expected to create a more secure and reliable crypto environment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As companies seek to comply with regulations, focusing on strategic planning, investing in compliance infrastructure, and developing a knowledgeable compliance team becomes extremely important. Embracing MiCA not just as a compliance challenge but as an opportunity to increase operational integrity and consumer trust can position companies for success in the increasingly regulated global crypto market.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-regulation-redefined-how-mica-affects-your-company/">Crypto regulation redefined: How MiCA affects your company</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-regulation-redefined-how-mica-affects-your-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-eu-mica.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-eu-mica.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI and blockchain: A match made in heaven or hell</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ai-and-blockchain-a-match-made-in-heaven-or-hell/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ai-and-blockchain-a-match-made-in-heaven-or-hell/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kadan Stadelmann]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 12:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=410958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest post by Kadan Stadelmann, CTO of Komodo Blockchain. From AI Models on Bitcoin to AI training data on a layer 2 blockchain, coins linked to AI crypto projects are all the rage in the altcoin universe. It&#8217;s a reflection of broader market conditions. Hot stock Nvidia (NVDA.O) has stolen headlines [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ai-and-blockchain-a-match-made-in-heaven-or-hell/">AI and blockchain: A match made in heaven or hell</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is a guest post by Kadan Stadelmann, CTO of Komodo Blockchain.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From AI Models on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> to AI training data on a layer 2 blockchain, coins linked to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/ai/">AI crypto</a> projects are all the rage in the altcoin universe.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s a reflection of broader market conditions. Hot stock Nvidia (NVDA.O) has stolen headlines since last year and put AI on the investing map. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That stock </span><strong><a href="https://www.bankrate.com/investing/trillion-dollar-companies/#:~:text=Nvidia%20(NVDA),a%20boom%20in%20artificial%20intelligence.">became</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the seventh public U.S. company valued at over $1 trillion. By March 2024, it became the world’s third most valuable company after Microsoft and Apple as the market cap </span><strong><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-03-04/nvidia-leaps-aramco-to-be-world-s-third-most-valuable-company">eclipsed</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $2 trillion. Investors yearn for exposure to machine learning technology at a clip that rivals the world’s largest companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AI tokens at the time of writing have a market value of $26.4 billion. Last April, that number was a mere $2.7 billion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CoinDesk Indices Computing Index includes AI-linked tokens and has increased more than 165% in the past 12 months. And trading volumes hit an all-time high of $3.8 billion in late February.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although many investors are chasing price gains, AI-linked crypto tokens provide an opportunity in crypto that is at the same time uncorrelated to crypto. These tokens&#8217; values are arguably more tied to the fate of the AI sector than to crypto.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment manager VanEck predicts that AI crypto revenue could reach a whopping $10.2 billion by 2030 on the low end with use cases similar to non-AI crypto projects—reward tokens, physical computation infrastructure, data verification, provenance, and more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To be sure, the AI blockchain revolution remains in its infancy. How the merger of these two exciting industries plays out is unknown. Bitcoin Maximalists, for instance, believe the entire crypto index could go to zero. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a long list of possible uses for AI tokens. Payments, trading models, machine-generated non-fungible tokens and blockchain-based marketplaces for AI applications to name a few.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Theoretically, blockchain improves the security of protocols with a decentralized and immutable settlement layer.</span></p>
<p>AI detects risks in real-time and provides an extra layer of security monitoring network activities, analyzing historical and provenance data and asset conditions, discovering anomalies, using predictive analytics to make smart contract conditions more efficient, and analyzing provenance data, asset conditions, and market trends.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Imagine a system where these two novel technologies pull and verify data while managing network loads.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain could be a public record of AI training. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AI algorithms improve threat detection and response; blockchain’s immutability of security-related data provides a robust defense against cyber threats paired with a decentralized approach to data management. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once the AI-verified information is recorded to the blockchain, it cannot be altered or deleted. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nonetheless, the merger of AI and blockchain poses threats.</span></p>
<h2><b>The Risks Of AI And Blockchain </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United Nations General Assembly adopted March 21, a global artificial intelligence (AI) resolution promoting “safe, secure, and trustworthy” AI development. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The European Parliament passed March 13 an AI Act to set governance standards for the Union.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, the European Commission </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/european-commission-asks-for-ai-risk-data-from-google-facebook-x-and-five-others/">launched a probe</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> into the use of AI.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Biden administration&#8217;s October 2023 executive order notes AI development&#8217;s safety and security problems. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, India </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/india-mandates-regulatory-approval-before-ai-tools-are-launched/">introduced AI requirements</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in March before the national elections.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AI and blockchain, both alone and combined, pose privacy and security risks. Vast amounts of sensitive data could one day depend on the security of AI-blockchain apps, and how these might be secured remains unclear.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AI requires vast amounts of data to learn, predict, and act. The data could become increasingly personal over time, posing a greater risk to privacy. Blockchain can counteract these risks by anonymizing data transactions to protect identity with methods including zero-knowledge proofs and also creating an immutable and often public record. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data recorded to a public blockchain can be deleted by nobody, presenting a conflict with privacy norms and laws such as the right to be forgotten. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The theoretical potential for AI to act on data secured by blockchain without human oversight raises significant questions about consent and privacy. </span></p>
<h2><b>Fostering Beneficial Innovation</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the quest to harness blockchain and AI without dystopia, the world must be guided by ethical principles and safety standards so that these technologies end up serving humanity&#8217;s best interests and solving our most pressing needs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A collaborative approach among developers, ethicists, and policymakers is needed to delineate clear boundaries for AI behavior and data integrity on blockchain networks. Developers must design innovative solutions to protect privacy and security in the new digital frontier.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The principles of transparency, accountability, and inclusivity ensure that AI and blockchain systems are designed with an understanding of their societal impacts. </span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ai-and-blockchain-a-match-made-in-heaven-or-hell/">AI and blockchain: A match made in heaven or hell</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ai-and-blockchain-a-match-made-in-heaven-or-hell/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ai-blockchain-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ai-blockchain-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTX investors agree to drop civil lawsuit against SBF if he snitches on celebrity promoters</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-investors-agree-to-drop-civil-lawsuit-against-sbf-if-he-snitches-on-celebrity-promoters/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-investors-agree-to-drop-civil-lawsuit-against-sbf-if-he-snitches-on-celebrity-promoters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 01:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>FTX investors may drop claims against the company&#8217;s co-founder and former CEO, Sam Bankman-Fried, in return for his support. Bloomberg reported on April 19 that, under a proposed settlement, Bankman-Fried would cooperate against celebrity promoters named as defendants in a $1.3 million civil lawsuit. The civil case currently names celebrities as defendants, including former NFL [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-investors-agree-to-drop-civil-lawsuit-against-sbf-if-he-snitches-on-celebrity-promoters/">FTX investors agree to drop civil lawsuit against SBF if he snitches on celebrity promoters</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> investors may drop claims against the company&#8217;s co-founder and former CEO, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/sam-bankman-fried/">Sam Bankman-Fried</a>, in return for his support.</p>
<p>Bloomberg reported on <a href="https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/ftx-investors-settle-with-sam-bankman-fried-to-pursue-promoters-1.2061522">April 19</a> that, under a proposed settlement, Bankman-Fried would cooperate against celebrity promoters named as defendants in a $1.3 million civil lawsuit.</p>
<p>The civil case currently names celebrities as defendants, including former NFL quarterback Tom Brady, former NBA player Shaquille O&#8217;Neal, and supermodel Gisele Bundchen.</p>
<p>Plaintiffs allege that the celebrities brought them into a Ponzi scheme by promoting FTX.</p>
<h2>SBF would provide information</h2>
<p>To cooperate, Bankman-Fried would need to provide plaintiffs&#8217; lawyers with details about entities related to FTX, including venture capital firms that invested in the exchange and accountants and lawyers that worked with the company during its operations.</p>
<p>He would also provide nonprivileged documents outlining his investments in the AI company <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/anthropic/">Anthropic</a> and an affidavit proving his negative net worth.</p>
<p>In exchange for Bankman-Fried&#8217;s cooperation, plaintiffs would drop current and future claims against him. Bloomberg said that plaintiffs acknowledged Bankman-Fried&#8217;s participation as &#8220;valuable&#8221; but recognized that the shift in focus could make their case&#8217;s outcome uncertain.</p>
<p>The judge must decide whether to approve the proposal.</p>
<h2>Past developments</h2>
<p>The relevant case, currently proceeding in the Southern District of Florida, brings together several civil lawsuits against various FTX promoters and insiders.</p>
<p>Several other defendants previously approached a settlement. A March 27 filing named FTX insiders Gary Wang, Caroline Ellison, and Nishad Singh, former FTX lawyer Daniel Friedberg, several internet personalities, and AFL quarterback William Trevor Lawrence as proposed settling defendants. The current status of the proposal is unclear.</p>
<p>Much earlier, in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tom-brady-other-celebrities-ask-court-to-dismiss-lawsuit-over-promoting-ftx/">April 2023</a>, some celebrity promoters <span class="BxUVEf ILfuVd" lang="en"><span class="hgKElc">—</span></span> including but not limited to Brady and Bundchen <span class="BxUVEf ILfuVd" lang="en"><span class="hgKElc">—</span></span> asked the court to dismiss claims. The relevant case, Garrison v. Bankman-Fried et al., became part of the consolidated case by June 2023.</p>
<p>All civil cases are distinct from the high-profile criminal case against Bankman-Fried, which has concluded. Bankman-Fried was convicted on criminal charges in November 2023 and received a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/former-ftx-ceo-sam-bankman-fried-sentenced-to-25-years-in-landmark-fraud-case/">24-year prison sentence</a> in March.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-investors-agree-to-drop-civil-lawsuit-against-sbf-if-he-snitches-on-celebrity-promoters/">FTX investors agree to drop civil lawsuit against SBF if he snitches on celebrity promoters</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-investors-agree-to-drop-civil-lawsuit-against-sbf-if-he-snitches-on-celebrity-promoters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/sbf-sam-bankman-fried-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/sbf-sam-bankman-fried-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IRS draft tax form for crypto defines unhosted wallets as brokers</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/irs-draft-tax-form-for-crypto-defines-unhosted-wallets-as-brokers/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/irs-draft-tax-form-for-crypto-defines-unhosted-wallets-as-brokers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Taxes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The IRS published a draft version of its 1099-DA reporting form and controversially included unhosted crypto wallets among its targets on April 19. Ji Kim, Chief Legal and Policy officer at the Crypto Council for Innovation, wrote that the IRS&#8217; approach is &#8220;unfortunate&#8221; as it does not recognize that unhosted wallet providers lack knowledge about [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/irs-draft-tax-form-for-crypto-defines-unhosted-wallets-as-brokers/">IRS draft tax form for crypto defines unhosted wallets as brokers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The IRS published a draft version of its 1099-DA reporting form and controversially included unhosted crypto wallets among its targets on <a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-dft/f1099da--dft.pdf">April 19</a>.</p>
<p>Ji Kim, Chief Legal and Policy officer at the Crypto Council for Innovation, <a href="https://twitter.com/_jikim/status/1781401395633013130">wrote that</a> the IRS&#8217; approach is &#8220;unfortunate&#8221; as it does not recognize that unhosted wallet providers lack knowledge about crypto transactions and the parties involved in each transaction.</p>
<p>Shehan Chandrasekera, Head of Tax at CoinTracker, similarly criticized the form. He <a href="https://twitter.com/TheCryptoCPA/status/1781403344172359826">argued</a> the effects could spill over to end users, who may need to engage in KYC verification when they create unhosted wallets or use unhosted wallets with services such as DeFi platforms.</p>
<p>However, Chandrasekera said that authorities will likely aim their enforcement efforts at unhosted wallet providers instead of end users.</p>
<p>Unhosted or non-custodial wallets do not store crypto balances with a third-party service. They are distinct from custodial wallets, a category that includes most exchange wallets.</p>
<h2>Form 1099-DA</h2>
<p>Form 1099-DA also asks brokers to provide certain on-chain data, including transaction IDs and wallet addresses related to each sale. Brokers should report the transaction ID and address originating the sold crypto — and a secondary address if they &#8220;transferred in&#8221; the funds from another of their hosted wallet addresses.</p>
<p>Experts responded to the requirement differently. Chandrasekera warned that collecting and reporting data, especially wallet addresses, &#8220;could lead to major privacy and security concerns.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, Ledgible&#8217;s VP of Tax Information Reporting, Jessalyn Dean, <a href="https://twitter.com/Ledgiblecrypto/status/1781325785543913583">noted</a> an exception to the rule. She said the form allows brokers not to provide addresses and transaction IDs if not applicable. She called the exception &#8220;necessary&#8221; because brokers often perform transactions in their internal recordkeeping systems rather than on-chain.</p>
<p>Another critical section reads, &#8220;Wash sale loss disallowed.&#8221; According to Dean, this does not bring crypto under wash sale rules. Instead, the section applies to digital assets currently subject to wash sale rules, such as stock, securities, and tokenized equities.</p>
<h2>Rules not yet finalized</h2>
<p>Crypto brokerage reporting rules have been in the making for some time. President Joe Biden&#8217;s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Infrastructure Act</a> in 2021 categorized certain crypto services as brokers in 2021. In August 2023, the Treasury and the IRS published a proposal for 1099-DA that largely resembles the contents of today&#8217;s draft form.</p>
<p>However, the draft form&#8217;s text indicates that the IRS has not finalized the form and that brokers should not use it in their current tax reports.</p>
<p>According to Ledgible, there is a 60-day comment period on the form.</p>
<p>The IRS has established separate rules for individual crypto investors. The regulator published a reminder on April 11 that crypto investors should report on various forms, including Form 1040. A top IRS member also <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/top-irs-member-says-pure-crypto-tax-crimes-on-the-rise-alongside-scams/">recently warned</a> of tax avoidance among crypto investors.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/irs-draft-tax-form-for-crypto-defines-unhosted-wallets-as-brokers/">IRS draft tax form for crypto defines unhosted wallets as brokers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/irs-draft-tax-form-for-crypto-defines-unhosted-wallets-as-brokers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/irs-crypto.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/irs-crypto.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Human Rights Foundation launches Finney Freedom Prize to reward contributions to Bitcoin for 110 years</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/human-rights-foundation-launces-finney-freedom-prize-to-reward-contributions-to-bitcoin-for-110-years/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/human-rights-foundation-launces-finney-freedom-prize-to-reward-contributions-to-bitcoin-for-110-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413724</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Human Rights Foundation (HRF) unveiled the Finney Freedom Prize on Bitcoin&#8217;s fourth halving day to celebrate the flagship crypto for enabling greater financial freedom for the world. The award is designed to honor significant global achievements in Bitcoin and human rights, reflecting Finney&#8217;s vision of using technology as a tool for liberation. The inaugural [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/human-rights-foundation-launces-finney-freedom-prize-to-reward-contributions-to-bitcoin-for-110-years/">Human Rights Foundation launches Finney Freedom Prize to reward contributions to Bitcoin for 110 years</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Human Rights Foundation (HRF) unveiled the Finney Freedom Prize on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> fourth <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-interest-higher-than-ever-with-under-12-hours-left-to-go/">halving day</a> to celebrate the flagship crypto for enabling greater financial freedom for the world.</p>
<p>The award is designed to honor significant global achievements in Bitcoin and human rights, reflecting Finney&#8217;s vision of using technology as a tool for liberation.</p>
<p>The inaugural Finney Freedom Prize was awarded posthumously to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/hal-finney/">Hal Finney</a>, recognizing his pioneering work during Bitcoin&#8217;s first halving era from 2009 to 2012. Finney&#8217;s widow, Fran Finney, who accepted the award on his behalf, chose to donate the prize to charity and said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We believe this prize will ensure Hal&#8217;s legacy endures, inspiring future generations to explore and expand the use of Bitcoin as a tool for achieving personal and collective freedom.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Finney, who succumbed to ALS in 2014, was a staunch advocate for civil liberties and a key figure in the early development of Bitcoin. He was the first person, after Bitcoin&#8217;s pseudonymous creator, Satoshi Nakamoto, to operate the software and partake in Bitcoin transactions.</p>
<h2>110-year legacy</h2>
<p>The Finney Freedom Prize will be distributed every four years on subsequent Bitcoin halving days, with a total of 28 awards slated over the next 110 years. The initiative is supported by a 33 BTC fund established by HRF.</p>
<p>Laureates will be recognized for their contributions to Bitcoin and human rights within specific halving periods and will receive a monetary prize of 1 Bitcoin (BTC) along with a physical award.</p>
<p>Nominations and selections for future laureates will be managed by the Genesis Committee, composed of notable figures in the Bitcoin community, including Farida Nabourema, Lisa Neigut, and Obi Nwosu, among others.</p>
<p>The committee will evaluate candidates based on their educational efforts about Bitcoin, contributions to its technology, promotion of decentralization, and efforts to enhance Bitcoin&#8217;s accessibility, particularly under oppressive regimes.</p>
<p>, with 1 BTC allocated for each award over the remaining halving events. Hal Finney&#8217;s Bitcoin will be donated to charity as directed by his widow, Fran Finney, who said:</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/human-rights-foundation-launces-finney-freedom-prize-to-reward-contributions-to-bitcoin-for-110-years/">Human Rights Foundation launches Finney Freedom Prize to reward contributions to Bitcoin for 110 years</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/human-rights-foundation-launces-finney-freedom-prize-to-reward-contributions-to-bitcoin-for-110-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-freedom.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-freedom.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chainalysis proposes $10 million Polkadot partnership to provide analytics solutions</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/chainalysis-proposes-10-million-polkadot-partnership-to-provide-analytics-solutions/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/chainalysis-proposes-10-million-polkadot-partnership-to-provide-analytics-solutions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 23:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chanalysis submitted a Polkadot governance proposal on April 18 that could lead to a $10 million partnership. The services provided by Chainalysis will include monitoring and tracing the DOT token activities on the Relay Chain, ensuring visibility of any potentially risky on-chain actions to regulators and institutional entities. This approach is aimed at maintaining a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chainalysis-proposes-10-million-polkadot-partnership-to-provide-analytics-solutions/">Chainalysis proposes $10 million Polkadot partnership to provide analytics solutions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/chainalysis/">Chanalysis</a> submitted a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/polkadot/">Polkadot</a> governance proposal on <a href="https://polkadot.subsquare.io/referenda/684">April 18</a> that could lead to a $10 million partnership.</p>
<p>The services provided by Chainalysis will include monitoring and tracing the DOT token activities on the Relay Chain, ensuring visibility of any potentially risky on-chain actions to regulators and institutional entities. This approach is aimed at maintaining a good standing with regulatory bodies and fostering a risk-aware environment.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Chainalysis will offer on-chain intelligence solutions to meet institutional requirements related to the listing of the DOT token, covering aspects such as investigations, compliance, and growth use cases.</p>
<p>The partnership would also include plans to engage in joint events, announcements, and case studies to promote the collaboration and highlight Chainalysis&#8217;s role in supporting Polkadot&#8217;s compliance framework.</p>
<p>The partnership would additionally offer on-chain intelligence to authorized institutional clients to support DOT token listings. The two companies would also collaborate in various areas to promote the compliance partnership.</p>
<h2>Little early support</h2>
<p>Chainalysis&#8217; proposal requests 1,000,000 of Polkadot&#8217;s DOT tokens or the equivalent value in US dollars (currently $6.82 million) for a three-year agreement. Chainalysis proposed the plan and will be the beneficiary if the plan succeeds.</p>
<p>So far, the proposal has received little support from members of the Pokadot community. A Polkadot ambassador with the handle Georgi_PS initially funded the proposal with a 400 DOT deposit. Since then, 11 voters have used 36,350 DOT to vote against the plan.</p>
<p>If the proposal succeeds, it could provide particular benefits. The proposal states that the Polkadot community aims to use Chainalysis software to improve market capitalization, market share, adoption, and popularity among institutions. It would also prevent fines and reputational damage resulting from regulatory issues.</p>
<p>Voting is scheduled to conclude by a May 16 deadline.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chainalysis-proposes-10-million-polkadot-partnership-to-provide-analytics-solutions/">Chainalysis proposes $10 million Polkadot partnership to provide analytics solutions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/chainalysis-proposes-10-million-polkadot-partnership-to-provide-analytics-solutions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/polkadot-dot-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/polkadot-dot-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
