<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:48:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Renzo&#8217;s ezETH token depeg triggers liquidations across DeFi platforms</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/renzos-ezeth-token-depeg-triggers-liquidations-across-defi-platforms/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/renzos-ezeth-token-depeg-triggers-liquidations-across-defi-platforms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[staked ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Renzo&#8217;s liquid restaking token (LRT), ezETH, experienced a significant depegging event that liquidated millions from &#8220;loopers&#8221; using the token as collateral on leverage protocols like Gearbox. According to data from CoinMarketCap, the digital asset&#8217;s value plunged to a low of $2,755 before recovering to its current level of $3,178 as of press time. Notably, decentralized [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/renzos-ezeth-token-depeg-triggers-liquidations-across-defi-platforms/">Renzo&#8217;s ezETH token depeg triggers liquidations across DeFi platforms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Renzo&#8217;s liquid restaking token (LRT), ezETH, experienced a significant depegging event that liquidated millions from &#8220;loopers&#8221; using the token as collateral on leverage protocols like Gearbox.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/renzo-restaked-eth/">data</a> from CoinMarketCap, the digital asset&#8217;s value plunged to a low of $2,755 before recovering to its current level of $3,178 as of press time.</p>
<p>Notably, decentralized exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/uniswap/">Uniswap</a> witnessed a more severe depegging of ezETH, with its value <a href="https://twitter.com/WazzCrypto/status/1782967316134662179">dropping</a> to as low as $700, attributed to liquidity challenges.</p>
<p>Renzo is a prominent liquid restaking protocol, with over $3 billion worth of assets locked on its platform, according to DeFillama <a href="https://defillama.com/protocol/renzo#information">data</a>.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">Liquidation galore</span></p>
<p>The DeFi protocol Gearbox confirmed that the depeg led to the liquidation of several Credit Accounts.</p>
<p>The protocol&#8217;s founder, 0xmikko, provided more insights into the situation, <a href="https://twitter.com/0xmikko_eth/status/1783032574882770986">saying</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;115 Credit Accounts were liquidated, 10,650 ezETH were sold on Balancer pool. Liquidation losses of 25.77 ETH were automatically covered by internal Gearbox reserve fund, no action needed.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Simultaneously, Cork Protocol, another DeFi platform, <a href="https://x.com/Corkprotocol/status/1783112148551377309">explained</a> that the liquidations caused a substantial sell-off of ezETH previously held as collateral. This flood of supply overwhelmed the market, driving the price of ezETH down to 0.2.</p>
<p>Interestingly, these liquidations occurred alongside the release of Renzo&#8217;s native REZ token, sparking the emergence of Renzo-related phishing scams on social platform X (formerly Twitter).</p>
<p>Web3 security firm Scam Sniffer <a href="https://x.com/realScamSniffer/status/1783128228787593383">identified</a> two instances where Renzo users cumulatively lost more than $500,000 to a malicious permit signature scam.</p>
<p>Amidst this market turmoil, trader czsamsunsb.eth capitalized on the situation, investing 4,099 <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">ETH</a> to acquire 4,221 ezETH. This move proved lucrative, as the trader earned a remarkable profit of 121.65 ETH, per Lookonchain&#8217;s <a href="https://x.com/lookonchain/status/1782997187829616684">findings</a>.</p>
<h2>What does this mean for LRTs?</h2>
<p>Crypto analyst Tommy <a href="https://twitter.com/0xtommy_eth/status/1783018222759055529">explained</a> that the depegging represents a significant risk across all LRTs, even with withdrawal options enabled. He noted that a depegging event in a decentralized exchange (DEX) pool could occur due to temporary imbalances.</p>
<p>Similarly, DeFi researcher Ignas <a href="https://twitter.com/DefiIgnas/status/1783083767449432189">warned</a> of potential exacerbation in LRT depegging, mainly if <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/eigenlayer-mainnet-launch-allows-restakers-to-delegate-stake-aims-to-extend-ethereum-security/">Eigenlayer</a>, the platform where these tokens operate, introduces two key upgrades of slashing and permissionless AVS.</p>
<p>Ignas explained that an AVS malfunction leading to slashing could reduce restaked ETH balances by a hypothetical 5%. While this might seem manageable for direct Eigenlayer stakers, it could trigger substantial disruption to LRT pegs due to liquidity concerns and subsequent panic-driven mass withdrawals.</p>
<p>He noted that while prices may stabilize post-slash, the interim period could witness harsh liquidations, and the risk of slashing grows as more AVSes come online.</p>
<p>Consequently, he added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;It&#8217;s all FUD right now as slashing won&#8217;t derail Eigenlayer but LRTs 1) with low liquidity 2) and are widely accepted as collateral can cause disproportional damage.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/renzos-ezeth-token-depeg-triggers-liquidations-across-defi-platforms/">Renzo&#8217;s ezETH token depeg triggers liquidations across DeFi platforms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/renzos-ezeth-token-depeg-triggers-liquidations-across-defi-platforms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ethereum-staking-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ethereum-staking-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 30 set for historic launch of Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs in Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/insights/april-30-set-for-historic-launch-of-bitcoin-and-ethereum-etfs-in-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Van Straten]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_insight&#038;p=414530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Quick Take In a significant development for the digital assets market, Hong Kong has officially approved the launch of exchange-traded funds (ETFs) for both Bitcoin and Ethereum. According to Eric Balchunas, a senior Bloomberg ETF analyst, these ETFs are set to commence trading on April 30, marking a significant milestone for the industry. As the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/april-30-set-for-historic-launch-of-bitcoin-and-ethereum-etfs-in-hong-kong/">April 30 set for historic launch of Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs in Hong Kong</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Quick Take</h2>
<p>In a significant development for the digital assets market, Hong Kong has officially approved the launch of exchange-traded funds (ETFs) for both Bitcoin and Ethereum. According to <a href="https://twitter.com/EricBalchunas/status/1783102626562760865">Eric Balchunas</a>, a senior Bloomberg ETF analyst, these ETFs are set to commence trading on April 30, marking a significant milestone for the industry.</p>
<figure style="width: 1013px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://slack-imgs.com/?c=1&amp;o1=ro&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fpbs.twimg.com%2Fmedia%2FGL5fHKYXcAAVGXQ.jpg%3Alarge" alt="Spot Bitcoin ETF: (Source: James Seyffart, Bloomberg)" width="1013" height="359" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Spot Bitcoin ETF: (Source: James Seyffart, Bloomberg)</figcaption></figure>
<p>As the news broke, <a href="https://x.com/JSeyff/status/1783088747854311583">James Seyffart</a>, another Bloomberg ETF analyst who has been closely following the ETF landscape in the United States, suggested that a potential fee war could emerge in Hong Kong, mirroring the competitive forces witnessed in the US market.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the ETF issuers in Hong Kong have set identical fees for their respective Bitcoin and Ethereum offerings. ChinaAMC has pegged its fees at 0.99%, while Harvest has opted for a unique approach, setting its management fee at 0% initially, with a 0.3% fee to be introduced after the first six months. Bosera, on the other hand, has settled on a management fee of 0.60%, according to data from Bloomberg Intelligence.</p>
<figure style="width: 952px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GL5fNaAXsAERvEy?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Spot Ethereum ETF: (Source: James Seyffart, Bloomberg)" width="952" height="359" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Spot Ethereum ETF: (Source: James Seyffart, Bloomberg)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Given the precedent set by the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/bitwise-head-of-alpha-strategies-explains-how-us-bitcoin-etfs-outperformed-expectations/">US fee war</a>, industry experts anticipate further developments in the pricing strategies of these ETF issuers.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/april-30-set-for-historic-launch-of-bitcoin-and-ethereum-etfs-in-hong-kong/">April 30 set for historic launch of Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs in Hong Kong</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-ethereum-hongkong-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-ethereum-hongkong-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin US ETFs inflows exceed new daily mining output on April 23</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-us-etfs-inflows-exceed-new-daily-mining-output-on-april-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Van Straten]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_insight&#038;p=414510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Quick Take Farside data shows that the Bitcoin (BTC) exchange-traded funds (ETFs) market saw a total inflow of $31.6 million on April 23. The market has experienced a surge in inflows over the past few days, with April 23 marking the third consecutive trading day of positive net inflows. BlackRock&#8217;s IBIT led the charge, which [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-us-etfs-inflows-exceed-new-daily-mining-output-on-april-23/">Bitcoin US ETFs inflows exceed new daily mining output on April 23</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Quick Take</h2>
<p><a href="https://farside.co.uk/?p=997">Farside</a> data shows that the Bitcoin (BTC) <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/blackrock-ibit-enters-elite-top-10-with-19-7-million-in-net-inflows-continuing-a-70-day-positive-run/">exchange-traded funds</a> (ETFs) market saw a total inflow of $31.6 million on April 23. The market has experienced a surge in inflows over the past few days, with April 23 marking the third consecutive trading day of positive net inflows.</p>
<p>BlackRock&#8217;s IBIT led the charge, which recorded a net inflow of $37.9 million, its highest since April 15. This brings IBIT&#8217;s total net inflow to an impressive $15,478.6 billion. Ark&#8217;s ARKB also saw a substantial inflow of $33.3 million, marking its most significant inflow since March 27 and pushing its total net inflow to $2,272.4 billion, according to data from Farside.</p>
<figure id="attachment_414511" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-414511" style="width: 764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-414511 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/btc-7.png" alt="BTC ETF Flow Table: (Source: Farside)" width="764" height="854" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/btc-7.png 764w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/btc-7-268x300.png 268w" sizes="(max-width: 764px) 100vw, 764px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-414511" class="wp-caption-text">BTC ETF Flow Table: (Source: Farside)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Farside data reports that five of the 11 Bitcoin ETFs on April 23 experienced inflows, with IBIT, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/fidelitys-bitcoin-etf-attracted-major-institutional-investors-in-q1/">FBTC</a>, BITB, ARKB, and EZBC leading the pack. However, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/new-grayscale-mini-trust-plans-to-offer-lowest-fees-in-bitcoin-etf-market-at-0-15/">Grayscale&#8217;s</a> GBTC continued to see outflows, with a $66.9 million outflow on April 23. Despite this, the fact that GBTC has seen four consecutive trading days of double-digit outflows is a promising sign that outflows are reducing. Since their launch, Bitcoin ETFs have collectively brought in $12,420.2 billion.</p>
<p>Data from <a href="https://heyapollo.com/bitcoin-etf">Heyapollo</a> shows that the daily Bitcoin flow into ETFs on April 23 was roughly 500 BTC, surpassing the total amount of Bitcoin mined on the same day, approximately 450 BTC.</p>
<figure id="attachment_414512" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-414512" style="width: 1527px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-414512 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apollo.png" alt="Net Bitcoin ETF Flows: (Source: Heyapollo)" width="1527" height="543" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apollo.png 1527w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apollo-300x107.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apollo-1024x364.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apollo-768x273.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1527px) 100vw, 1527px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-414512" class="wp-caption-text">Net Bitcoin ETF Flows: (Source: Heyapollo)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-us-etfs-inflows-exceed-new-daily-mining-output-on-april-23/">Bitcoin US ETFs inflows exceed new daily mining output on April 23</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-etf-flows.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-etf-flows.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria denies freezing over 300 P2P accounts on more crypto exchanges amid forex concerns</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/nigeria-freezes-over-300-accounts-on-more-crypto-exchanges-amid-forex-concerns/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/nigeria-freezes-over-300-accounts-on-more-crypto-exchanges-amid-forex-concerns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bybit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kucoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nigerian authorities are gearing up for the next phase of their crackdown on crypto trading, targeting peer-to-peer (P2P) platforms like OKX, Binance, KuCoin, and Bybit, according to a trending circular on social media platform X. Meanwhile, the Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) said the information contained in the circular did not originate from it, claiming [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nigeria-freezes-over-300-accounts-on-more-crypto-exchanges-amid-forex-concerns/">Nigeria denies freezing over 300 P2P accounts on more crypto exchanges amid forex concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nigerian authorities are gearing up for the next phase of their crackdown on crypto trading, targeting peer-to-peer (P2P) platforms like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/okx/">OKX</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kucoin/">KuCoin</a>, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bybit/">Bybit</a>, according to a trending circular on social media platform X.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) <a href="https://x.com/cenbank/status/1783081492018602076">said</a> the information contained in the circular did not originate from it, claiming it is &#8220;fake content.&#8221; People familiar with the matter stated that backtracking on unpopular policies was not uncommon in the region.</p>
<h2>The memo</h2>
<p>Per the trending circular, the CBN ordered financial institutions in the country to identify individuals or entities transacting with these exchanges and implement a six-month Post No Debit (PND) instruction on their accounts.</p>
<p>According to the bank, the mentioned platforms are not licensed to operate in Nigeria and are currently under investigation. It added that defaulters of this directive would be faced with severe regulatory sanctions.</p>
<p>The bank also warned that any trader &#8220;buying and selling <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tether/">USDT</a> illegally&#8221; would be arrested.</p>
<p>The CBN further reminded regulated financial entities in the country that they were barred from dealing in cryptocurrencies or facilitating payments for crypto exchanges.</p>
<p>Olumide Adesina, a business journalist, explained that <span class="css-1qaijid r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0 r-poiln3">the CBN&#8217;s official stance was that only entities regulated by the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nigeria-to-tighten-crypto-regulation-in-wake-of-binance-disputes/">Nigerian Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</a> in the crypto market could deal with </span><span class="css-1qaijid r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0 r-poiln3">banks.</span></p>
<h2>Over 300 P2P accounts frozen</h2>
<p>In a recent press briefing, Ola Olukayode, the chairman of the Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFFC), noted that transactions on P2P platforms like KuCoin were exacerbating the country&#8217;s foreign exchange challenges.</p>
<p>He said the anti-graft agency had frozen about 300 suspected illegal forex accounts trading on P2P platforms. Notably, over $15 billion passed through one of these platforms in the last year.</p>
<p>This development comes as the Nigerian government has adopted a stringent stance towards crypto to stabilize the foreign exchange market. Initially, the authorities attributed the Nigerian Naira&#8217;s weak value against the US Dollar to currency traders&#8217; <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-drops-nigerian-naira-from-p2p-platform-amid-forex-manipulation-concerns/">speculative activities</a> on the crypto exchange Binance.</p>
<p>The exchange has denied these allegations but is still facing trial, alongside two of its executives, for tax evasion and money laundering.</p>
<p>Binance said it is cooperating with the authorities and called for the release of its detained employees.</p>
<p><em>April 24 Update: Updated to include information from the Central Bank of Nigeria.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nigeria-freezes-over-300-accounts-on-more-crypto-exchanges-amid-forex-concerns/">Nigeria denies freezing over 300 P2P accounts on more crypto exchanges amid forex concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/nigeria-freezes-over-300-accounts-on-more-crypto-exchanges-amid-forex-concerns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/nigeria-p2p-crackdown.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/nigeria-p2p-crackdown.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US DOJ seeks 36-month sentence and $50 million fine for ex-Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/us-doj-seeks-36-month-sentence-and-50-million-fine-for-binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/us-doj-seeks-36-month-sentence-and-50-million-fine-for-binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 08:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Changpeng Zhao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giggle Academy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US Department of Justice has recommended a 36-month prison sentence alongside a $50 million fine for the former CEO of Binance, Changpeng Zhao. In response, Zhao&#8217;s legal team contends that his incarceration would be unprecedented, citing no prior instances of imprisonment in similar cases. Instead, they proposed an alternative of probation, potentially with home [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-doj-seeks-36-month-sentence-and-50-million-fine-for-binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao/">US DOJ seeks 36-month sentence and $50 million fine for ex-Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Department of Justice has recommended a 36-month prison sentence alongside a $50 million fine for the former CEO of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/changpeng-zhao/">Changpeng Zhao</a>.</p>
<p>In response, Zhao&#8217;s legal team contends that his incarceration would be unprecedented, citing no prior instances of imprisonment in similar cases. Instead, they proposed an alternative of probation, potentially with home confinement at his residence in Abu Dhabi.</p>
<p>Zhao is currently free on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-court-tightens-grip-on-changpeng-zhao-with-travel-and-passport-restrictions/">bail in the United States</a>, and his sentencing is <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-founder-changpeng-zhao-sentencing-rescheduled-for-april-30/">slated for April 30</a>.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">Why does the DOJ want 36 months for Zhao?</span></p>
<p>Zhao initially faced a potential 18-month prison term as per his plea deal. However, the DOJ contended in its April 23 filing that the extent of Zhao&#8217;s wrongdoing was significant, warranting a harsher penalty.</p>
<p>The authorities emphasized that Zhao and Binance deliberately targeted US users as part of their expansion strategy while disregarding local regulations. The prosecutors asserted that Zhao&#8217;s actions were intentional, driven by a calculated business decision to flout US laws in pursuit of growth and personal gain.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the DOJ highlighted Zhao&#8217;s negligence in implementing adequate anti-money laundering measures on the Binance platform, enabling illicit funds to flow unchecked.</p>
<p>DOJ argued:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;[Zhao] chose not to comply with fundamental U.S. anti-money-laundering (AML) requirements; he chose not to implement and maintain an effective know-your-customer (KYC) system, which prevented effective transaction monitoring and allowed suspicious and criminal users to transact through Binance.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Consequently, the DOJ argued that his sentencing should be used to send a message to the world and deter others from building &#8220;fortunes and business empires by breaking US laws.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;A three-year custodial sentence, together with the agreed $50 million fine, would achieve specific and general deterrence,&#8221; DOJ concluded.</p></blockquote>
<h2>Zhao&#8217;s response</h2>
<p>Zhao&#8217;s lawyers claimed the embattled founder &#8220;deeply regrets his offense, and he has shown exceptional acceptance of responsibility and remediation.&#8221;</p>
<p>The lawyers <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.328570/gov.uscourts.wawd.328570.81.0.pdf">noted</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;[Zhao] is a first-time, non-violent offender who committed an offense with no intention to harm anyone. He presents no risk of recidivism. He has appeared in this country voluntarily to accept responsibility.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Due to this, the legal team urged the court to sentence him to probation in line with precedent.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-doj-seeks-36-month-sentence-and-50-million-fine-for-binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao/">US DOJ seeks 36-month sentence and $50 million fine for ex-Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/us-doj-seeks-36-month-sentence-and-50-million-fine-for-binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/cz-binance-prison.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/cz-binance-prison.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Runes made up 57.7% of transactions on halving day</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-runes-made-up-57-percent-of-transactions-on-halving-day/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-runes-made-up-57-percent-of-transactions-on-halving-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 01:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin runes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[runes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Launched on the day of the Bitcoin halving, Runes are a form of data embedded directly into Bitcoin transactions. Unlike simple financial transfers, Runes encapsulate additional information within these transactions.  Bitcoin Runes operate by utilizing a method known as &#8220;transaction augmentation,&#8221; which allows users to embed arbitrary data into transaction outputs. Runes can store a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-runes-made-up-57-percent-of-transactions-on-halving-day/">Bitcoin Runes made up 57.7% of transactions on halving day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Launched on the day of the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> halving, Runes are a form of data embedded directly into Bitcoin transactions. Unlike simple financial transfers, Runes encapsulate additional information within these transactions. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Bitcoin Runes operate by utilizing a method known as &#8220;transaction augmentation,&#8221; which allows users to embed arbitrary data into transaction outputs. Runes can store a variety of data types, from simple messages to more complex contract-like scripts.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This mechanism is distinctly different from other Bitcoin-based innovations such as Ordinals and BRC-20 tokens. Ordinals inscribe data into individual satoshis, turning each into a discrete and uniquely identifiable unit of data. It makes Ordinals ideal for representing digital artifacts like images or texts on the Bitcoin blockchain.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> On the other hand, BRC-20 tokens are a token standard similar to Ethereum&#8217;s ERC-20, which is designed for issuing and managing tokens on Bitcoin&#8217;s sidechains — specifically the RSK Smart Contract Network.</span></p>
<p>The Runes protocol operates using a system known as Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). A UTXO represents a specific amount of Bitcoin that hasn&#8217;t been spent and can be used to fund new transactions. Runes are assigned to a UTXO via an OP_RETURN function, which allows data to be embedded in transactions without cluttering the network.</p>
<p>In a transaction, a Rune is linked to a UTXO through an OP_RETURN output that specifies the output location, a unique numerical ID for the Rune, and the amount of Rune being transacted. This setup also handles Rune characteristics such as divisibility and other metadata, all encoded within the same transaction. The transfer of Runes between parties uses Bitcoin&#8217;s secure framework to detail which Runes are moving from one UTXO to another.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The strategic launch of Runes on the day of the halving leveraged the attention the event got from the broader market. This timing was chosen to maximize visibility and impact, leveraging the increased attention during halving when miner rewards are reduced, and the future price of Bitcoin is hotly debated.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The immediate impact Runes had on the Bitcoin network was huge. Even though the market was expecting high fees and congestion around the halving, the impact Runes had seems to have been unexpected. </span></p>
<p>Although Runes were designed to minimize network clutter by using OP_RETURN outputs, which are provably unspendable and thus do not contribute directly to the growth of the UTXO set, they can still lead to network congestion due to their popularity and the volume of transactions they generate.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">On April 19, the day before the halving, most transactions on the Bitcoin network were regular financial transactions, accounting for 86.7% of the total transaction share. Ordinals and BRC-20 transactions accounted for 6.5% and 6.9% of the total share, respectively.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">On April 20, the day of the halving, Runes transactions accounted for 57.7% of all transactions on the Bitcoin network. Financial transactions accounted for a 41.5% share, while Ordinals and BRC-20 took up 0.5% and 0.2% of transactions, respectively. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Runes continued to dominate the network throughout the weekend, accounting for 51.6% of the total transactions on April 21. The dominance slightly decreased by April 22, dropping to 42.5%, with Bitcoin financial transactions accounting for 56.5% of the total transactions processed that day.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_414243" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-414243" style="width: 1764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-414243" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-transaction-share-by-type.png" alt="bitcoin transaction share by type" width="1764" height="1000" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-transaction-share-by-type.png 1764w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-transaction-share-by-type-300x170.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-transaction-share-by-type-1024x580.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-transaction-share-by-type-768x435.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-transaction-share-by-type-1536x871.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1764px) 100vw, 1764px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-414243" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the share of transactions on the Bitcoin network by type from Sep. 1, 2023, to April 23, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dune.com/cryptokoryo/runes">Dune Analytics</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The financial implications of Runes were equally significant, as evidenced by the allocation of transaction fees. On April 20, Runes accounted for 57.7% of the transactions paid on the Bitcoin network.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The share of fees from financial transactions dropped from 86.6% on April 19 to 38.7% on April 20. However, the share of fees from Runes decreased in the days since the halving, as they accounted for 34.5% of the fees on April 21 and 22.8% on April 22. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_414244" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-414244" style="width: 1764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-414244" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-fees-by-type-of-transaction.png" alt="bitcoin fees by type of transaction" width="1764" height="1000" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-fees-by-type-of-transaction.png 1764w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-fees-by-type-of-transaction-300x170.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-fees-by-type-of-transaction-1024x580.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-fees-by-type-of-transaction-768x435.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-fees-by-type-of-transaction-1536x871.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1764px) 100vw, 1764px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-414244" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the share of fees on the Bitcoin network by transaction type from Sep. 1, 2023, to April 23, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dune.com/cryptokoryo/runes">Dune Analytics</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">As of April 23, there have been 1.973 million Runes transactions.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_414242" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-414242" style="width: 1764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-414242" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/runes-number-of-transactions.png" alt="runes number of transactions" width="1764" height="688" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/runes-number-of-transactions.png 1764w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/runes-number-of-transactions-300x117.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/runes-number-of-transactions-1024x399.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/runes-number-of-transactions-768x300.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/runes-number-of-transactions-1536x599.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1764px) 100vw, 1764px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-414242" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the daily and cumulative number of Runes transactions from April 19 to April 23, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dune.com/cryptokoryo/runes">Dune Analytics</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">They generated 1,484 BTC in fees and reached a cumulative volume of 73,765 BTC. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_414241" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-414241" style="width: 1764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-414241" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes-cumulative-volume.png" alt="bitcoin runes cumulative volume" width="1764" height="896" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes-cumulative-volume.png 1764w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes-cumulative-volume-300x152.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes-cumulative-volume-1024x520.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes-cumulative-volume-768x390.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes-cumulative-volume-1536x780.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1764px) 100vw, 1764px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-414241" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the daily and cumulative volume for Bitcoin Runes from April 19 to April 23, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dune.com/cryptokoryo/runes">Dune Analytics</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Despite their bombastic launch, the immediate effects of Runes on the network have somewhat moderated in the days following the halving. The decline in the share of Runes in transactions and fees suggests that while the initial excitement was high, the ongoing integration of Runes into regular transaction patterns might see a more gradual growth.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The full consequences Runes will have on the Bitcoin network are yet to be understood. A significant part of the market has been celebrating the introduction of a new form of interaction with the Bitcoin blockchain. While some are focused on the speculative opportunities standards like Runes and Ordinals enable, others seem excited about the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ord-io-prepares-for-new-bitcoin-standard-with-2-million-funding-boost/">innovation and users</a> this could bring to the Bitcoin ecosystem.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">However, an even larger part of the market has been warning about the increased load on the network caused by Runes, which could lead to higher fees and slower transaction times. The main issue critics seem to have is the dilution of Bitcoin&#8217;s purity. An expensive, congested network affects not only Bitcoin&#8217;s utility as a means of payment but also as a store of value.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Nonetheless, there seems to be a chance the network adjusts to the existence of Runes and absorbs the pressure they create. A relatively similar discourse surrounded Ordinals upon their launch, and almost a year and a half later, the data shows their impact is minimal.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> While we might see more volatility in terms of fees in the coming weeks and months, it will take longer to see whether Runes become a foundational component of Bitcoin transactions or just a niche market within a larger ecosystem. </span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-runes-made-up-57-percent-of-transactions-on-halving-day/">Bitcoin Runes made up 57.7% of transactions on halving day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-runes-made-up-57-percent-of-transactions-on-halving-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-runes.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grayscale, BlackRock Ethereum ETF applications updated amid SEC delays</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-blackrock-ethereum-etf-applications-updated-amid-sec-delays/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-blackrock-ethereum-etf-applications-updated-amid-sec-delays/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Grayscale Investments and BlackRock have updated their spot Ethereum ETF applications despite the SEC delaying its decision on the matter in recent weeks and expectations leaning toward rejection. Grayscale filed an S-3 registration statement with the SEC on April 23. The submission marks the latest step toward the firm&#8217;s proposed conversion of its existing Grayscale Ethereum [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-blackrock-ethereum-etf-applications-updated-amid-sec-delays/">Grayscale, BlackRock Ethereum ETF applications updated amid SEC delays</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/grayscale-investments/">Grayscale Investments</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blackrock/">BlackRock</a> have updated their spot <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> ETF applications despite the SEC delaying its decision on the matter in recent weeks and expectations leaning toward rejection.</p>
<p>Grayscale filed an S-3 registration statement with the SEC on April 23. The submission marks the latest step toward the firm&#8217;s proposed conversion of its existing Grayscale Ethereum Trust to a spot exchange-traded fund (ETF).</p>
<p>Grayscale referred to the submission as &#8220;another key filing,&#8221;  along with NYSE Arca&#8217;s earlier Form 19b-4 filing.</p>
<p>Grayscale also filed an <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/2020455/000119312524106957/0001193125-24-106957-index.htm">S-1 registration statement</a> for a mini Ethereum ETF, a counterpart to its proposed <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/new-grayscale-mini-trust-plans-to-offer-lowest-fees-in-bitcoin-etf-market-at-0-15/">mini Bitcoin ETF</a>. The SEC has not yet approved either mini ETF.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Nasdaq amended BlackRock&#8217;s 19b-4 filing to include a proposed rule change through which the exchange intends to list and trade shares of BlackRock&#8217;s planned iShares Ethereum Trust.</p>
<p>The update proposes cash-based creation and redemptions instead of in-kind creations and redemptions. This aligns the proposed fund with competing Ethereum ETF applications and previously approved spot Bitcoin ETFs.</p>
<h2>Decision due in May</h2>
<p>The SEC has punted the deadlines on several Ethereum ETFs in recent weeks and is expected to decide on the applications simultaneously in May.</p>
<p>Expectations around Ethereum ETF approvals are at an all-time low. Bloomberg ETF analyst Eric Balchunas, who initially said the odds of approval stood at 70% earlier in the year, updated his prediction to &#8220;<a href="https://twitter.com/EricBalchunas/status/1772372601098162624">a very pessimistic 25%</a>&#8221; chance of approval.</p>
<p>Polymarket reports an 11% chance that the SEC will approve an Ethereum ETF by May 31, represented as betting odds.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-blackrock-ethereum-etf-applications-updated-amid-sec-delays/">Grayscale, BlackRock Ethereum ETF applications updated amid SEC delays</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-blackrock-ethereum-etf-applications-updated-amid-sec-delays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ethereum-etf.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ethereum-etf.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jane Street Capital now holds over 5% of Coinbase stock</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/jane-street-capital-now-holds-over-5-of-coinbase-stock/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/jane-street-capital-now-holds-over-5-of-coinbase-stock/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 23:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jane Street Capital has accumulated substantial Coinbase stock. According to financial intelligence site Fintel, Jane Street owned 5.3% of Coinbase&#8217;s outstanding shares in February. COIN was valued at $140.86 at the time of the company&#8217;s 13G filing on Feb. 9, placing the value of its holdings at $1.4 billion. At a current share price of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jane-street-capital-now-holds-over-5-of-coinbase-stock/">Jane Street Capital now holds over 5% of Coinbase stock</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jane Street Capital has accumulated substantial <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> stock.</p>
<p>According to financial intelligence site <a href="https://fintel.io/so/us/coin">Fintel</a>, Jane Street owned 5.3% of Coinbase&#8217;s outstanding shares in February.</p>
<p>COIN was valued at $140.86 at the time of the company&#8217;s 13G filing on Feb. 9, placing the value of its holdings at $1.4 billion.</p>
<p>At a current share price of $236.40, the same shares are worth approximately $2.4 billion, though it is unclear whether Jane Street&#8217;s holdings have changed since February.</p>
<p>Jane Street&#8217;s current holdings represent an increase from previous months. Yahoo! Finance <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/COIN/holders">indicates</a> that Jane Street held just 1.92% of outstanding shares in December, valued at $888 million.</p>
<h2>Jane Street among largest investors</h2>
<p>Jane Street is now among the largest investors in Coinbase&#8217;s public stock.</p>
<p>Vanguard Group notably exceeds Jane Street&#8217;s holdings. According to Fintel, Vanguard held 7.44% of outstanding Coinbase shares in February.</p>
<p>Yahoo! Finance data indicates that other companies have invested significantly in Coinbase. One top investor is the world&#8217;s largest asset manager, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blackrock/">BlackRock</a>, which held 4.36% of outstanding Coinbase shares in December.</p>
<p>Nikko Asset Management Americas held 2.64% of outstanding Coinbase shares, while the crypto-focused VC firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/paradigm/">Paradigm</a> held 2.31% of outstanding shares. Cathie Wood&#8217;s investment management firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ark-invest/">Ark Invest</a>, meanwhile, held 2.26% of outstanding shares as of the end of the first quarter.</p>
<h2>Wall Street leans in on crypto</h2>
<p>Jane Street Capital is a major trading firm and one of the largest market makers. As such, it is highly notable that the firm has invested in Coinbase, which has become one of the highest-cap publicly traded crypto companies since going public in April 2021.</p>
<p>However, Coinbase is just one option for institutional investors seeking exposure to the crypto sector now that the SEC has approved spot Bitcoin ETFs.</p>
<p>Various companies&#8217; recent 13F filings show that institutional investors are becoming interested in spot Bitcoin ETFs from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/financial-advisors-start-disclosing-bitcoin-exposure-via-etfs/">BlackRock, Fidelity</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/fidelitys-bitcoin-etf-attracted-major-institutional-investors-in-q1/">Grayscale</a>.</p>
<p>Spot Bitcoin ETFs have accumulated a market capitalization of more than $58 billion in less than four months of trading, with BlackRock&#8217;s IBIT notable recording inflows for 70 consecutive trading days — making it one of the best performing ETF launches in history.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jane-street-capital-now-holds-over-5-of-coinbase-stock/">Jane Street Capital now holds over 5% of Coinbase stock</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/jane-street-capital-now-holds-over-5-of-coinbase-stock/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/coinbase-premium.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/coinbase-premium.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jack Dorsey’s Block completes Bitcoin mining chip, announces development of full system</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/jack-dorseys-block-completes-bitcoin-mining-chip-announce-development-of-full-system/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/jack-dorseys-block-completes-bitcoin-mining-chip-announce-development-of-full-system/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 22:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jack Dorsey&#8217;s firm Block has unveiled a significant advancement in Bitcoin (BTC) mining technology with the completion of its three-nanometer (3nm) mining chip. The company is now finalizing a full tape out of the chip at a leading global semiconductor foundry, marking a substantial upgrade from its earlier five-nanometer prototype. The new chip targets improved [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jack-dorseys-block-completes-bitcoin-mining-chip-announce-development-of-full-system/">Jack Dorsey’s Block completes Bitcoin mining chip, announces development of full system</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/jack-dorsey/">Jack Dorsey&#8217;s</a> firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/block/">Block</a> has unveiled a significant advancement in Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/?s=Bitcoin">BTC</a>) mining technology with the completion of its three-nanometer (3nm) mining chip.</p>
<p>The company is now finalizing a full tape out of the chip at a leading global semiconductor foundry, marking a substantial upgrade from its earlier five-nanometer prototype.</p>
<p>The new chip targets improved efficiency and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/decentralized-mining-pool-ocean-by-jack-dorsey-joins-bitcoin-hash-rate-surge/">decentralization in Bitcoin mining</a>, aligning with industry needs as it transitions into the fifth mining epoch after the recent fourth halving of the block subsidy.</p>
<p>Drawing on the success of the tested 5nm chip prototype — which met all design expectations and yielded vital data — Block has optimized the 3nm chip to enhance performance and support mining operators in a fiercely competitive market.</p>
<p>According to the firm, these insights played a crucial role in developing the 3nm chip, which enhances mining hardware performance and enables miners to remain competitive in a challenging market.</p>
<h2>Fully mining system</h2>
<p>Beyond the standalone mining chip, Block is also pioneering a complete mining system. The system capitalizes on the company&#8217;s expertise in product and software development, system engineering, robust supply chain management, and comprehensive customer support. It aims to introduce innovations and improvements in mining hardware form factors and use cases.</p>
<p>The firm plans to leverage this integrated approach to spur innovation in mining hardware configurations and functional applications, thus meeting a broader range of miner needs.</p>
<p>Block said it has been <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jack-dorseys-payments-company-block-seeks-input-on-mining-kit/">engaging directly</a> with the Bitcoin mining community to pinpoint challenges and areas for improvement across several aspects of mining operations, including pre-sales discovery, purchasing processes, hardware reliability, maintenance, software features, transparency, and post-sales support.</p>
<p>The company has invited the mining community to continue offering feedback to further refine and enhance its products. Those interested can share their experiences and suggestions via the designated contact email as Block continues to update and expand its mining hardware solutions.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jack-dorseys-block-completes-bitcoin-mining-chip-announce-development-of-full-system/">Jack Dorsey’s Block completes Bitcoin mining chip, announces development of full system</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/jack-dorseys-block-completes-bitcoin-mining-chip-announce-development-of-full-system/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/crypto-mining.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/crypto-mining.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEC seeking $5.3 billion in fines from Terraform Labs, Do Kwon</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-seeking-5-3-billion-in-fines-from-terraform-labs-do-kwon/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-seeking-5-3-billion-in-fines-from-terraform-labs-do-kwon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 21:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=414332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) wants nearly $5.3 billion in fines from Terraform Labs and its former CEO, Do Kwon for violations of the US securities laws and charges of fraud. The agency detailed its requested fines in an April 19 legal filing. The SEC is primarily seeking $4.2 billion in disgorgement plus $545.7 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-seeking-5-3-billion-in-fines-from-terraform-labs-do-kwon/">SEC seeking $5.3 billion in fines from Terraform Labs, Do Kwon</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) wants nearly $5.3 billion in fines from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/terraform-labs/">Terraform Labs</a> and its former CEO, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/do-kwon/">Do Kwon</a> for violations of the US securities laws and charges of fraud.</p>
<p>The agency detailed its requested fines in an <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysd.594150/gov.uscourts.nysd.594150.232.0.pdf">April 19</a> legal filing. The SEC is primarily seeking $4.2 billion in disgorgement plus $545.7 million in prejudgment interest.</p>
<p>The disgorgement aims to have Terraform Labs and Kwon surrender &#8220;unjust enrichment&#8221; earned from token sales to institutional investors, sales via a Luna Foundation Guard contract with Genesis Asia Pacific, and sales on crypto exchanges between June 2021 and May 2022.</p>
<p>The regulator is also seeking civil penalties, including a $420 million fine against Terraform Labs and a $100 million fine against Kwon.</p>
<p>The SEC said each civil penalty is a small fraction of the defendants&#8217; ill-gotten gains but acts as punishment and deterrence.</p>
<h2>Additional restrictions</h2>
<p>The SEC also requested nonmonetary remedies, including &#8220;obey-the-law&#8221; injunctions preventing violations of the Securities Act of 1933 and Exchange Act of 1934.</p>
<p>Additionally, the watchdog intends to impose conduct-based injunctions preventing the defendants from engaging in the purchase, offer, or sale of crypto asset securities, including but not limited to Terra-related tokens such as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/terrausd/">UST</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/mirror-protocol/">MIR</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/terra/">LUNA</a>, wLUNA, and LUNA 2.0.</p>
<p>It also aims to prevent the defendants from &#8220;inducing&#8221; others into such transactions.</p>
<p>Furthermore, it aims to prevent Terraform Labs from discharging its monetary remedies through bankruptcy. The firm filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/terraform-labs-filed-for-bankruptcy-to-protect-against-potential-sec-money-judgment/">January</a>.</p>
<p>The agency also intends to permanently bar Kwon from serving as an officer or director of a publicly held company and compel him to provide a sworn accounting.</p>
<h2>Terraform and Kwon respond</h2>
<p>The defendants responded to the expected remedies in related filings.</p>
<p>First, Terraform Labs&#8217; legal team said that the court must impose remedies based only on token sales proven to have occurred in the US. It asserted that most conduct and sales happened outside the US and that court proceedings have not yet addressed this matter.</p>
<p>Terraform&#8217;s legal team also asserted that the SEC is not entitled to disgorgement because of a lack of pecuniary harm or &#8220;out-of-pocket loss.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kwon and his legal representation also argued a lack of pecuniary harm and denied there is evidence that Kwon received ill-gotten gains separately from Terraform Labs. The relevant filing reads:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There are no illegal profits for Mr. Kwon to disgorge.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Both parties asserted that maximum civil penalties should be lower than the SEC&#8217;s requested amounts. In one estimate, Terraform Labs&#8217; defense suggested a maximum civil penalty of $3.5 million, while Kwon&#8217;s defense suggested a civil penalty below $1 million.</p>
<p>Both parties also argued that injunctions are unwarranted and suggested that further offenses are unlikely based on current circumstances.</p>
<p>The SEC initially filed charges against Terraform Labs and Do Kwon in February 2023. The trial began in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-begins-multi-billion-dollar-fraud-trial-against-terraform-labs-do-kwon/">March</a>, and the court found both parties liable for fraud in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jury-finds-do-kwon-terraform-labs-liable-for-multi-billion-dollar-fraud/">April</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-seeking-5-3-billion-in-fines-from-terraform-labs-do-kwon/">SEC seeking $5.3 billion in fines from Terraform Labs, Do Kwon</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-seeking-5-3-billion-in-fines-from-terraform-labs-do-kwon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/do-kwon-terra-labs.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/do-kwon-terra-labs.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
