<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 01:57:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>SEC claims Justin Sun&#8217;s alleged visits to US grant it personal jurisdiction to pursue legal action</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-claims-justin-suns-alleged-visits-to-us-grant-it-personal-jurisdiction-to-pursue-legal-action/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-claims-justin-suns-alleged-visits-to-us-grant-it-personal-jurisdiction-to-pursue-legal-action/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 01:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US SEC filed an amended complaint in its case against Justin Sun and other defendants on April 18, arguing that Justin Sun&#8217;s alleged visits to the US should grant it the jurisdiction required to pursue legal action. The regulator alleged that Sun &#8220;traveled extensively&#8221; to the US while he and several companies carried out [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-claims-justin-suns-alleged-visits-to-us-grant-it-personal-jurisdiction-to-pursue-legal-action/">SEC claims Justin Sun&#8217;s alleged visits to US grant it personal jurisdiction to pursue legal action</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US SEC filed an amended complaint in its case against <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/justin-sun/">Justin Sun</a> and other defendants on <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysd.596044/gov.uscourts.nysd.596044.59.0.pdf">April 18</a>, arguing that Justin Sun&#8217;s alleged visits to the US should grant it the jurisdiction required to pursue legal action.</p>
<p>The regulator alleged that Sun &#8220;traveled extensively&#8221; to the US while he and several companies carried out unregistered offers and sales of BTT and TRX tokens.</p>
<p>According to the watchdog, Sun spent over 380 days in the US between 2017 and 2019 and made business trips to major cities, including New York City, Boston, Massachusetts, and San Francisco. He carried out the trips on behalf of the Tron Foundation and the BitTorrent Foundation  — both of which are also named as defendants in the case.</p>
<p>The SEC wants to use these trips to claim jurisdiction over Sun and the companies to pursue regulatory and legal action in the US.</p>
<h2>Wash trading</h2>
<p>The SEC alleged that Sun and the companies engaged in a wash trading scheme on the now-defunct crypto exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bittrex/">Bittrex</a>.</p>
<p>Though the original complaint identified many of the same wash trading activities, it identified the exchange on which wash trading took place only as an unnamed &#8220;trading platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>The agency included the fact that Bittrex is based in the US alongside its other claims to personal jurisdiction over Sun and the other defendants.</p>
<p>The amended complaint also alleges that Sun personally communicated with and provided documents to Bittrex circa 2018 to have the exchange list the TRX crypto. The documents link Sun to the other companies, and Sun personally signed some documents.</p>
<h2>Countering the request for dismissal</h2>
<p>The latest allegations address the concerns raised by Sun in his request to dismiss the SEC case in March due to a lack of personal jurisdiction. Defense lawyers argued that Sun is a foreign national and not &#8220;at home&#8221; in the US and advanced similar arguments for the companies.</p>
<p>The request for dismissal also identified the supposed improper distributions on Bittrex but said that &#8220;there is no allegation that any US resident purchased or attempted to purchase TRX on this unidentified platform, or that the effort to list TRX succeeded.&#8221;</p>
<p>The SEC sued Sun and the other defendants in March 2023. At the time, it primarily based personal jurisdiction claims around the allegation that sales focused on investors in the Southern District of New York and the allegation that celebrity promoters contacted individuals in the US via social media.</p>
<p>The SEC separately sued Bittrex in April 2023 and settled the case in August 2023. The company halted operations globally in late 2023.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-claims-justin-suns-alleged-visits-to-us-grant-it-personal-jurisdiction-to-pursue-legal-action/">SEC claims Justin Sun&#8217;s alleged visits to US grant it personal jurisdiction to pursue legal action</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-claims-justin-suns-alleged-visits-to-us-grant-it-personal-jurisdiction-to-pursue-legal-action/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/justin-sun-sec.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/justin-sun-sec.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IMF says Bitcoin has become necessary financial tool for preserving wealth amid financial instability</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/imf-acknowledges-bitcoins-significant-role-in-preserving-wealth-amid-financial-instability/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/imf-acknowledges-bitcoins-significant-role-in-preserving-wealth-amid-financial-instability/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin (BTC) is increasingly serving as a critical channel for cross-border financial flows amid global financial instability, according to a new report by the International Monetary Fund (IMF). The report — called &#8220;A Primer on Bitcoin Cross-Border Flows&#8221; — sheds light on how the decentralized nature of Bitcoin is being leveraged to bypass traditional banking [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/imf-acknowledges-bitcoins-significant-role-in-preserving-wealth-amid-financial-instability/">IMF says Bitcoin has become necessary financial tool for preserving wealth amid financial instability</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/?s=Bitcoin">BTC</a>) is increasingly serving as a critical channel for cross-border financial flows amid global financial instability, according to a new report by the International Monetary Fund (IMF).</p>
<p>The report — called &#8220;A Primer on Bitcoin Cross-Border Flows&#8221; — sheds light on how the decentralized nature of Bitcoin is being leveraged to bypass traditional banking systems, especially in regions experiencing economic distress or strict capital controls.</p>
<h2>Necessary financial tool</h2>
<p>According to the IMF, residents of countries with restrictive financial regulations are turning to Bitcoin to move capital across borders more freely.</p>
<p>The report highlighted significant transaction volumes originating from countries like Argentina and Venezuela, where citizens face hyperinflation and stringent financial controls.</p>
<p>In these regions, Bitcoin has become a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/imf-warns-banning-crypto-may-not-be-an-effective-long-term-strategy/">necessary financial tool</a> for preserving wealth and accessing global markets rather than just a speculative investment.</p>
<p>One of the report&#8217;s authors, Eugenio Cerutti, wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Bitcoin transactions provide a way for individuals in high-inflation countries to stabilize their savings and participate in global commerce on terms that aren&#8217;t possible through their local currencies.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>However, the IMF report also cautioned against the potential risks associated with the widespread use of Bitcoin for cross-border flows.</p>
<p>The lack of oversight and the anonymity provided by cryptocurrencies can complicate the efforts of regulators to monitor and control financial transactions to prevent illicit activities such as money laundering.</p>
<h2>On-chain volume</h2>
<p>The study reviewed both on-chain and off-chain transaction data to explore the trends behind Bitcoin&#8217;s use across borders. It found that Bitcoin transactions are not only substantial in volume but also exhibit unique characteristics compared to traditional capital flows.</p>
<p>Unlike typical foreign investments that are sensitive to economic indicators like currency strength, Bitcoin flows show a higher correlation with cryptocurrency-specific sentiments, such as market volatility and user sentiment indexes — like the Fear and Greed Index.</p>
<p>The analysis also pointed out that on-chain Bitcoin transactions, which are recorded on the blockchain and offer more security, tend to be larger than off-chain transactions. This indicates that the robust security features of blockchain technology often protect larger financial stakes.</p>
<p>The IMF called for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/imf-paper-proposes-risk-assessment-framework-for-integrating-crypto-into-financial-system/">international cooperation and regulatory frameworks</a> that encompass the unique aspects of digital assets. Such measures would help mitigate the risks while harnessing the benefits of digital currencies, especially as tools for economic freedom in countries with restrictive financial environments.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/imf-acknowledges-bitcoins-significant-role-in-preserving-wealth-amid-financial-instability/">IMF says Bitcoin has become necessary financial tool for preserving wealth amid financial instability</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/imf-acknowledges-bitcoins-significant-role-in-preserving-wealth-amid-financial-instability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-digital-gold.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-digital-gold.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meta announces Llama 3, launches dedicated AI web portal</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/meta-announces-llama-3-launches-dedicated-ai-web-portal/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/meta-announces-llama-3-launches-dedicated-ai-web-portal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 23:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Meta announced the launch of Llama 3, the latest version of its large language model (LLM), on April 18, describing it as a &#8220;major leap over Llama 2.&#8221; The company said it has initially released the first two models of the current version, featuring 8B and 70B parameters, with upcoming models slated to feature 400B [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/meta-announces-llama-3-launches-dedicated-ai-web-portal/">Meta announces Llama 3, launches dedicated AI web portal</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta announced the launch of Llama 3, the latest version of its large language model (LLM), on <a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/meta-llama-3/">April 18</a>, describing it as a &#8220;major leap over Llama 2.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company said it has initially released the first two models of the current version, featuring 8B and 70B parameters, with upcoming models slated to feature 400B parameters.</p>
<p>Meta emphasized Llama 3  was trained with a &#8220;large, high-quality training dataset&#8221; featuring over 15 trillion tokens, 7x larger than Llama 2 and featuring 4x more code. Llama 3 also features filtering techniques, including NSFW filters, to ensure data quality.</p>
<p>LLama 3 outperforms Llama 2 and competing models such as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/anthropic/">Anthropic&#8217;s</a> Claude Sonnet, Mistral Medium, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/openai/">OpenAI&#8217;s</a> Chat GPT-3.5 more than half the time across 12 use cases.</p>
<p>The first releases of Llama 3 are text-based models. However, future releases will be multilingual and multimodal. They will also feature longer context and demonstrate better performance in reasoning and coding, which Meta described as &#8220;core LLM capabilities.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company plans to deploy Llama 3 on all major cloud providers, model API providers, and other services. It plans to launch the product &#8220;everywhere.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Broader user access</h2>
<p>Llama 3 is aimed at developers, but Meta has <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2024/04/meta-ai-assistant-built-with-llama-3/">also launched</a> new ways for end users to access AI services in the US and more than 12 other countries.</p>
<p>One new addition is a dedicated website called Meta AI, where users can access AI-powered writing assistance, trivia games, simulated job interviews, and homework help.</p>
<p>Meta has also integrated Meta AI with all its products, including Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp, and Messenger. Furthermore, the company offers the service via Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses in the US and plans to extend it to its Meta Quest VR headset.</p>
<p>In an announcement, CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/mark-zuckerberg/">Mark Zuckerberg</a> said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We believe that Meta AI is now the most intelligent AI assistant that you can freely use.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>News of Meta&#8217;s expanded AI products comes shortly after upgrades to competing services. ChatGPT upgraded to GPT-4 Turbo on April 11, while <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/microsoft/">Microsoft</a> Copilot upgraded to GPT-4 Turbo starting in March, advancing the race between consumer-oriented AI services.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/meta-announces-llama-3-launches-dedicated-ai-web-portal/">Meta announces Llama 3, launches dedicated AI web portal</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/meta-announces-llama-3-launches-dedicated-ai-web-portal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/meta-llama.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/meta-llama.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scaramucci says Bitcoin is &#8216;still very young,&#8217; predicts $200k long-term price after halving</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/scaramucci-says-bitcoin-is-still-very-young-predicts-200k-long-term-price-after-halving/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/scaramucci-says-bitcoin-is-still-very-young-predicts-200k-long-term-price-after-halving/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 21:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SkyBridge Capital founder Anthony Scaramucci said that Bitcoin is &#8220;still very young&#8221; in terms of adoption and predicted significant long-term growth despite its current volatility and recent price fluctuations influenced by global events. In an interview focused on the flagship crypto&#8217;s trajectory, Scaramucci highlighted that Bitcoin is still early in its adoption curve, likening its [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/scaramucci-says-bitcoin-is-still-very-young-predicts-200k-long-term-price-after-halving/">Scaramucci says Bitcoin is &#8216;still very young,&#8217; predicts $200k long-term price after halving</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/skybridge-capital-management/">SkyBridge Capital</a> founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/anthony-scaramucci/">Anthony Scaramucci</a> said that <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/?s=Bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> is &#8220;still very young&#8221; in terms of adoption and predicted significant long-term growth despite its current volatility and recent price fluctuations influenced by global events.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/video/2024/04/18/bitcoin-is-still-very-young-in-terms-of-adoption-says-skybridge-capitals-anthony-scaramucci.html">interview</a> focused on the flagship crypto&#8217;s trajectory, Scaramucci highlighted that Bitcoin is still early in its adoption curve, likening its current stage to the early days of the internet around 1999.</p>
<p>Scaramucci also predicted that Bitcoin will <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/skybridge-founder-scaramucci-says-bitcoin-still-heading-to-500000/">surpass</a> the market capitalization of gold in the coming years as it matures as an asset class and the regulatory landscape becomes more accepting.</p>
<h2>Adoption curve</h2>
<p>He emphasized that Bitcoin might not stabilize as a reliable inflation hedge or store of value until it surpasses a billion users, which suggests continued volatility in the near term.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Bitcoin is on an adoption curve. If you go back to Web 1, Bitcoin is sort of at the 1999 point in the spectrum, so just imagine where we went from Web 1 to where we are today.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Scaramucci&#8217;s remarks come at a time when Bitcoin has shown resilience despite geopolitical tensions and market uncertainties, such as the recent conflict involving Iran and Israel.</p>
<p>He acknowledges that events like these could temporarily impact Bitcoin&#8217;s value, possibly leading to a 10% to 15% fall in value in the short term. However, he remains <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/record-breaking-bitcoin-price-surge-on-horizon-as-otc-desks-dry-up-10x-research-predicts/">optimistic about its future</a>, especially with <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/financial-advisors-start-disclosing-bitcoin-exposure-via-etfs/">institutional interests</a> such as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blackrock-and-fidelitys-bitcoin-etfs-make-history-with-record-streak-of-inflows/">spot Bitcoin ETFs</a> and potential involvement from wirehouses and the 401k market.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin to $200k</h2>
<p>Scaramucci predicted that Bitcoin&#8217;s value could surge 3x to 4x in the months after the halving based on its historical performance over the past 15 years. He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Long term, with the halving coming this week, I think this thing trades to 170k, possibly to $200,000.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Scaramucci also compared Bitcoin&#8217;s investment profile to that of early-stage Amazon, noting the extreme volatility and substantial gains it experienced over the long term. He suggested that Bitcoin could similarly reward long-term investors who are willing to endure the price swings.</p>
<p>He added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;In a rolling four-year period, no one has ever lost money in Bitcoin.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Furthermore, Scaramucci touched upon the growing influence of ETFs in Bitcoin ownership and price discovery. He dismissed concerns about the centralization of Bitcoin ownership through ETFs, arguing that the market is still largely decentralized and that ETFs serve as a vital bridge to traditional investors.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/scaramucci-says-bitcoin-is-still-very-young-predicts-200k-long-term-price-after-halving/">Scaramucci says Bitcoin is &#8216;still very young,&#8217; predicts $200k long-term price after halving</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/scaramucci-says-bitcoin-is-still-very-young-predicts-200k-long-term-price-after-halving/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Anthony-Scaramucci.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Anthony-Scaramucci.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US lawmakers&#8217; proposed ban on algorithmic stablecoins draws industry backlash</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/us-lawmakers-proposed-ban-on-algorithmic-stablecoins-draws-industry-backlash/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/us-lawmakers-proposed-ban-on-algorithmic-stablecoins-draws-industry-backlash/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 21:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A recent legislative bill introduced by US Senators Cynthia Lummis and Kirsten Gillibrand has drawn the crypto industry&#8217;s ire due to a proposed ban on algorithmic stablecoins. Former Blockchain Association member Jake Chervinsky called the Lummis-Gillibrand Payment Stablecoin Act &#8220;deeply flawed&#8221; on April 17. He warned that the bill would only permit centralized and custodial [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-lawmakers-proposed-ban-on-algorithmic-stablecoins-draws-industry-backlash/">US lawmakers&#8217; proposed ban on algorithmic stablecoins draws industry backlash</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent legislative bill introduced by US Senators Cynthia Lummis and Kirsten Gillibrand has drawn the crypto industry&#8217;s ire due to a proposed ban on algorithmic stablecoins.</p>
<p>Former Blockchain Association member Jake Chervinsky called the Lummis-Gillibrand Payment Stablecoin Act &#8220;deeply flawed&#8221; on April 17. He <a href="https://twitter.com/jchervinsky/status/1780636220575334418">warned that</a> the bill would only permit centralized and custodial stablecoins.</p>
<p>Chervinsky added that the proposed ban violates principles outlined in his testimony to Congress in 2023. He said in his testimony that legislators should focus on regulating custodial stablecoins and avoid regulating algorithmic stablecoins until further study.</p>
<p>Aaron Day, Chairman and CEO of the Daylight Freedom Foundation and a Brownstone Institute fellow, <a href="https://twitter.com/AaronRDay/status/1780939420058652724">also opposed</a> the proposed ban on algorithmic stablecoins and asserted the bill<span class="css-1qaijid r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0 r-poiln3"> would </span><span class="css-1qaijid r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0 r-poiln3">benefit banks</span> rather than crypto. He argued that banks&#8217; involvement in stablecoins &#8220;sets the stage&#8221; for central bank digital currencies (CBDCs).</p>
<p>However, the Federal Reserve has repeatedly said it has no intention to issue a CBDC due to the Fed Now system.</p>
<h2>Shift from</h2>
<p>FOX Business reporter Eleanor Terrett said the Lummis-Gillibrand bill initially did not include such <a href="https://twitter.com/EleanorTerrett/status/1780979994438553664">harsh restrictions</a>, based on her sources in Washington, DC.</p>
<p>Terret said lawmakers aimed to reach &#8220;moderate positions on &#8230; contentious issues,&#8221; including but not limited to the bill&#8217;s proposed restrictions on algorithmic stablecoins.</p>
<p>Her sources did not reveal why lawmakers shifted their initial perspective but said that all affected parties are &#8220;not particularly excited about the bill&#8221; in its current state despite its nominally bipartisan support.</p>
<p>The sources added that the bill is mainly a sign of growing pressure for stablecoin regulation in the Senate and an indirect attempt to have lawmakers engage in a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/stablecoin-regulation-more-likely-this-year-following-key-discussions-among-lawmakers/">separate stablecoin bill</a> led by House Financial Services Committee chair <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/patrick-mchenry/">Patrick McHenry</a>.</p>
<h2>Bill bans unbacked stablecoins.</h2>
<p>One section of the Lummis-Gillibrand Payment Stablecoin Act, as introduced on April 17, explicitly prohibits unbacked algorithmic stablecoins.</p>
<p>The bill and its backing members do not describe any incident to justify the proposed ban. However, the collapse of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/terraform-labs/">Terraform Labs&#8217;</a> algorithmic stablecoin TerraUSD in May 2022 has likely played a role in the lawmakers&#8217; decision to include the prohibition in the legislation.</p>
<p>The collapse — which wiped $80 billion in value from the crypto market in May 2022 — has raised concerns about algorithmic approaches to valuation — even as other competing algorithmic stablecoins such as Ampleforth (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/usdd/">USDD</a>), Frax (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/frax/">FRAX</a>), and Ampleforth (AMPL) continue to circulate close to the value of the US dollar.</p>
<p>Instead, the bill only permits depository institutions and non-depository trust institutions to issue stablecoins and does not set out a clear path to compliance for existing stablecoin firms.</p>
<p>The bill <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-senators-propose-bipartisan-bill-to-preserve-us-dollar-dominance-by-regulating-stablecoins/">also aims</a> to prevent the illegal use of stablecoins and creates separate federal and state regulatory regimes, among other specific requirements.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-lawmakers-proposed-ban-on-algorithmic-stablecoins-draws-industry-backlash/">US lawmakers&#8217; proposed ban on algorithmic stablecoins draws industry backlash</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/us-lawmakers-proposed-ban-on-algorithmic-stablecoins-draws-industry-backlash/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/stablecoin-supply.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/stablecoin-supply.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>URPD metric indicates a lack of liquidity for Bitcoin below $60,000</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/insights/urpd-metric-indicates-a-lack-of-liquidity-for-bitcoin-below-60000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Van Straten]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 18:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_insight&#038;p=413183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Quick Take Bitcoin experienced a 4% rally on April 18, bouncing back from just below $60,000 on April 17. CryptoSlate has identified $58.8k as a major support level — which is the short-term holder realized price (STH RP) that has previously acted as support during bull runs. If Bitcoin drops below the support level, it [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/urpd-metric-indicates-a-lack-of-liquidity-for-bitcoin-below-60000/">URPD metric indicates a lack of liquidity for Bitcoin below $60,000</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Quick Take</h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Bitcoin experienced a 4% rally on April 18, bouncing back from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-barely-holds-on-to-60k-as-bears-retest-march-lows/">just below $60,000</a> on April 17. <em>CryptoSlate</em> has identified $58.8k as a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/short-term-holder-realized-price-holds-steady-despite-weekend-bitcoin-drop-uptrend-persists/">major support level</a> — which is the short-term holder realized price (STH RP) that has previously acted as support during bull runs.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">If Bitcoin drops below the support level, it could signal a bearish trend, similar to the breach of STH RP in May 2021 that kicked off the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/research-btc-and-eth-bear-market-started-in-mid-2021-data-suggests/">bear market</a>.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The URPD (Unspent Realized Price Distribution) metric, as defined by <a href="https://studio.glassnode.com/metrics?a=BTC&amp;category=&amp;m=indicators.UrpdEntityAdjusted">Glassnode</a>, shows the prices at which the current set of Bitcoin UTXOs were created — with each bar representing the amount of existing BTC that last moved within a specific price bucket.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413278" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413278" style="width: 1800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-413278 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1.png" alt="URPD: (Source: Glassnode)" width="1800" height="1013" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1.png 1800w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1-1536x864.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1800px) 100vw, 1800px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413278" class="wp-caption-text">URPD: (Source: Glassnode)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Interestingly, less than 5% of the Bitcoin supply is between $50,000 and $60,000 — a range that Bitcoin moved through in just two days between Feb. 26 and Feb. 28.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">A significant portion of the liquidity and supply lies within the $40,000 to $45,000 range, which could be a short-term price target if the critical STH RP support is lost.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/urpd-metric-indicates-a-lack-of-liquidity-for-bitcoin-below-60000/">URPD metric indicates a lack of liquidity for Bitcoin below $60,000</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1.png" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/URPD-1.png" length="1800" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>JP Morgan CEO calls Bitcoin ‘Ponzi Scheme’ despite serving as Authorized Participant for BlackRock ETF</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/jp-morgan-ceo-calls-bitcoin-ponzi-scheme-despite-serving-as-authorized-participant-for-blackrock-etf/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/jp-morgan-ceo-calls-bitcoin-ponzi-scheme-despite-serving-as-authorized-participant-for-blackrock-etf/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 18:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon reiterated his strong skepticism toward Bitcoin on April 18, calling it a &#8220;fraud&#8221; and a &#8220;Ponzi scheme&#8221; despite the lender&#8217;s involvement in BlackRock&#8217;s spot BTC exchange-traded fund (ETF). Dimon, who has a history of critiquing the digital currency, made the latest comments during an interview on Bloomberg TV, where he [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jp-morgan-ceo-calls-bitcoin-ponzi-scheme-despite-serving-as-authorized-participant-for-blackrock-etf/">JP Morgan CEO calls Bitcoin ‘Ponzi Scheme’ despite serving as Authorized Participant for BlackRock ETF</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon reiterated his strong skepticism toward <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> on April 18, calling it a &#8220;fraud&#8221; and a &#8220;Ponzi scheme&#8221; despite the lender&#8217;s involvement in BlackRock&#8217;s spot BTC exchange-traded fund (ETF).</p>
<p>Dimon, who has a history of critiquing the digital currency, made the latest comments during an <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/videos/2024-04-17/when-jpmorgan-ceo-jamie-dimon-speaks-the-world-listens-video">interview</a> on Bloomberg TV, where he expressed doubts about Bitcoin&#8217;s utility and legitimacy as a form of money.</p>
<p>He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Bitcoin and similar cryptocurrencies are simply not functional as currencies. If they think they&#8217;re a currency, there&#8217;s no hope for it. It&#8217;s essentially a Ponzi scheme dressed up as tech innovation.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Despite the JP Morgan CEO&#8217;s long-standing criticism of Bitcoin, the lender has been serving as an Authorized Participant for BTC ETFs since their launch and has been involved in several blockchain-based projects for numerous years.</p>
<p>Dimon acknowledged the potential of certain aspects of blockchain technology during the interview, particularly those that enable smart contracts. He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There are elements within the broader crypto sector, such as those facilitating smart contracts and blockchain applications, that do present real value.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The veteran banker&#8217;s comments come amid a backdrop of fluctuating crypto values, with Bitcoin having recently rebounded to trade around the $63,000 mark, significantly up from its lows but well below its all-time high.</p>
<h2>Growth despite criticism</h2>
<p>Dimon has been vocal about his concerns with cryptocurrencies in the past, citing their potential to enable illegal activities such as money laundering, fraud, and tax evasion due to their anonymity and lack of regulation.</p>
<p>He has previously called for more stringent oversight to prevent the financial crimes associated with cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>Despite Dimon&#8217;s critical stance over the years, the crypto market has continued to grow, with Bitcoin&#8217;s market capitalization recently surpassing $1.2 trillion. His comments reflect ongoing debates within the financial community about the viability and safety of investments in cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>Industry analysts suggest that while skepticism like Dimon&#8217;s is not uncommon among traditional financial leaders, the innovation and adoption of blockchain technology show no signs of slowing down. As discussions about the regulatory framework continue, the future of cryptocurrencies remains a hotly contested topic across global financial markets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jp-morgan-ceo-calls-bitcoin-ponzi-scheme-despite-serving-as-authorized-participant-for-blackrock-etf/">JP Morgan CEO calls Bitcoin ‘Ponzi Scheme’ despite serving as Authorized Participant for BlackRock ETF</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/jp-morgan-ceo-calls-bitcoin-ponzi-scheme-despite-serving-as-authorized-participant-for-blackrock-etf/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/jamie-dimon-bitcoin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/jamie-dimon-bitcoin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Polkadot introduces JAM upgrade and 10 million DOT prize to enhance network capabilities</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/polkadot-introduces-jam-upgrade-and-10-million-dot-prize-to-enhance-network-capabilities/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/polkadot-introduces-jam-upgrade-and-10-million-dot-prize-to-enhance-network-capabilities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polkadot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gavin Wood, Polkadot&#8217;s founder, introduced the Gray Paper outlining the upcoming Join-Accumulate Machine (JAM) upgrade for the network. This announcement was made during Wood&#8217;s presentation on Polkadot&#8217;s future at the Token2049 crypto conference in Dubai. Web3 Foundation, the entity behind Polkadot, further announced a 10 Million DOT prize pool to foster diversity within the development [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/polkadot-introduces-jam-upgrade-and-10-million-dot-prize-to-enhance-network-capabilities/">Polkadot introduces JAM upgrade and 10 million DOT prize to enhance network capabilities</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gavin-wood/">Gavin Wood</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/polkadot/">Polkadot&#8217;s</a> founder, introduced the Gray Paper outlining the upcoming Join-Accumulate Machine (JAM) upgrade for the network. This announcement was made during Wood&#8217;s presentation on Polkadot&#8217;s future at the Token2049 crypto conference in Dubai.</p>
<p>Web3 Foundation, the entity behind Polkadot, further <a href="https://medium.com/web3foundation/announcing-the-jam-implementers-prize-e79f8ebc506d">announced</a> a 10 Million DOT prize pool to foster diversity within the development of the JAM protocol.</p>
<p>According to the firm:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The JAM Implementer’s Prize is designed to catalyze this by funding and supporting projects that contribute to the development of JAM implementations from the outset.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>What is JAM?</h2>
<p>JAM is a decentralized hybrid system designed to offer secure and scalable smart contract functionalities. It combines certain features from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> within Polkadot&#8217;s architectural framework.</p>
<p>Polkadot said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;JAM is a protocol combining elements of both Polkadot and Ethereum. It is a prospective path to replace the Relay Chain with a more modular, minimalistic design.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Web3 Foundation added that JAM would allow Polkadot to run generic &#8220;services,&#8221; smart contract logic to process the execution result on cores. A parachains service will run existing Substrate-based parachains, meaning developers can still use Substrate to develop and deploy their blockchains.</p>
<p>In essence, JAM provides a global singleton permissionless object environment—akin to Ethereum&#8217;s smart-contract environment—paired with secure sideband computation parallelized over a scalable node network.</p>
<p>Goku, a supporter of the blockchain network, <a href="https://twitter.com/0xgoku_/status/1780940377597350294">explained</a> that the upgrade would allow Polkadot<br />
to become &#8220;a true multi-core world computer capable of handling any type of service or app without scalability, security, or efficiency issues.&#8221; He added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;[Polkadot] has already become a multi-core processor, but this was limited to parachains. The idea is to generalize this even further, to be utterly unopinionated about what and how things are deployed, turning all parachains, aka rollups, into an application layer service, with Polkadot transforming into something akin to cloud service infrastructure.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, the proposed upgrade would continue to utilize the network&#8217;s DOT token. Following the news, the digital asset bucked its current downward trend to rise by around 3% to as high as $7. However, it has retraced to $6.62 as of press time.</p>
<p>It should be noted that the JAM upgrade is still subject to Polkadot&#8217;s community approval via the network&#8217;s on-chain, decentralized governance.</p>
<p><em>[Editor&#8217;s Note: When interacting with any competition or airdrop links, remember to triple-check the domain authenticity to ensure you are connecting to a valid source.]</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/polkadot-introduces-jam-upgrade-and-10-million-dot-prize-to-enhance-network-capabilities/">Polkadot introduces JAM upgrade and 10 million DOT prize to enhance network capabilities</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/polkadot-introduces-jam-upgrade-and-10-million-dot-prize-to-enhance-network-capabilities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/gavin-wood.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/gavin-wood.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holding Bitcoin has been unprofitable only on these days</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/insights/holding-bitcoin-has-been-unprofitable-only-on-these-days/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Van Straten]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_insight&#038;p=413177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Quick Take According to data gathered by Newhedge over the past 5,024 days, dating back to 2010, Bitcoin has been profitable for an impressive 4,947 days. This means that the digital asset has only experienced 77 days of being unprofitable, equating to a 98.5% profitability rate. Despite the recent bearish sentiment in the market, Bitcoin [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/holding-bitcoin-has-been-unprofitable-only-on-these-days/">Holding Bitcoin has been unprofitable only on these days</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Quick Take</h2>
<p>According to data gathered by <a href="https://newhedge.io/terminal/bitcoin/profitable-days">Newhedge</a> over the past 5,024 days, dating back to 2010, Bitcoin has been profitable for an impressive 4,947 days. This means that the digital asset has only experienced 77 days of being unprofitable, equating to a 98.5% profitability rate. Despite the recent bearish sentiment in the market, Bitcoin continues to trade at around $63,000, with only brief periods in April and November 2021, and from Feb. 28 to April 17, it has been more profitable.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413205" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413205" style="width: 2025px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-413205 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/profit.png" alt="Bitcoin Profitable days: (Source: Newhedge)" width="2025" height="975" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/profit.png 2025w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/profit-300x144.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/profit-1024x493.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/profit-768x370.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/profit-1536x740.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2025px) 100vw, 2025px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413205" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin Profitable days: (Source: Newhedge)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The bearish sentiment surrounding Bitcoin can be attributed to several factors, including the upcoming <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/historical-patterns-repeat-as-bitcoin-declines-before-halving/">halving event</a> and the digital assets&#8217;s tendency to experience negative price performance before the halving. Additionally, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitb-bitwises-btc-etf-experiences-first-outflow-since-launch/">ETF</a> inflows have started to dry up and even turn negative. While potential conflict in the Middle East remains a concern, the recent drop in Brent Crude Oil prices from $92 to $87 suggests that the worst may be behind us.</p>
<p>In a positive turn of events, Bitcoin <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/funding-rate-turns-negative-as-bitcoin-drops-below-64k/">funding rates</a> have flipped back to positive after being negative over the weekend. Historically, this has been a good contrarian indicator for marking bottoms in cycles.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413230" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413230" style="width: 1800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-413230 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/funding.png" alt="Futures Perpetual Funding Rate: (Source: Glassnode)" width="1800" height="1013" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/funding.png 1800w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/funding-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/funding-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/funding-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/funding-1536x864.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1800px) 100vw, 1800px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413230" class="wp-caption-text">Futures Perpetual Funding Rate: (Source: Glassnode)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/holding-bitcoin-has-been-unprofitable-only-on-these-days/">Holding Bitcoin has been unprofitable only on these days</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/unprofitable-days.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/unprofitable-days.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tether champions decentralized systems expanding tech, AI, education and financial reach</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/tether-champions-decentralized-systems-with-expanded-tech-and-financial-services/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/tether-champions-decentralized-systems-with-expanded-tech-and-financial-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since its inception, Tether has expanded from a stablecoin to a financial linchpin in developing regions, according to its CEO Paulo Ardoino, speaking at Token 2049 in Dubai. Asserting its new role as an ecosystem architect with the launch of a multi-divisional framework aimed at fostering resilient, future-ready financial systems. The company, known for its [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-champions-decentralized-systems-with-expanded-tech-and-financial-services/">Tether champions decentralized systems expanding tech, AI, education and financial reach</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since its inception, <a href="/coins/tether">Tether</a> has expanded from a stablecoin to a financial linchpin in developing regions, according to its CEO Paulo Ardoino, speaking at Token 2049 in Dubai. Asserting its new role as an ecosystem architect with the launch of a multi-divisional framework aimed at fostering resilient, future-ready financial systems.</p>
<p>The company, known for its leading stablecoin USDT, just surpassed a $109 billion market cap and has become a financial powerhouse due to its prominent position as a top 20 holder of US Treasury bills. Ardoino announced at the conference that Tether is setting its sights beyond crypto, venturing into initiatives that underpin various sectors, including peer-to-peer communications, Bitcoin mining, education, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-launches-ai-arm-data-aimed-at-building-open-source-lmms-via/">artificial intelligence</a>.</p>
<p>Tether&#8217;s push into these sectors reflects a significant shift in the company&#8217;s vision, one that is built on the philosophy of decentralization and disintermediation. Per Tether, the new website <a href="http://tether.io">tether.io</a> has been introduced as a platform dedicated to the company&#8217;s broadened mission. It emphasizes creating financial, technological, and educational tools with the intent to empower individuals, communities, and nations, particularly in emerging markets.</p>
<p>The scope of Tether&#8217;s expanded <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-plans-500m-investment-into-bitcoin-mining-operations/">vision</a> is comprehensive, with four new business divisions structured to drive innovation and accessibility in technology and education. Tether Data is diving into the development and strategic investment of emergent technologies. With initiatives like Holepunch that promote advanced peer-to-peer technologies and significant investments in artificial intelligence frontrunners like Northern Data Group, Tether Data aims to advance the frontiers of digital capabilities.</p>
<p>In digital asset services, Tether Finance stands as the foundation for Tether&#8217;s established stablecoin products and financial solutions. It advocates for the democratization of the economic system through blockchain technology and is set to lead the launch of platforms for digital asset tokenization, which could catalyze broader adoption of digital currencies.</p>
<p>Tether Power focuses on aligning Bitcoin mining operations with sustainable energy practices, thereby upholding Tether&#8217;s commitment to fostering financial freedom while emphasizing responsible growth. Meanwhile, Tether Edu is propelling global digital skills education, supporting initiatives and partnerships that expand knowledge and proficiency in emerging technologies. Its endeavors include collaborating on projects like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/swiss-city-lugano-to-accept-bitcoin-tether-for-tax-payments/">Lugano&#8217;s Plan B</a> and investing in platforms like the Academy of Digital Industries.</p>
<p>As these divisions converge on the new framework, Tether is cementing its role as a trailblazer in the digital asset space. By reinforcing its commitment to disintermediating traditional financial systems, Tether aims to enhance financial inclusion and establish a groundwork for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/lugano-teams-with-tether-to-drive-citywide-blockchain-adoption/">infrastructure</a> that sustains innovation and autonomy.</p>
<p>&#8220;We disrupted the traditional financial landscape with the world&#8217;s first and most trusted stablecoin. Now, we&#8217;re daring to kickstart inclusive infrastructure solutions, dismantling traditional systems for fairness,&#8221; stated Ardoino.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;With this evolution beyond our traditional stablecoin offerings, we are ready to build and support the invention and implementation of cutting-edge technology that removes the limitations of what&#8217;s possible in this world. We&#8217;re Tether. We use technology to empower individuals, communities, cities, and nations to become self-sustainable, independent, and free. Be unstoppable together.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Tether&#8217;s advancements outline a transformative blueprint for the future of financial and technological ecosystems, with the potential to redefine how <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/el-salvador-launches-exclusive-bitcoin-driven-freedom-visa-with-tether/">communities</a> interact with and benefit from the digital revolution.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-champions-decentralized-systems-with-expanded-tech-and-financial-services/">Tether champions decentralized systems expanding tech, AI, education and financial reach</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/tether-champions-decentralized-systems-with-expanded-tech-and-financial-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/tether-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/tether-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
