<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>&lt;title&gt;</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
	<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/news/</link>
	<description>&lt;description&gt;</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:04:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.coinspeaker.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>News | Coinspeaker</title>
	<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/news/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Swiss Bitcoin Bulls to Lobby Central Bank to Include BTC in National Reserves</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/swiss-bitcoin-central-bank-btc-reserves/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/swiss-bitcoin-central-bank-btc-reserves/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tolu Ajiboye]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/swiss-bitcoin-central-bank-btc-reserves/">Swiss Bitcoin Bulls to Lobby Central Bank to Include BTC in National Reserves</a></p>
<p>A Swiss non-profit group is making a second attempt to convince the central bank to add Bitcoin to its national reserves.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/swiss-bitcoin-central-bank-btc-reserves/">Swiss Bitcoin Bulls to Lobby Central Bank to Include BTC in National Reserves</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/swiss-bitcoin-central-bank-btc-reserves/">Swiss Bitcoin Bulls to Lobby Central Bank to Include BTC in National Reserves</a></p>
<p>Bitcoin bulls in Switzerland are working on getting the Swiss National Bank (SNB) to officially hold Bitcoin (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BTC</a>) as part of its reserves. A few Bitcoiners have now launched efforts at a referendum to make a small adjustment to Switzerland’s constitution to add Bitcoin reserves to Gold.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin in Swiss National Reserves</h2>
<p>According to a local news <a href="https://www.nzz.ch/wirtschaft/nun-kommt-die-volksinitiative-welche-die-nationalbank-zum-kauf-von-bitcoin-verpflichten-will-ld.1827256" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">report</a> from Neue Zürcher Zeitung (NZZ), the constitution states that the Swiss National Bank creates currency reserves from its income, and holds a part of it in Gold. A non-profit think tank, 2B4CH, now wants the relevant constitutional article to read “Gold and Bitcoin”.</p>
<p>2B4CH founder and chairman Yves Bennaïm said the organization is already hard at work:</p>
<blockquote><p>“We are in the process of completing the organizational preparations for the committee and preparing the documents that must be submitted to the State Chancellery in order to start the process.”</p></blockquote>
<p>To achieve any success, 2B4CH must get 100,000 signatures from citizens within 18 months before a referendum is held.</p>
<p>This is not the think tank’s first attempt at lobbying the SNB to hold reserves in Bitcoin. In 2021, 2B4CH <a href="https://twitter.com/2B4CH/status/1446386254829006853?s=20" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">launched</a> the initiative in a thread posted on X (formerly Twitter), looking to amend Article 99 Clause 3 of the Federal Constitution. At the time, 2B4CH noted that it was not “too optimistic about getting a law actually passed”. However, it hoped to get 100k signatures to open a public conversation and debate.</p>
<h2>Switzerland Would Have Been $32 Billion Richer</h2>
<p>According to Luzius Meisser, President of Bitcoin trading platform Bitcoin Suisse, the move would allow Switzerland to operate independently of the European Central Bank (ECB). Meisser is currently helping Bennaïm with the initiative and will have 3 minutes to plead their case before the SNB at an April 26 meeting.</p>
<p>The NZZ report states that Meisser previously asked the SNB to buy 1 billion Swiss francs a month at the 2022 general meeting. According to him, Switzerland would be richer by $32.9 billion (30 billion Swiss francs) if it had taken Meisser’s advice. The Bitcoin Suisse President is now saying that delaying this move would be detrimental to Switzerland. According to him, other central banks will set their eyes on Bitcoin and buy the asset. This will force Switzerland to eventually buy Bitcoin at much higher prices.</p>
<p>Bennaïm and Meisser’s efforts are significantly creating awareness for Bitcoin and its potential uses. Even if the current attempt fails again, the efforts, including Meisser’s upcoming SNB speech, are strong enough to keep the conversation going for a while.</p>
<p>In 2022, the SNB Chairman Thomas Jordan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/swiss-national-bank-opposed-holding-bitcoin-reserve-currency-2022-04-29/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">said</a> at its general meeting that “we do not believe Bitcoin meets the requirements of currency reserves. That’s why we have until now decided not to have Bitcoin on our balance sheet”. Otherwise, “buying Bitcoin is not a problem for us. We can do that either directly or can buy investment products which are based on Bitcoin,” said he.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/swiss-bitcoin-central-bank-btc-reserves/">Swiss Bitcoin Bulls to Lobby Central Bank to Include BTC in National Reserves</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/swiss-bitcoin-central-bank-btc-reserves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EigenLayer Is Facing Major Yield Crisis, Analyst Explains Why</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Godfrey Benjamin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eigenlayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/">EigenLayer Is Facing Major Yield Crisis, Analyst Explains Why</a></p>
<p>The analyst proposed two potential remedies to EigenLayer's yield crisis: a bottom-up and a top-down strategy.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/">EigenLayer Is Facing Major Yield Crisis, Analyst Explains Why</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/">EigenLayer Is Facing Major Yield Crisis, Analyst Explains Why</a></p>
<p>A recent analysis by a crypto analyst has revealed a major threat to EigenLayer’s promise of enhanced security and scalability. The analyst chudnov on the X platform <a href="https://twitter.com/chudnovglavniy/status/1782253767116894553" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">stated</a> that an imminent yield crisis on the EigenLayer could potentially cause revenue to “fall off a cliff”.</p>
<h2>Looming Threats on EigenLayer</h2>
<p>While EigenLayer’s Token-Locking contract boasts an impressive $15 billion in Total Value Locked (TVL), the analyst noted that the Actively Validated Service (AVS) required to secure the network will require only 10% of this amount.</p>
<p>The EigenLayer protocol is an <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ethereum</a> (ETH)-based project that aims to improve the network&#8217;s Proof-of-Stake (PoS) consensus using a method known as restaking. The EigenLayer team claims to have solved several of Ethereum&#8217;s security inefficiencies and a recent <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/restaking-protocol-eigenlayer-ethereum-mainnet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report</a> reveals that the protocol boasts more than $13 billion in user deposits.</p>
<p>However, chudnov expressed concern that opening the door to over $15 billion in deposits could be too much for the network to handle. He emphasized that this could lead to a yield crisis, where the supply outstrips the available demand, resulting in a downward pressure on prices.</p>
<p>The analyst’s argument is centered on the discrepancy between the amount of ETH deposited through EigenLayer&#8217;s LRT (Liquidity-Restaking Token) and the actual security needs of the AVS nodes.</p>
<p>Although the deposited ETH is delegated to node operators to secure the AVS and earn rewards, the analyst questions whether any of these AVS nodes need large amounts of ETH being deposited for security. As an example, he cited EigenDA and Lagrange, two services developed on top of Ethereum using the EigenLayer primitives that require less capital than $1.5 billion of security.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">7/ So, what is the solution?</p>
<p>There are two ways (not mutually exclusive):<br />1. bottom-up<br />2. top-down</p>
<p>&mdash; chudnov (@chudnovglavniy) <a href="https://twitter.com/chudnovglavniy/status/1782253767116894553?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<h2>The Way Forward for EigenLayer</h2>
<p>The analyst proposed two potential remedies to EigenLayer&#8217;s yield crisis: a bottom-up and a top-down strategy. The analyst&#8217;s bottom-up approach suggests that there may be an attempt to artificially create a market for ETH by incentivizing the creation of “shitcoins” that, in turn, require a larger security budget.</p>
<p>According to the analyst, this approach would effectively transform EigenLayer into a pass-through mechanism for a pool of airdrops without any real utility for the deposited ETH.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the top-down approach involves the Eigenlayer team developing financial tools on top of the existing restaking mechanisms within EigenLayer to offset the opportunity costs associated with holding restaked ETH.</p>
<p>The analyst argues that EigenLayer could potentially reduce the burden on the AVS security budget by creating additional financial products and services on top of the existing infrastructure, such as money markets or derivatives. This approach combines financial innovation to drive sustainable and organic growth for EigenLayer.</p>
<p>The analyst is tilted toward the first approach but highlights that it may not be a sustainable one because artificially inflating tokenomics and creating “artificial security demand” can be a short-term solution. He points out that the token prices can suffer if the alt market takes a hit and the excess capital held by the AVS nodes might not be efficiently allocated if the security budget is overestimated.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/">EigenLayer Is Facing Major Yield Crisis, Analyst Explains Why</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/eigenlayer-yield-crisis-analyst/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance Releases Update on Step Size Adjustment on Spot Trading Pairs</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Temitope Olatunji]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celestia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fetch.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inj]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[injective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/">Binance Releases Update on Step Size Adjustment on Spot Trading Pairs</a></p>
<p>Binance has assured users that these adjustments will not disrupt ongoing spot trading or other related functionalities.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/">Binance Releases Update on Step Size Adjustment on Spot Trading Pairs</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/">Binance Releases Update on Step Size Adjustment on Spot Trading Pairs</a></p>
<p>In a bid to enhance trading liquidity and user experience, <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/binance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Binance</a> has <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/square/post/7103728543474" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">announced</a> upcoming modifications to its trading increments, known as step size, for several digital assets. This move aims to streamline trading operations and facilitate more efficient price discovery across various cryptocurrency markets.</p>
<h2>Targeted Crypto Assets and Step Size Modification</h2>
<p>The step size adjustment will impact a diverse range of cryptocurrencies, including <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/fetch-fet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fetch.ai</a> (FET), <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/injective-inj-price-3000-increase-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Injective</a> (INJ), <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/solana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Solana</a> (SOL), and <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/celestia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Celestia</a> (TIA). Step size, a crucial trading parameter, defines the smallest intervals at which an order&#8217;s quantity can be adjusted. By making adjustments to these increments, Binance aims to create a smoother and more liquid trading environment for these digital assets.</p>
<p>According to the announcement, the step size updates will be implemented in two phases. The first phase, scheduled for April 29, 2024, at 05:00 UTC, will target trading pairs involving FET and INJ. In this phase, the step size for pairs such as FET/BNB, FET/BTC, and INJ/USDT will be changed to make order execution more precise.</p>
<p>The second phase, slated the same day but at a different hour, at 07:00 UTC, will focus on SOL and TIA trading pairs. Pairs such as SOL/BNB, SOL/USDT, and TIA/BTC will undergo step size modifications, enabling traders to place orders with greater precision and potentially enhancing market depth.</p>
<p>The platform provided a table detailing the specific changes to the step sizes for each affected trading pair. The step size for the FET/BNB pair will decrease from 1 to 0.1, allowing for more precise order placement. Similarly, the INJ/BTC pair&#8217;s step size will be reduced from 0.1 to 0.01. More so, the SOL pairs involving currencies such as BNB, BTC, and EUR, among others, will change from  0.01 to 0.001.</p>
<h2>Effect of the Update on Spot Trading on Binance</h2>
<p>The exchange has assured traders that these adjustments will not disrupt ongoing spot trading or other related functionalities. Existing spot orders placed before the step size update will continue to be matched with the original step size, ensuring a smooth trading environment for active traders on the platform.</p>
<p>To accommodate the changes, the exchange has urged traders to reassess their trading strategies and adjust accordingly. The platform acknowledged the potential inconvenience caused by these modifications and expressed its commitment to minimizing disruptions during the transition period.</p>
<p>For developers and traders relying on Binance&#8217;s Application Programming Interfaces (APIs), the step size information will also be updated. They will be able to access the latest step size data through the provided link.</p>
<p>The step-size adjustments further reveal Binance&#8217;s continuous effort toward fostering a smooth and improved trading environment for its vast user base. This latest improvement will provide traders with greater control over their order executions, enhancing their trading capabilities and potentially opening more profitable opportunities within the FET, INJ, SOL, and TIA markets on Binance&#8217;s platform.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/">Binance Releases Update on Step Size Adjustment on Spot Trading Pairs</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-update-spot-trading-pairs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jesse Pollak Foresees Meme Coins as Key to Base’s Growth</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chimamanda U. Martha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[base]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[degen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toshi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/">Jesse Pollak Foresees Meme Coins as Key to Base&#8217;s Growth</a></p>
<p>Pollak disclosed that hundreds of meme projects and developers are currently evolving, building, and creating to bring their culture and energy into the Base economy as well as the capital market.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/">Jesse Pollak Foresees Meme Coins as Key to Base&#8217;s Growth</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/">Jesse Pollak Foresees Meme Coins as Key to Base&#8217;s Growth</a></p>
<p>Jesse Pollak, one of the brains behind the development of Coinbase layer-2 scaling solution Base, said meme coins would be the primary driver of new users to the Ethereum-based protocol.  Speaking at a hackathon event over the weekend in New York, Pollak <a href="https://twitter.com/jessepollak/status/1781743145795059850?s=19" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">highlighted</a> the significant role memes play in the network&#8217;s growth strategy. He also acknowledged that the asset class has brought tremendous success to Base in terms of onboarding so far.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s been a ton of energy on Base. One thing that has really stood out to us is that we&#8217;re seeing these memes today onboard thousands and thousands of people into this new economy,&#8221; he said.</p>
<h2>Bringing the World On-chain</h2>
<p>Pollak believes that memes are an important aspect of the crypto economy, and the layer-2 protocol aims to bring the world on-chain.</p>
<p>He further noted that apart from serving as a speculative tool, meme creators on the protocol are actively exploring innovative ways to attract new users into their communities.</p>
<p>As a result of their continuous efforts to creatively engage and onboard more individuals, the Base creator believes the asset class will be instrumental in bringing in millions of new users to Base in the coming years.</p>
<p>&#8220;The thing we&#8217;ve built more conviction on is that in the years ahead, we&#8217;re actually going to see these memes bring in millions more people [to Base] — they&#8217;re going to be one of the biggest drivers because they&#8217;re doing that work constantly to onboard more and more folks through that in a really creative way,&#8221; said Pollak.</p>
<h2>Top Meme Projects on Base</h2>
<p>Pollak further disclosed that hundreds of meme projects and developers are currently evolving, building, and creating to bring their culture and energy into the Base economy as well as the capital market.</p>
<p>According to data from <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/brett" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CoinGecko</a>, BRETT is currently the leading memecoin on Base, boasting a market capitalization of $567 million. Since the beginning of March, the token has experienced a price surge of 7,780%.</p>
<p>Other top meme projects on the layer-2 blockchain after BRETT are DEGEN, with a market cap of $435 million, and TOSHI, with a market cap of $185 million.</p>
<h2>Milestone Achievements</h2>
<p>In less than a year of launch, Base has achieved a series of milestones and is currently ranked among Ethereum&#8217;s top five scaling solutions.</p>
<p>Last month, the protocol recorded $356 million in transactions within 24 hours. Activities on the network continued to surge after the Ethereum<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-developers-dencun-upgrade-eth-price/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Dencun upgrade</a> in mid-March, which reduced fees for layer-2 networks.</p>
<p>According to Web3 firm DefiLlama, Base&#8217;s total value locked (TVL) continued to rise, <a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Base" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">reaching</a> an all-time high of $1.65 billion on April 21. The figure shows a 250% increase since the beginning of March 2024.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the network <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coinbases-l2-base-400-tps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">achieved</a> another milestone by processing between 300 and 400 transactions per second (TPS) for the first time since its launch.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/">Jesse Pollak Foresees Meme Coins as Key to Base&#8217;s Growth</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/jesse-pollak-meme-coins-base/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Transaction Fees Plummet after Record High during BTC Halving Event 2024</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bena Ilyas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gbtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grayscale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Runes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/">Bitcoin Transaction Fees Plummet after Record High during BTC Halving Event 2024</a></p>
<p>While the­ Runes launch initially led to a surge in fe­es, it remains uncertain whe­ther this represe­nts a long-term, sustainable source of re­venue for miners.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/">Bitcoin Transaction Fees Plummet after Record High during BTC Halving Event 2024</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/">Bitcoin Transaction Fees Plummet after Record High during BTC Halving Event 2024</a></p>

<p>Bitcoin transaction fee­s reached an all-time pe­ak on April 20, coinciding with the <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BTC halving event 2024</a> and now declined substantially on April 21. According to the <a href="https://ycharts.com/indicators/bitcoin_average_transaction_fee" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">data</a> from YCharts, the ave­rage fee pe­r transaction plunged from an all-time high of $128.45 down to a more re­asonable $34.80.</p>



<p>The initial surge in transactions­ seems connecte­d to the release­ of Runes protocol, created by Case­y Rodarmor. Runes is similar to <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/guides/erc-token-standards-complete-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethere­um&#8217;s ERC-20 tokens</a>. Its launch triggered a frenzy of activity as use­rs rushed to make rune-base­d meme coins. Howeve­r, this sudden surge in activity congested the­ network, causing transaction fees to skyrocke­t.</p>



<h2 id="h-bitcoin-transaction-fees-see-81-million-spike" class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Transaction Fees See $81 Million Spike</h2>



<p>The Bitcoin ne­twork experience­d a significant surge in total transaction fees, re­flecting a notable trend. According to <a href="https://ycharts.com/indicators/bitcoin_total_transaction_fees_per_day" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">data</a> from YCharts, the­ fees skyrockete­d from $7.7 million on April 19 to a remarkable $81 million on the 20th, amid the­ halving event and the Rune­s launch. However, the fees subse­quently decrease­d to $22.37 million on the 21, highlighting pote­ntial scalability challenges within the ne­twork.</p>



<p>While the­ Runes launch initially led to a surge in fe­es, it remains uncertain whe­ther this represe­nts a long-term, sustainable source of re­venue for miners. However, some­ anticipated Runes would become­ a significant fee gene­rator; early signs suggest otherwise­. For example, the­ floor prices for Runestone NFT ite­ms dropped ne­arly 50% within one day as of April 21, <a href="https://magiceden.io/ordinals/marketplace/runestone" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">according</a> to Magic Eden.</p>



<p>Howeve­r, the situation is not e­ntirely unfavorable for cryptocurrency mine­rs. Ordinal collections like Bitcoin Pullets and Node­Monkes, which generate­ fees from transactions, have e­xperienced price­ increases during the same­ timeframe. This suggests a pote­ntial future where various digital asse­ts, not only traditional transactions, contribute to the re­venue earne­d by miners.</p>



<h2 id="h-grayscale-predicts-bitcoin-s-path-to-10-trillion-market-cap" class="wp-block-heading">Grayscale Predicts Bitcoin&#8217;s Path to $10 Trillion Market Cap</h2>



<p>Despite the short-term challenges, industry experts believe these eve­nts reveal Bitcoin mining&#8217;s economic future­. Grayscale, the manager of the world&#8217;s largest Bitcoin Trust (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/guides/what-is-grayscale-bitcoin-trust/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GBTC</a>), says if transaction charge­s stabilize at a higher rate than historically obse­rved, future halvings&#8217; impact on miner re­venue will diminish. </p>



<p>Looking decades ahead­, Bitcoin&#8217;s total worth may inflate to $10 trillion and network traffic soars, so transaction fees could build a significant income­ for miners. However, achieving such scalability and wide­spread adoption will require­ ongoing development efforts and innovative approaches to mitigate network congestion.</p>



<p>&#8220;A preview of what’s to come in Bitcoin mining economics decades from now, as Bitcoin monetizes into a $10 trillion+ asset, demand for the network is orders of magnitude larger than today, and we’ve had a few more halvings,&#8221; said Grayscale.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/">Bitcoin Transaction Fees Plummet after Record High during BTC Halving Event 2024</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-transaction-fees-plummet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>12 Solana Presale Meme Coin Projects ‘Completely Abandoned’ Less than Month Later</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mayowa Adebajo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogwifhat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[like]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moonke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wif]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zachxbt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/">12 Solana Presale Meme Coin Projects &#8216;Completely Abandoned&#8217; Less than Month Later</a></p>
<p>The projects had raised a combined $26.7 million, albeit through the controversial presale method.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/">12 Solana Presale Meme Coin Projects &#8216;Completely Abandoned&#8217; Less than Month Later</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/">12 Solana Presale Meme Coin Projects &#8216;Completely Abandoned&#8217; Less than Month Later</a></p>
<p>The last 30 days saw no less than 12 Solana presale meme coin projects being “completely abandoned”. That is, according to a recent X <a href="https://twitter.com/zachxbt/status/1782130097895477469?s=19" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">post</a> by popular independent blockchain detective ZachXBT.</p>
<p>Per the post, the projects had raised a combined $26.7 million, albeit through the controversial presale method. However, investigations have revealed that nearly all the tokens have plummeted since launch, with a particular one not even taking off with any token launch at all.</p>
<p>ZachXBT detailed a meme coin dubbed ‘I like this coin’ as probably the most expensive one in the Solana presale meme coin projects pack that has been abandoned. The meme coin, which sported the ticker LIKE, raised a staggering 52,220 Solana (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/solana/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SOL</a>) ($7.7 million at current prices) and launched with a market capitalization of $577 million on March 17. However, the meme coin shed over 90% of its value within the first eight hours of launch. As of press time, LIKE is down 83.08% from its launch price, per CoinMarketCap <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/likecoin/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">data</a>.</p>
<p>Other than its price movement, the official X account of the LIKE coin has not posted anything since March 31. Additionally, the supposed founder pokeee.eth has not mentioned the coin in a long while as well.</p>
<p>Another notable token in the list of abandoned presale meme coin projects is MOONKE. The token launched on March 20 to a rather outsized valuation of about  $500 million. However, just as was the case with LIKE, MOONKE soon began its own downward spiral that saw it plunge over 99% from its launch price in just a few hours.</p>
<p>Notably, a project reportedly raised 4,567 SOL (over $810,000 at current prices) but never even launched a token.</p>
<h2>Meme Coin Frenzy Dying Down?</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, it is worth noting that there might be a larger thing at play considering that the market’s appeal for memecoins has somewhat dwindled in recent weeks. For a better perspective, even bigger Solana-based meme coins are somehow losing their steam. For instance, Dogwifhat (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/dogwifhat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WIF</a>) has lost over 45% since April 1.</p>
<p>Without a doubt, meme coins are currently a shadow of themselves. Just last month, they were doing impressive numbers to the point that market analysts started drawing comparisons to the 2017 boom era of the Ethereum initial coin offering (ICO). However, one might also recall that, although hundreds of crypto projects raised millions of dollars during that period, most of them eventually failed to live up to expectations.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/">12 Solana Presale Meme Coin Projects &#8216;Completely Abandoned&#8217; Less than Month Later</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/12-solana-meme-coin-projects-abandoned/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>$60 Million Tether (USDT) Already Issued on TON within Three Days after Launch</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bhushan Akolkar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avalanche]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[near]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[omni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ton foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ton network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usdc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/">$60 Million Tether (USDT) Already Issued on TON within Three Days after Launch</a></p>
<p>Last week at the Token2049 crypto conference in Dubai, Tether unveiled its partnership with the TON Foundation, enabling Tether to mint USDT on the TON blockchain.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/">$60 Million Tether (USDT) Already Issued on TON within Three Days after Launch</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/">$60 Million Tether (USDT) Already Issued on TON within Three Days after Launch</a></p>
<p>Soon after Tether announced bringing its <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/tether/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USDT</a> stablecoin to the TON blockchain network last week on April 19, there&#8217;s been a massive issuance happening so far. As per reports, over $60 million in USDT is already issued on TON, thus making it the 11th largest blockchain for Tether.</p>
<p>During the Token2049 crypto conference in Dubai last week, Tether announced its collaboration with the TON Foundation. This allows Tether to freely mint its USDT stablecoin on the TON blockchain. Apart from USDT, Tether also launched its gold-pegged Tether Gold (XAUT) stablecoin on TON.</p>
<p>The Open Network team announced on X that cross-border payments were effortless, free, and instantaneous, likening the process to sending a text message to Telegram&#8217;s extensive user base of 900 million individuals.</p>
<p>Paolo Ardoino, CEO of Tether, remarked in an April 21 post on X that the endeavor had seen a promising beginning, with $35 million USDT issued on TON. Nevertheless, as per the Tether Transparency <a href="https://tether.to/en/transparency/?tab=usdt" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">report</a>, the authorized supply issued on TON has expanded to $60 million by 11:30 pm UTC on April 21.</p>
<h2>The Tether and TON Collaboration</h2>
<p>This collaboration between Tether and the TON blockchain will allow Telegram users to freely transfer their USDT across all platforms and almost instantly. “All you need to do is send a DM, no need for a blockchain address, and no need to download a new app,” said Telegram.</p>
<p>USDT on the TON Network comes with fully integrated on-ramps from most of the global fiat currencies. Additionally, very soon, global off-ramps will allow users to withdraw the supported fiat currencies directly to their cards or banks.</p>
<p>However, more than 50% of Tether&#8217;s circulating supply is currently on the Tron blockchain. The circulation of USDT on Ethereum has decreased to $51 billion, as more Tether is being utilized on alternative blockchains to mitigate the high network fees experienced on <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ethereum</a>.</p>
<p>Solana stands as the third-largest network accommodating Tether, with a total issuance of $1.9 billion. Additionally, the stablecoin has been deployed on various other blockchains such as Avalanche, Omni, Cosmos, Tezos, Near, EOS, and Celo.</p>
<p>Tether&#8217;s share in the entire stablecoin market is currently at 69%. On the other hand, Circle, its closest rival has a market share of 21%. Tether&#8217;s expansion into the TON blockchain shows its efforts to reduce its concentration from two major players.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/">$60 Million Tether (USDT) Already Issued on TON within Three Days after Launch</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/60m-tether-usdt-ton-three-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Price Rallies Above $66K Following BTC Halving 2024</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Muchoki]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Story of the Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin halving 2024]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc halvin 2024]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/">Bitcoin Price Rallies Above $66K Following BTC Halving 2024</a></p>
<p>The Bitcoin race to $100K and beyond was triggered by the BTC halving event 2024 over the weekend amid heightened demand from institutional investors.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/">Bitcoin Price Rallies Above $66K Following BTC Halving 2024</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/">Bitcoin Price Rallies Above $66K Following BTC Halving 2024</a></p>
<p>Following Saturday’s fourth <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitcoin (BTC) halving</a>, daily emissions have dropped to 450 coins, worth around $29.7 million. The approval of spot Bitcoin ETFs in the United States has helped increase the overall demand. Combined with the recent approval of spot BTC ETFs in Hong Kong, it is safe to assume the Bitcoin bulls are in control.</p>
<p>Furthermore, almost all indicators are pointing to an inevitable new all-time high (ATH) in the coming weeks.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Network Reorganization</h2>
<p>Bitcoin miners have been preparing for the halving event in the past week, whereby the overall hash rate dropped from 700Ehash/s on April 14 to around 595Ehash/s on Monday. The continued increment in the overall mining difficulty has compelled miners from all over the world to upgrade their rigs to the latest versions.</p>
<p>Following the notable changes in Bitcoin miners, the cost of sending BTC has experienced significant volatility in the past few days. Over the weekend, overall fees paid to Bitcoin miners surged despite a decline in non-zero addresses. According to hash price data provided by mempool.space, the cost of sending <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitcoin</a> via a high-priority option is around $10.18, while that of a low-priority priority is about $8.7.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fees paid to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a> miners have surged to 1,258 <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$BTC</a>, yet the creation of new <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BTC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BTC</a> addresses has declined, reaching just 260,838. <a href="https://t.co/7PXARJxURw">pic.twitter.com/7PXARJxURw</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ali (@ali_charts) <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1782167174897127692?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 21, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Remarkably, on-chain data shows that Bitcoin miners have continued to hoard more coins, despite the reorganization of the mining rigs. Perhaps, Bitcoin miners are upgrading their rigs to renewable energy sources through tax cuts and credits. Moreover, the escalating Middle East crisis is set to increase the general cost of crude oil amid rising fiat inflation.</p>
<h2>What Next for BTC Price after Bitcoin Halving 2024</h2>
<p>For the first time in Bitcoin’s history, the flagship coin closed around 2021’s bull cycle top during the fourth halving event. As a result, most crypto analysts are extremely bullish on Bitcoin price and the rest of the cryptocurrency market. According to a popular crypto analyst Ali Martinez, Bitcoin price is on the cusp of a nearly 70 percent uproar based on the Market Value to Realized Value (MVRV) ratio.</p>
<p>Notably, the crypto analyst noted that the MVRV ratio dipped below the 90-day average, which has historically been a popular buying opportunity.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Every time the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a> MVRV Ratio falls below its 90-day average since November 2022, it signals a prime <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BTC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BTC</a> buying opportunity with an average gain of 67%! </p>
<p>This opportunity is upon us again, indicating it might be the perfect time to buy <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$BTC</a>. <a href="https://t.co/nPMjF2GTpr">pic.twitter.com/nPMjF2GTpr</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ali (@ali_charts) <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1782052167177654702?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 21, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>A similar bullish outlook was issued by a popular analyst alias MikyBull Crypto, who added that Bitcoin price must consistently close above the daily 50 Moving Average (MA). The crypto analyst further pointed out that Bitcoin price has been trading inside a horizontal consolidation, but the bulls are in control.</p>
<p>Moreover, the daily Relative Strength Index (RSI) has already broken out of a bullish flag, thus indicating more gains ahead.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/">Bitcoin Price Rallies Above $66K Following BTC Halving 2024</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-price-66k-btc-halving-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Halving 2024: Implications for Miners and Market Dynamics</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Godfrey Benjamin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 11:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Story of the Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin halving 2024]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc halving 2024]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297377</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/">Bitcoin Halving 2024: Implications for Miners and Market Dynamics</a></p>
<p>The price trajectory of Bitcoin has remained little unchained despite speculations and projections by different analysts before the halving.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/">Bitcoin Halving 2024: Implications for Miners and Market Dynamics</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/">Bitcoin Halving 2024: Implications for Miners and Market Dynamics</a></p>
<p>Cryptocurrency’s Olympic-like event, the Bitcoin halving 2024 was completed at 12 a.m. GMT Saturday with immediate implications for mining companies in the ecosystem of digital assets. The halving, which is the completion of a pre-coded Bitcoin software update, occurs every four years as that is the time it takes to mine 210,000 blocks in the network.</p>
<h2>Mechanics of Bitcoin Halving</h2>
<p>According to the <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/289921/bitcoins-fourth-halving-block-sees-additional-2-4-million-reward-paid-as-fee" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">report</a>, this year’s halving, the fourth in the series appears to be from the crypto mining pool ViaBTC with an additional 37.6256 BTC ($2,401,399) &#8220;reward paid as fees of the 3,050 transactions which were included in the block&#8221;.  The previous three halving events occurred in 2012, 2016 and 2020.</p>
<p>With the halving completed, the first major implication is the reduction in the mining reward by 50%. This adjustment, preordained by the code governing Bitcoin&#8217;s blockchain, aims to maintain a hard cap of 21 million Bitcoin units and prevent inflation in the digital currency.</p>
<p>The first Bitcoin halving in 2012 rewarded miners with 50 BTC for mining a block and that constant reduction means miners will now earn 3.125 BTC per each mined block. This reduction mechanism is a constant programmed by Satoshi Nakamoto, Bitcoin’s anonymous founder.</p>
<p>Although Bitcoin advocates view the halving as a positive catalyst for the market as it will reduce the supply of new tokens amid rising demand, analysts have suggested that the event was largely priced into the market. Despite the potential bullish impact on the market, macroeconomic factors such as signals from the Federal Reserve and geopolitical tensions may temper short-term bullishness toward Bitcoin.</p>
<h2>Impact of Bitcoin Halving Event 2024</h2>
<p>The halving event is set to have a significant financial impact on Bitcoin mining companies, potentially wiping out billions of dollars in annual revenue. Ahead of this year’s halving, analysts at American investment banking giant<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/jpmorgan-chase/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co</a> (NYSE: JPM), highlighted challenges for miners to include production cost, decline in income, and electricity concerns.</p>
<p>Before the halving, several mining companies scouted for sustainable mining options with a Texas-based Bitcoin mining firm Giga Energy partnering with<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-miners-argentinian-firms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Argentinian Firms</a>. As the sector braces for consolidation, publicly-listed Bitcoin miners are expected to gain market share, leveraging greater access to funding and equity financing.</p>
<p>Past halving events have been completed without disrupting the functioning of the Bitcoin blockchain. Miners will now rely increasingly on transaction fees as a source of revenue amidst dwindling rewards. There are 64 expected halving events before reaching the 21 million cap around 2140 when all Bitcoin blocks would be mined.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the price trajectory of Bitcoin has remained little unchained despite speculations and projections by different analysts before the halving. For instance, Bitwise CEO <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitwise-ceo-bitcoin-price-halving-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hunter Horsley</a> predicted the digital asset’s surge to $100,000 after the halving event. However, market watchers say it is still too early but a bullish run is anticipated in the coming days.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, the price of Bitcoin is pegged at $63,665.87, down by 1.61% in the past 24 hours.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/tether-usdt-xaut-ton/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/bitcoin-halving-2024-market-dynamics/">Bitcoin Halving 2024: Implications for Miners and Market Dynamics</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tether Brings USDT and XAUT Stablecoins to TON Network</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/tether-usdt-xaut-ton/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Temitope Olatunji]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paolo ardoino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tether gold]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toncoin network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usdt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xaut]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/tether-usdt-xaut-ton/">Tether Brings USDT and XAUT Stablecoins to TON Network</a></p>
<p>Tether CEO further explained that expanding USDT and XAUT on The Open Network will help in the improvement of decentralized applications across different sectors.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/tether-usdt-xaut-ton/">Tether Brings USDT and XAUT Stablecoins to TON Network</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/tether-usdt-xaut-ton/">Tether Brings USDT and XAUT Stablecoins to TON Network</a></p>
<p>Tether, the prominent stablecoin issuer behind <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/tether/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USDT</a>, has made an announcement regarding the integration of its stablecoins on The Open Network (TON) blockchain. At the Token2049 crypto event in Dubai, Tether&#8217;s CEO Paolo Ardoino unveiled plans to launch both the US dollar-pegged USDT and the gold-backed Tether Gold (XAUT) stablecoins on the TON network.</p>
<p>Ardonio emphasized the impact of the expansion to the blockchain network; he revealed that the launch of USDT and XAUT on TON is expected to facilitate seamless value transfers and enhance liquidity within the ecosystem. By leveraging the blockchain, users can anticipate an experience comparable to traditional financial systems, while benefiting from the advantages of decentralized cryptocurrency infrastructure.</p>
<p>Tether&#8217;s CEO further explained that expanding USDT and <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/tether-gold/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XAUT</a> on The Open Network will help in the improvement of decentralized applications across different sectors, ultimately enhancing the functionality and utility of the TON ecosystem. It will also boost usage and seamless transaction between its telegram users.</p>
<p>According to the announcement, the USDT stablecoin will go live on the blockchain on April 20th, marking a milestone in Tether&#8217;s expansion strategy. The XAUT stablecoin will follow suit, although a specific launch date was not provided. This development represents growth for XAUT, as it will now be available on a second blockchain network, extending its reach beyond <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ethereum</a>.</p>
<p>The decision to integrate USDT and XAUT on the TON blockchain not only signifies an important step for Tether but also bolsters TON&#8217;s standing within the cryptocurrency market. Recently, its native cryptocurrency, Toncoin, surpassed the popular meme-coin Dogecoin in market capitalization, solidifying its position as a significant player in the crypto space.</p>
<h2>Toncoin Trading Volumes and Price Surge after Announcement</h2>
<p>The integration of Tether&#8217;s stablecoins on TON promises to deliver a more streamlined financial experience for traders and investors within its ecosystem. This development has already had an impact on the market performance of <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/the-open-network/">Toncoin</a>, with the announcement triggering a surge in trading volume and price appreciation.</p>
<p>In the hours following the news, Toncoin&#8217;s trading volume skyrocketed by 125%, while its price experienced a 30% increase. This uptick in trading activity and price appreciation reflects the confidence and optimism of traders and investors in the potential of the TON ecosystem, buoyed by the integration of Tether&#8217;s stablecoins. Moreover, Toncoin has risen to rank 8th in market capitalization, solidifying its position as a formidable player in the cryptocurrency market.</p>
<p>The growth of the coin’s popularity and market performance has been further reinforced by a recent announcement from Telegram. The messaging app declared recently that it will officially accept Toncoin as a payment method for advertisements on its platform. This development has also been part of the driving force behind the adoption and increase of onboarding within the TON ecosystem.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hashkey-deposits-withdrawals-binance-wallets/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/tether-usdt-xaut-ton/">Tether Brings USDT and XAUT Stablecoins to TON Network</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=3028 metric#misses=208 metric#hit-ratio=93.6 metric#bytes=1327543 metric#prefetches=234 metric#store-reads=182 metric#store-writes=15 metric#store-hits=241 metric#store-misses=178 metric#sql-queries=37 metric#ms-total=168.77 metric#ms-cache=22.07 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1126 metric#ms-cache-ratio=13.1 -->