<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>&lt;title&gt;</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
	<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/news/</link>
	<description>&lt;description&gt;</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:09:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.coinspeaker.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>News | Coinspeaker</title>
	<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/news/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Stablecoin Adoption Sees 15% Surge as Number of Holders Inches Close to 100M</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/stablecoin-adoption-surge-holders-100m/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/stablecoin-adoption-surge-holders-100m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mayowa Adebajo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stablecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stablecoin adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stablecoin regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=298051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/stablecoin-adoption-surge-holders-100m/">Stablecoin Adoption Sees 15% Surge as Number of Holders Inches Close to 100M</a></p>
<p>Despite their dominance in active address counts, TRON and BSC pale in comparison to Ethereum and Solana in terms of transfer volumes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/stablecoin-adoption-surge-holders-100m/">Stablecoin Adoption Sees 15% Surge as Number of Holders Inches Close to 100M</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/stablecoin-adoption-surge-holders-100m/">Stablecoin Adoption Sees 15% Surge as Number of Holders Inches Close to 100M</a></p>
<p>Stablecoins are fast growing in popularity, and the result is now evident in the number of addresses that hold them. According to the <a href="https://app.rwa.xyz/stablecoins?utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">data</a> from rwa.xyz, such addresses have climbed 15% this year alone, soaring to a record high of over 93.6 million.</p>
<p>These digital assets, which maintain a 1:1 peg to external references like the US dollar, can be classified into three main types. They are fiat-backed, crypto-backed, and algorithmic stablecoins.</p>
<p>Of all stablecoins, though, Tether (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/tether/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USDT</a>) is unquestionably the biggest in terms of the number of holders. About 80% of all stablecoin addresses hold USDT, then closely followed by USDC and BUSD. As of this publication, there are 35 stablecoins in circulation with a collective market capitalization of $157 billion. Of that lot, Tether USDT boasts a market cap of $114.07 billion.</p>
<p>As in the number of addresses that hold stablecoin, the number of addresses actively transferring stablecoins has also surged. March alone saw over 26 million active addresses, a record amount that signaled significant retail investor participation. These transactions took place primarily on TRON and Binance Smart Chain (BSC).</p>
<p>Meanwhile, despite their dominance in active address counts, TRON and BSC pale in comparison to Ethereum and Solana in terms of transfer volumes.</p>
<h2>Growing Use Cases</h2>
<p>It might be worth noting that the stablecoin holding addresses have been on a steady rise for months. Even during the 2022 crypto bear market and seemingly against all odds, the tally continued on the uptrend.</p>
<p>According to analysts, that growth could be linked to increased investor interest in assets that promise more stability. Especially considering the rapid interest rate hikes that the Federal Reserve was implementing at the time.</p>
<p>Besides, a 2022 Federal Reserve <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/ifdp/files/ifdp1334.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">report</a> also noted that there were rising use cases for stablecoins. These include and are not limited to cross-border payments, internal fund transfers, and liquidity management within firms.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the versatile digital assets can serve an array of purposes depending on the geographical location. For instance, a country like Zimbabwe struggling with inflation would utilize stablecoins for payments, remittances, and store of value assets. More stable economies, on the other hand, may use stablecoins to facilitate crypto purchases.</p>
<p>Rating agency S&amp;P predicts that regulatory clarity will encourage banks to adopt stablecoins. As Coinspeaker also recently <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/us-bill-unbacked-algorithmic-stablecoins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a>, US Senators Cynthia Lummis and Kirsten Gillibrand introduced a comprehensive 179-page bill aimed at regulating stablecoins.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/stablecoin-adoption-surge-holders-100m/">Stablecoin Adoption Sees 15% Surge as Number of Holders Inches Close to 100M</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/stablecoin-adoption-surge-holders-100m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Ethereum Be Classified as Security? Crypto Analyst Offers Perspective on Raging Controversy</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Temitope Olatunji]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eth etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ether etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaneck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=298041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/">Will Ethereum Be Classified as Security? Crypto Analyst Offers Perspective on Raging Controversy</a></p>
<p>The debate on whether Ethereum should be classified as a security or not holds significant implications for the potential approval of an Ethereum ETF</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/">Will Ethereum Be Classified as Security? Crypto Analyst Offers Perspective on Raging Controversy</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/">Will Ethereum Be Classified as Security? Crypto Analyst Offers Perspective on Raging Controversy</a></p>
<p>The cryptocurrency space has been in a debate concerning the approval of Ethereum as a security by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/sec/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEC</a>). This discussion has been ongoing for a considerable period, with various analysts and industry experts offering diverse perspectives on the matter&#8217;s outcome.</p>
<h2>New York Attorney General Fuels the Debate</h2>
<p>Recently, a crypto analyst and legal adviser Metalaw <a href="https://x.com/MetaLawMan/status/1782802278732234823" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">weighed</a> in on the matter, making reference to the action taken by New York Attorney General (NYAG) Letitia James approximately a year ago. In this past move, Attorney General James made headlines by publicly asserting that Ethereum, one of the leading cryptocurrencies in the market, is a security.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Will <a href="https://twitter.com/GaryGensler?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GaryGensler</a> declare <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24ETH&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$ETH</a> a security?</p>
<p>Maybe.</p>
<p>Don&#39;t forget, NYAG Letitia James already did this a year ago and issued a press release trumpeting the move.</p>
<p>&quot;This action is one of the first times a regulator is claiming in court that ETH, one of the largest cryptocurrencies…</p>
<p>&mdash; MetaLawMan (@MetaLawMan) <a href="https://twitter.com/MetaLawMan/status/1782802278732234823?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>This assertion was made during a legal battle against the cryptocurrency exchange KuCoin, where <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ethereum</a> was likened to LUNA and UST. James&#8217; argument hinges on the notion that ETH  is a speculative asset that relies on the efforts of third-party developers to generate profits for its holders, thereby necessitating registration as a security before being sold.</p>
<p>The debate on whether Ethereum should be classified as a security or not holds significant implications for the potential approval of an Ethereum ETF, as securities are subject to stringent regulatory oversight and registration requirements. This stance has garnered attention, as SEC Chairman Gary Gensler has refused to deny the possibility of Ethereum being classified as a security, stating that it depends on the facts and the laws of the United States.</p>
<h2>Diverging Views from Industry Experts</h2>
<p>While the approval of Ethereum as a security could lead to an ETH ETF approval, it has generated excitement among traders and investors who anticipate a potential price surge akin to the one witnessed after the approval of the Bitcoin ETF. However, issuers of the ETH ETF have expressed skepticism about a positive outcome.</p>
<p>VanEck CEO Jan van Eck has indicated that the approval is likely to be rejected, drawing parallels with the lengthy process involved in the approval of Bitcoin ETFs. He stated that regulators typically provide comments on applications, and this process took weeks before the Bitcoin ETFs were approved, but currently, no such signs are evident for Ethereum.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Eric Balchunas, a senior ETF analyst at Bloomberg, has estimated the odds of spot ether ETFs being approved in May at a mere 35%. While acknowledging that there are reasons for approval, he noted that the signs and sources that previously indicated optimism for the Bitcoin spot ETF approval are lacking in Ethereum&#8217;s case.</p>
<p>As the debate on whether Ethereum is a security or not gets intense, the cryptocurrency community stays hopeful, eagerly awaiting a decision that could push the price of Ethereum even higher. Traders and investors see the approval as a powerful catalyst that might spark a bullish rally. This is supported by observations of large wallet holders <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/whales-ethereum-xrp-fluctuations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">purchasing more ETH</a>, indicating strong confidence in its future.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/">Will Ethereum Be Classified as Security? Crypto Analyst Offers Perspective on Raging Controversy</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/ethereum-security-crypto-analyst/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria’s Central Bank Issues Denial Regarding Alleged Freeze on Crypto Accounts</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bena Ilyas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/">Nigeria&#8217;s Central Bank Issues Denial Regarding Alleged Freeze on Crypto Accounts</a></p>
<p>The situation be­came confusion when the ce­ntral bank of Nigeria initially refuted the re­port on X, only to remove the de­nial. Later, they asse­rted that the allegations we­re indeed false, leading to uncertainty regarding the­ true circumstances.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/">Nigeria&#8217;s Central Bank Issues Denial Regarding Alleged Freeze on Crypto Accounts</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/">Nigeria&#8217;s Central Bank Issues Denial Regarding Alleged Freeze on Crypto Accounts</a></p>

<p>The Ce­ntral Bank of Nigeria (CBN) <a href="https://twitter.com/cenbank/status/1783081492018602076" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">rejecte­d</a> claims it instructed banks and financial companies to identify crypto exchange users. Re­ports stated accounts engaging in such transactions were put on Post No Debit (PND) for six-month re­strictions. However, the CBN de­nied issuing directives re­quiring identification of crypto traders and temporary account fre­ezes. </p>



<p>The situation be­came confusion when the ce­ntral bank initially refuted the re­port on X, only to remove the de­nial. Later, they asse­rted that the allegations we­re indeed false, leading to uncertainty regarding the­ true circumstances.</p>
<p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This information does not originate from the Central Bank of Nigeria. <br><br>For authentic updates, please visit the official website of the Bank at <a href="https://t.co/R9TQU0eRpp">https://t.co/R9TQU0eRpp</a>. <a href="https://t.co/LCoUvalMRy">pic.twitter.com/LCoUvalMRy</a></p>&mdash; Central Bank of Nigeria (@cenbank) <a href="https://twitter.com/cenbank/status/1783081492018602076?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 24, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>



<p>In Decembe­r 2023, the financial institution allowed banks to facilitate transactions for lice­nsed crypto exchanges, lifting a two-ye­ar prohibition. However, this rece­nt reversal shows growing concerns within the Nigerian gove­rnment regarding cryptocurrency&#8217;s pote­ntial impact on economic stability within the nation.</p>



<h2 id="h-binance-faces-scrutiny-amid-nigeria-s-naira-crisis" class="wp-block-heading">Binance Faces Scrutiny amid Nigeria&#8217;s Naira Crisis</h2>



<p>Nigeria has been struggling with substantial devaluations of its nationwide curre­ncy, the naira. Inflation escalated to an alarming 29.9% by April 2024. See­king stability, authorities scrutinize cryptocurrency platforms, vie­wing them as potential destabilize­rs amidst this financial turmoil.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/binance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Binance</a>, the­ largest crypto exchange, has been a focal point of the CBN&#8217;s scrutiny. In 2023, the bank raised concerns about $26 billion worth of suspicious financial transactions passing through Binance­ Nigeria. These transactions alle­gedly involved unknown sources and use­rs, prompting investigations.  </p>



<p>Adding fuel to the fire, Binance executive Tigran Gambaryan currently <a href="https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/stock-market-today-dow-jones-04-03-2024/card/binance-and-its-detained-american-staffer-face-more-charges-in-nigeria-ymYObhVbuplBK9gYvhAv" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">faces</a> alle­gations of money laundering in Nigeria, according to officials regarding regulations. Me­anwhile, another executive, Nadeem Anjarwalla, who accompanie­d Gambaryan, evaded custody and currently faces e­xtradition proceedings from Kenya. </p>



<p>The CBN pre­viously restricted access to we­bsites facilitating crypto trading, allowing users the unofficial exchange­ rates for the Nigerian Naira. This move highlights their concerns regarding unregulated channels pote­ntially influencing the currency&#8217;s valuation. </p>



<p>For the Nige­rian crypto community, clear regulations are e­ssential for a secure digital asse­t landscape. Establishing guideline­s promotes legitimacy. Furthermore, imple­menting measures to protect users&#8217; interests is vital to e­nsure a fair and balanced approach towards cryptocurrency adoption in Nige­ria.</p>
<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/" rel="prev">next</a><p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/">Nigeria&#8217;s Central Bank Issues Denial Regarding Alleged Freeze on Crypto Accounts</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/nigerias-central-bank-crypto-accounts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto Messaging App iMe Partners DWF Labs for Ecosystem Growth </title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chimamanda U. Martha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dwf labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[floki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[klaytn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=298030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/">Crypto Messaging App iMe Partners DWF Labs for Ecosystem Growth </a></p>
<p>iMe said the partnership with DWF Labs will significantly impact the future of decentralized communication and finance.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/">Crypto Messaging App iMe Partners DWF Labs for Ecosystem Growth </a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/">Crypto Messaging App iMe Partners DWF Labs for Ecosystem Growth </a></p>
<p>iMe Platform, a Web3 social media messaging app powered by Telegram&#8217;s application programming interface (API), has secured a strategic partnership with DWF Labs, a crypto-focused market maker, to promote its ecosystem and enhance growth.</p>
<p>The platform, co-founded by Alex Borutskiy, offers multifunctional capabilities, granting users access to the decentralized finance (DeFi) ecosystem and the artificial intelligence (AI) market. It also includes a crypto wallet that enables users to interact with the emerging economy.</p>
<h2>iMe Partners DWF Labs for Ecosystem Expansion</h2>
<p>iMe plans to further develop its ecosystem through its partnership with DWF Labs.</p>
<p>In a social media <a href="https://x.com/iMePlatform/status/1783071643117474276" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">announcement</a> on April 24, the platform said the collaboration with the crypto market maker was accompanied by a financial investment, although the multifunctional messaging app did not disclose the amount it received from DWF Labs.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">🔥 iMe and <a href="https://twitter.com/DWFLabs?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DWFLabs</a> have officially joined forces in a strategic partnership! 🔥</p>
<p>⚡️ DWF Labs represents the new generation of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Web3?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Web3</a> investors and market makers, distinguishing itself as one of the world&#39;s foremost high-frequency crypto trading entities.</p>
<p>🙌 The scope of the… <a href="https://t.co/T0szz41lRm">pic.twitter.com/T0szz41lRm</a></p>
<p>&mdash; iMe Smart Platform (@iMePlatform) <a href="https://twitter.com/iMePlatform/status/1783071643117474276?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 24, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>The Web3 platform said the funds will empower the project to fulfill its commitment to the community while exploring new avenues for growth and innovation. Additionally, the funds will provide the necessary resources and support to expand its reach and impact.</p>
<p>In addition to the financial investment, the partnership will see DWF Labs provide market-making and yield support to iMe. The move aims to foster a more vibrant trading environment within the iMe ecosystem.</p>
<p>The market-making is expected to enhance liquidity and trading opportunities for users interacting with the platform, ultimately driving the project&#8217;s growth and success.</p>
<h2>Blockchain Partnerships with DWF Labs</h2>
<p>iMe said the partnership with DWF Labs will significantly impact the future of decentralized communication and finance. The union is expected to bring about positive changes and advancements in the crypto space.</p>
<p>&#8220;The union between iMe and DWF Labs will redefine the future of decentralized communication and finance, bringing accessible and hype-worthy technology to the #crypto community worldwide,&#8221; said iMe on X.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, iMe is not the only crypto platform that has recently partnered with DWF Labs. This year alone, other blockchain projects such as Klaytn and Floki Inu have also secured strategic partnerships with the firm.</p>
<p>Klaytn, an open-source, public blockchain known for its focus on enterprise-grade reliability and scalability, received financial investment from DWF Labs through the sale of its native token, KLAY. On the other hand, Floki Inu, a meme project inspired by Elon Musk&#8217;s Shiba Inu dog, secured a substantial $10 million investment from DWF Labs.</p>
<p>In 2023, DWF Labs invested in several other projects, including TokenFi, DMCC, ARPA Network, AirDAO, and <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/dwf-labs-doubles-down-conflux-28-m-invested/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Conflux</a>. These investments reflect DWF Labs&#8217; commitment to supporting innovative blockchain projects and technologies across the industry.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/">Crypto Messaging App iMe Partners DWF Labs for Ecosystem Growth </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/crypto-ime-partners-dwf-labs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Floki and Pepe Leads in Bullish Breakout Ahead of Anticipated Meme Coin Season</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Muchoki]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[floki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pepe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiba inu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sib]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=298018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/">Floki and Pepe Leads in Bullish Breakout Ahead of Anticipated Meme Coin Season</a></p>
<p>The meme coin industry, led by Dogecoin and Shiba Inu, has played a crucial role in onboarding more investors to the cryptocurrency industry.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/">Floki and Pepe Leads in Bullish Breakout Ahead of Anticipated Meme Coin Season</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/">Floki and Pepe Leads in Bullish Breakout Ahead of Anticipated Meme Coin Season</a></p>
<p>The meme coin industry has grown to a major sector, with more than $56 billion in market cap and around $7.6 billion in daily average trading volume. Almost all layer-one (L1) and layer-two (L2) chains are using flashy meme coins to attract more on-chain activities.</p>
<p>Moreover, the initial rise of Shiba Inu (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/shiba-inu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SHIB</a>), and Dogecoin (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/dogecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOGE</a>) has inspired a new generation of meme coins including frog-themed, and cat-themed, among many others. The meme coin industry is expected to continue playing a crucial role in the ongoing crypto bull run.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, investors should be extra vigilant while dealing with new and flashy meme coins to avoid holding coins without liquidity and have high potential risks of rug pulls.</p>
<h2>Top Meme Coin to Lead Bullish Recovery</h2>
<p>Bitcoin dominance has been eating into the altcoin market cap for the past year fueled by the heightened demand from institutional investors. However, most analysts believe an altseason will kickstart soon as BTC holders continue to distribute their profits to different altcoins.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, traders should keep a close watch on the ETH/BTC pair, which is the ultimate indicator of the onset of the anticipated altseason.</p>
<h2>Floki (FLOKI)</h2>
<p>Floki is a fast-growing meme coin, with a fully diluted valuation of about $2 billion, backed by a thriving community. According to the latest market data, the Floki price edged over 15 percent higher in the past 24 hours to trade around $0.002 on Wednesday during the mid-London session.</p>
<p>According to a popular crypto analyst alias Captain Faibik, Floki&#8217;s price is en route to retesting its all-time high (ATH) following a breakout of a daily bullish flag. Notably, the crypto analyst expects the Floki price to rally as much as 3X from current levels in the coming days.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24FLOKI&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$FLOKI</a> has also Broke out of Bullish Flag on the Daily timeframe Chart. ✅</p>
<p>Looks Promising for 2-3x Bullish Rally in the Coming Days. 📈<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Crypto?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Crypto</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FLOKI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FLOKI</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FLOKIUSDT?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FLOKIUSDT</a> <a href="https://t.co/Q2Jsr3h027">pic.twitter.com/Q2Jsr3h027</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Captain Faibik (@CryptoFaibik) <a href="https://twitter.com/CryptoFaibik/status/1782981498297057549?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 24, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>The Floki ecosystem is fast transforming into a vibrant web3 ecosystem, especially through its FlokiFi Locker system. For instance, Altoscan, a web3 project developing an open-source block explorer compatible with all rollups, used Floki Locker to lock $18 million worth of $ATS for 15 months on Tuesday.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="474" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">And more. <a href="https://t.co/UFbG427yda">pic.twitter.com/UFbG427yda</a></p>
<p>&mdash; FLOKI (@RealFlokiInu) <a href="https://twitter.com/RealFlokiInu/status/1783066735177773457?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 24, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<h2>Pepe (PEPE)</h2>
<p>As <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/when-will-pepe-continue-its-bullish-rally-as-bears-show-no-sign-of-slowing-down/">Coinspeaker previously reported</a>, frog-themed and Ethereum-based meme coin, Pepe (PEPE), has faced immense competition from other potentially influential meme coins led by Solana-based projects.  According to the latest market data, Pepe&#8217;s price gained over 17 percent in the past 24 hours to trade around $0.0000079 at the time of this report.</p>
<p>Following the recent uproar, Captain Faibik <a href="https://x.com/cryptofaibik/status/1782980847269818714?s=46" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">believes</a> Pepe&#8217;s price is well positioned for at least a 3X rally in the coming days.</p>
<p>Notably, Coinbase International announced on Tuesday that its 1000PEPE-PERP, its latest perpetual future listing based on Pepe, is now available for trading.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/">Floki and Pepe Leads in Bullish Breakout Ahead of Anticipated Meme Coin Season</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/floki-pepe-bullish-meme-coin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renzo Introduced REZ Tokenomics and ezPoints Claiming Details</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Godfrey Benjamin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rez]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=298014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/">Renzo Introduced REZ Tokenomics and ezPoints Claiming Details</a></p>
<p>While the total supply of the REZ token is 10 billion, the initial circulating supply is pegged at 1.05 billion.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/">Renzo Introduced REZ Tokenomics and ezPoints Claiming Details</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/">Renzo Introduced REZ Tokenomics and ezPoints Claiming Details</a></p>
<p>With the end of Renzo&#8217;s Season 1 ezPoints campaign drawing closer, the liquid staking protocol has <a href="https://mirror.xyz/renzoprotocol.eth/gwO9wyZoOTg79yUw1hnS6q_eJGvfCj1CkmQFa8z32zU" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">released REZ tokenomics</a> and the claiming details of the ezPoints.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ieo/renzo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Renzo Protocol</a>, the Season 1 ezPoints campaign will end on April 26. The protocol confirms that it has experienced immense growth in the volume of active users and the Total Value Locked (TVL). The growth in its TVL has placed Renzo amongst the top 10 Decentralized Finance (DeFi) protocols.</p>
<h2>Renzo Season 2 Starts on April 26</h2>
<p>Notably, Season 2 will kick off almost immediately as the current season ends on Friday, April 26. The decentralization process will follow on April 30 and this will be marked by the launch of REZ, the native token of the Renzo Protocol.</p>
<p>Users cannot claim their REZ until May 2 when 5% of the total REZ supply will be distributed, representing 500 million units. The distribution would be done based on each user&#8217;s accumulated ezPoints. Notably, 2% of the earmarked 5% airdrop will go to Milady Maker and SchizoPosters communities respectively.</p>
<p>While the total supply of the REZ token is 10 billion, the initial circulating supply is pegged at 1.05 billion. The largest percentage of the token distribution will be allocated to investors and the smallest (2.5%) to Launchpool like Binance which recently announced the restaking protocol as its <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/binance-renzo-53rd-project-launchpool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">53rd project</a>.</p>
<p>Most of the largest wallets will be subjected to a 50% unlock at TGE and another 50% linear, vesting over six months. Renzo Protocol plans to relocate unclaimed or unvested tokens to loyal users who maintain their relationship with the platform. Eligible wallets from Season 1 will get additional boost for the next phase but this is based on a condition.</p>
<p>“&#8230;..as long as your ezETH balance from Season 1 remains in your wallet or in any of the Renzo DeFi integrations,” the protocol noted.</p>
<p>The REZ token can be used for several activities including for voting on governance proposals, precisely for matters involving the Renzo Protocol.</p>
<h2>Renzo Season 1 Comes to an End</h2>
<p>Some of the highlights from Season 1 are a deposit of $3.5 billion, restaking market share of 33.5%, and over 250,000 users.</p>
<p>For a liquid staking protocol that launched barely four months ago, Renzo has hit several significant milestones. In this short time, the protocol was able to unlock native restaking on seven networks including Ethereum, Coinbase&#8217;s Base, Arbitrum, Mode, Blast, BNB Smart Chain, and Linea. Renzo also recorded ezETH on Layer-2 accounts for 24% of the total Renzo TVL.</p>
<p>Per a published statement, Renzo stated that it is the first restaking protocol to bring both native ETH and LST deposits, with stETH and wBETH making up about $110 million of the TVL in a matter of two weeks of its launch.</p>
<p>Since January till now, Renzo has been <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-chainlink-ethereum-liquid-eigenlayer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">integrated</a> into Morpho Blue, Balancer, Curve, Pendle, and some other platforms.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/">Renzo Introduced REZ Tokenomics and ezPoints Claiming Details</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/renzo-rez-tokenomics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Australia Records 1,000 Bitcoin ATMs Milestone</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mayowa Adebajo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin atm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc atm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/">Australia Records 1,000 Bitcoin ATMs Milestone</a></p>
<p>By April 2023, the country had already overtaken Asia on the Bitcoin ATM count roll.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/">Australia Records 1,000 Bitcoin ATMs Milestone</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/">Australia Records 1,000 Bitcoin ATMs Milestone</a></p>
<p>Active Bitcoin ATMs in Australia have now crossed the 1,000 mark, making the country the third-largest hub for crypto ATMs. As of publication, Australia now hosts an active network of 1,002 <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitcoin</a> ATMs, and joins the United States and Canada as the only countries to achieve this feat.</p>
<p>Australia&#8217;s latest figure means that the country now hosts 2.7% of the global Bitcoin ATM network. Meanwhile, the <a href="https://coinatmradar.com/charts/geo-distribution/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">data</a> from Coin ATM Radar suggests that the US hosted its first 1,000 crypto ATMs in November 2017. Canada also hit the milestone in January 2021.</p>
<p>However, the US has now added many more, and is now home to 31,170 machines, an impressive 82.8% of the global Bitcoin ATMs. Canada on the other hand currently controls 2,918 crypto ATMs, accounting for 7.8% of the global lot.</p>
<h2>Growing Adoption of Bitcoin ATMs in Australia</h2>
<p>Interestingly, the Bitcoin ATM market was relatively inactive in Australia until the end of 2022. However, as private firms began to enter into the market, it blossomed exponentially.</p>
<p>The timing of this surge is noteworthy, with Australia&#8217;s ascent coinciding with a global wave of interest in cryptocurrencies. By April 2023, the country had already overtaken Asia on the Bitcoin ATM count roll. That means it had a count greater than China, Japan, Singapore and India combined.</p>
<p>With its current installation momentum, Australia is poised to surpass even Europe any time soon. Europe currently boasts a network of 1,617 Bitcoin ATMs, representing 4.3% of the global size. Member countries in Europe that have significant numbers of crypto ATMs include Spain with 261, El Salvador (215), Poland (211), and Germany (194).</p>
<p>Australia&#8217;s journey towards crypto dominance is not without challenges. Regulatory scrutiny, security concerns, and market volatility stand as potential roadblocks. However, the nation&#8217;s unwavering commitment to innovation and its embrace of emerging technologies speak well for a promising future in the crypto sphere.</p>
<p>As Australia celebrates this milestone, it sends a clear message to the world about its intent to be at the forefront of global crypto adoption. Despite a slow start, Australia may just have positioned itself as a global crypto hub.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/">Australia Records 1,000 Bitcoin ATMs Milestone</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/australia-1000-bitcoin-atms-milestone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong Set to Launch Approved Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs Next Week</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chimamanda U. Martha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funds & ETFs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eth etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ether etf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum etf]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/">Hong Kong Set to Launch Approved Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs Next Week</a></p>
<p>The launch of the ETFs next week in Hong Kong will likely draw comparisons with the three-month-old US Bitcoin funds, which have already made a significant impact on Wall Street.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/">Hong Kong Set to Launch Approved Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs Next Week</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/">Hong Kong Set to Launch Approved Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs Next Week</a></p>
<p>Hong Kong is on the brink of introducing its crypto-based exchange-traded funds (ETFs) for trading. According to a recent Bloomberg report citing people familiar with the matter, the country&#8217;s spot Bitcoin (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BTC</a>) and Ethereum (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ether</a>) ETFs will debut on exchanges early next week.</p>
<p>The new developments follow Hong Kong&#8217;s <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-spot-bitcoin-ethereum-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">approval</a> of several crypto ETF applications on April 15, 2024. Chinese financial services companies such as China Asset Management and Bosera Capital, through their Hong Kong subsidiaries, obtained approval from the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) to offer their customers new investment products.</p>
<h2>Hong Kong to Begin Trading ETFs by April Ending</h2>
<p>Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-23/hong-kong-bitcoin-btc-ether-eth-etf-launches-to-test-crypto-hub-ambition">said</a> that these companies are already in the final stages of preparation to commence trading for the crypto investment vehicles by the end of April.</p>
<p>Investors in the Asian market will soon have access to both BTC and Ether through these ETFs, allowing them to invest in the two leading cryptocurrencies without directly engaging with the digital asset market.</p>
<p>The ETF boom began in January when the US Securities and Exchange Commission (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/sec/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEC</a>) <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/sec-11-spot-bitcoin-etfs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">approved</a> 11 applications submitted by asset managers like BlackRock, Grayscale Investments, Fidelity Investments, ARK 21 Shares, and Invesco Galaxy.</p>
<p>With the US leading the way, Hong Kong has joined the trend, paving the way for investors in the Asian region to explore the crypto economy.</p>
<p>However, unlike Bitcoin ETFs in the US, which are structured for cash redemption, Hong Kong&#8217;s crypto ETFs will utilize an in-kind subscription and redemption model. This approach allows for the direct exchange of underlying assets for ETF units and vice versa.</p>
<h2>Potential Inflows vs Expectations</h2>
<p>Bloomberg&#8217;s report suggested that the launch of the ETFs next week in Hong Kong will likely draw comparisons with the three-month-old US Bitcoin funds, which have already made a significant impact on Wall Street. The US ETFs have already accumulated a total of $56 billion in assets, and the crypto community anticipates that Hong Kong&#8217;s ETFs will achieve similar success if mainland Chinese investors are allowed to participate in the market.</p>
<p>Last week, Coinspeaker <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ether-etf-china/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that Alessio Quaglini, the CEO of Hex Trust, a crypto custodian firm, said there is a chance Chinese investors might have access to Hong Kong&#8217;s crypto ETFs due to unclear regulations regarding these funds in the country.</p>
<p>Analysts speculate that if Chinese investors are able to participate, the ETFs could attract a massive inflow of around $25 billion.</p>
<p>However, Bloomberg&#8217;s ETF expert, Eric Balchunas, believes that Hong Kong might realistically see inflows of up to $500 million, considering the SFC has yet to approve ETFs from major asset management giants like <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/blackrock/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BlackRock</a>.</p>
<p>Bloomberg also noted that the amount of funds generated from these crypto ETFs will indicate Hong Kong&#8217;s progress toward becoming a leading financial hub for cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>The country, along with Dubai, Singapore, and the United Kingdom, is competing to become a hub for modern financial innovations.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/">Hong Kong Set to Launch Approved Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs Next Week</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/hong-kong-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-next-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Worldcoin to Boost WLD Supply by 19% in Next Six Months, WLD Price under Pressure</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bhushan Akolkar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam altman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wld]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worldcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/">Worldcoin to Boost WLD Supply by 19% in Next Six Months, WLD Price under Pressure</a></p>
<p>Worldcoin will pump a staggering 1.5 million WLD tokens every week for six months straight would lead to an increase of 36 million WLD token supply, amounting to ~$200 million as per the current supply.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/">Worldcoin to Boost WLD Supply by 19% in Next Six Months, WLD Price under Pressure</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/">Worldcoin to Boost WLD Supply by 19% in Next Six Months, WLD Price under Pressure</a></p>
<p>Sam Altman&#8217;s iris-scanning digital identity project Worldcoin announced that it would increase the supply of its WLD tokens by a staggering 19% over the period of the next six months. Worldcoin said that it plans to implement this through the private sale to non-US institutions.</p>
<p>In its blog post on Tuesday, April 23, Worldcoin stated that the Worldcoin foundation subsidiary World Assets, which is in charge of the WLD assets, will sell nearly 1.5 million Worldcoins (WLD) worth a staggering $8.5 million every week via a series of “private placements to a select group of institutional trading firms” outside the United States.</p>
<p>“World Assets expects to sell between 0.5 million and 1.5 million WLD per week on average. The circulating supply of WLD will thus increase correspondingly,&#8221; noted Worldcoin in its <a href="https://worldcoin.org/blog/announcements/circulating-supply-update-sales-trading-firms" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">blog post</a>.</p>
<p>Pumping a staggering 1.5 million WLD tokens every week for six months straight would lead to an increase of 36 million WLD token supply, amounting to ~$200 million as per the current supply. Worldcoin currently has a supply of 193 million WLD tokens in the market. This shows that it is planning to add nearly 19% of the additional supply to the market.</p>
<p>As soon as the news of Worldcoin increasing the WLD supply spread, the price of the WLD token came under some selling pressure. As of press time, Worldcoin (WLD) is trading 3.5% down at a price of $5.45 and a market cap of over $1.058 billion.</p>
<p>Worldcoin stated its intention to engage in negotiations with individual trading firms, particularly those in competition with one another, to conduct private placements at or near prevailing Worldcoin (WLD) market prices. This strategy aims to mitigate the potential price impact on the token.</p>
<h2>About the Worldcoin (WLD) Project</h2>
<p>Worldcoin is the pet project of OpenAI CEO <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/persons/sam-altman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sam Altman</a> current Wolrdcoin CEO Alex Blania, and Max Novendstern, launched last year in July 2023, in beta. This crypto-based digital identity project markets itself as providing a solution to identity issues evolving through rapid developments in AI along with a push for a new model of universal basic income through its native WLD token.</p>
<p>Users of Worldcoin register their identity through the company&#8217;s &#8220;World App&#8221; by scanning their retinas at machines called &#8220;Orbs,&#8221; as designated by the company. In return for their biometric data, users receive approximately 25 Worldcoin, which is presently valued at around $137.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/">Worldcoin to Boost WLD Supply by 19% in Next Six Months, WLD Price under Pressure</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/worldcoin-boost-wld-supply/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple Switches US On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) Clients from XRP to USDT Following Last Year’s Court Order</title>
		<link>https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/</link>
					<comments>https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tolu Ajiboye]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 10:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[odl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usdt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.coinspeaker.com/?p=297981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/">Ripple Switches US On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) Clients from XRP to USDT Following Last Year&#8217;s Court Order</a></p>
<p>Ripple has allegedly moved all US ODL customers from using XRP as the bridge currency, to USDT, in compliance with a 2023 court ruling.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/">Ripple Switches US On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) Clients from XRP to USDT Following Last Year&#8217;s Court Order</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com">Coinspeaker</a><br />
<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/">Ripple Switches US On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) Clients from XRP to USDT Following Last Year&#8217;s Court Order</a></p>
<p>A recent court filing submitted by <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/ripple-labs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ripple</a> against the United States Securities and Exchange Commission (<a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/organizations/sec/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEC</a>) reveals that Ripple has made a few changes to its services in the United States. According to the filing, Ripple now uses Tether’s USDT instead of XRP as the bridge currency for its On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) services for US clients.</p>
<h2>Ripple Uses USDT for ODL in the US</h2>
<p>Ripple’s decision to switch to USDT stems from last year’s court ruling, which concluded that the institutional sale of <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/xrp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XRP</a> tokens violates security laws in the US. Following the verdict, Ripple decided to use non-US entities as contract parties to handle the sale of XRP to ODL customers. The filing also notes that all ODL clients in the US now use “a non-XRP bridge currency”.</p>
<p>In addition to the filing, a popular XRP proponent Crypto Eri posted an update on X. Crypto Eri’s post contains a screenshot of an alleged internal note from Ripple President Monica Long detailing the company’s move to XRP from <a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/coins/tether/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USDT</a>. According to Long:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Immediately following the Order, we took steps to migrate each US-based ODL customer from using XRP as the bridge currency in ODL to using USDT (or the contract was terminated.) We should continue to use USDT (or BTC or other vetted stablecoins) for US based flows unless otherwise approved by Legal.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Making this change indicates Ripple’s willingness to continue providing its ODL services to customers in the US, while adhering to legal restrictions. Long’s message specified the non-US entities used for ODL are Singaporean. The Ripple president noted that these entities are the primary contracting entities used to sell XRP contracts to new ODL customers “who are predominantly foreign.”</p>
<p>Long also included an XRP minimum requirement enforced in 2023. According to Crypto Eri’s image, Ripple required all ODL customers or their corporate owners to have at least $5 million in assets, except for “otherwise sophisticated entities.” She added that Legal gets to determine whether or not an entity qualifies as “sophisticated.” The rule is likely to ensure that ODL clients have robust reserves to continuously cater to their business needs and protect the end customers.</p>
<h2>XRP Sales May Affect Ripple&#8217;s Revenue</h2>
<p>Ripple’s filing contains indications that XRP sales are integral to the company’s financials. The document shows that according to Ripple’s accounting expert, Anthony Bracco, Ripple’s books show that without accounting for revenue from the sale of XRP, the company operated a loss from April 1, 2014, through December 22, 2020.</p>
<p>Ripple recently filed a motion against the SEC, disputing the agency’s request for a $2 billion fine against the company. According to Ripple, the fine should be $10 million at most. In the <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/z57n3w37mr6mirqaajutn/Ripple-Remedies-Opposition-4.22.24.pdf?rlkey=dzxh1l6z47qcczbckorjncchp&amp;e=2&amp;dl=0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">filing</a>, Ripple notes that it is willing to adhere to guidance in the future. However, the company says the SEC’s requests are “Draconian” and “ungrounded in law or principle”. Ripple has asked the court to reject the request.<a class="infinscroll_next_page_link" style="display:none" href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/left-curve-arthur-hayes-crypto-surge/" rel="prev">next</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/">Ripple Switches US On-Demand Liquidity (ODL) Clients from XRP to USDT Following Last Year&#8217;s Court Order</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.coinspeaker.com/ripple-odl-clients-xrp-usdt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=2894 metric#misses=186 metric#hit-ratio=94.0 metric#bytes=1315472 metric#prefetches=220 metric#store-reads=159 metric#store-writes=16 metric#store-hits=228 metric#store-misses=156 metric#sql-queries=39 metric#ms-total=151.19 metric#ms-cache=21.94 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1261 metric#ms-cache-ratio=14.5 -->