<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Merkle News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://themerkle.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://themerkle.com/</link>
	<description>HODL</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:22:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2016/03/cropped-merkle-white-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>The Merkle News</title>
	<link>https://themerkle.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>BlockDAG&#8217;s 30,000X ROI Potential Vs. Chainlink &#038;Toncoin</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/blockdags-30000x-roi-potential-vs-chainlink-toncoin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Best Presale to Buy: Chainlink And Toncoin Overshadowed By BlockDAG&#8217;s 30,000X ROI Potential, Moonshot Teasers, And Miner X30  Standing out in the world of cryptocurrency requires innovation and resilience. This introduction delves into how Chainlink&#8217;s durability and Toncoin&#8217;s AI partnerships measure up in the crypto economy, compared to how BlockDAG sustains but excels by leveraging innovative technology.  The analysis evaluates cryptocurrency market performance, highlighting BlockDAG&#8217;s advanced tech infrastructure enhanced by futuristic devices like Miner X30, setting it up for a potential 30,000x ROI. With a remarkable $20.1 million already raised in presales and a striking celebration in Las Vegas, coupled </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/blockdags-30000x-roi-potential-vs-chainlink-toncoin/">BlockDAG&#8217;s 30,000X ROI Potential Vs. Chainlink &amp;Toncoin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Best Presale to Buy: Chainlink And Toncoin Overshadowed By BlockDAG&#8217;s 30,000X ROI Potential, Moonshot Teasers, And Miner X30 </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Standing out in the world of cryptocurrency requires innovation and resilience. This introduction delves into how Chainlink&#8217;s durability and Toncoin&#8217;s AI partnerships measure up in the crypto economy, compared to how </span><a href="https://blockdag.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">BlockDAG</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> sustains but excels by leveraging innovative technology. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The analysis evaluates cryptocurrency market performance, highlighting BlockDAG&#8217;s advanced tech infrastructure enhanced by futuristic devices like Miner X30, setting it up for a potential 30,000x ROI. With a remarkable $20.1 million already raised in presales and a striking celebration in Las Vegas, coupled with an exciting moonshot keynote teaser, BlockDAG is positioning itself for universal recognition. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Analysing Chainlink&#8217;s 48% Price Drop &amp; Recovery</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Chainlink has demonstrated remarkable resilience in the face of market downturns. Recently, despite a substantial drop from a yearly high of $22.86 to $11.78, representing a 48% decrease, Chainlink managed a robust recovery. On April 13, the price rebounded, reclaiming a long-standing support level at $13.25, defying the initial breakdown predictions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"> <a href="https://blockdag.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-80743 size-large" src="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161224_200-1024x128.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="85" srcset="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161224_200-1024x128.jpg 1024w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161224_200-300x38.jpg 300w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161224_200.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This rebound was supported by a bullish divergence in the RSI indicator, a promising sign of potential upward momentum reminiscent of the previous 370% surge in late 2023. With these technical indicators, investors are keenly watching Chainlink as it hints at another significant price rise, bolstering its position among the top altcoins for 2024.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>AI Partnerships Propel Toncoin into DeFi Spotlight</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin has seen its influence in the DeFi sector skyrocket, with a threefold increase in user activity and a total value locked (TVL) surged to $157.8 million. This growth is spurred by strategic AI-related partnerships and consistent market performance that saw the cryptocurrency hit new all-time highs multiple times last month. Currently trading at $7.00, Toncoin reflects a robust bullish sentiment, driven by a recent 85% price surge. Its ability to consistently outperform market expectations and its entrenched position in the top ten cryptocurrencies make it a </span><span style="font-weight: 400">formidable player in the digital finance arena.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-80742" src="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161226_707.jpg" alt="" width="900" height="600" srcset="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161226_707.jpg 900w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161226_707-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>BlockDAG- The First DAG To Sell Out 8 Billion BDAG Coins</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BlockDAG</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> integrates blockchain and Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) tech thereby creating a hybrid technology that resolves and enhances the security, scalability, and decentralisation issues. BlockDAG has achieved a milestone by reaching 10,000-15,000 TPS which has propelled the brand to mint an astounding $20.1 Million in presale funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The brand’s ingenious architecture enables near real-time transactions and strengthens its potential to mint a gratuity of 30,000X ROI. As BDAG&#8217;s price rises from $0.005 to $0.006 reflecting growing investor interest it can be seen that BlockDAG sets up a case for both tech and remarkable returns. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://blockdag.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-80741 size-large" src="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161228_439-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161228_439-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161228_439-300x169.jpg 300w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161228_439.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As the keynote highlights, BlockDAG’s X30 miner mines up to 600 BDAG and combines high power with practical design, offering a significant 280 GH/s hash rate that triples mining efficiency in a compact form. It utilises advanced ASIC technology tailored for the BlockDAG ecosystem, ensuring maximum performance and scalability. Ideal for both new and seasoned miners, the X30 is a strategic investment in the future of crypto mining, designed to enhance earning potential and adapt to various environments with its manageable size and noise levels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BlockDAG has garnered global recognition as it was showcased in the Las Vegas Sphere celebrating the launch of DAGPaper and sold 8 billion coins in no time. And then it&#8217;s the mind-blowing keynote teaser that has ignited an avalanche of interest within the crypto community anticipating a keynote display on the moon.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Why BlockDAG Holds the Competitive Edge</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The dissection of the strategies and market performances of Chainlink, Toncoin, and BlockDAG, leads to a realisation that BlockDAG&#8217;s innovative approach to merging DAG with blockchain technology positions it as futuristic crypto in the crypto market that has led the brand to amass an overwhelming $20.1 million presale funding. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The ability to handle large transaction volumes with cutting-edge devices like Miner X30 elevates its potential to mint 30,000X ROI. Coupled with the monumental moonshot keynote teaser that previews the keynote display on the moon, the future of this crypto looks universal. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://blockdag.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-80740 size-large" src="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161230_044-1024x128.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="85" srcset="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161230_044-1024x128.jpg 1024w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161230_044-300x38.jpg 300w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240424_161230_044.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
<p><b>Join BlockDAG Presale Now!</b></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Website: <a href="https://blockdag.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">https://blockdag.network</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Presale: <a href="https://purchase.blockdag.network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">https://purchase.blockdag.network</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Telegram: <a href="https://t.me/blockDAGnetworkOfficial" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">https://t.me/blockDAGnetworkOfficial</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Discord: <a href="https://discord.gg/Q7BxghMVyu" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">https://discord.gg/Q7BxghMVyu</a><i> </i></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is a sponsored press release. Please do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any projects. Read the full disclosure <a href="https://themerkle.com/press-release-150-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/blockdags-30000x-roi-potential-vs-chainlink-toncoin/">BlockDAG&#8217;s 30,000X ROI Potential Vs. Chainlink &amp;Toncoin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stablecoin Market Shows Strong Recovery, Approaching All-Time High</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/stablecoin-market-shows-strong-recovery-approaching-all-time-high/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 06:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The stablecoin market has been on a robust recovery path since October 2023, demonstrating resilience and steady growth. Recently, the stablecoin market cap has surged to $160 billion, edging closer to its previous all-time high of $188 billion with each passing day. The stablecoin market has been in a strong recovery since October of 2023. Here&#39;s why it matters👇 The stablecoin market cap recently reached $160 billion, inching closer to the all-time high of $188 billion every day. ➖Stablecoins play a crucial role in DeFi, serving as the… pic.twitter.com/xrMB0qWWqO &#8212; IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) April 23, 2024 Stablecoins are essential components of </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/stablecoin-market-shows-strong-recovery-approaching-all-time-high/">Stablecoin Market Shows Strong Recovery, Approaching All-Time High</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The stablecoin market has been on a robust recovery path since October 2023, demonstrating resilience and steady growth. Recently, the <a href="https://themerkle.com/tag/stablecoin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stablecoin</a> market cap has surged to $160 billion, edging closer to its previous all-time high of $188 billion with each passing day.</strong></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The stablecoin market has been in a strong recovery since October of 2023.  Here&#39;s why it matters👇</p>
<p>The stablecoin market cap recently reached $160 billion, inching closer to the all-time high of $188 billion every day. </p>
<p>➖Stablecoins play a crucial role in DeFi, serving as the… <a href="https://t.co/xrMB0qWWqO">pic.twitter.com/xrMB0qWWqO</a></p>
<p>&mdash; IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1782688537642402298?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Stablecoins are essential components of the DeFi (Decentralized Finance) ecosystem, serving as foundational pillars for numerous protocols and platforms. Their increasing market cap not only bolsters the growth of DeFi but also ensures its sustainability over time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">One of the key contributions of a thriving stablecoin market cap is its role in enhancing liquidity within the broader cryptocurrency market. This heightened liquidity fosters smoother and more efficient operations across various crypto assets, facilitating seamless transactions and market activities.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24DAI&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$DAI</a> saw $240B in on-chain transaction volume last week. </p>
<p>Not only is this a new weekly high for <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24DAI&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$DAI</a>, it&#39;s also more than all other stablecoins combined! <a href="https://t.co/pgm3pv7M5M">pic.twitter.com/pgm3pv7M5M</a></p>
<p>&mdash; IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1782746025461006574?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Moreover, stablecoins play a vital role as entry points for fiat money into the cryptocurrency market. Their stability and reliability make them preferred instruments for investors looking to enter the crypto space, thereby supporting inflows of new capital into the market.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>$240 Billion On-Chain Transaction Volume In Record </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Recent data from Intotheblock underscores the significance of stablecoins, particularly highlighting the impressive performance of $DAI. With $240 billion in on-chain transaction volume recorded last week, $DAI has not only set a new weekly high but has also surpassed all other stablecoins combined in transaction volume.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This remarkable achievement further solidifies the pivotal role of stablecoins in the cryptocurrency landscape, affirming their status as indispensable assets driving liquidity, stability, and growth within the market.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As the stablecoin market continues its upward trajectory, its growing significance underscores the importance of monitoring its developments closely. With stablecoins serving as linchpins for various aspects of the crypto ecosystem, their continued expansion is poised to shape the future dynamics of decentralized finance and beyond.</span></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is not trading or investment advice. Always do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any services.</em></p>
<p><strong>Follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/themerklehash" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">@themerklehash</a> to stay updated with the latest Crypto, NFT, AI, Cybersecurity, and Metaverse news!</strong></p>
<p><em>Image Source: aleksandrasova</em><em>/<a href="https://www.123rf.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">123RF</a> // Image Effects by <a href="https://www.cartoonize.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Colorcinch</a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/stablecoin-market-shows-strong-recovery-approaching-all-time-high/">Stablecoin Market Shows Strong Recovery, Approaching All-Time High</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>XRP Whales Accumulate As Price Surges Ahead Of Altcoin Pack</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/xrp-whales-accumulate-as-price-surges-ahead-of-altcoin-pack/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 06:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The recent price movement of XRP has caught the attention of crypto whales, who have been actively accumulating the digital asset amidst its fluctuations. Over the past week alone, these whales have acquired more than 31 million XRP tokens, signaling a bullish sentiment in the market. Currently trading at $0.544, XRP has outperformed many other altcoins, experiencing a notable 6% jump and reaching as high as $0.5687 today. This surge in price underscores growing investor confidence in the asset, potentially indicating a shift in market dynamics. $XRP dropped from $0.62 to $0.41, and #crypto whales took notice. They&#39;ve bought over </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/xrp-whales-accumulate-as-price-surges-ahead-of-altcoin-pack/">XRP Whales Accumulate As Price Surges Ahead Of Altcoin Pack</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The recent price movement of <a href="https://themerkle.com/tag/xrp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XRP</a> has caught the attention of crypto whales, who have been actively accumulating the digital asset amidst its fluctuations. </strong></p>
<p>Over the past week alone, these whales have acquired more than 31 million XRP tokens, signaling a bullish sentiment in the market.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Currently trading at $0.544, XRP has outperformed many other altcoins, experiencing a notable 6% jump and reaching as high as $0.5687 today. This surge in price underscores growing investor confidence in the asset, potentially indicating a shift in market dynamics.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24XRP&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$XRP</a> dropped from $0.62 to $0.41, and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/crypto?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#crypto</a> whales took notice. They&#39;ve bought over 31 million <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XRP?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#XRP</a> in just the past week! <a href="https://t.co/3FCA3PR3hi">pic.twitter.com/3FCA3PR3hi</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ali (@ali_charts) <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1782702831973085397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">A significant development in the XRP ecosystem is the increasing number of wallets holding at least 1 million XRP tokens. This metric has seen a steady uptick over the past six weeks, rising by 3.1%. Remarkably, the current count of such wallets stands at 2,013, just one shy of the all-time high recorded on June 17, 2023.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>XRP Wallets With 1 Million Tokens Makes Massive Recovery In Number</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This trend highlights a growing interest among investors and stakeholders in XRP, with many opting to hold substantial amounts of the digital currency in their wallets. The near-attainment of the previous all-time high in the number of large XRP holders further reinforces the positive sentiment surrounding the asset.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Comparing the current scenario to historical milestones, it&#8217;s noteworthy that XRP wallets holding 1 million or more coins reached their peak on June 17, 2023, with a count of 2,014. Fast forward to April 22, 2024, and the number of such wallets is on the cusp of matching this record, with 2,013 wallets currently in existence.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">🐳 The price of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XRP?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#XRP</a> has jumped ahead of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/altcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#altcoin</a> pack, jumping +6% and as high as $0.5687 today. The amount of wallets, 2,013, holding at least 1M <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24XRP&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$XRP</a> has been surging over the past six weeks (rising 3.1%), and is within 1 wallet of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AllTimeHigh?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AllTimeHigh</a>. <a href="https://t.co/2ZfC9v79x9">https://t.co/2ZfC9v79x9</a> <a href="https://t.co/rqKgcOYJJx">pic.twitter.com/rqKgcOYJJx</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Santiment (@santimentfeed) <a href="https://twitter.com/santimentfeed/status/1782524613987320181?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Overall, the recent surge in XRP&#8217;s price, coupled with the increased accumulation by crypto whales and the impending milestone in wallet counts, paints a promising picture for the future trajectory of the digital asset. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As market participants continue to monitor these developments closely, XRP remains poised for further growth and potential milestones in the days ahead.</span></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is not trading or investment advice. Always do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any services.</em></p>
<p><strong>Follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/themerklehash" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">@themerklehash</a> to stay updated with the latest Crypto, NFT, AI, Cybersecurity, and Metaverse news!</strong></p>
<p><i>Image Source: iuriimotov/</i><a href="https://www.123rf.com/" rel="nofollow"><i>123RF</i></a><i> // Image Effects by </i><a href="https://www.cartoonize.net/" rel="nofollow"><i>Colorcinch</i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/xrp-whales-accumulate-as-price-surges-ahead-of-altcoin-pack/">XRP Whales Accumulate As Price Surges Ahead Of Altcoin Pack</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>O2T Presale Shoots For The Moon As Best Scaleable Defi Cryptocurrency 2024 Whilst Polygon Tumbles</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/o2t-presale-shoots-for-the-moon-as-best-scaleable-defi-cryptocurrency-2024-whilst-polygon-tumbles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Null Transaction PR]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 18:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The cryptocurrency landscape is ever-evolving, and as Polygon (MATIC) currently faces significant market challenges, a new contender, Option2Trade (O2T), is quickly rising to prominence. The O2T presale has captured the attention of investors globally, positioning itself to become the leading scalable DeFi cryptocurrency of 2024. This surge in interest contrasts sharply with the struggles faced by Polygon (MATIC), providing a clear view of the shifting dynamics within the DeFi space. Unpacking the O2T Presale Phenomenon The presale phase of Option2Trade (O2T) has seen unprecedented enthusiasm, drawing investors from various sectors of the crypto community. The appeal of O2T lies in </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/o2t-presale-shoots-for-the-moon-as-best-scaleable-defi-cryptocurrency-2024-whilst-polygon-tumbles/">O2T Presale Shoots For The Moon As Best Scaleable Defi Cryptocurrency 2024 Whilst Polygon Tumbles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The cryptocurrency landscape is ever-evolving, and as Polygon (MATIC) currently faces significant market challenges, a new contender, <a href="https://option2tradepresale.com/" rel="nofollow">Option2Trade (O2T)</a>, is quickly rising to prominence. The O2T presale has captured the attention of investors globally, positioning itself to become the leading scalable DeFi cryptocurrency of 2024. This surge in interest contrasts sharply with the struggles faced by Polygon (MATIC), providing a clear view of the shifting dynamics within the DeFi space.</strong></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><b>Unpacking the O2T Presale Phenomenon</b></h2>
<p>The presale phase of Option2Trade (O2T) has seen unprecedented enthusiasm, drawing investors from various sectors of the crypto community. The appeal of O2T lies in its innovative approach to scalability, a critical factor that has plagued many DeFi platforms, including <a href="https://www.analyticsinsight.net/bullrun-incoming-how-matics-8-surge-signals-a-crypto-rebound/" rel="nofollow">Polygon (MATIC)</a>. As Polygon (MATIC) works through its scalability issues, <a href="https://option2tradepresale.com/" rel="nofollow">Option2Trade (O2T)</a> has introduced novel solutions that promise to handle large volumes of transactions without compromising speed or security.</p>
<p><img class="size-large wp-image-80727 aligncenter" src="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8-1024x159.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="106" srcset="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8-1024x159.jpg 1024w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8-300x47.jpg 300w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><b>O2T&#8217;s Scalability Solutions: A Game Changer</b></h2>
<p>One of the key factors propelling the presale of <a href="https://option2tradepresale.com/" rel="nofollow">Option2Trade (O2T)</a> is its cutting-edge scalability solutions. Unlike Polygon (MATIC), which has often struggled with network congestion during peak times, O2T utilizes a layered architecture that effectively distributes the load, ensuring smooth and efficient transaction processing. This technological advancement not only positions O2T as a superior alternative to Polygon (MATIC) but also sets a new standard for what traders and investors can expect from DeFi platforms.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><b>Gaining the Competitive Edge Over Polygon (MATIC)</b></h2>
<p>As <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/polygon/" rel="nofollow">Polygon (MATIC)</a> tumbles due to its ongoing challenges, <a href="https://option2tradepresale.com/" rel="nofollow">Option2Trade (O2T)</a> is quickly gaining ground. The differences in market reception can largely be attributed to Option2Trade (O2T)’s proactive approach to addressing common DeFi issues, which has resonated well with the crypto community. Investors disillusioned with Polygon’s (MATIC) slower response to scalability are increasingly turning to Option2Trade (O2T), attracted by its robust infrastructure and the promise of higher returns on their investments.</p>
<p><img class="size-large wp-image-80727 aligncenter" src="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8-1024x159.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="106" srcset="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8-1024x159.jpg 1024w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8-300x47.jpg 300w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/image1-8.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><b>The Future of DeFi Lies with Innovators Like O2T</b></h2>
<p>The trajectory of <a href="https://option2tradepresale.com/" rel="nofollow">Option2Trade (O2T)</a> suggests a bright future, not just for the platform itself but for the entire DeFi sector. As traditional players like Polygon (MATIC) continue to navigate their respective challenges, new technologies and platforms like Option2Trade (O2T) are essential for driving the next wave of innovation in decentralized finance. The success of its presale is a clear indicator that the market is ready for a scalable, efficient, and user-friendly DeFi solution.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><b>Conclusion: A New Leader Emerges</b></h2>
<p>As 2024 approaches, the landscape of DeFi is set for a reshuffling, with Option2Trade (O2T) leading the charge. The problems faced by Polygon (MATIC) have only highlighted the need for platforms like Option2Trade (O2T), which not only promise scalability but also deliver on those promises effectively. For investors and users looking for the next big thing in DeFi, Option2Trade (O2T) represents not just a safe bet, but a potentially revolutionary one.</p>
<p><b>For more information on the Option2Trade (O2T) Presale: </b></p>
<p>Use promo code <b>O2T Launch</b> to get 15% bonus</p>
<p>Visit <a href="https://option2tradepresale.com/" rel="nofollow">Option2Trade (O2T)</a></p>
<p><b>Join and become a community member: </b></p>
<p><a href="https://t.me/O2TOfficial" rel="nofollow">https://t.me/O2TOfficial</a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/Option2Trade_" rel="nofollow">https://twitter.com/Option2Trade (O2T)</a></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is a sponsored press release. Please do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any projects. Read the full disclosure <a href="https://themerkle.com/press-release-150-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/o2t-presale-shoots-for-the-moon-as-best-scaleable-defi-cryptocurrency-2024-whilst-polygon-tumbles/">O2T Presale Shoots For The Moon As Best Scaleable Defi Cryptocurrency 2024 Whilst Polygon Tumbles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Does Raboo Stack Up Against Toncoin and Maker in Today’s Crypto Market</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/how-does-raboo-stack-up-against-toncoin-and-maker-in-todays-crypto-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 15:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Utility tokens were created as a methodology to access specific products or services in the blockchain and not as “value” coins. Yet, utility coins have skyrocketed in value. One needs to look at Binance Coin to see how utility tokens can be remarkable investments in the crypto market. Toncoin and Maker are both utility coins making a name as investment drivers. But how does newcomer Raboo – now in presale &#8211; stack up against the best utility tokens as an investment vehicle?   Toncoin (TON): A Leader Among Utility Tokens in the Crypto Market Toncoin has positioned itself as one of </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/how-does-raboo-stack-up-against-toncoin-and-maker-in-todays-crypto-market/">How Does Raboo Stack Up Against Toncoin and Maker in Today’s Crypto Market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span style="font-size: 16px">Utility tokens were created as a methodology to access specific products or services in the blockchain and not as “value” coins. Yet, utility coins have skyrocketed in value. One needs to look at Binance Coin to see how utility tokens can be remarkable investments in the </span><span style="font-size: 16px">crypto market</span><span style="font-size: 16px">. </span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> and </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> are both utility coins making a name as investment drivers. But how does newcomer </span><a href="https://rabootoken.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> – now in presale &#8211; stack up against the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">best utility tokens</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> as an investment vehicle?  </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><strong>Toncoin (TON): A Leader Among Utility Tokens in the Crypto Market</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> has positioned itself as one of the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">best utility tokens</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> within the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">crypto market</span><span style="font-weight: 400">, driven by its deep integration with the Telegram ecosystem. The strategic decision by Telegram to adopt</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> for transactions has spurred significant growth and utility for the token. This integration facilitates a seamless transactional environment where advertisers and content creators can transact using </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> directly within the app.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The utility of </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> extends beyond simple transactions. The token is pivotal in the Telegram network for purchasing unique usernames, creating a vibrant economy around digital identities. The </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> blockchain has seen a substantial increase in wallet creations and active transactions, signaling strong prospects for </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> adoption.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><strong>Maker (MKR): Stablecoin’s Governance Token Goes Big</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> (MKR) is another token vying for a spot as one of the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">best utility tokens</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> in the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">crypto market</span><span style="font-weight: 400">. As a governance token, MKR enables holders to participate in the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> Protocol’s decision-making processes, particularly in risk management and logistics for the Dai stablecoin. This influence is essential since it immediately affects the system’s financial stability and operational directives.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> also serves a unique economic purpose by being burned or created in reaction to the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> system’s financial health. For example, when fees are paid, </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker </span><span style="font-weight: 400">is burned, reducing overall supply and potentially raising value. In contrast, when the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> ecosystem has a financial shortfall, new </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> tokens can be minted and sold to recapitalize the system, assuring its long-term viability and resilience to bankruptcy.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><strong>Raboo (RABT): Strategically Capitalizing on the Crypto Market</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> (RABT) is a vibrant newcomer ready to make substantial inroads into the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">crypto market</span><span style="font-weight: 400">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> capitalizes on two of the digital economy’s fastest-growing industries by leveraging its one-of-a-kind blend of AI and meme culture. Its platform is intended to actively involve users rather than simply entertain them, resulting in a dedicated community centered on its cryptocurrency. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This strategic strategy enables </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> to capitalize on trends that prefer interactive and immersive experiences, setting it apart from standard cryptocurrencies. Furthermore, </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span><span style="font-weight: 400">’s integration of modern technology to evaluate and adapt to industry trends equips it to respond quickly to movements in the crypto landscape, placing it well to capitalize on market growth and investor interest in creative crypto projects.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><strong>Conclusion:</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The </span><span style="font-weight: 400">best utility tokens</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> like </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Toncoin</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> and </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Maker</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> are must-haves for any crypto portfolio. But for real growth potential, the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> presale is the way to go. The </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> presale has already gained nearly a million dollars from over 1400 token holders. </span><span style="font-weight: 400">Raboo</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> is available at $0.0036, and is set to grow 233% during its presale alone, making it one of the hottest coins on the</span><span style="font-weight: 400"> crypto market</span><span style="font-weight: 400">. </span></p>
<p><b>You can participate in the Raboo presale </b><a href="https://rabootoken.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><b>here</b></a><b>.</b></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is a sponsored press release. Please do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any projects. Read the full disclosure <a href="https://themerkle.com/press-release-150-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/how-does-raboo-stack-up-against-toncoin-and-maker-in-todays-crypto-market/">How Does Raboo Stack Up Against Toncoin and Maker in Today’s Crypto Market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MEME Madness: BEFE Coin Dominates the Trending Scene This Week</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/meme-madness-befe-coin-dominates-the-trending-scene-this-week/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 15:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The crypto market has been on the rise since the beginning of this year and people have anticipated the market to become one of the largest assets in the finance world. People are expecting to earn more than double the amount they invested in the span of a year through the crypto market. The BEFE coin is one such cryptocurrency in the market that is predicted to be profitable in an explosive sense. The token was launched not too long ago but has still created a community for itself with a lot of high-profile investors. The most ironic thing about </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/meme-madness-befe-coin-dominates-the-trending-scene-this-week/">MEME Madness: BEFE Coin Dominates the Trending Scene This Week</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span style="font-size: 16px">The crypto market has been on the rise since the beginning of this year and people have anticipated the market to become one of the largest assets in the finance world. People are expecting to earn more than double the amount they invested in the span of a year through the crypto market.</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The </span><a href="https://befetoken.com/?utm_source=23APRIL" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> coin is one such cryptocurrency in the market that is predicted to be profitable in an explosive sense. The token was launched not too long ago but has still created a community for itself with a lot of high-profile investors. The most ironic thing about BEFE is that it was launched as a meme currency.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Let’s take a look at what has hyped BEFE coin so much and why is it dominating the trending scene of the market.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><strong>The Rise of BEFE Coin </strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE coin entered the market, not too long ago, as a parody instrument to the cryptocurrency market. But one of the things that made it distinct from the other meme currencies was the blockchain collaboration and versatile use cases of the token. Initially, the BEFE coin was not too popular and it was only used as a joke or for humorous reasons.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">But later with the changes in the performance of the </span><a href="https://befetoken.com/?utm_source=23APRIL" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> coin, the token started to grow at a very rapid rate. BEFE coin has close collaboration with the Bitgert chain and it helped BEFE become the primary token for a lot of projects. This is because of the fastest transaction speeds offered by the Bitgert chain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE coin has also innovated to improve the performance of the token in the market and be a great asset for ongoing projects. The BEFE coin is now being used as a primary token on a lot of high-profile crypto projects.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><strong>Analyzing the Market Performance</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">According to the market performance statistics, the </span><a href="https://befetoken.com/?utm_source=23APRIL" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> coin has been actively growing in the market. The volatility rate of the BEFE coin is nearly 12% which is not too much and means that people are not selling instantly for quick profits. Then the feed &amp; greed ratio of the BEFE coin is quite low which means that there is a bullish sentiment for the BEFE coin in the market.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The BEFE coin has managed to improve its performance in very little time. BEFE coin trading volume increases every day at a nearly 5% rate which has helped the token now become a mid-cap token with huge potential. The BEFE coin has managed to create several support regions in the market too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE coin is growing in such a way that it has been on the news for a long time now. BEFE coin has an RSI score of nearly 55 and a positive MACD and moving average value too. All these stats fall in the favour of the BEFE coin and suggest that users invest in it.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><span style="font-weight: 400"><strong>Conclusion</strong> </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The BEFE coin is growing in the crypto market owing to the technological and managerial renewals that have happened in the last few months. BEFE coin is now at the forefront of cryptocurrencies to be invested in. Analysts suggest that the BEFE coin will be able to reach $0.002596 soon which will be quite a huge profit for current investors too. So, if you are looking for a token to earn incredibly from, then the BEFE coin is one to be chosen.</span></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is a sponsored press release. Please do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any projects. Read the full disclosure <a href="https://themerkle.com/press-release-150-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/meme-madness-befe-coin-dominates-the-trending-scene-this-week/">MEME Madness: BEFE Coin Dominates the Trending Scene This Week</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitgert Coin Price Set to Soar Amid Exchange Growth Momentum</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/bitgert-coin-price-set-to-soar-amid-exchange-growth-momentum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 15:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The critical decisions that are made will have a significant impact on the position of returns that investors will get in return as the cryptocurrency is buzzing to enter a bull run. While expectations are fixated on the pump which has been suspected by experts, numerous investors are on an exploration spree, looking for quality systems to subsidize on.  Bitgert exchange is without a distrustfulness, the most suitable option, both in terms of performance and options. Taking a close look at the progress that has been made by the exchange therefore far, it&#8217;s apparent that the future looks promising and </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/bitgert-coin-price-set-to-soar-amid-exchange-growth-momentum/">Bitgert Coin Price Set to Soar Amid Exchange Growth Momentum</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;font-size: 16px"><strong>The critical decisions that are made will have a significant impact on the position of returns that investors will get in return as the cryptocurrency is buzzing to enter a bull run.</strong> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;font-size: 16px">While expectations are fixated on the pump which has been suspected by experts, numerous investors are on an exploration spree, looking for quality systems to subsidize on. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitgert exchange is without a distrustfulness, the most suitable option, both in terms of performance and options. Taking a close look at the progress that has been made by the exchange therefore far, it&#8217;s apparent that the future looks promising and has a lot to offer. Bitgert exchange expansion backs up claims by multitudinous specialists and observers on a implicit blast in worth of Bitgert coin. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Investors Getting Their Bags Filled With Bitgert As Exchange Expands </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Over the most recent couple of months, Bitgert coin has swamped to further than 162% in price valuation with swapping volume recording an upturn also. These are unmistakable suggestions that a large number of investors are laboriously buying and dealing with Bitgert. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The way </span><a href="https://bitgert.com/?utm_source=23APRIL" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitgert exchange</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> works makes it possible to keep growing. A duty of 5 is paid for each sale made on the chain. This duty is used to buy back Bitgert coins, which are also burned. As a result, there will be a significant drop in force, which will affect a significant increase in valuation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Because of the excellent serviceability on the exchange to encourage design growth, Bitgert is one of the assiduity&#8217;s most promising coins. Bitgert uses an aggressive burning medium, which has contributed to the rise in value because it has created failure in the face of rising investor demand for the coin. This has been seen by quite a many people and amped steal as the eventuality for a blast is clear. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Right from the negative season till the morning of the bull run, Bitgert has been remarkable in performing, giving fiscal backers more than 194% return of enterprise. New investors have rushed in to take advantage of this wealth- creating occasion as a result of this increase in interest. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Protrusions On Bitgert Price Soar With It’s Growing Exchange</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Despite the huge uptrends, </span><a href="https://bitgert.com/?utm_source=23APRIL" rel="nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">Bitgert&#8217;s</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> current capitalization is good enough to go through a much bigger bullish run than it has in the history. Investors have realized the necessity of exercising the exchange and savoring nothing but streamlined deals thanks to the benefits Bitgert exchange offers, which include unexampled scalability, cost-effective deals, and hard- cinch security. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Grounded on expert analysis, Bitgert is anticipated to perform better and progress overhead in the coming months. The coin&#8217;s immolations and former performance support this analysis. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Rounding Up </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">It&#8217;s obviously true that Bitgert&#8217;s growing instigation is a long way from terminating at any point in the near future with investors exercising the exchange reliably. In order to keep a close eye on the design, regular exploration should also be conducted. On this </span><a href="https://bitgert.com/?utm_source=23APRIL" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">website</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">, learn further about Bitgert. </span></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is a sponsored press release. Please do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any projects. Read the full disclosure <a href="https://themerkle.com/press-release-150-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/bitgert-coin-price-set-to-soar-amid-exchange-growth-momentum/">Bitgert Coin Price Set to Soar Amid Exchange Growth Momentum</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>These DeFi Tokens Will Be Your Best Buy For 2024 &#8211; ETFSwap (ETFS), Avalanche (AVAX), And Stacks (STX) </title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/these-defi-tokens-will-be-your-best-buy-for-2024-etfswap-etfs-avalanche-avax-and-stacks-stx/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 15:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The DeFi industry hosts numerous exciting projects that deliver innovative features and services. Among these projects are Avalanche (AVAX), ETFSwap (ETFS), and Stacks (STX). Both Avalanche (AVAX) and Stacks (STX) are open-source, decentralised blockchains built to facilitate easy access to DeFi tools.  Given their excellent use cases, the governance tokens of both projects are excellent choices if you are looking to buy into top crypto projects for 2024. However, if you prefer to buy into new crypto projects, then ETFSwap (ETFS) is a solid project to opt for. Wondering what makes ETFSwap (ETFS) special. Let’s give you the details. Avalanche </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/these-defi-tokens-will-be-your-best-buy-for-2024-etfswap-etfs-avalanche-avax-and-stacks-stx/">These DeFi Tokens Will Be Your Best Buy For 2024 &#8211; ETFSwap (ETFS), Avalanche (AVAX), And Stacks (STX) </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The DeFi industry hosts numerous exciting projects that deliver innovative features and services. Among these projects are Avalanche (AVAX), </span><a style="font-size: 16px" href="https://etfswap.io/?utm_source=themerkel&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=0423" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ETFSwap (ETFS)</a><span style="font-weight: 400">, and Stacks (STX). Both Avalanche (AVAX) and Stacks (STX) are open-source, decentralised blockchains built to facilitate easy access to DeFi tools. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Given their excellent use cases, the governance tokens of both projects are excellent choices if you are looking to buy into top crypto projects for 2024. However, if you prefer to buy into new crypto projects, then ETFSwap (ETFS) is a solid project to opt for. Wondering what makes ETFSwap (ETFS) special. Let’s give you the details.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Avalanche (AVAX): Lightning-Fast Blockchain With Huge Financial Prospects</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Often tagged as an Ethereum killer, the Avalanche (AVAX) blockchain offers three crucial features: scalability, transaction speed, and cost-efficiency. Given its appeal, the project has grown significantly since its testnet was first launched in May 2019.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Recently, the Avalanche (AVAX) experienced a surge in the total value locked on the blockchain. During this period, the TVL on the platform was worth over $1.5 billion. This metric is quite telling as it indicates the level of user trust in the Avalanche (AVAX). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">According to the </span><a href="https://www.binance.com/en/price-prediction/avalanche" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">Binance consensus rating</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">, the Avalanche (AVAX) token is expected to hit $ 41.46 before 2024 runs out. This projection also indicates that the AVAX token has the potential to hit $55 by 2030. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">With the potential of another bull run on the horizon, user trust should increase, leading to further growth in the price of the AVAX token.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Stacks (STX): Reliable Blockchain With Potential For More DeFi Growth</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/stacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">Stacks (STX)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> is a decentralized blockchain that allows smart contracts and decentralized apps (dApps) to connect to Bitcoin. Although the Stacks (STX) blockchain is different from Bitcoin, both platforms are compatible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The STX token holds the distinction of being the pioneer cryptocurrency to receive approval from the United States Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), while also being fully regulated by the agency. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As part of its use cases, investors can also stack STX tokens to earn Bitcoin. This has caused belief in the Stacks (STX) project to skyrocketed. As of April 15, 2024, the total value of assets locked on the Stacks blockchain is over $150 million, with the expectation that Stacks (STX)  will continue to grow.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>ETFSwap: Leading The Charge Towards Secure Investment Opportunities</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://etfswap.io/?utm_source=themerkel&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=0423" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">ETFSwap (ETFS) </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">is a unique DeFi platform that offers users access to exchange-traded funds (ETFs) by tokenizing them on the blockchain. This way, investors of all sizes are able to take advantage of the growing Spot Bitcoin ETFs, as well as other ETFs, without having to worry about going through a third party.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The platform also offers easy access to market-making and perpetual trading services, as well as allowing users to maximize their profits using its leverage features. ETFSwap (ETFS) provides up to 10x leverage, meaning that users can maximize profits by up to 1,000%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As a DeFi platform, ETFSwap (ETFS) delivers a permissionless environment to its users. Investors do not need to fulfill any KYC requirements before accessing their services. As a result, your activities are free from scrutiny from regulatory bodies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The platform has been extensively audited by CyberScope, an industry leader in blockchain security, and the result fo this audit revealed no vulnerabilities in the platform. This means that the platform’s smart contracts are completely safe to interact with.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">ETFSwap also provides staking services for its users, allowing them to earn passive income by staking their ETFS tokens. It will also reward its community for their participation, with 4% of its supply allocated to community incentives.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://etfswap.io/?utm_source=themerkel&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=0423" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-80710 size-full" src="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240423_162411_179.jpg" alt="" width="798" height="119" srcset="https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240423_162411_179.jpg 798w, https://themerkle.com/wp-content/uploads-new/2024/04/IMG_20240423_162411_179-300x45.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 798px) 100vw, 798px" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Join The ETFS Presale Now</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Currently, ETFSwap (ETFS) is in stage 1 of its presale and the tokens are being sold for the low price of $0.00854. This low price means that there is a huge runway for growth, with experts predicting that the token’s price could reach $1. Such a price point would mean a 100x return on investment for stage 1 investors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As a relatively new project, </span><a href="https://etfswap.io/?utm_source=themerkel&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=0423" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">ETFSwap (ETFS) </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">has more potential for growth than Avalanche (AVAX) and Stacks (STX). So far, over 22 million have been sold during stage 1 of the presale as crypto investors have latched onto the ETFSwap (ETFS) wagon. </span></p>
<p><b>For more information about the ETFS Presale:</b></p>
<p><a href="https://etfswap.io/?utm_source=themerkel&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_campaign=0423" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">Visit ETFSwap Presale</span></a></p>
<p><a href="https://linktr.ee/etfswap" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">Join The ETFSwap Community</span></a></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is a sponsored press release. Please do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any projects. Read the full disclosure <a href="https://themerkle.com/press-release-150-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/these-defi-tokens-will-be-your-best-buy-for-2024-etfswap-etfs-avalanche-avax-and-stacks-stx/">These DeFi Tokens Will Be Your Best Buy For 2024 &#8211; ETFSwap (ETFS), Avalanche (AVAX), And Stacks (STX) </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MakerDAO&#8217;s $MKR Faces Decline As Whales Make Moves</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/makerdaos-mkr-faces-decline-as-whales-make-moves/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 15:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maker DAO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MKR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Profit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>MakerDAO&#8217;s native token $MKR has experienced a 4% decline in the past 24 hours and a 6% drop over the course of the last 7 days, signaling a challenging period for the cryptocurrency. Recent on-chain reports reveal that MakerDAO Multisign 0xbba has deposited 421.985 MKR, equivalent to $1.29 million, to Wintermute Trading OTC at a price of $3,046 before the price downturn. This deposit adds to the multisign&#8217;s overall activity, which has seen 9,043 MKR deposited to Wintermute Trading OTC at an average price of $3,291, totaling $29.76 million, since the price surge on March 17, 2024.  Multisign 0xbba, likely </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/makerdaos-mkr-faces-decline-as-whales-make-moves/">MakerDAO&#8217;s $MKR Faces Decline As Whales Make Moves</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>MakerDAO&#8217;s native token <a href="https://themerkle.com/tag/mkr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$MKR</a> has experienced a 4% decline in the past 24 hours and a 6% drop over the course of the last 7 days, signaling a challenging period for the cryptocurrency.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Recent on-chain reports reveal that MakerDAO Multisign 0xbba has deposited 421.985 MKR, equivalent to $1.29 million, to Wintermute Trading OTC at a price of $3,046 before the price downturn. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This deposit adds to the multisign&#8217;s overall activity, which has seen 9,043 MKR deposited to Wintermute Trading OTC at an average price of $3,291, totaling $29.76 million, since the price surge on March 17, 2024. </span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Multisign 0xbba, likely <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerDAO?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerDAO</a>, has consistently moved <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24MKR&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$MKR</a> out before price drops!</p>
<p>In the past 2 weeks, the multisign sent 4,535 <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24MKR&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$MKR</a> ($14.4M) in total almost daily to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Wintermute?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Wintermute</a> Trading, which then deposited to CEX like <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Binance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Binance</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Coinbase?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Coinbase</a>, or <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Kraken?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Kraken</a>,</p>
<p>And the price… <a href="https://t.co/cZanltuTnA">https://t.co/cZanltuTnA</a> <a href="https://t.co/ZK9uyzXO0G">pic.twitter.com/ZK9uyzXO0G</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Spot On Chain (@spotonchain) <a href="https://twitter.com/spotonchain/status/1782247721375867200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Notably, the price has tended to slightly decrease following each deposit. Currently, the multisign still holds 21,928 MKR, valued at $66.36 million.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Some $MKR Whales Sells Off Some Profits </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In addition to multisign activity, a whale profiting $3.51 million through $MKR transactions sold 1,500 MKR on the chain in the past two hours at an average price of $3,045. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Subsequently, the whale recharged 4.48 million USDT into Binance, possibly in anticipation of purchasing at the market&#8217;s bottom.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="zh" dir="ltr">2024.03 通过 <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24MKR&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$MKR</a> 波段获利 351 万美金的巨鲸，过去两小时在链上卖出 1500 枚 MKR，卖出均价 $3045；随后将 448 万枚 USDT 充值进币安，或许是去抄底了？</p>
<p>这部分 MKR 是 04.11 以均价 $3325 从币安转出的，此次卖出亏损了 42 万美金，剩余部分仍浮亏 14 万美金😂</p>
<p>钱包地址 <a href="https://t.co/5agHlcRBTz">https://t.co/5agHlcRBTz</a> <a href="https://t.co/QpITUxNxOm">pic.twitter.com/QpITUxNxOm</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ai 姨 (@ai_9684xtpa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ai_9684xtpa/status/1782322097681019216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The portion of MKR sold was transferred from Binance on April 11 at an average price of $3325, resulting in a loss of $420,000. The remaining portion of MKR still holds a floating loss of $140,000.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">These recent movements within the $MKR ecosystem highlight the active participation of whales and multisign entities, shaping the token&#8217;s market dynamics. As the cryptocurrency faces a period of decline, investors are closely monitoring these developments for potential insights into future price trends and market sentiment.</span></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is not trading or investment advice. Always do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any services.</em></p>
<p><strong>Follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/themerklehash" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">@themerklehash</a> to stay updated with the latest Crypto, NFT, AI, Cybersecurity, and Metaverse news!</strong></p>
<p><i>Image Source: kaedeezign/</i><a href="https://www.123rf.com/" rel="nofollow"><i>123RF</i></a><i> // Image Effects by </i><a href="https://www.cartoonize.net/" rel="nofollow"><i>Colorcinch</i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/makerdaos-mkr-faces-decline-as-whales-make-moves/">MakerDAO&#8217;s $MKR Faces Decline As Whales Make Moves</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BEFE Coin&#8217;s Price Projections: Optimizing Investment Returns</title>
		<link>https://themerkle.com/befe-coins-price-projections-optimizing-investment-returns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Will Izuchukwu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 15:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://themerkle.com/?p=80703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Cryptocurrency market has been really active since the beginning of 2024 and many new coins have recently made the news because of their high growth potential. Additionally, the investors have also recognized the importance of diversifying their portfolios. So, while, legacy players like Bitcoin and Ethereum are there, it is important to also show some trust in the relatively new coins that are yet to be discovered by the masses. This is where the BEFE coin started to impress one and all. Being a meme coin, it was obviously hilarious. However, its approach towards functionality and sustainability is what </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/befe-coins-price-projections-optimizing-investment-returns/">BEFE Coin&#8217;s Price Projections: Optimizing Investment Returns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Cryptocurrency market has been really active since the beginning of 2024 and many new coins have recently made the news because of their high growth potential. Additionally, the investors have also recognized the importance of diversifying their portfolios.</strong></p>
<p>So, while, legacy players like Bitcoin and Ethereum are there, it is important to also show some trust in the relatively new coins that are yet to be discovered by the masses.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This is where the </span><a href="https://befetoken.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE coin </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">started to impress one and all. Being a meme coin, it was obviously hilarious. However, its approach towards functionality and sustainability is what attracted the new age investors. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Analysts are bullish on BEFE and choose it as the top pick for investors and traders seeking substantial profits. Let us understand why is this the case. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>BEFE’s Consistent Growth</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Recent news reveals that investors are rushing to buy BEFE coin as it gears up for further upward price movement. Since its launch late last year, BEFE has been a top altcoin choice for investors. This explains why its 510% surge came as no surprise, given its impressive track record.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">While BEFE has recently consolidated, many experts cite technical indicators and strong community support as compelling reasons to get in now. Additionally, even key technical markers suggest a potential 200% gain in the days to come.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">With BEFE&#8217;s price performance linked to Bitgert&#8217;s momentum and its burning mechanism, a profitable run seems closer than ever. So, this rising altcoin star is waiting for smart investors to seize the moment.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>BEFE’s Approach Towards Sustainable Growth</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The </span><a href="https://befetoken.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE coin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> aims to revolutionize blockchain trading in the cryptocurrency space. Its low transaction fees have generated the kind of popularity that other cryptocurrencies crave. Transaction fees are a major barrier that many investors face while making small or big investments in altcoins multiple times.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE&#8217;s mission is to completely remove this obstacle to make use of the blockchain&#8217;s full potential for investors and traders. By offering low-cost, efficient trading, navigating the crypto space becomes far easier. Demand for the BEFE coin is expected to increase even more as it becomes the go-to solution for tackling high transaction fees.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>What&#8217;s Next for BEFE?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE&#8217;s rise and popularity in the Crypto market has caught the attention of many experts who are predicting bullish forecasts for its future. Its integration with the Ethereum Chain and Binance Smart Chain is a key factor that could push it to new heights.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This cross-chain compatibility offers investors the choice between the most popular blockchains, enhancing flexibility and accessibility.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center"><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://befetoken.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400">BEFE&#8217;s </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">commitment to providing investors with exceptional opportunities is clear from its accessible use cases. This, combined with its impressive performance and bullish expert outlook, makes BEFE the standout cryptocurrency to buy now.</span></p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This is a sponsored press release. Please do your research before buying any cryptocurrency or investing in any projects. Read the full disclosure <a href="https://themerkle.com/press-release-150-2/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com/befe-coins-price-projections-optimizing-investment-returns/">BEFE Coin&#8217;s Price Projections: Optimizing Investment Returns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://themerkle.com">The Merkle News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
