<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
            <rss version = "2.0"
                xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
                xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
                xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
                xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
                xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
                <channel>
                    <title>News &#8211; Finance Magnates | Financial and business news</title>
<atom:link href="https://www.financemagnates.com//feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//</link>
<description></description>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:14:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator></generator>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[“Mobile First” as a Standard: Techysquad Redefines Web Accessibility and Responsiveness]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/mobile-first-as-a-standard-techysquad-redefines-web-accessibility-and-responsiveness/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/mobile-first-as-a-standard-techysquad-redefines-web-accessibility-and-responsiveness/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:55:35 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/mobile-first-as-a-standard-techysquad-redefines-web-accessibility-and-responsiveness</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">“Mobile first” has created a massive paradigm shift in the past decade, gradually creeping into the hearts and minds of consumers. In 2022, the number of active mobile subscriptions exceeded the entire world’s population by 0.63 billion, the Telecommunication Union (ITU) signalled.</p><p class="MsoNormal">For <a href="https://techysquad.com/">TECHYSQUAD IT INFRASTRUCTURE CO. L.L.C</a>, a Dubai-registered technology provider of Forex CRM and Web design solutions for the brokerage and fintech sectors, “mobile first” is the standard. Understanding the impact of mobile technology on every aspect of daily life, the tech firm set out to revolutionise web accessibility and responsiveness on mobile devices. </p><p class="MsoNormal">With over a decade of expertise in fintech, Techysquad has established itself as a tech partner of choice for top-tier banks and asset management firms as well as fintechs, Forex and crypto brokers, equipping them with the right tools to future-proof their business. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Its unwavering commitment to excellence extends beyond design aesthetics, ensuring optimal functionality and full compatibility with any operating system and platform. Prioritising user experience, the technology provider understands the importance of delivering a website that is both eye-pleasing and loads fast. </p><p class="MsoNormal">“‘Your business, anytime, anywhere, on any device’ is our motto when it comes to web design and development,” Nikunj Tagadiya, CTO at Techysquad, said candidly. </p><p class="MsoNormal">“As a rule, we tend to process information from top to bottom. This is known as the ranking effect. Mobile device usage is directly linked to a stronger ranking effect. Also, users’ increasingly lower attention span and the reduced display screen size of mobile devices have greatly contributed to the way traders filter trade-related information. This is exactly where Techysquad makes every difference. More than an eye-catching web interface, we offer an immersive experience that increases user engagement across devices,” he explained.</p><p class="MsoNormal">From navigation to responsiveness, Techysquad’s website development services cover every aspect of UI/UX. The technology developer arms businesses with the arsenal they need to keep their clients engaged at every stage of their journey, on mobile and PC.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Techysquad developers work tirelessly to ensure mobile compatibility. Using a combination of programming languages, the team places great emphasis on website responsiveness. This helps businesses to easily adapt to the evolving demands of a mobile-driven audience and maximise their online reach and potential to convert leads into paying customers.</p><p class="MsoNormal">In addition to providing mobile-friendly web solutions, the company also takes pride in developing bespoke web-based solutions designed to meet the specific needs of each client, enabling quick scalability and adaptability for sustainable growth. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Fusing unique branding elements, such as graphics, colours, and fonts with a dynamic design and advanced coding, Techysquad makes Forex and crypto brokerage brands truly stand out. </p><p class="MsoNormal">“Creativity is key to bringing any brand story to life, but when you combine it with intelligent programming, miracles happen,” said Jignesh Patel, Team Leader at Techysquad.</p><p class="MsoNormal">This statement echoes through the company’s value proposition, which no matter how crowded the marketplace is, still shines through. Leveraging a robust infrastructure, Techysquad builds reliable and mobile-friendly websites integrated with a powerful <a href="https://techysquad.com/forex-crm-solution/">Forex CRM</a> that helps brokers keep tabs on the entire platform activity - from onboarding to trading and compliance reporting.</p><p class="MsoNormal">This unified approach to brokerage management won the company one of the highest distinctions for an “Outstanding Contribution in the IT Field” from the Excellence Awards in 2023.</p><p class="MsoNormal">By offering an integrated brokerage platform, including web design, development and CRM, Techysquad emerges as the go-to technology provider for trading platform operators looking for sustainable growth.</p><p class="MsoNormal">To explore Techysquad’s solutions or to book a demo, <a href="https://techysquad.com/contact-us/">contact the team</a>.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[“Gamification of Education Can Be a Game Changer:” Traders Education’s CEO]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/interview/gamification-of-education-can-be-a-game-changer-traders-educations-ceo/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/interview/gamification-of-education-can-be-a-game-changer-traders-educations-ceo/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:55:33 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/interview/gamification-of-education-can-be-a-game-changer-traders-educations-ceo</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">“Education is still a must, but the gamification of the product could be a game changer,”  Francois Albessard, the owner and CEO of Traders Education, told Finance Magnates. His comments were made while demand for trading-related educational content was increasing.</p><p dir="ltr">“There is an increasing demand for social media and video content,” he said and added that “a key factor for better engagement or retention is the ability to provide traders with the right tools/content at the right time and on the right platform.”</p><p dir="ltr">Traders Education offers white-label educational solutions to platforms providing trading services. Albessard revealed that about 20 brands are currently using the company's solutions, highlighting its offerings to trading academies and prop-trading firms, along with brokers.</p><p dir="ltr">“We observed a significant growth in 2023, which was the logical outcome after months of intense work on redesigning the product and creating a new identity,” the CEO added. “About the number of users, we estimate that there are 40 to 70 thousand unique users of the product every month, which is about twice as much as a year ago.”</p><p dir="ltr">Although several brokers develop their educational content in-house, the process is cumbersome and takes massive resources and time. </p><p dir="ltr">Albessard pointed out the strategies and challenges of brokers around educational: “Over the past few months, we’ve seen several major brokers revamping their trading academy (i.e., etoro, Plus500, etc). It shows that education is still a major component of the trader’s journey. However, building a bespoke academy takes time and requires a large team. These two factors may be underestimated in some cases.”</p><p dir="ltr">“An Academy for Prop Trading”</p><p dir="ltr">Apart from the regular brokerages, the surge in prop trading demand over the recent years pushed the demand for education content, and Traders Education was quick enough to jump into that arena.</p><p dir="ltr">“We realized that <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/interview/prop-trading-can-outgrow-traditional-fx-and-cfd-industry-oandas-emerging-markets-head/">prop-trading firms</a> pay specific attention to the educational content and tools provided to traders,” Albessard mentioned. “We designed an academy for a prop-trading firm back in 2019.”</p><p dir="ltr">“We adapted our product in two major ways. The first one was the creation of a dashboard to track the students’ journey at the academy. This would allow firms to identify student’s interests and assist them during their learning process. Another important change was the ability to create packages with different levels. Overall, the content offered to prop-trading firms has to be well structured, accessible, and actionable.”</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The concept of brokers and prop firms offering free trading education can seem quite ironic. Essentially, these entities profit from traders' losses, raising questions about the real motive behind providing educational resources. <a href="https://t.co/GPys5DZdgA">pic.twitter.com/GPys5DZdgA</a></p>— TRADER BENDAVE (@TraderBenDave) <a href="https://twitter.com/TraderBenDave/status/1769369114605216104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 17, 2024</a></blockquote><p dir="ltr">“Each Trader Goes through Multiple Stages”</p><p dir="ltr">As the competition in the brokerage space gets fierce, the demand for offerings like <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/crypto-education-resources-and-tools-for-learning-about-blockchain-and-digital-assets/">educational materials</a> also increases. The broker wants to differentiate its services from the competition by offering quality educational materials.</p><p dir="ltr">“Thanks to our clients’ feedback, we understand that there is a need to increase user engagement. This can be achieved by adding quizzes, simulations, or alerts, for instance. This trend is also reflected in prop trading nowadays,” Albessard said.</p><p dir="ltr">Despite the demand for educational resources, such content must be sorted correctly and strategically based on the traders’ appetite.</p><p dir="ltr">Emphasizing the strategies to target the traders, Albessard explained that: “Each trader goes through multiple stages for which they require specific tools. The video academy and trading courses are used mostly by beginners at the start of their journey (conversion). Other trading and market analysis tools are also essential but may be used at a later stage (retention). In a nutshell, my tip would be to provide traders with the right content at the right time.”</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Dear Traders, I assure you that if you fully commit to your trading education, approaching it with a mindset of continuous learning and practical application through backtesting and forward testing, you will witness tangible results. It typically takes 1-2 years of meticulous…</p>— Adrian Trades LIVE (@realaditrades) <a href="https://twitter.com/realaditrades/status/1778505045064990943?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 11, 2024</a></blockquote><p dir="ltr">An Employee-Turned-Owner</p><p dir="ltr">Based in Cyprus, Traders Education was founded in 2013 and was part of a holding company. Albessard joined the company in 2019 as the Head of Sales.</p><p dir="ltr">“There was some structural change in the project quickly after [I joined], yet it was too soon to take the lead as I needed time to get more familiar with the industry,” Albessard added. “The product development and operations slowed down during the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/the-impact-of-covid-19-on-fintech-and-its-long-term-effects/">COVID-19 period</a>.”</p><p dir="ltr">“Fortunately, we held several meetings with the group’s top management and drew a plan to rebuild the product. The first positive changes were visible a few months later, with new people joining the team, the release of a new logo/website, and the renewal of the educational content. Unfortunately, there was an unexpected turn of events at the end of 2022 when the owners expressed their will to pause the project.”</p><p dir="ltr">“For some reason, I saw it as an opportunity for the company and the team. The former owners were not opposed to a potential acquisition. Therefore, the whole process happened smoothly, and the transfer was completed in April 2023, exactly a year ago.”</p><p dir="ltr">Albessard additionally highlighted that, under his leadership, the company redesigned several widgets, such as the economic calendar, the market watch, and the calculator.</p><p dir="ltr">“By the end of the year, we managed to develop new partnerships as well as strengthen the existing ones with both our providers and clients,” he said.</p><p dir="ltr">“AI Is a Part of Our Day-to-Day Operations”</p><p dir="ltr">Talking about the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/trending/ai-in-2023-rises-falls-and-evolution/">importance of artificial intelligence (AI)</a>, Albessard said that new-age technology “has become part of our day-to-day operations, helping us with various areas of our business, mostly with content creation and design.”</p><p dir="ltr">“An example of AI-powered tools used by Traders Education is for the creation of voiceovers or subtitles. These tools help to simplify some tasks, and, therefore, allow us to focus on more complex and creative aspects of our work. However, we are also aware of its limitations and perhaps its ethical considerations.”</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Mango Markets’ Manipulator Faces up to 20 Years in Jail after Jury Conviction]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/mango-markets-manipulator-faces-up-to-20-years-in-jail-after-jury-conviction/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/mango-markets-manipulator-faces-up-to-20-years-in-jail-after-jury-conviction/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 06:22:01 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/mango-markets-manipulator-faces-up-to-20-years-in-jail-after-jury-conviction</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A federal jury in New York yesterday (Thursday) convicted Avraham 'Avi' Eisenberg, a crypto trader, for fraud and market manipulation in carrying out a $110 million heist from the decentralized cryptocurrency exchange Mango Markets. It was the first conviction in a cryptocurrency market manipulation case.</p><p>Jail Time Ahead</p><p>He is now facing substantial prison time: the commodities fraud count and the commodities manipulation count against him each carry a maximum imprisonment of 10 years, while the count of wire fraud carries a maximum sentence of up to 20 years. His sentencing is scheduled for July 29.</p><p>“This ground-breaking prosecution epitomizes this office’s ability to employ innovative methods and cutting-edge law enforcement tools to continue to protect all financial markets,” US Attorney Damian Williams said.</p><p>A $110 Million Heist</p><p>In October 2022, Eisenberg used two accounts to sell a large number of perpetual contracts of Mango’s crypto token MNGO from one of his accounts to the other, thus artificially inflating the price by 1,300 percent in under an hour. He then used the token as collateral to borrow $110 million in other cryptocurrencies from Mango Markets and quickly withdrew the funds. In doing so, he essentially withdrew all the cryptocurrencies deposited on the DeFi platform.</p><p>Later, he negotiated a settlement with Mango Markets and agreed to return $67 million to the decentralized autonomous organization governing the protocol. He was <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/defi-protocol-mango-markets-manipulator-is-arrested/">arrested in December 2022 in Puerto Rico</a>.</p><p>In court, the defense lawyers tried to convince the jury that Eisenberg’s trades on Mango Markets were “successful and legal” and “fully complied” with the decentralized protocol’s scant rules. However, the jury sided with the prosecutors' portrayal of it as a “brazen” fraud and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/interview/crypto-market-manipulation-is-still-alive-and-well-says-orbs-ilan-sterk/">manipulation</a>.</p><p>The US Commodity Futures Trading Commission also brought <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/cftc-charges-mango-markets-manipulator-with-fraud/">civil fraud and market manipulation charges against Eisenberg</a>.</p><p>“Manipulative trading puts our financial markets and investors at risk,” the Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General, Nicole Argentieri, said. “This prosecution, the first involving the manipulation of cryptocurrency through open-market trades, demonstrates the Criminal Division’s commitment to protecting U.S. financial markets and holding wrongdoers accountable, no matter what mechanism they use to commit manipulation and fraud.”</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Kraken Acquires TradeStation Crypto]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/kraken-acquires-tradestation-crypto/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/kraken-acquires-tradestation-crypto/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 05:23:53 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/kraken-acquires-tradestation-crypto</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The crypto exchange Kraken has acquired TradeStation Crypto, the digital asset-focused division of online brokerage TradeStation, to support its expansion efforts in the United States, Coindesk reported.</p><p>However, the closing date of the acquisition and other details remain unclear as neither company has announced anything officially. The financials of the deal have not been revealed.</p><p>Kraken’s Push in the US</p><p>“We can confirm Kraken has recently purchased TradeStation's crypto business,” a Kraken spokesperson wrote in an email confirming the acquisition to the crypto-focused publication. “This transaction is part of our efforts to accelerate our US presence and will support further growth and new product opportunities for Kraken in the US.”</p><p>Indeed, Florida-based TradeStation Crypto holds money transmitter licenses in 47 states in the US, Washington DC, and Puerto Rico, according to the Financial Crimes Enforcement Center’s database. These licenses are necessary for running crypto exchange operations and registrar businesses in compliance with federal laws in the US.</p><p>A Global Expansion Plan</p><p>Headquartered in San Francisco, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/kraken/">Kraken </a>is focused on its expansion, both domestically and internationally. In Europe, the exchange recently obtained multiple licenses, including regulatory approval in Spain and Ireland. Furthermore, the American exchange acquired BCM, a Dutch crypto exchange, late last year to expand its presence in continental Europe.</p><p>Recently, Kraken expanded its services with the launch of a <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/kraken-steps-up-the-game-with-the-introduction-of-crypto-wallet/">self-custodial cryptocurrency wallet</a>. The exchange also offers a dedicated platform to its institutional clients, along with custodial solutions.</p><p>Meanwhile, Kraken is facing regulatory backlash. <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/sec-sues-kraken-for-registration-failure-mixing-customers-funds/">The US securities regulator has charged the exchange</a> with illegally operating an unregistered securities exchange, broker, dealer, and clearing agency, and with mixing customers’ money and crypto assets with its own.</p><p>Interestingly, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/sec-hits-tradestation-crypto-with-15-million-penalty-over-unregistered-services/">TradeStation Crypto settled with the Securities and Exchange Commission</a> earlier this year by paying $1.5 million for offering crypto lending products, which were categorised as unregistered securities.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[JPMorgan's CEO Jamie Dimon Renews Attack on Bitcoin, Calls It "Fraud"]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/jpmorgans-ceo-jamie-dimon-renews-attack-on-bitcoin-calls-it-fraud/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/jpmorgans-ceo-jamie-dimon-renews-attack-on-bitcoin-calls-it-fraud/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 19:52:50 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/jpmorgans-ceo-jamie-dimon-renews-attack-on-bitcoin-calls-it-fraud</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jamie Dimon recently affirmed
his longstanding stance against Bitcoin. In an interview with Bloomberg
TV, the CEO of JPMorgan labeled the leading digital asset a
"fraud" and "Ponzi Scheme." According to Dimon, Bitcoin lacks the fundamental
qualities necessary to function as a currency. </p><p>Dimon Labels Bitcoin "Ponzi Scheme"</p><p>"Crypto, if you mean crypto like Bitcoin, I've
always said it's a fraud. If they think there is a currency, there's no hope for
it. It's a Ponzi scheme, it is a public decentralized Ponzi scheme," Dimon mentioned. He dismissed Bitcoin as merely a speculative
asset, saying those who view it as a legitimate form of
money are misguided.</p><p>Despite acknowledging <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Bitcoin</a>'s role in modern
financial markets, Dimon does not believe that the token has the potential to
function as a currency. Throughout the years, he has consistently expressed
skepticism about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/bitcoin/" class="terms__main-term" id="261088a9-0f41-4202-a73c-31f75ba6bd93">Bitcoin</a>, citing concerns about volatility and the lack of regulation. Despite the growing acceptance of the asset by mainstream
institutions, Dimon's stance has not changed.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">JUST IN: JPMorgan CEO Jamie Dimon says <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a> is a fraud and a ponzi scheme.JPMorgan is an authorized participant for BlackRock's Spot Bitcoin ETF. <a href="https://t.co/4tpjkaZ0TV">pic.twitter.com/4tpjkaZ0TV</a></p>— Watcher.Guru (@WatcherGuru) <a href="https://twitter.com/WatcherGuru/status/1780981956655640843?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2024</a></blockquote><p>In January, while speaking during the World Economic Forum
in Davos, Dimon said that he was officially done discussing Bitcoin. He likened it to a "pet rock," CNBC reported. His comments echoed similar sentiments he
expressed in 2021 and the previous year in Davos, terming Bitcoin as
"worthless" and a "hyped-up fraud." However, Dimon's remarks
highlighted a distinction between <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/blockchain/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="be18ed01-45fc-4044-b447-06802a10dbcd">blockchain</a> technology and Bitcoin.</p><p>Perspective on Smart Contracts</p><p>Dimon acknowledged the practical applications of
blockchain technology in facilitating efficient transactions and data transfer. He is optimistic about smart
contract-enabled blockchains, such as Ethereum, which facilitate the execution of financial transactions without the need for intermediaries.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Jamie Dimon on the cryptocurrency industry: "I'd close it down" <a href="https://t.co/vimnFywEjk">https://t.co/vimnFywEjk</a></p>— CBS Mornings (@CBSMornings) <a href="https://twitter.com/CBSMornings/status/1733849045850886191?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 10, 2023</a></blockquote><p>In his latest remarks with Bloomberg TV, Dimon said:
"If it's a crypto coin that can do something like, you know, a smart
contract that has value, there will be smart contracts and blockchain
works."</p><p>Dimon's latest comments arrived a day before the most important event in the Bitcoin blockchain: <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/bitcoin-halving-countdown-why-it-may-not-guarantee-price-surge/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Bitcoin halving</a>. This event occurs approximately every four years and cuts the rewards for Bitcoin miners by half. Currently, the cryptocurrency world is excited about the upcoming halving, especially with recent developments like the approval of spot Bitcoin ETFs.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Tastytrade Partners with Unusual Whales for Options Trading]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/tastytrade-partners-with-unusual-whales-for-options-trading/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/tastytrade-partners-with-unusual-whales-for-options-trading/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:37:49 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/tastytrade-partners-with-unusual-whales-for-options-trading</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The online trading brokerage firm Tastytrade has
partnered with Unusual Whales, an options trading platform. Through this partnership, users of the Unusual Whales' Options Flow platform will gain direct access to options trading using Tastytrade's accounts.</p><p>Scott Sheridan, the CEO of Tastytrade, mentioned:
"We're huge fans of Unusual Whales and the transparency they bring to the
markets, enabling traders to make informed decisions." The integration of Tastytrade's
tools on the Unusual Whales platform aims to provide traders with trading
insights.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re huge fans of Unusual Whales and the transparency they bring to the markets, enabling traders to make informed decisions <a href="https://t.co/a71EeAyLgF">https://t.co/a71EeAyLgF</a></p>— Jared Kirui (@JaredLopta79285) <a href="https://twitter.com/JaredLopta79285/status/1781007389942030511?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Expanding Reach and Offerings</p><p>Recently, Tastytrade <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/igs-tastytrade-opens-new-office-in-chicago-commits-600k-to-non-profit-organization/" target="_blank" rel="follow">launched</a> a new 35,000-square-foot
office space and studios in Chicago, along with a commitment to invest $600,000 in the
Greenwood Project, a non-profit organization dedicated to fostering diversity
in finance.</p><p>JJ Kinahan, the CEO of IG North America and President of
Tastytrade, emphasized the importance of the opportunity to drive
positive change. By investing in the Greenwood Project, Tastytrade aims to
support talented Black and Latino students and contribute toward an inclusive
financial services industry.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Have you heard the news? Exciting things are happening in Fulton Market. <a href="https://t.co/E8IpGpqhrY">https://t.co/E8IpGpqhrY</a></p>— tastytrade (@tastytrade) <a href="https://twitter.com/tastytrade/status/1777692741834564044?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 9, 2024</a></blockquote><p>In 2021, IG Group acquired Tastytrade to strengthen its position in the retail options and futures market. This action preceded the group's entry into the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/r/retail-trading/" class="terms__main-term" id="2d172307-15c6-4278-a100-fcbb8d9c19c9">retail trading</a> market in the US.</p><p>Acquisition and Growth</p><p>Following the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/a/acquisition/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="3180494d-8751-4a02-9476-86dc1cd4d2e2">acquisition</a>, Tastytrade, now part of the
IG Group, has diversified its offerings to encompass a range of trading options
catering to retail investors. The firm reported a surge in revenue from its US
operations in FY23, highlighting its growth in the financial market.</p><p>Additionally, IG Group's American division is <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/ig-groups-american-arm-joins-fia-expands-its-global-trading-network/" target="_blank" rel="follow">a member</a> of the Futures Industry Association. The spread betting and CFD trading firm joined the association to expand its reach into the lucrative US market. This initiative underscored the group's efforts to foster international collaborations and strengthen its presence in the financial trading sector.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[ceτi AI Acquires Big Energy Investments Inc. in Latest Move]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/cei-ai-acquires-big-energy-investments-inc-in-latest-move/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/cei-ai-acquires-big-energy-investments-inc-in-latest-move/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:01:49 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/cei-ai-acquires-big-energy-investments-inc-in-latest-move</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>ceτi AI (http://taoceti.ai/) a leader in decentralized artificial intelligence infrastructure, is pleased to announce its acquisition of Canadian company Big Energy Investments Inc., a firm specializing in strategic investment in high-performance computing infrastructure. This acquisition marks a significant first step in ceτi AI’s strategy to advance the development and accessibility of AI technologies.</p><p>Strategic Acquisition and Enhanced Capabilities</p><p>Following the acquisition, Big Energy Investments, Ltd. has reached agreements in principle to acquire advanced high-performance computing (HPC) infrastructure, including five HPC servers, each equipped with 8 NVIDIA H100 Tensor Core GPUs, and two NVIDIA Quantum-2 InfiniBand switches, set to be delivered in May 2024. These agreements are anticipated to be executed within the next week, underscoring the commitment to enhancing the technological capabilities promptly.</p><p>This strategic enhancement is pivotal for the initial North American deployment of the ceτi AI Infrastructure Network, which will utilize the ceτi AI Intelligent Compute Fabric to manage and provide compute resources to decentralized AI networks, decentralized physical infrastructure networks (DePIN), and various other applications.</p><p>Strategic Deployment and Pilot Implementation</p><p>The new HPC infrastructure will underpin the first North American deployment of the ceτi AI Intelligent Compute Fabric, which manages the ceτi AI Infrastructure Network. This network is designed to provide essential compute resources to a variety of decentralized client networks and is a critical component of ceτi AI’s broader mission to democratize AI technology through decentralization. The pilot implementation will not only demonstrate the capabilities of the ceτi AI solution but also initiate revenue generation and accumulation for the CETI token ecosystem.</p><p>Roadmap and Future Plans</p><p>The successful integration and demonstration of this infrastructure will set the stage for immediate expansion to data-center scale implementations, significantly scaling up ceτi AI’s operational capabilities. Work continues to progress on the CETI token ecosystem, with its introduction being the next major milestone on the ceτi AI roadmap.</p><p>Executive Insight</p><p>"This acquisition marks a significant milestone in ceτi AI's growth trajectory, aligning with our strategic goals to bolster our infrastructure and accelerate the development of decentralized AI technologies. By integrating Big Energy Investments' resources and capabilities, we are better positioned to innovate and expand our reach across North America," said Dennis Jarvis, CEO of ceτi AI.</p><p>Forward-Looking Statements</p><p>This press release contains forward-looking statements relating to expected future events and anticipated results that are subject to significant risks and uncertainties. These include, but are not limited to, the final procurement and integration of HPC infrastructure, the deployment and performance of the ceτi AI Intelligent Compute Fabric, and the broader adoption and impact of the CETI token ecosystem. Actual outcomes and results may differ materially from what is expressed or forecasted in such forward-looking statements due to a variety of factors.</p><p>About ceτi AI</p><p>ceτi AI is at the forefront of revolutionizing artificial intelligence through decentralization. Committed to innovation and accessibility, ceτi AI develops globally distributed, high-performance, scalable AI infrastructure designed to empower developers and networks worldwide. By democratizing access to state-of-the-art resources, ceτi AI aims to accelerate the advancement of AI technologies, making them more diverse and universally accessible. Our mission extends beyond infrastructure development; we are building a foundation for the future of AI, ensuring it grows in a manner that benefits all of humanity without sacrificing freedom of choice or expression.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Coinbase's Former Executive Nana Murugesan Named President of Ethereum Scaling Firm]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/coinbases-former-executive-nana-murugesan-named-president-of-ethereum-scaling-firm/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/coinbases-former-executive-nana-murugesan-named-president-of-ethereum-scaling-firm/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:09:20 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/coinbases-former-executive-nana-murugesan-named-president-of-ethereum-scaling-firm</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase's former Vice President for Business
Development, International, and Listings, Nana Murugesan, has joined the
Ethereum scaling solution firm Matter Labs as the President. Murugesan will
lead the firm's operations, which encompass marketing, communication, finance,
and legal.</p><p>According to LinkedIn, he previously served as the
Managing Director of International Markets and Mobile Partnerships at Snap for
more than three years. Besides that, Murugesan dedicated nine years to working as the Vice
President and General Manager for Services and New Business at Samsung
Electronics.</p><p>Blockchain Scaling Solutions</p><p>Alex Gluchowski, the Co-Founder and CEO of Matter
Labs, mentioned: "We are excited to welcome Nana to the Matter Labs team,
where his expertise will be instrumental in advancing our vision to scale
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/blockchain-technology/" target="_blank" rel="follow">blockchain technology</a> to a mainstream audience, powered by zero-knowledge
technology." </p><p>"Nana's unique combination of world-class scaling
experience and deep industry insights will be invaluable. His proven leadership
skills will play a pivotal role in driving the growth of our cutting-edge
engineering solutions and fortifying our go-to-market strategies as we build
the future of finance."</p><p>With a background in electrical engineering, computer engineering, and business administration, Murugesan brings a multidisciplinary approach to his new role at Matter Labs. He is expected to lead the development of engineering solutions in <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/blockchain/" class="terms__main-term" id="be18ed01-45fc-4044-b447-06802a10dbcd">blockchain</a> technology at the firm, which has more than 60 employees across nearly 35 countries.</p><p>Murugesan Targets Blockchain Adoption </p><p>Matter Labs is a research and development company that focuses on creating technology solutions for scaling the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/ethereum/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Ethereum</a> blockchain. Some of its solutions include zero-knowledge technology, which aims to facilitate fast, secure, and scalable transactions.</p><p>Speaking about his appointment, Murugesan said: “I’m
thrilled to join Matter Labs during this crucial phase. With zkSync, we’re
tackling the end-game of blockchain <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/s/scalability/" target="_blank" rel="follow">scalability</a> and enabling practical
applications with developers to bring in the next billion users.” </p><p>“My experience with scaling high-growth companies will
help as we expand our community and partner ecosystem around the world. I look
forward to partnering with Alex and the team on this ambitious mission to
accelerate the ongoing financial revolution.”</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Cash for Cypherpunks: The Deutsche Bundesbank and MIT Forge a Digital Euro Pact]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/cash-for-cypherpunks-the-deutsche-bundesbank-and-mit-forge-a-digital-euro-pact/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/cash-for-cypherpunks-the-deutsche-bundesbank-and-mit-forge-a-digital-euro-pact/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:00:48 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/cash-for-cypherpunks-the-deutsche-bundesbank-and-mit-forge-a-digital-euro-pact</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The clinking of coins
and the satisfying rustle of bills might soon be relegated to the realm of
nostalgia. Central banks around the world are whispering sweet nothings to
blockchain technology, exploring the creation of Central Bank Digital
Currencies (CBDCs). <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/mit-german-central-bank-research-cbdc-privacy-new-project">The latest tango </a>is between the Massachusetts Institute of
Technology's Digital Currency Initiative (DCI) and the Deutsche Bundesbank,
Germany's central bank. Their focus? Designing a digital euro that prioritizes
both security and, more interestingly, user privacy.</p><p>This newfound love
affair between central banks and cryptography might seem strange bedfellows.
After all, haven't these bastions of financial stability spent decades keeping
a watchful eye on the flow of money? Isn't a digital currency, easily traceable
and monitored, a dream come true for regulators? Not quite.</p><p>The Bundesbank, under
President Joachim Nagel, <a href="https://www.bundesbank.de/en/press/press-releases/bundesbank-and-mit-media-lab-to-conduct-joint-research-into-central-bank-digital-currency-cbdc--914150">acknowledges the allure of complete oversight</a>.
However, they also recognize the growing public unease with private
corporations hoarding our financial data like digital dragons guarding their
treasure. The current system, where every latte purchase and online transaction
becomes part of a meticulously crafted consumer profile, leaves a sour taste in
many mouths.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Preserving privacy is essential as digital transactions increase. Today <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/JoachimNagel?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#JoachimNagel</a> President <a href="https://twitter.com/bundesbank?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@bundesbank</a> announced a new collaboration with DCI to explore privacy-preserving designs for central bank digital currency during a speech <a href="https://twitter.com/medialab?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@medialab</a>. More info: <a href="https://t.co/5TJ7mw61eX">https://t.co/5TJ7mw61eX</a> <a href="https://t.co/2Nr7O3HG1v">pic.twitter.com/2Nr7O3HG1v</a></p>— Digital Currency Initiative (@mitDCI) <a href="https://twitter.com/mitDCI/status/1780270116426661915?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 16, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Nagel puts it bluntly:
"Private digital payment solutions often use third-party services that
gain access to consumers’ payment data, which they can use for commercial
purposes." This isn't just about targeted advertising for the latest
artisanal catnip; it's about the potential for discrimination, manipulation,
and the erosion of financial privacy.</p><p>The digital euro, as
envisioned by the Bundesbank and DCI, aims to be different. It aspires to be a
digital cash equivalent, offering the same level of anonymity associated with
physical currency. This doesn't mean a free-for-all for money launderers and
rogue states. The Bundesbank assures us that safeguards will be in place, with
potential holding limits on digital euro accounts to prevent financial
shenanigans.</p><p>But why rock the boat?
Why tinker with a system, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/the-money-makeover-will-central-bank-digital-currencies-break-the-bank-literally/">albeit one with privacy concerns</a>, that seems to be
working well enough? The answer lies in the shifts transforming the
financial ecosystem. As Nagel aptly points out, "German bank cards, for example,
don't always work in other euro area countries." This lack of seamless
integration within a supposedly unified currency zone highlights the
limitations of the current system.</p><p>A digital euro, built on
robust and secure technology, has the potential to streamline cross-border
transactions, fostering a more efficient and inclusive financial ecosystem.
Additionally, it could act as a bulwark against the rising tide of private digital
currencies like Facebook's Diem (now Meta Diem). These privately issued
alternatives, while offering convenience, raise concerns about control over the
money supply and potential dominance by a select few tech giants.</p><p>The Bundesbank and DCI's
collaboration is just one piece of a much larger puzzle. Central banks around
the world, from the Federal Reserve Bank of Boston to the Bank of Canada, are
all waltzing with the idea of CBDCs. The motivations vary, but the undercurrent
of concern about privacy and the future of money is undeniable.</p><p>This digital currency
revolution, however, is not without its skeptics. Some fear that CBDCs could
destabilize the financial system by encouraging citizens to bypass traditional
banks and park their money directly with the central bank. Others worry about
the potential for government overreach, with the ability to track and
potentially control spending habits.</p><p>The road ahead for the
digital euro is long and winding. Public education and open dialogue will be
crucial in addressing these concerns and ensuring widespread adoption. But one
thing is clear: the future of money is likely to be a fascinating dance between
the tried-and-true methods of the past and the innovative potential of
cryptography. The Bundesbank and DCI's collaboration is a step in that
direction, a digital foxtrot with the potential to reshape the financial
landscape for years to come.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Klarna Card Shakes Up US Payments]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/klarna-card-shakes-up-us-payments/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/klarna-card-shakes-up-us-payments/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:00:10 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/klarna-card-shakes-up-us-payments</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Move over, plastic
fantastic. The era of opaque interest rates, surprise fees, and the
ever-present threat of late payment penalties might be nearing its end. At
least, that's the promise Klarna is making <a href="https://www.klarna.com/international/press/new-and-improved-klarna-card-announced-in-the-us-empowering-smarter-spending-and-greater-financial-control/">with its US debut of the Klarna
Card</a>, a new financial instrument
aiming to be the smarter, smoother way to shop and pay.</p><p>Klarna, the Swedish
buy-now-pay-later (BNPL) giant, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/klarnas-wikipink-throws-a-wrench-into-the-credit-card-machine/">has already carved a niche for itself in the
payments industry</a>. Their model lets consumers split purchases into
installments, typically interest-free, offering a more controlled alternative
to traditional credit cards. Now, with the Klarna Card, they're taking things a
step further. This physical and virtual Visa card integrates seamlessly with
the Klarna app, allowing users to not only manage payments but also shop for
the best deals and track spending in one centralized location.</p><p>But what truly sets the
Klarna Card apart is its commitment to transparency. No more buried fees
lurking in the fine print – Klarna boasts zero annual fees, no monthly fees,
and even waives foreign transaction fees for international purchases. This
focus on upfront clarity is a welcome change in an industry notorious for its
hidden costs.</p><p>The traditional credit
card model has long been criticized for its tendency to encourage impulsive
spending and rack up debt.</p><p> Klarna counters this by promoting responsible
financial behavior. The Klarna Card operates on a debit system, meaning users
can only spend what they have available. Additionally, it offers a variety of
flexible payment options, empowering users to choose how they want to manage
their purchases. They can opt to pay their statement in full each month to
avoid interest charges, make early payments to chip away at larger purchases,
or split eligible transactions into 3 or 6 installments with interest. This
level of control allows users to tailor their repayment strategy to their
unique financial situation.</p><p>This focus on
responsible spending is underscored by Klarna's data. </p><p>They report that a
significantly lower percentage of their BNPL users incur late fees compared to
traditional credit card users. This suggests that the Klarna model, with its
emphasis on transparency and control, might be nudging users towards healthier
financial habits.</p><p>Of course, the Klarna
Card isn't a magic bullet. Approval requires meeting eligibility criteria,
including a credit check. For those who qualify, however, the Klarna Card
presents a compelling alternative. It offers the convenience and security of a
traditional credit card, with the added benefits of transparency, flexibility,
and the potential for rewards through the Klarna app.</p><p>The Klarna Card's
arrival in the US throws down a gauntlet to established credit card companies.
Consumers are increasingly demanding more from their financial tools, and
Klarna is stepping up to deliver. Whether this new entrant will disrupt the
status quo remains to be seen, but one thing is certain: the Klarna Card
injects a dose of competition into the payments industry, which can only
benefit consumers seeking smarter ways to manage their money.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Dollars Get a Digital Dialogue: The CHIPS Network Embraces ISO 20022]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/dollars-get-a-digital-dialogue-the-chips-network-embraces-iso-20022/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/dollars-get-a-digital-dialogue-the-chips-network-embraces-iso-20022/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:59:50 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/dollars-get-a-digital-dialogue-the-chips-network-embraces-iso-20022</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The gears of global
finance, once oiled by cryptic acronyms and proprietary protocols, are
undergoing a quiet revolution. On April 8th, 2024, a seemingly mundane
transaction – a payment between two major banks – <a href="https://www.theclearinghouse.org/payment-systems/Articles/2024/04/CHIPS_ISO_CA_MUFG_First_Payment_04-17-2024">marked a turning point for
the CHIPS network</a>, the world's largest private-sector high-value clearing and
settlement system. This wasn't just another transfer of funds; it was the first
payment conducted using the ISO 20022 messaging format, a standardized language
poised to streamline the symphony of international finance.</p><p>For decades, the CHIPS
network, the dominant player in US dollar clearing, relied on a system that,
while efficient, lacked a certain fluency. Messages were akin to telegrams,
conveying the bare essentials of a transaction – sender, receiver, amount. This
functional minimalism served its purpose, but it also created limitations.
Richer data, crucial for regulatory compliance, fraud detection, and even
supply chain optimization, remained trapped within siloed systems.</p><p>The ISO 20022 standard
breaks down these communication barriers. </p><p>With
ISO 20022, payments become more than just the movement of money; they carry
embedded information about invoices, customs declarations, and even the
ultimate purpose of the funds. This newfound eloquence opens doors to a future
of smoother, faster, and more transparent cross-border payments.</p><p>And the benefits extend
beyond mere efficiency: the standardized format fosters interoperability
between the CHIPS network and other global systems, creating a more unified
financial ecosystem. Think of it as the Rosetta Stone of finance, enabling
previously disparate systems to converse seamlessly. This newfound harmony
could lead to a reduction in processing errors, faster settlement times, and
ultimately, a more cost-effective financial infrastructure.</p><p>The adoption of ISO
20022 by CHIPS isn't just a technological upgrade; it's a strategic move.</p><p> The
world of finance is increasingly interconnected, and the US dollar remains a
critical player on the global stage. By embracing this new standard, CHIPS positions
itself as a leader in the evolution of international payments, ensuring its
continued relevance in a rapidly changing landscape.</p><p>Of course, this shift
isn't without its challenges. Implementing a new messaging format across a vast
network like CHIPS requires significant coordination and investment. Banks and
other financial institutions need to adapt their systems and processes to
accommodate the richer data exchange. But the potential rewards – <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/the-double-edged-sword-of-faster-payments/">faster
transactions</a>, improved transparency, and a more interconnected financial
ecosystem – make the effort worthwhile.</p><p>The successful
completion of the first ISO 20022 payment on the CHIPS network is a testament
to the collective effort of the financial industry. It's a symbol of progress,
a step towards a future where international payments are conducted with the
same ease and efficiency as domestic transactions. While the full impact of
this shift remains to be seen, one thing is certain: the once-terse dialogue of
global finance is evolving into a richer conversation, paving the way for a
more streamlined and transparent financial future.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Breaking: Prop Trading Firm The Funded Trader Is Back Online, but Is It Fully Operational?]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/prop-trading-firm-the-funded-trader-is-online-but-is-it-fully-operational/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/prop-trading-firm-the-funded-trader-is-online-but-is-it-fully-operational/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:32:21 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Brokers]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/prop-trading-firm-the-funded-trader-is-online-but-is-it-fully-operational</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The website of The Funded Trader, a prop trading platform operated by Easton Consulting Technologies, is back online after a 21-day blackout. Although the website's features appear unchanged, some aspects seem to be non-operational.</p><p>A Theme or an Operational Website?</p><p>A peculiar label reading “theme activated successfully” appears at the top of the prop trading platform’s website.</p><p>Most platform features, including challenge details, appear to be functional at first glance. However, the payments page for purchasing challenges looks unusual, and crypto payment functionality is unavailable.</p><p>The website also provides a phone number, but the recorded message says that the platform is not offering support on phone and refers to its website.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">.<a href="https://twitter.com/thefundedtrader?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@thefundedtrader</a> website is back up But no announcement, still millions not paid out, accounts failed due to inactivity while down and no new credentials given out - yet you can still buy new challenges. <a href="https://t.co/4A3A7IorW5">pic.twitter.com/4A3A7IorW5</a></p>— The Prop Journalist (@PropJournalist) <a href="https://twitter.com/PropJournalist/status/1780946526216257959?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2024</a></blockquote><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/breaking-prop-trading-firm-the-funded-trader-pauses-all-operations/">The Funded Trader suspended its operations</a> on March 28, citing temporary reasons. It pledged to relaunch services after 21 days, even featuring a countdown on the website. While the countdown was not precisely accurate, as the website did not go live the moment the countdown reached zero, the website became active within a few hours.</p><p>Interestingly, all social channels of The Funded Trader are notably quiet, with no announcements about the relaunch. Angelo Ciaramello, the Chief Executive Officer of The Funded Trader, even unfollowed everyone on X (previously Twitter) and refrained from posting for weeks, despite being active on social media previously.</p><p>Manual Breach of Accounts</p><p>Numerous self-proclaimed customers of The Funded Trader claim their accounts were “manually breached” due to rule violations.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I don’t understand anymore, they come back and they breach my account for no reason, please explain <a href="https://twitter.com/thefundedtrader?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@thefundedtrader</a> <a href="https://t.co/FHm3zYTsfx">pic.twitter.com/FHm3zYTsfx</a></p>— Daniel (@Jachike99) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jachike99/status/1780947550360510606?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2024</a></blockquote><p>The Funded Trader boasts over 80,000 accounts. However, the platform has faced numerous controversies, with <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/traders-rage-as-prop-firm-the-funded-trader-delays-payouts-for-up-to-a-month/">dozens of traders accusing it of denying payouts</a>. While Ciaramello dismissed these allegations as “propaganda,” the platform later acknowledged suspending payouts for a “<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/prop-trading-firm-the-funded-trader-cites-internal-audit-to-suspend-payouts/">self-imposed internal audit</a>,” only to suspend services shortly after.</p><p>During a live YouTube broadcast, Ciaramello presented a graphic indicating that in the first two months of 2024, The Funded Trader disbursed over $17 million to clients while withholding withdrawals of just over $2 million during the same period.</p><p>In addition to The Funded Trader, Easton controls several other prop trading platforms. Skilled Funded Trader, another Easton-controlled prop trading platform, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/easton-controlled-skilled-funded-trader-suspends-prop-trading-operations/">also suspended its operations</a> around the same time as The Funded Trader.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Tokenizing Real-World Assets Redefines Financial Inclusivity: A $16 Trillion Outlook]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/tokenizing-real-world-assets-redefines-financial-inclusivity-a-16-trillion-outlook/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/tokenizing-real-world-assets-redefines-financial-inclusivity-a-16-trillion-outlook/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Itai Avneri]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/tokenizing-real-world-assets-redefines-financial-inclusivity-a-16-trillion-outlook</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>We are standing on the cusp of a new era when digital and
traditional finance converge to create social and economic transformation.
Where barriers to entry once stood, technological advancements are making it
possible for anyone to access wealth-creation opportunities that were once the
domain of the elite few. At the forefront of this transformation is the
emergence of tokens, specifically those that represent real-world assets, such
as stocks, bonds, real estate and others. </p><p>By reimagining ownership and trading of assets, tokenization
is unlocking doors to financial opportunities previously out of reach to many.
This shift is not just altering market dynamics, it's laying the foundation for
a more equitable and accessible <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/financial/">financial</a> future
when empowerment and freedom aren't just ideals but tangible realities.</p><p>Investing in Appreciating Assets - an Economic Necessity</p><p>The ability to invest capital into assets, instead of
holding cash, is not a luxury but a necessity for every household
looking to survive and thrive. Holding cash, often perceived as a safe bet, is
a silent thief eroded by the relentless march of inflation. Consider this, $100
in 2004, sitting idly, would have the purchasing power of merely $60 today.
Contrast this, with the dynamism of the stock market the same amount invested
in the S&amp;P 500 over the same period would have quintupled to an impressive
$470.</p><p>Yet, the landscape of stock ownership reveals a stark
imbalance. The wealthiest 10% in the US control an overwhelming 93% of stocks,
illustrating a deep-seated inequality in financial opportunity and access. This
inequality is magnified when looking at sectors like private equity and private
credit, where doors often remain closed to everyday <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/investors/">investors</a>. </p><p>Enter Tokenization, the Great Equalizer</p><p>While a distinctly counter-culture ethos characterized the
early days of blockchain, it wasn’t long before traditional financial
institutions sought to leverage this technology to improve existing
financial pipelines. Thus began the race to tokenize the world and empower
traditional assets like stock, bonds, and real estate with the benefits of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/blockchain/">blockchain</a>, such as
24/7/365 trading, fractional ownership, transparency, and programmability.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">“The most important first step is to get in there and start to engage in the ecosystem”—Sandy Kaul of <a href="https://twitter.com/FTI_Global?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FTI_Global</a>.How banks and asset managers can get started with tokenization ⬇️ <a href="https://t.co/kG2MdNrUdv">pic.twitter.com/kG2MdNrUdv</a></p>— Chainlink (@chainlink) <a href="https://twitter.com/chainlink/status/1780568641945145730?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 17, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Yet, perhaps the greatest advantage of the tokenization of
traditional asset classes is the ability to encourage retail participation.
Take the Republic Note, for example, a <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/digital-asset/">digital asset</a>
representing the Republic’s private equity portfolio of over 600 companies, including SpaceX, Maven, and Gumroad. All retail investors have to do to gain
exposure to the portfolio is sign up for INX.One, the trading platform where
the Republic Note trades 24/7/365. Such a privilege was unthinkable in the
pre-tokenization era.</p><p>The Tokenization Market Is Huge</p><p>The total addressable market for tokenization is huge, with
hundreds of trillions of dollars worth of real-world assets waiting to come on
chain. According to Boston Consulting Group, the tokenized asset market is
projected to grow to a staggering $16 trillion by 2030. We are still in the
early stages of this transformation, with only about 0.03% of the total market
size currently captured. At this low level of market penetration, a golden
opportunity presents itself to innovative asset managers, institutions, and
investors who wish to position themselves on the cusp of a new financial era. </p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HSBC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#HSBC</a> to Expand Tokenized Asset Offerings — CEO Says He's 'Very Comfortable' With <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Tokenization?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Tokenization</a> <a href="https://t.co/mjFwfPN7Fw">https://t.co/mjFwfPN7Fw</a></p>— Bitcoin.com News (@BTCTN) <a href="https://twitter.com/BTCTN/status/1780046494390735053?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 16, 2024</a></blockquote><p>However, navigating this evolving landscape is not without
its challenges. Regulatory frameworks vary significantly across the globe,
creating a complex mosaic of compliance requirements for <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/asset-managers/">asset managers</a>
and investors. This inconsistency in regulations poses a considerable hurdle,
as entities must adapt and comply with diverse legal standards in different
jurisdictions. </p><p>Despite these challenges, the opportunity presented in the
tokenization of real-world assets is too significant to ignore. Innovative
asset managers, institutions, and investors looking to capitalize on this shift
should collaborate with <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/tokenization/">tokenization</a>
leaders to capitalize on this rare chance to be at the forefront of a financial
revolution. </p><p>Towards a Holistic Tokenized Future</p><p>Tokenzied real-world assets are not growing in a vacuum.
Indeed, no single type of digital asset will monopolize this new financial
dawn. Rather, the true power of digital assets is unleashed when different
forms of digital assets interface with one another. </p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">“The Bank for International Settlements (BIS) has teamed up with the central banks of France, Japan, South Korea, Mexico, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, and the United States Federal Reserve Banks to explore asset tokenization.”<a href="https://t.co/IfCuWBVWAt">https://t.co/IfCuWBVWAt</a></p>— Securitize (@Securitize) <a href="https://twitter.com/Securitize/status/1780653330420654179?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 17, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin, tokenized real-world assets,
and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/cbdc/">Central Bank Digital
Currencies (CBDCs)</a> emerge as the foundational pillars of this modernized
financial landscape. Each serves a unique role and can empower its peers
to reach further than they can on their own. For example, enabling investors to
purchase stocks, bonds, and real estate with crypto opens up entirely new
investment avenues for crypto investors to diversify their holdings. </p><p>The coexistence is a testament to the fact that financial
inclusivity and progress don't demand the dominance of one over the others, but
thrive on their mutual support and integration. As we move forward, this triad
of digital assets is poised to redefine not just investment and currency, but
the very fabric of economic interaction and empowerment.</p>

This article was written by Itai Avneri at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[B2Broker Increases Leverage on Major FX Pairs to 1:200]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/b2broker-increases-leverage-on-major-fx-pairs-to-1200/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/b2broker-increases-leverage-on-major-fx-pairs-to-1200/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:20:32 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/b2broker-increases-leverage-on-major-fx-pairs-to-1200</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://b2broker.com/" target="_blank" rel="follow">B2Broker</a>, as a leading Prime of Prime liquidity provider, is committed to perfection. They constantly study their clients' requests and empower them with the most satisfactory tools and solutions to attract more end-users and secure a competitive advantage in the market. In this regard, they have increased the leverage to 1:200 for major FX pairs, thereby lowering margin requirements from 1% to 0.5%. </p><p>Furthermore, they have raised leverage up to 1:50 for BTCUSD and ETHUSD, decreasing margin requirements from 10% to 2% and improving clients' market position significantly.</p><p>More Details About B2Broker Liquidity Solutions</p><p>B2Broker's liquidity solutions have expanded considerably during recent years. Currently, they propose 1500+ instruments across eight asset classes, such as FOREX, Crypto CFD, Spot Indices, Precious Metals, Single Stocks, ETFs, Commodities and NDFs CFD.</p><p>B2Broker secures access to deep liquidity pools from Tier-1 providers, facilitating tight spreads and ultra-fast execution. Cutting-edge technology platforms and FIX API integrations like <a href="https://b2broker.com/bbp/" target="_blank" rel="follow">B2Trader</a>, <a href="https://b2broker.com/products/ctrader-white-label/" target="_blank" rel="follow">cTrader</a>, oneZero, Prime XM, Centroid, TFB, TradeLocker, Your Bourse, FX Cubic, and MT4/MT5 allow for seamless connectivity across numerous trading systems. </p><p>Additionally, it supports the aggregation and distribution of liquidity across multiple channels and improves trade execution and risk management.</p><p>The fundamental powers of B2Brokers' liquidity solutions include a strong infrastructure, vast connectivity options, and the proficiency to develop tailored liquidity setups for specific client requirements. </p><p>As industry leaders, they have presented notable creative solutions. Last year, B2Broker <a href="https://b2broker.com/ndf/" target="_blank" rel="follow">introduced NDFs</a> as a new asset class in the form of CFDs, with the advantage of next-day settlements. Furthermore, pioneering in the market, they introduced crypto CFDs based on spot and perpetual futures LPs. Now, they have managed to propose the most competitive margin conditions in the market.</p><p>B2Broker's balance sheet has been significantly strengthened, with over 250 institutional clients and 30 professional funds. This robust financial foundation is the base of their ability to fulfil clients' demands and boost leverage!</p><p>With the increased leverage on highly demanded trading pairs in key markets such as FX and Crypto, B2Broker empowers brokers to offer their traders greater flexibility to manage their capital.</p><p>John Murillo, Chief Dealing Officer of B2Broker Group of Companies, mentioned:</p><p>“This strategic update not only enhances our clients' competitive edge but also augments their capacity to cater to the evolving demands of their clientele, attract new business, and elevate their service standards by leveraging our liquidity solutions. </p><p>Thanks to our robust balance sheet and extensive client base, coupled with our impressive trading volumes, we stand at the forefront of the market. Our innovative mindset has been evident throughout our journey. We were the first to introduce crypto CFDs based on spot and, later, on perpetual futures. In addition to FOREX, today, we proudly offer over 150 crypto CFD pairs, a testament to our commitment to innovation and meeting the diverse needs of our clients.”</p><p>To Summarise</p><p>B2Broker is a prominent leader in the FinTech sector, modernising the industry with noteworthy contributions over the last decade. This company delivers solutions that cater to diverse business models, guaranteeing that their clients stay ahead of the competition and lead the trends. </p><p>With the latest update, B2Broker has considerably <a href="https://b2broker.com/news/b2broker-raises-leverage-on-major-forex-pairs-to-1200/" target="_blank" rel="follow">boosted its leverage</a> to provide the most competitive conditions for institutional clients, professional traders, brokerages, hedge funds, proprietary trading desks, and other financial institutions.</p><p>Contact B2Broker today for tailored solutions that drive success!</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Over 1K Builders, Partners & Investors Gather at Inaugural Global Event to Celebrate Sui]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/over-1k-builders-partners-investors-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/over-1k-builders-partners-investors-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 14:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/over-1k-builders-partners-investors-gather-at-inaugural-global-event-to-celebrate-sui</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Over 1,000 projects, partners, investors, and enthusiasts from 65 countries around the world gathered last week in Paris to celebrate Sui at the vaunted Layer 1’s inaugural global Sui Basecamp conference.</p><p class="MsoNormal">At its first-ever annual event held during Paris Blockchain Week, Sui was feted by developers and builders from around the world during a two-day event. Speakers at Sui Basecamp spanned all aspects of the industry from payments to gaming to e-commerce to major league sports, offering commentary in keynotes, panels, and fireside chats. </p><p class="MsoNormal">The event was punctuated by three major announcements. In partnership with Playtron, the Sui team announced the SuiPlay0x1, the world’s first lightweight handheld gaming device designed with native Web3 capabilities, and promising new gaming experiences. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Additionally, First Digital Labs, joined an announcement that FDUSD, the fastest-growing stablecoin in crypto, will be the first native dollar-backed stablecoin on Sui, a boon to Sui’s DeFi ecosystem, which is already the fastest-growing in the industry. Finally, Sui announced Enoki, a suite of Web3 utilities that will make it very simple for enterprises to leverage decentralized solutions inside their applications, products and services. </p><p class="MsoNormal text-align-start">Sui Basecamp attendees from 65 countries had the opportunity to meet each other face-to-face.</p><p class="MsoNormal">“In building Sui, we began with a blank canvas, aiming to create the preeminent platform for decentralized applications without the structural limitations we saw in other blockchains,” said Evan Cheng, Co-founder and CEO of Mysten Labs, originator of the Sui Network. “Less than a year after launching Sui’s mainnet, the remarkable strength of Sui’s performance has confirmed the approach. From nearly limitless horizontal scalability to industry leading speed of execution to achieving the most transactions in a single day of any blockchain ever, Sui’s performance has been exceptional and the network has only scratched the surface.”</p><p class="MsoNormal">The industry veterans who founded Sui launched its mainnet nearly a year ago to great expectations, and the network has performed exceptionally well. Rather than cloning an existing network, the Sui team started from scratch to build an entirely new infrastructure layer that addressed the shortcomings of existing blockchains. They started by creating Move, a novel smart contract language, and on top of it created a new architecture centered around objects that enables performance and functionality that is simply not available on existing blockchains. The result is a blockchain that is singular in the industry — the universal coordination layer for intelligent assets.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Sui (https://sui.io/) is an industry leader with lightning-fast transactions, with time to finality clocked at just 400 milliseconds. Likewise, Sui’s scalability is also at the pinnacle, reaching 297,000 TPS in a controlled environment. But the Sui team is also constantly improving its technology. At the conference, members of the Sui team unveiled the next advancement in speed and scalability in the form of Mysticeti, which significantly accelerates Sui’s time to finality, and Pilotfish, which enables nearly unlimited horizontal scaling by validators.</p><p class="MsoNormal">And beyond performing in test environments, at just four months old, Sui broke the record for transactions executed in a single day, achieving a higher figure than any existing blockchain while fees remained low and stable. Notably, in nearly a year of its mainnet, Sui has not experienced a single minute of downtime.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Gradually, after a series of community events around the world, media stories highlighting Sui’s remarkable early milestones, sustained ecosystem growth and multiple stories of builders eschewing other blockchains to leverage the Sui network, builders, developers, investors and the broader community have begun to understand the potential for Sui’s groundbreaking blockchain technology. The crowds that gathered for Sui Basecamp 2024 represented the culmination of Sui’s arrival.</p><p class="MsoNormal">“The overwhelming turnout and the vibrant enthusiasm at the inaugural Sui Basecamp event reflects a Sui community that is captivated by Sui’s potential to make people’s lives better," said Greg Siourounis, Managing Director of the Sui Foundation. “In the coming months, the Sui Foundation will continue to focus on expanding the ecosystem of projects leveraging Sui and the number of users benefiting from those applications as we work to make Sui one of the blockchains most widely adopted to solve real world challenges. With cutting edge technology and the most dedicated and professional community in web3 behind it, Sui’s progress so far is just a glimpse of what this network will achieve.”</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Aptos Labs Collaborates with Microsoft, Brevan Howard and SK Telecom]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:52:06 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/aptos-labs-collaborates-with-microsoft-brevan-howard-and-sk-telecom</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Aptos Ascend, powered by Microsoft Azure OpenAI and implemented in consultation with Boston Consulting Group, to enable regulatory-compliant digital asset management at scale for financial institutions with global reach. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Aptos Labs (https://aptosascend.com/) today announced a collaboration with Microsoft, Brevan Howard, and SK Telecom (SKT) to deliver to the global financial market Aptos Ascend, a suite of end-to-end institutional solutions including a permissioned network and Digital Asset Controls powered by SKT’s Wallet-as-a-Service product and the scalable, secure Aptos blockchain. Aptos Ascend will also tap Brevan Howard’s industry leadership and expertise to develop a seamless path for any major bank or financial institution to begin offering digital currency and asset management to their clients responsibly and at scale. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Boston Consulting Group (BCG) will be Aptos' Labs preferred consulting partner, leveraging its global expertise in decentralized finance, digital assets, and AI to work with companies to implement the solutions. As one of the world's leading management consulting firms, BCG has a strong track record in delivering and implementing large-scale digital transformations for major financial institutions.</p><p class="MsoNormal">“Global institutions require superior levels of compliance, security, trust, and innovation to service customers, operate across borders, and adhere to regulations at every level,” said Mo Shaikh, Co-Founder &amp; CEO of Aptos Labs. “In collaboration with SKT, Brevan Howard and Microsoft, Aptos Ascend will provide the world’s financial institutions, banks, and tech-forward money markets with a performant, compliant, secure, and scalable gateway to decentralized finance on Aptos that will evolve for years to come.”“We see a tremendous opportunity at the intersection of AI and distributed ledger technologies and are pleased to support Aptos and the Ascend Project as they apply these technologies in financial services," says Adrian Crockett, GM &amp; Head of Product, Microsoft Cloud for Financial Services.</p><p class="MsoNormal">“We continue to have high conviction in the positive impact that the application of Web3 and blockchain technology will have on the financial services industry,” said Gautam Sharma, CEO &amp; CIO of Brevan Howard Digital. “It is still early days, and we are pleased to support initiatives like Ascend that may help propel the industry forward.”“With a growing trend of tokenization in traditional finance, we expect the partnership to create a strong model for innovation in the future financial market," said Oh Se-hyeon, Vice President and Head of Web3 CO at SKT. “Built upon SKT's trusted KYC/authentication business experience, T wallet (Wallet as a Service) aims to provide a stable platform for various crypto services to be provided with high reliability and security.”</p><p class="MsoNormal">In addition to bringing traditional finance giants, innovative fintech partners, money market platforms, and global investment firms into the Web3 fold, Aptos Ascend will enable organizations to:</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Unlock unparalleled transaction efficiency with the Aptos blockchain thanks to an industry-leading sub-second latency—built for scale to achieve more than 30,000 transactions per second (TPS).</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Use the Move smart contract language and Digital Asset Controls, which provide secure asset management, privacy options, and formal verification of smart contracts, greatly reducing the risk of hacks.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Collaborate with like-minded partners to build an extended ecosystem from the start to deliver scale from day one to encourage adoption.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Further explore financial services solutions with dedicated support from the Aptos Labs’ engineering team to develop additional functions and features as required.</p><p class="MsoNormal">The institution-ready, end-to-end financial suite will use Microsoft Azure and Azure OpenAI Service, along with Brevan Howard’s international and market-specific investment expertise, and SKT's regulatory-compliant Web3 technology, to pair innovative trade finance offerings with a decentralized, scalable, data-rich, and accessible network. Adding BCG’s strategic consulting expertise will enable Aptos Labs clients to implement the technology solutions seamlessly within their institutions. While the Aptos Ascend solutions will continue to evolve, immediate value at a global scale will take the form of:</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Expanding decentralized finance to institutional capital.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Unlocking the uncollateralized lending market for Web3.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Releasing the liquidity of tokenized assets on a global scale.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Aptos Ascend is designed to help regulated institutions around the world meet their obligations to customers, regulators, and other stakeholders. Further, Aptos Ascend includes unparalleled customizable configurations to meet specific business and regulatory requirements, including:</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Access controls to help institutions meet regulatory requirements.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Controls over the types of transactions allowed and which entities can control transaction types.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Tools to maintain account and transaction privacy.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Embedded features for Know Your Customer (KYC) and anti-money laundering (AML) checks and other regulatory considerations.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[“Many Payments Firms Are Already Using Stablecoins”: Neo’s CEO]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/interview/many-payments-firms-are-already-using-stablecoins-neos-ceo/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/interview/many-payments-firms-are-already-using-stablecoins-neos-ceo/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/interview/many-payments-firms-are-already-using-stablecoins-neos-ceo</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">“Half of the payments on the chain are using stablecoins at some point,” Laurent Descout, the Founder and CEO of Neo, told Finance Magnates, adding that the holding period could be minimal, “often immediate release,” and “that's becoming extremely common now.”</p><p dir="ltr">Founded in 2017, Neo provides forex and payment solutions to corporates. It offers multi-currency accounts “designed for corporate purpose only” and specializes in “very large transfers.”</p><p dir="ltr">Descout highlighted that such use of stablecoins has “grown tremendously in the last three years,” pointing out: “As a client, you don't necessarily see it because you give a mandate to your payment service provider to channel the funds, say US dollars from London to somewhere else.”</p><p dir="ltr">Neo has yet to use stablecoins, but it supports other companies using it.</p><p dir="ltr">“We do have a lot of other payment companies and clients using <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/stablecoins-a-balancing-act-of-trust-in-the-crypto-domain/">stablecoins </a>at some point in the payments chain,” Descout added. “We definitely plan to use stablecoins as a means of payments in some corridors by 2025.”</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Cross-Border Payments: Transforming Global Remittances Cryptocurrencies offer fast, low-cost, and borderless payment solutions, revolutionizing the remittance industry. By bypassing traditional banking intermediaries and leveraging blockchain technology, individuals can send and…</p>— Mariana Castillo (@Chululuqa) <a href="https://twitter.com/Chululuqa/status/1779089120968483195?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 13, 2024</a></blockquote><p dir="ltr">Descout revealed that his company has over 300 corporate clients and processes an average of GBP 500 million monthly payments. In 2023, the company handled about GBP 6 billion in payment volume and generated about EUR 5 million in revenue.</p><p dir="ltr">Neo is headquartered in Barcelona, with offices in the United Kingdom. Interestingly, the UK is also a significant market for the company as about 40 percent of its clients are from there, while others are primarily from Western European countries. The company is presently expanding beyond the European markets and has sizable operations in Canada with plans to expand to <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/singapore/">Singapore</a>.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Cross border payments are going to go through a massive regulatory shift in coming years is what I strongly feel. The pressure BAAS providers are feeling globally will move to cross border payment providers. I expect lot of regulatory positions shifting</p>— Prajit Nanu (@prajitn) <a href="https://twitter.com/prajitn/status/1777398410640769324?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 8, 2024</a></blockquote><p dir="ltr">“Companies Need to Diversify Their Banking Partners”</p><p dir="ltr">Although there are a few other players like Neo in the “$150 billion a year market,” according to Descout, the company's primary purpose is to challenge the dominance of banks, whose services are “extremely expensive with very poor customer service.”</p><p dir="ltr">Additionally, trust in the banking system felt the repercussions of the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/institutional-forex/after-silicon-valley-bank-collapse-us-fed-announces-internal-investigation/">collapse of Silicon Valley Bank</a>, which had many corporate clients, last year. Although the ripple effect of SVB's collapse did not reach Europe, customers have become cautious.</p><p dir="ltr">“Companies need to <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/corporates-spoiled-for-choice-when-it-comes-to-cash-pooling/">diversify their banking partners</a>,” the CEO of Neo added. “The diversification strategy was used to be true for credit, but I would say it should be for operational purposes.”</p><p dir="ltr">“We believe that this is a trend that every company should follow and not rely on one partner. We see more crises coming, and the environment is becoming more and more unstable, whether it is due to geopolitical interest rates or many things that we don't even think about. So, the corporate treasures must come to reality and work with several things.”</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">How are corporates adapting their strategies following the banking crisis? Get the latest insights from <a href="https://twitter.com/Refinitiv?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Refinitiv</a>. <a href="https://t.co/8Mi0xmv3IX">https://t.co/8Mi0xmv3IX</a> <a href="https://t.co/JLwSWkpxuN">pic.twitter.com/JLwSWkpxuN</a></p>— Refinitiv, an LSEG business (@Refinitiv) <a href="https://twitter.com/Refinitiv/status/1697610705766109444?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2023</a></blockquote><p dir="ltr">“Build Your Payment Corridors Very Carefully”</p><p dir="ltr">Pointing out the risks of international payments infrastructure, Descout said that: “a lot of networks [are] connecting together [and they have been increasing] over the last [few] years."</p><p dir="ltr">“When you think about a dollar traveling from London to Singapore, it may have crossed maybe five or six banks or PSPs,” Descout explained. “That generates many risks: a payment being blocked by one of those banks, a payment reference being lost or scratched by the system of one of those banks. Of course, that doesn't mean you will lose your money, but it may mean that your money is blocked somewhere or isn’t received by whoever you are trying to pay.”</p><p dir="ltr">“That's why you need to work with payment partners who are extremely well connected to the network and have access to the tools to track the payments and ensure that information leveling is correctly done.”</p><p dir="ltr">Pointing at the challenges of the payment providers, Descout added: “You need to build your payment corridors very carefully. There is no point in having a fast solution if, on the receiving side or the issuing side, the quality of the exchange and the liquidity are not there.”</p><p dir="ltr">He further believes there will be “challenges in the coming years around <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/federal-reserves-new-real-time-payment-network-goes-live-in-35-banks/">interconnectivity of clearing systems</a>.”</p><p dir="ltr">“The interconnectivity of major clearing systems, and in some cases more local ones, will drive a lot of changes because it's becoming more and more doable to collect monies somewhere and pay somewhere else. I think that will bring many interesting things ahead in terms of international services and definitely for crypto payments supports.”</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Revolut got a banking licence in Mexico. What does that mean for Fintech? Cross-border is so hot right now. My take 👇Revolut has secured a banking institution licence from Mexico's National Banking and Securities Commission and aims to gain a share of the cross-border payments…</p>— Simon Taylor (@sytaylor) <a href="https://twitter.com/sytaylor/status/1778466507653095714?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 11, 2024</a></blockquote><p dir="ltr">“AI Is Bringing a Lot of Analytics Capabilities”</p><p dir="ltr">Like other industries, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/ai-and-the-malleable-frontier-of-payments/">artificial intelligence (AI) impacts payment flows</a>. And, according to Descout, AI is “already transforming” the payments industry.</p><p dir="ltr">“The main advantage of AI now is going to be on the compliance side of things,” he said. “We are, as a payment company, bound by strict regulations. We are required to collect more and more information as a payment institution to analyze more and more information on payment changes, which are complex as sometimes we don't even see the entire payment change.”</p><p dir="ltr">“AI is bringing a lot of analytics capabilities, and we can look at thousands of transactions and spot anomalies, which may trigger some questioning or some analysis all in a couple of seconds. AI is definitely going to transform the compliance side of our business, making payments quicker and services better.”</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Tanssi Foundation Announces 'Let’s Forkin' Dance']]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/tanssi-foundation-announces-lets-forkin-dance/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/tanssi-foundation-announces-lets-forkin-dance/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:39:06 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/tanssi-foundation-announces-lets-forkin-dance</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">The Tanssi Foundation, a key contributor to the development of Tanssi's community and ecosystem, has unveiled "Let’s Forkin' Dance," the Tanssi Incentivized TestNet campaign. This initiative is designed to incentivize participants and propel community growth and network activity in preparation for the upcoming Tanssi Network launch later this year.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Backed by leading investors like Arrington Capital, HashKey Capital, Fenbushi, Borderless, The Wormhole Cross-Chain Fund, KR1, YBB, SNZ Capital, and Scytale Digital, alongside angel investors such as Gavin Wood, Tanssi is at the forefront of reinventing the deployment of application-specific blockchains (appchains). These appchains play a crucial role in creating decentralized, user-centric applications. Traditionally, deploying appchains has been cumbersome and time-consuming, often forcing developers to settle for less secure and centralized alternatives. Tanssi's protocol aims to simplify this process to just a few clicks, significantly reducing deployment times from months to minutes.</p><p class="MsoNormal">In just six months since its launch, Dancebox, Tanssi's TestNet, has supported over 700 appchain deployments in fields such as DeFi, NFTs, real-world assets, and gaming, showing rapid market adoption. This major step toward the official launch of the Tanssi Network showcases the vibrant activity anticipated once the network is live, inviting everyone to actively participate in the ecosystem.</p><p class="MsoNormal">The Tanssi Incentivized TestNet – Pathway to Mainnet Success</p><p class="MsoNormal">Community-named "Let’s Forkin' Dance" (LFD) introduces a dynamic mix of on-chain and off-chain challenges designed to engage a broad spectrum of the ecosystem—from builders and casual users to key network supporters. This initiative not only celebrates community involvement but also equips participants with practical, hands-on experience in Tanssi’s environment ahead of the official mainnet launch.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Campaign Highlights:</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Three Tracks for Participation: Designed for a broad community including Tanssians (general users), Builders (ecosystem projects), and Block Producers.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Incentives: Allocating 1% of the Tanssi Network as incentives for top participants in the campaign.</p><p class="MsoNormal">·       Ecosystem Quests: Featuring engaging on-chain quests from various appchain projects within the Tanssi ecosystem.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Getting Involved: The campaign officially kicks off on April 30. users can stay updated or sign up for alerts at tanssi.network.</p><p class="MsoNormal">"Since its inception, Tanssi has been dedicated to simplifying the deployment of application-specific blockchains (appchains), making them more accessible, and ultimately bringing forward the web3 infrastructure landscape," said Francisco Agosti, Tanssi Co-founder and CEO of Moondance Labs. "Let’s Forkin Dance is a significant step towards launching Tanssi’s mainnet, and will help strengthen the community of developers and users who will be essential once Tanssi goes live.”</p><p class="MsoNormal">About Tanssi Network</p><p class="MsoNormal">Tanssi’s appchain infrastructure protocol (https://www.tanssi.network) is designed to simplify and accelerate the deployment of appchains. By connecting a chain to Tanssi, it is instantly transformed into a modular appchain. This transition grants access to a developer-friendly and permissionless environment, fully stocked with all essential infrastructural components to run a chain right out of the box. Key features include a shared and decentralized network of block producers, ensuring robust security and data retrievability, alongside seamless integrations with vital tools like bridges, wallets, block explorers, RPC endpoints, indexers, oracles, and more. As a result, appchains can be deployed in just minutes—a significant improvement over the typical months-long process.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[CFI Diversifies Services with Options Trading]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/cfi-diversifies-services-with-options-trading/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/cfi-diversifies-services-with-options-trading/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 13:36:21 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/cfi-diversifies-services-with-options-trading</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>CFI Financial Group has launched options trading on
its multi-asset trading platform. This service allows investors to trade
contracts that grant them the right to buy or sell an asset at a predetermined price
within a specific timeframe. </p><p>According to Zawya, this offering enables CFI's
clients to access a range of options on US securities, facilitating the
flexibility to engage on both sides of the market using Call and Put options.
The service is accessible for download on iOS and Android devices.</p><p>Diversification with Options </p><p>With fees starting at $1 per contract, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/cfi-financial/" target="_blank" rel="follow">CFI</a> has
assured traders that they can maximize their returns while minimizing costs.
Traders can customize their strategies by selecting
preferred strike prices and trade sizes. Beyond options trading, the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/m/multi-asset/" target="_blank" rel="follow">multi-asset</a> platform
offers investment opportunities across various asset
classes. It encompasses features like <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/r/risk-management/" class="terms__main-term" id="aedb745c-adf9-415f-97e2-ee56a920f0f8">risk management</a>
tools and technical indicators.</p><p>Hisham Mansour, the Co-Founder and Managing Director of CFI,
mentioned: "With the launch of options trading, we are taking a significant
step forward in our journey to widen access to the global financial markets,
offering our clients an expanded suite of financial instruments and
unparalleled trading opportunities."</p><p>Last year, CFI Group expanded its global presence with
a <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/cfi-group-expands-its-reach-with-the-launch-of-cfi-oman/" target="_blank" rel="follow">new subsidiary</a>, CFI Oman. The group launched the entity alongside a
significant sponsorship deal with Sheffield United Football Club. CFI Oman was the fourth subsidiary launched by the company in 2023, while the partnership with Sheffield United boosted CFI's involvement
in European football.</p><p>CFI Group's Expansion</p><p>As part of the deal, CFI became the club's
front-of-shirt sponsor and official financial trading partner. With previous
engagements, including partnerships with renowned figures like Pep
Guardiola, the Dubai-based firm is leveraging sports sponsorships to boost its
visibility.</p><p>CFI Group's expansion into Oman underscored its
commitment to empowering traders worldwide. With CFI Oman joining its diverse
portfolio of subsidiaries, which includes ventures in Egypt and Kuwait, the company has twelve regulatory licenses across
various regions. </p><p>Commenting about the new subsidiary, Mansour emphasized the
strategic significance of entering the Omani market with the aim of providing
local investors with access to global markets and trading technologies. </p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Orfinex Adds Financial Commission's Membership for Dispute Resolution]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/orfinex-adds-financial-commissions-membership-for-dispute-resolution/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/orfinex-adds-financial-commissions-membership-for-dispute-resolution/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:36:42 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/orfinex-adds-financial-commissions-membership-for-dispute-resolution</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Financial Commission has announced the approval of
Orfinex as its newest Member, marking the company's inclusion in the
self-regulatory forum for resolving disputes in the FX industry. Orfinex's
status as an Approved Broker Member took effect on April 17th, 2024, following
the endorsement of its membership application.</p><p>Financial Commission Welcomes Orfinex as Newest Member</p><p>Membership in the Financial Commission grants Orfinex and
its customers access to various services, including protection for up to
€20,000 per submitted complaint through the Financial Commission's Compensation
Fund. The Commission serves as an impartial third-party mediation platform,
aiding in the resolution of complaints when direct agreement between parties is
unattainable.</p><p>For Orfinex and other approved members and their clients
engaged in CFDs, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/f/forex/" class="terms__main-term" id="6faa6714-7f7b-4d23-b1c5-c0d40807d613">forex</a>, and cryptocurrency markets, the Financial Commission
offers a resolution process compared to traditional regulatory channels like
arbitration or local courts.</p><p>Orfinex joins an array of brokerages and independent service
providers utilizing the Financial Commission's services as part of their focus
on clients while adhering to membership requirements.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Orfinex joins Financial Commission as approved broker member - Multi-asset brokerage firm Orfinex has become a member of the Financial Commission, joining the ranks of the self-regulatory organization. This accreditation reassures traders that the firm meets the quality stan... <a href="https://t.co/7AS9CHZwKL">pic.twitter.com/7AS9CHZwKL</a></p>— The Industry Spread (@industryspread) <a href="https://twitter.com/industryspread/status/1780760439141417283?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2024</a></blockquote><p>About Orfinex, the company is a regulated <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/t/trading-platform/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="f85800b2-ccf5-4f50-9e8e-780d32afc6f6">trading platform</a>
under the Financial Sector Conduct Authority in Melbourne, Australia,
operating since 2015. With a clientele spanning both retail and institutional
sectors, Orfinex is noted for its provision of client support, utilization of
advanced trading infrastructure, and experience in global trading.</p><p>Deceptive Tactics Uncovered by Financial Commission</p><p>The Financial Commission <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/alert-financial-commission-probes-impersonation-scam-targeting-traders/">updated
on its investigation of a scam involving fake representatives</a> posing as its
personnel, targeting traders for fraud, as reported by <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com" target="_blank" rel="follow">Finance
Magnates</a>. Previously cautioned on December 15, 2023, the Commission warned
against deceptive practices by imposters offering funds recovery and chargeback
services for a fee. </p><p>These fraudulent individuals used fake legal service
companies to deceive victims. They also falsified contact details resembling
legitimate digital asset wallet providers like Blockchain.com to extract fees
for illegitimate services. </p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
</channel></rss>