<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
            <rss version = "2.0"
                xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
                xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
                xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
                xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
                xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
                <channel>
                    <title>News &#8211; Finance Magnates | Financial and business news</title>
<atom:link href="https://www.financemagnates.com//feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//</link>
<description></description>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:05:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator></generator>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Jareer Hiary Takes Helm as CEO in CFI UAE's Leadership Transition]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/jareer-hiary-takes-helm-as-ceo-in-cfi-uaes-leadership-transition/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/jareer-hiary-takes-helm-as-ceo-in-cfi-uaes-leadership-transition/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:20:22 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/jareer-hiary-takes-helm-as-ceo-in-cfi-uaes-leadership-transition</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>CFI Financial Markets LLC (“CFI UAE”), the UAE division of
CFI Financial Group, has announced a leadership transition, with
Jareer Hiary stepping into the role of CEO. Hiary will succeed Nidal Abdelhadi,
who will now focus on personal ventures. This transition follows closely on the
heels of the launch of CFI’s SCA-regulated entity in UAE as a Category One
licensed broker.</p><p>Abdelhadi previously served as CEO of the group's DIFC
entity, Credit Financier Invest Limited, before transitioning to lead
CFI Financial Markets LLC. He played a pivotal role in establishing the latter
as a regulated entity under the UAE’s Securities and Commodities Authority.</p><p>CEO Role at CFI UAE Awaits Regulatory Approval</p><p>Jareer Hiary brings experience to his new role as CEO of CFI
UAE. His journey within the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/cfi-group/" target="_blank" rel="follow">CFI Group </a>began in 2018 when he joined the
Jordanian division, where he swiftly rose to the positions of Branch Manager
and Co-Head of Business Development. </p><p>Expressing his enthusiasm for his new role, Hiary stated:
"It is an honor to step up as CEO and lead the group’s Emirati entity
through its next phase of growth. Building on the solid foundation and recent
achievements of Nidal, I look forward to steering our team towards further
innovations and success.</p><p>During his tenure in Jordan, Hiary contributed to the division's growth and success, showcasing
talent, industry knowledge, and business acumen. These attributes position him
as an ideal candidate to spearhead CFI UAE's next phase of growth in the United
Arab Emirates. Formal approval of Hiary's appointment as CEO is
pending final regulatory clearance.</p><p>Saudi Super Cup with CFI as Official Partner</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/cfi-notes-role-as-partner-in-saudi-super-cups-abu-dhabi-inauguration/">CFI
announced its partnership as the Official Partner of the Saudi Super Cup</a>, an
event taking place in Abu Dhabi from April 8th to 11th, 2024, as reported by <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/">Finance Magnates</a>. Hosted by Abu
Dhabi's Department of Culture and Tourism, the Saudi Super Cup featured top
Saudi teams like Al-Ittihad, Al-Wehda, Al-Hilal, and Al-Nassr. The tournament
promised excitement with football legends Cristiano Ronaldo and Karim Benzema,
alongside regional prestigious stars such as Salem Al Dawsari and Abderrazak
Hamdallah, competing for the cup.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Liqudinet Seeks to Facilitate Large, Illiquid Trades with New Initiative]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/liqudinet-seeks-to-facilitate-large-illiquid-trades-with-new-initiative/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/liqudinet-seeks-to-facilitate-large-illiquid-trades-with-new-initiative/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Institutional FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/liqudinet-seeks-to-facilitate-large-illiquid-trades-with-new-initiative</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In a move
to enhance its block trading capabilities, Liquidnet, an agency execution
specialist, has unveiled its SuperBlock initiative. The first offering under
this initiative, SuperBlock Matching, allows traders to easily signal and
participate in exceptionally large or illiquid block trades.</p><p>Liquidnet Launches
SuperBlock Initiative to Facilitate Large, Illiquid Trades</p><p>The
SuperBlock initiative is designed to leverage Liquidnet's global buy-side
community and expertise in block trading to create a protected space for
executing the most challenging trades. SuperBlock Matching aims to provide a more efficient and user-friendly environment for Liquidnet's members by focusing on trades that vary in size based on market and stock market capitalization.</p><p>"SuperBlock
is a direct response to a request from our Membership and an extension of our
existing block trading offering," stated Mark Govoni, the CEO of Liquidnet.</p><p>The launch
of SuperBlock Matching marks the first in a series of planned workflows and
services under the SuperBlock initiative, which aims to help Liquidnet's
members find unique liquidity and execute their most difficult trades more easily.</p><p>As a global
markets infrastructure and data solutions provider, Liquidnet continues to
expand its network, which currently includes over 1,000 institutional investors
managing a combined $33 trillion in equity and fixed-income assets across 49
markets and six continents.</p><p>"Fast-forward
to today, and we have an efficient environment that we believe will
significantly improve opportunities for members to systematically trade very
large blocks," said Rob Cranston, the Global Head of Equities Product at Liquidnet. He also credited the company's innovation hub, Liquidnet Labs, with developing and testing SuperBlock Matching.</p><p>Liquidnet's Expansion and
Partnerships in the Financial Industry</p><p>The technology-driven
agency specializing in execution services has been making significant strides
in expanding its global listed derivatives offering. In April, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/moves/morgan-stanley-exec-jumps-ship-to-join-liquidnets-futures-division/">the firm hired
Alex Grinfeld</a>, a former Executive Director at Morgan Stanley, to co-head its futures
business in the Americas. </p><p>Towards the
end of last year, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/institutional-forex/liquidnet-enhances-platform-with-ai-from-bondit-for-better-trading/">Liquidnet announced a partnership with BondIT</a>, a provider of
investment technology, to integrate BondIT's Scorable Credit Analytics into
Liquidnet's fixed-income trading platform. This integration leverages data
science, explainable AI, and machine learning solutions to enhance the
platform's capabilities.</p><p>Also in
late 2023, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/institutional-forex/liquidnet-takes-on-banks-with-new-derivatives-tool/">Liquidnet unveiled a new pre-trade analytics tool</a> for listed
derivatives, available in both the US and Europe. The tool aims to provide
valuable insights, such as volume, liquidity, and projected activity, to
traders before they execute a trade, empowering them to make more informed
decisions.</p><p>Meanwhile,
TP ICAP, Liquidnet's parent company, reported a net statutory profit of £74
million for 2023, with an adjusted figure of £227 million. Despite a 28.1
percent decline in the statutory profit, the adjusted figure saw a 17 percent
increase. The company also allocated £30 million to its buyback program,
demonstrating its financial stability and commitment to shareholder value.</p><p>Although
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/institutional-forex/tp-icap-extends-share-buyback-by-30-million-as-2023-remained-profitable/">revenue from the Liquidnet division experienced a slight decline of 1%,</a> the
group emphasized the successful completion of Liquidnet's integration, which
resulted in annualized cost savings of £43 million, surpassing the initial
target of £30 million.</p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[NAGA and CAPEX.com Merger Gets Shareholders’ Nod: 2 New Licenses in Pipeline]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/naga-and-capexcom-merger-gets-shareholders-nod-2-new-licenses-in-pipeline/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/naga-and-capexcom-merger-gets-shareholders-nod-2-new-licenses-in-pipeline/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:00:27 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Brokers]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/naga-and-capexcom-merger-gets-shareholders-nod-2-new-licenses-in-pipeline</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The shareholders of publicly listed NAGA GROUP AG (XETRA: N4G) have approved the merger of the broker with CAPEX.com. As many as 99.81 percent of the NAGA shareholders voted in favor of the merger at the extraordinary general meeting held on April 12.</p><p>Expansion Plans</p><p>The press release today (Monday) further revealed that the Hamburg-listed broker is seeking two additional regulatory licenses, which are in the process of approval. However, it did not specify the jurisdictions of the sought-after licenses.</p><p>Currently, NAGA and CAPEX hold nine regulatory licenses together.</p><p>“Securing this vote will allow us, after the regulatory approvals for the merger, to execute the new business plan,” Octavian Patrascu, the new CEO of the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/naga/">NAGA Group</a>, said in a statement. “We are expanding the global reach of NAGA and upgrading the SuperApp to offer a true all-in-one user experience, unique in the world of Fintech.”</p><p>A Strategic Merger</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/naga-and-capexcom-to-merge-projecting-250m-revenue/">NAGA and CAPEX.com agreed to the merger</a> last December. Under the agreement, Patrascu, the founder and CEO of CAPEX.com, was appointed as the Group CEO of the merged entity. He also injected $9 million into NAGA via a convertible bond, making him the largest shareholder in the company.</p><p>Originally, the closure of the deal was planned for the end of Q2 2024, which is now pending customary regulatory approval.</p><p>The merger was very strategic as the two brokers will benefit from their respective expertise domains and market reach. With the merger, the two brokers are expecting to generate $250 million in revenue over the next three years and save about $10 million annually.</p><p>The two platforms already have over 1.6 million registered users, and the roadmap of the merged entity is aiming to add over 5 million registered users by 2025/26.</p><p>Patrascu's vision is to create a "New NAGA" with market expansion and enhancements of products and applications. He is also moving towards making a "Superapp" with plans to unify all existing NAGA services into a single, integrated platform.</p><p>Interestingly, Ben Bilski, who founded NAGA and headed the broker until June 2023, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/moves/ben-bilski-leaves-naga-group-only-3-months-after-merger-with-capexcom/">separated from the company last March</a>, only three months after the announcement of the merger.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA["Turkish Robinhood" Raises $45 Million, Aims to Expand Reach to MENA]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/turkish-robinhood-raises-45-million-aims-to-expand-reach-to-mena/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/turkish-robinhood-raises-45-million-aims-to-expand-reach-to-mena/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:49:11 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Brokers]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/turkish-robinhood-raises-45-million-aims-to-expand-reach-to-mena</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Midas, a fintech
startup that allows millions of Turks to access investing markets, announced
today (Monday) that it has raised $45 million in a Series A funding round led
by Canada's Portage. </p><p>The round
also saw participation from International Finance Corporation, Spark Capital,
Earlybird Digital East Fund, and Revo Capital, who had previously invested in
the company's $11 million seed round in 2022.</p><p>Midas Raises $45 Million
to Expand Retail Investing in Turkey and Beyond</p><p>Founded
just three years ago, Midas has already amassed over 2 million users in Turkey
by offering low-cost access to US and Turkish equities through its mobile app.
The company has built its own infrastructure for clearing, custody, and
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/e/execution/" class="terms__main-term" id="60010adb-9e25-4bff-9822-c9210deec853">execution</a>, enabling it to provide a seamless user experience in a market where
retail investing was previously limited</p><p>“We have
already brought affordable, quick access to US and Turkish equities to millions
of people in Turkey,” said Egem Eraslan, the CEO and Founder of Midas. “This
fundraise will allow us to expand our product suite further.”</p><p>Midas plans
to use the fresh funding to expand its product suite by launching cryptocurrency trading, mutual funds, and savings accounts. The company is also
eyeing expansion beyond Turkey into the MENA region in the next 2-5 years.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="tr" dir="ltr">🎉 Midas’a 45 milyon dolarlık rekor yatırım!Finansal teknolojiler alanında Türkiye’nin en büyük erken aşama Seri A yatırımını almanın mutluluğunu yaşıyoruz.Bize ve gelecek planlarımıza inanan kullanıcı ve yatırımcılarımıza teşekkür ederiz.🔗 <a href="https://t.co/nXuG4rXC5R">https://t.co/nXuG4rXC5R</a> <a href="https://t.co/zmMDjRAESS">pic.twitter.com/zmMDjRAESS</a></p>— Midas (@getmidas) <a href="https://twitter.com/getmidas/status/1782321156113969379?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></blockquote><p>“Midas is leading a wave of transformation within Turkey’s financial landscape,” Paul Desmarais III, the Co-Founder of Portage and CEO and Chairman of Sagard, said: “Globally, Portage invests in transformational financial technology, and Midas is poised to lead that initiative in a region of early adopters.”</p><p>The $45
million Series A is one of the largest raised by a Turkish <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/f/fintech/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="891edcf3-475e-45f3-a8b8-3ba2e7d37339">fintech</a> recently,
just behind the $50 million raised by embedded finance startup Param in 2022.
It comes after Midas hit profitability last year and announced plans to double
its headcount to over 400 employees and grow its user base to 5 million by the
end of 2024.</p><p>Due to its
investment approach and commission-free nature, Midas is often called
the "<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/robinhood/">Turkish Robinhood</a>." Although there is a significant size
difference between the two businesses, with Robinhood's assets under management
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/robinhoods-trading-volumes-and-client-assets-surge-over-50-in-a-year/">growing by 59% to $119 billion</a> over the last year, investors believe that Midas
has the potential to follow in the footsteps of its older and larger
counterpart.</p><p>Although the funding round was substantial, it certainly wasn't the largest to occur recently in Europe. As Finance Magnates reported last week, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/google-bets-big-on-monzo-values-the-uk-fintech-at-5-billion/">the digital bank Monzo raised $400 million</a> from CapitalG, Google’s independent growth fund. A month earlier, Finom, a payment service provider for small businesses, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/finom-finds-raising-50m-quite-easy-despite-tough-climate/">secured $50 million in a Series B funding round</a> co-led by existing investor General Catalyst and new investor Northzone.</p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[4 Crypto Investing Mistakes Newbies Must Avoid]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/4-crypto-investing-mistakes-newbies-must-avoid/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/4-crypto-investing-mistakes-newbies-must-avoid/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:12:47 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/4-crypto-investing-mistakes-newbies-must-avoid</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Did you know around 1 billion people worldwide use cryptocurrency? While it’s a speculative asset class that can be more of a roller-coaster experience than some people are comfortable with, crypto can be part of any prudent investor’s strategy for financial stability.</p><p class="MsoNormal">The same source adds that nearly one in four Americans acknowledge they’re unclear about how cryptocurrency works, which is one reason investors willing to take the plunge should be careful. You can lose more than your shirt with bad crypto investment moves -- so caution is necessary.</p><p class="MsoNormal">One survey shows that almost four in 10 American investors who've held crypto have divested their holding for south of what they bought it for. Whether you want to dabble in crypto or establish a strong position in one or more cryptocurrencies, you’ll want to make money.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Continue reading to see four investing mistakes to avoid as a new cryptocurrency investor.</p><p class="MsoNormal">1. Don’t Invest Until You Know What You’re Getting Into (Research Is Your Friend)</p><p class="MsoNormal">When people think about investors who've become millionaires by investing in Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, they often pay scant attention to horror stories. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Those stories involve people who've lost money chasing the dream of a bonanza of riches. Desiring to invest in crypto is one thing, but understanding this asset class and how it operates is another thing. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Any investment, especially in an asset class as speculative as crypto, requires patience. You must understand the terms, analyze the options, and gauge your risk tolerance. Many new crypto investors fail by spending money on an asset class they don't know. That’s a recipe for disaster.</p><p class="MsoNormal">It’s always vital to research something before making a decision -- and that’s true no matter what you’re focusing on. If seeking a business phone system for the office, you should research the space to make an informed selection. </p><p class="MsoNormal">When buying index funds off the stock market, you’ll want to invest sufficient time to find the right stocks. If seeking a fleet management system for your company’s vehicles, you should assess specific needs, see what’s on the market, create a shortlist of candidates, and <a href="https://cetaris.com/request-a-demo?hsCtaTracking=c0932482-8c20-4a75-a830-10ebfe36782c%7Ce9817a76-3d51-4525-97d7-e10d73e36a14">try some demos</a> before choosing one.</p><p class="MsoNormal">2. Don’t Keep All Your Crypto in a Digital Wallet (Consider a Cold Wallet)</p><p class="MsoNormal">According to one source, the worldwide cryptocurrency wallet market size was <a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/crypto-wallet-market-report">$8.42 billion in 2022</a>, and it's on pace to expand at a 24.8% compound annual growth rate from 2023 to 2030. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Grand View Research notes that one of the drivers for the adoption of this technology is the growing recognition from individual and institutional investors of crypto as a legitimate asset class. </p><p class="MsoNormal">While online wallets are popular and convenient, they also present risks for investors. A quick online search will reveal articles about cybersecurity attacks against owners of online crypto wallets -- and how successful the cyber criminals are. It's better to invest in a cold wallet, also called a hardware wallet or offline wallet, that will keep your crypto holdings safer. </p><p class="MsoNormal">3. Don’t Invest for the Short-Term Period (Think Long Term Instead)</p><p class="MsoNormal">One reason some investors get into crypto investing is the hope to turn modest investments into huge returns over the short-term period. However, this type of investment strategy rarely works. Some get lucky and hit the jackpot, but they're the exception rather than the rule. Investing based on the exception is a good way to lose more than your shirt.</p><p class="MsoNormal">When you understand the speculative nature of crypto, you’ll see this asset class isn't suited for short-term investments. You need to hang in there for the long term and accept the roller-coaster nature of the asset class. </p><p class="MsoNormal">4. Don’t Forget Crypto Wallet Passwords (You Could Lose Your Holdings)</p><p class="MsoNormal">Another mistake crypto investors need to avoid is forgetting their crypto wallet passwords. It happens more often than you might think. If you have an online crypto wallet, put your crypto holdings in it, and later forget the password, you could be in serious trouble. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Remember that crypto isn’t regulated as many other investment classes are. If you lose your password, there’s no customer service you can contact to access it or reset it. You could lose your holdings, which can sour your experience as a crypto investor.</p><p class="MsoNormal">If you’re interested in crypto investments, consider these four mistakes to avoid at all costs. Whether you’re a beginner or a pro, mistakes like the ones listed above can jeopardize your crypto investment strategy and leave you with a case of buyer’s remorse.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Appital Equips Asset Managers with Liquidity Stream Feature]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/appital-equips-asset-managers-with-liquidity-stream-feature/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/appital-equips-asset-managers-with-liquidity-stream-feature/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Institutional FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/appital-equips-asset-managers-with-liquidity-stream-feature</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Appital, a peer-to-peer price discovery and liquidity
sourcing technology for asset managers, has introduced a new feature aimed at
enhancing opportunistic liquidity within the market.</p><p>Facilitating Targeted Deal Access</p><p>The newly launched functionality, dubbed 'Appital Trending
Equities,' represents an industry-first innovation integrated into Appital
Insights. It empowers deal originators on the buyside to proactively stimulate
unique liquidity in the market prior to the launch of a deal. Concurrently,
participating buyside firms gain access to potential deals that may soon hit
the platform, focusing on equities relevant to their portfolios and meeting
specific criteria, such as minimum average daily volume (ADV) or pricing
thresholds.</p><p>Mark Badyra, the CEO, Appital, said: “Buyside trading desks will
receive a list of trending equities within the Appital platform, which they can
discuss with their PMs to identify opportunities they wish to participate in.
Traders and portfolio managers are empowered to discover and react to deal flow
opportunities that are unique in the market, and generate alpha themselves.” </p><p>This feature aims to unlock latent liquidity, facilitate the
bookbuilding process, and enable trading desks and portfolio managers (PMs) to
adopt a more opportunistic approach. By generating orders in the market that
might not otherwise exist, the functionality contributes to liquidity events
that might not occur through traditional channels.</p><p>In addressing prevalent challenges such as decreasing
liquidity in the lit market, reliance on the market close, and a reduction in
high-touch sales trading and associated liquidity opportunities, 'Appital
Trending <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/e/equities/" class="terms__main-term" id="d6e02698-4c6b-44dd-ab57-9ff12763325c">Equities</a>' aims to involve PMs in the deal flow effectively.</p><p>Attracting Market Interest with Client Base Growth</p><p>The new functionality is already operational and in use by
asset managers who are leveraging the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/appital/">Appital</a> platform,
experiencing significant traction. Notably, approximately 50 indications have
been discovered by portfolio management teams, representing over $1 billion in
potential liquidity.</p><p>These <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/l/liquidity/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="47c3bef3-27ee-4953-8504-159e1b829b33">liquidity</a> event predictions stem from Appital Insights,
introduced in Q4 2023. This tool enables buyside institutions to assess the
feasibility of executing larger ADV orders without raising alarms in the
market.</p><p>Presently, Appital boasts a client base comprising more than
40 asset managers with over $15 trillion assets under management (AUM).
Additionally, over 60 more asset managers, managing an additional $30 trillion
AUM, are in the onboarding stage, demonstrating considerable market interest in
the platform's capabilities.</p><p>Brian Guckian, the Chief Business Development Officer, Appital,
added: “We have seen great traction due to our neutral market position and the
trust in our platform. Asset managers are happy to share responses to Appital
because we are not conflicted on the data and insights and deal originators can
better manage their risk before launching a bookbuild.”</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[ASIC Pulls the Plug on This Retail Broker's Financial Services License]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/asic-pulls-the-plug-on-this-retail-brokers-financial-services-license/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/asic-pulls-the-plug-on-this-retail-brokers-financial-services-license/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/asic-pulls-the-plug-on-this-retail-brokers-financial-services-license</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>(The
Australian Securities and Investments Commission (<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/asic/">ASIC</a>) has revoked the
Australian Financial Services (AFS) license of JB Markets Pty Ltd, effective
from 12 April 2024, citing the company's failure to meet financial requirements
and maintain adequate resources.</p><p>ASIC Revokes JB Markets'
AFS License Over Financial Inadequacies</p><p>The
cancellation comes after JB Markets' license <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/asic-suspends-licenses-of-jb-markets-first-city-amid-compliance-failures/">was suspended on 8 November 2023</a> due to the company reporting a net deficiency of assets over liabilities and
failing to meet financial holding requirements for the financial years 2019 to
2022. <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/a/asic/" class="terms__main-term" id="dfb41d67-b79e-4b09-b365-1f341b85a51b">ASIC</a> also determined that JB Markets did not possess adequate financial
resources to provide the financial services under its AFS license.</p><p>"ASIC considers that canceling JB Markets AFS license will protect the interests of potential consumers, promote confidence in the financial services industry, and encourage professionalism by those who provide financial services.," the regulatory body stated in a press release.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We have cancelled the Australian financial services licence of JB Markets for failing to comply with financial requirements, and failing to have adequate resources to provide the services covered by its licence <a href="https://t.co/Q4GMT3j439">https://t.co/Q4GMT3j439</a> <a href="https://t.co/F3csRmNpLt">pic.twitter.com/F3csRmNpLt</a></p>— ASIC Media (@asicmedia) <a href="https://twitter.com/asicmedia/status/1782286484331999671?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></blockquote><p>JB Markets
held AFS license number 323182 from July 2008, which authorized the company to
provide financial product advice, deal in financial products, make a market in
financial products, and operate custodial or depository services for retail and wholesale clients.</p><p>Under the
Corporations Act, ASIC is empowered to suspend or cancel an AFS license if a
licensee fails to fulfill its general <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/o/obligations/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="5dbcbf88-8622-4828-a29c-70a680d32fb5">obligations</a>, which include meeting
financial requirements and ensuring adequate resourcing. JB Markets has the
right to appeal ASIC's decision by applying to the Administrative Appeals
Tribunal for a review.</p><p>ASIC
imposes stringent financial requirements on AFS licensees to ensure they
possess sufficient financial resources to conduct their business in compliance
with financial services laws. These requirements serve as crucial consumer
protection measures, aiming to minimize the risk of a disorderly wind-up in the
event of a business failure.</p><p>Over the last year, the regulator <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/asic-grants-332-australia-financial-services-license-in-fy23/">issued 332 AFS licenses</a> and suspended 26 of them.</p><p>ASIC Wipes Out 3,500
Fraudulent Investment Websites</p><p>In March, ASIC
disclosed the achievements of its initiative to combat investment scams. Recent
statistics indicate that since initiating its website takedown capability in
July 2023, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/asic-wipes-out-3500-fraudulent-investment-websites-in-anti-scam-initiative/">approximately 3,500 deceptive investment sites have been removed</a>,
significantly enhancing the protection of Australians against online fraud.</p><p>Furthermore,
ASIC elaborated on the successes of its regulatory and enforcement activities.
Over the six months ending December 31, 2023, ASIC obtained nearly $60
million in civil penalties and successfully facilitated nine criminal
convictions.</p><p>The
revocation of JB Markets' license reminds us of the importance of
adhering to financial regulations and maintaining adequate resources in the
financial services industry. </p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Andrew Mreana Leaves Spotware Systems]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/andrew-mreana-leaves-spotware-systems/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/andrew-mreana-leaves-spotware-systems/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:51:01 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/andrew-mreana-leaves-spotware-systems</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Andrew Mreana, the Head of Growth of Spotware Systems, has announced his resignation from the company today (Monday). He is leaving the technology provider after a short stint of ten months.</p><p dir="ltr">Spotware’s Head of Growth Departs</p><p dir="ltr">“After 1 amazing year with #cTrader, my mission with this great platform provider came to an end, Mreana noted in a LinkedIn post. “It was a pleasure undertaking the Head of Growth position, helping Sales and Marketing departments grow and representing the company in the media at many international events.”</p><p dir="ltr">Spotware Systems is known for its trading platform, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/prop-trading-firm-funding-pips-introduces-ctrader-in-diversification-push/">cTrader</a>, which it licenses to brokerages and other trading services providers. It remains unclear if the Cypriot company will name a replacement for Mreana or keep the role vacant. </p><p dir="ltr">A Diverse Career with Brokers</p><p dir="ltr">Mreana had a long career working with financial services providers, especially the forex and contracts for differences (CFDs) brokers. Before Spotware, he was a Call Center Manager and Head of Sales for an unnamed company in the FX and CFDs domain. He also founded a couple of platforms, including DOT Financial News.</p><p dir="ltr">According to his LinkedIn profile, Mreana started as a Sales Executive at a Cyprus-based financial services company in 2012 and then moved to the United Kingdom after a couple of years for a similar role with another company. </p><p dir="ltr">He returned to Cyprus in 2015 as a Client Specialist at Alvexo, a Limassol-based CFDs brokerage, where he spent one year. He then joined FXGlobe as a Senior Account Manager and, after six months, moved to <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/brokers/fca-orders-everfx-to-stop-offering-cfds-to-uk-customers/">EverFX</a>, a now-shuttered brokerage, in the same role. Mreana left EverFX in 2017, until when the broker seemed to have operated normally. However, then things slowly started to unravel and it turned out to be a massive scam, and its CEO and mastermind, who goes by the name ‘Pablo A’, was <a href="https://financemagnates.com/forex/police-arrest-everfxs-spanish-top-gun-at-airport-in-barcelona/">arrested by the Spanish police </a>in December 2022.</p><p dir="ltr">Mreana also worked as a Cryptocurrency Analyst at Seven Finances and as a Trading Education Officer at another forex firm.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Nium Names Chief Payments Officer, Expands Trulioo Partnership]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/nium-names-chief-payments-officer-expands-trulioo-partnership/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/nium-names-chief-payments-officer-expands-trulioo-partnership/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:38:22 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/nium-names-chief-payments-officer-expands-trulioo-partnership</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Nium, a real-time cross-border payment solutions provider, has announced several
changes to its leadership team and business partnerships. The company has
appointed Alexandra Johnson to the newly-created position of Chief Payments
Officer (CPO) and has expanded its existing partnership with Trulioo, an
identity verification platform. </p><p>These moves
are part of Nium's efforts to strengthen its global payments network and
improve its compliance capabilities.</p><p>Alexandra Johnson
Appointed as Nium’s Chief Payments Officer</p><p>In a newly created position, Alexandra Johnson will serve as Nium's CPO, overseeing
the company's global banking and payment operations. Johnson brings extensive
experience in the banking and payments industry, having previously held
leadership roles at Bank of America and JP Morgan. </p><p>"Alex's
experience in banking and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/p/payments/" class="terms__main-term" id="f1d2a713-da14-4a6b-8fcd-e8f360d07f45">payments</a> is invaluable, and I'm excited to see her tackle this role head-on and contribute to the growth of the
business,” commented Prajit Nanu, the Co-Founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/nium/">Nium</a>.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">New Exec Alert 🚀 Alexandra Johnson is joining Nium as Chief Payments Officer! Alexandra brings a wealth of experience in the banking and payments space, making her the perfect fit to spearhead Nium's global banking and payment operations. <a href="https://t.co/LpdpCRow3R">https://t.co/LpdpCRow3R</a> <a href="https://t.co/R8aR0HB4Yz">pic.twitter.com/R8aR0HB4Yz</a></p>— Nium (@NiumGlobal) <a href="https://twitter.com/NiumGlobal/status/1782206825343169013?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></blockquote><p>As Chief
Payments Officer, Johnson will manage and expand Nium's payments network, ensure compliance with regulatory policies, and collaborate with risk and compliance teams across various markets. </p><p>"I am
ready and excited for the opportunity to level-up the already stellar network
that exists at Nium and deliver innovative and market leading solutions to our
customers across the globe,” Johnson added.</p><p>Nium Expands Partnership
with Trulioo </p><p>Nium has
also announced an expanded partnership with Trulioo to enhance its UK
operations and deliver rapid, compliant payment experiences. The collaboration
leverages Trulioo's identity verification capabilities, enabling Nium to comply
with stringent Know Your Customer (KYC) and Anti-Money Laundering (AML)
regulations while maintaining a seamless customer experience.</p><p>Since
integrating Trulioo's Person Match identity verification solution, Nium has
seen a 27% increase in its overall KYC verification rate in the UK, with
customers being verified in less than 6.43 seconds. </p><p>“As we
assessed our U.K. <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/c/compliance/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="569f58ee-534c-44f0-a7cd-f55b0f9a2b2a">compliance</a> requirements, leveraging our trusted relationship
with Trulioo only made sense,” said Dylan Lowrey, General Counsel at Nium. “Trulioo
Person Match provides us with comprehensive data sets, which are crucial for
identity verification.”</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Trulioo, an identity platform with proven global coverage for person and business verification, yesterday announced at Money20/20 Asia its collaboration with Nium. <a href="https://t.co/Or82pf5etQ">https://t.co/Or82pf5etQ</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/collaboration?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#collaboration</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/compliancetechnology?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#compliancetechnology</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/moneytransfer?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#moneytransfer</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/nium?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#nium</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/payments?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#payments</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Solutions?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Solutions</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WBO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WBO</a> <a href="https://t.co/gaIoiqPi0O">pic.twitter.com/gaIoiqPi0O</a></p>— World Business Outlook (@wboutlook) <a href="https://twitter.com/wboutlook/status/1782293125483941956?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Nium's Growing Global
Presence</p><p>Nium's
recent appointments and partnerships come as the company expands
its global presence. Its payout network supports 100 currencies across 190+ countries, and its growing card issuance business is available in 34 countries.</p><p>The company
holds regulatory licenses and authorizations in more than 40 countries,
enabling seamless onboarding, rapid integration, and compliance across
geographies. </p><p>In
February, the company announced that it was <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/nium-expands-in-india-gains-2-in-principal-payments-license/">expanding its services to India</a>
after obtaining local licenses. A few weeks ago, it became the first global fintech to receive <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/nium-becomes-first-global-fintech-to-penetrate-japans-walled-garden/">Japanese authorization</a> to process large financial
transactions. Meanwhile, the company has partnered <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/ebury-and-nium-forge-partnership-for-cross-border-payments-in-brazil/">with Ebury</a>, another payment
fintech. This collaboration focuses on cross-border payments in Brazil.</p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Another Broker Eyes Latam: TopFX Onboards Regional Director]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/another-broker-eyes-latam-topfx-onboards-regional-director/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/another-broker-eyes-latam-topfx-onboards-regional-director/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:33:14 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/another-broker-eyes-latam-topfx-onboards-regional-director</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The ambitions of TopFX Global in the emerging markets of Latin America have become clearer as the forex and contracts for differences (CFDs) broker has appointed Nordine Mejd as the Director for the Latam region. According to his LinkedIn profile, he assumed the role earlier this month.</p><p>Brokers’ Focus on Latam</p><p>TopFX Global, the Seychelles-registered entity that operates globally, holds a Seychelles licence. Its retail offerings include CFDs on forex, indices, shares, metals, energies, ETFs, and cryptocurrencies. The brand is also known for its institutional offerings, as it operates as a prime CFDs broker with 12 years of expertise in liquidity services.</p><p>For the new role, Mejd is based in the Cyprus offices of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/topfx/">TopFX</a>.</p><p>Several other brokers have also been focusing on their strategies in the growing Latam markets, which are emerging markets alongside Asia and Africa. Recently, ATFX appointed a <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/moves/atfx-targets-latin-american-market-announces-new-growth-manager/">Growth Manager for the Latam region</a>, while Exness opened its <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/brokers/exness-eyes-latam-expansion-with-new-uruguay-office/">first physical office in Uruguay</a> last year.</p><p>Two of the largest countries in the Latam region, Brazil and Mexico, have populations of 204 million and 131 million in 2023, respectively, according to the IMF. <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/analysis/intelligence-report-betting-on-brazil-and-mexico-is-it-worth-it/">If only 0.2 percent of the population of these two countries trade CFDs</a>, as is the case for the UK, there is a potential for 290,000 active trading accounts in Brazil and 450,000 in Mexico.</p><p>Time with Other Brokers</p><p>Mejd brings more than a decade of experience in the financial services industry to his new role at TopFX. Most recently, he was the Chief Operating Officer at SEC Markets, a retail CFDs broker with claimed presences in Dubai and St Vincent and the Grenadines. There, he spent the last year.</p><p>However, his most prominent experience was at TTCM Traders Trust, a multi-licensed CFDs broker, where he spent ten years of his career. As seen on his LinkedIn profile, he joined the Cyprus offices of the broker as the Head of Portfolio Management in mid-2013 and then climbed up the corporate ladder to become the Head of Business Development and then the Executive Director. He parted with that company last year.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[CFDs Broker Ec Markets Gives the Marketing Team a Boost by Hiring Nick Xydas]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/cfds-broker-ec-markets-gives-the-marketing-team-a-boost-by-hiring-nick-xydas/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/cfds-broker-ec-markets-gives-the-marketing-team-a-boost-by-hiring-nick-xydas/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 05:24:07 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/cfds-broker-ec-markets-gives-the-marketing-team-a-boost-by-hiring-nick-xydas</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Ec Markets, a forex and contracts for differences (CFDs) broker, has strengthened its team with the recent appointment of Nick Xydas as the Marketing Director.</p><p>Announcing the move on LinkedIn, Xydas noted: “Excited to announce that I've recently joined Ec Markets as Marketing Director, with a vision to propel it into a global brand!” </p><p> “Thrilled to contribute to the growth and evolution of this already established powerhouse.”</p><p>A Multi-Regulated Broker</p><p>Ec Markets offers retail trading services under multiple regulatory licences, including those obtained from regulators in the United Kingdom, Seychelles, and Mauritius. Its offerings include spot forex, metals, crude oil, indices, and cryptocurrency CFDs. However, it does not offer cryptocurrency CFDs in the UK <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/regulation/uks-crypto-derivatives-ban-starts-today/">due to local regulations</a>.</p><p>Ec Markets Group <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/ec-markets-group-gains-membership-on-london-stock-exchange/">obtained membership in the London Stock Exchange</a> last year.</p><p>"With the company's recent achievement of gaining membership on the London Stock Exchange, we have a solid foundation to propel EC Markets into the forefront of the global financial market," Xydas said.</p><p>An Experienced Marketer</p><p>Xydas will be joining Ec Markets from Matworks, a Cyprus-based IT company where he was the Chief Marketing Officer for about the last year. Prior to that, he was the CMO at CreditPilot, another Cypriot company specialising in digital and mobile financial services, transactional and payment infrastructure. Matworks and CreditPilot are entities under the same group.</p><p>He also worked in the marketing teams of multiple brokers. According to his LinkedIn profile, he spent about three years at FXGT, a Cyprus-based FX and CFDs broker. There, he joined as the Marketing Technology Manager and later became the Head of Business Development for its Japanese unit.</p><p>Other industry experience of Xydas includes a two-year stint at <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/eurotrader-group/">Eurotrader</a>, then a nascent forex brokerage, where he was responsible for the development, implementation, and execution of digital marketing plans and oversaw the full integration of CRM and client area. Further, he was the Head of Marketing and Communications for Totalserve Group for about three years, where he supervised the tax and corporate services providers’ online and offline presence. He additionally planned and implemented the company's market strategies.</p><p>"Nick's extensive experience in marketing, particularly within the fintech sector, aligns perfectly with our ambitions for EC Markets," said the CEO of Ec Markets, Matthew Smith. "His appointment underscores our commitment to strategic leadership and innovation as we embark on this exciting phase of growth."

</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[How Data Analytics Drive Next-Generation Business Financing]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/how-data-analytics-drive-next-generation-business-financing/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/how-data-analytics-drive-next-generation-business-financing/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alan Lin]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Data]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/how-data-analytics-drive-next-generation-business-financing</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I've been in fintech for a number of years, and one thing
has become increasingly clear: the role of data analytics in finance is not
just growing, it's completely revolutionising how we make lending decisions.
Traditional lending models rely on static data that is often outdated and
generic, but we are now afforded the ability to be increasingly granular when
making financial decisions. </p><p>However, while lots of data is great, we need to understand
how to effectively translate this data, action it, and embed it into a better
customer experience. Our <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/revenue-based-finance/">revenue-based
finance (RBF)</a> business model relies on a seamless customer journey, so it’s
particularly important to me that we get this right across the business,
especially when handling diverse financial requirements, from smaller loans to
significant investments.   </p><p>A Holistic Approach to Business Health That Is More than
Just Numbers</p><p>Traditional credit models often view <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/business/">businesses</a> through a
black-and-white lens, primarily relying on credit scores and financial
accounts. In contrast, data analytics offers a more nuanced and informative
approach. We're now able to look beyond mere numbers, considering factors like
seasonality and recent performance trends. It's about creating a full picture
of a business’s health and potential, rather than just ticking boxes.  </p><p>This is particularly important in sectors such as
e-commerce, which is where we initially invested predominantly. When tackling a
concept like seasonality, traditional <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/analysis/">analysis</a> of balance
sheets or inventory during off-peak seasons can be misleading. Looking at, and
cross-referencing, a range of different data points allows us to
delve deep into the cyclic nature of e-commerce sales and infer correlations
with other inputs such as marketing spend or a specific campaign or event,
identifying peak periods and contextualising performance. </p><p>For example, we have financed many <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/e-commerce/">e-commerce</a> companies
that typically display low revenue in certain months. However, a detailed
analysis of their historical stock and marketing activities often reveals
significant sales surges during expected key periods, such as Black Friday. </p><p>Interestingly, we also observe less predictable spikes. For
example, one of our clients aligns their stock and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/m/marketing/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="48d4594c-de24-47ac-9f1b-aa2e0da8374a">marketing</a> expenditure with
major global music festivals. They typically experience a notable increase in
revenue about two weeks before these festivals start. This holistic approach
allows us to recognise distinct patterns and tailor our financing to each
business.   </p><p>Speed, Access, and Flexibility as the Three Pillars of
Modern Financing</p><p>Data without action is just that: data. The success of
modern financing, and RBF in particular, can be defined by three key pillars: speed,
access, and flexibility, and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/data-analytics/">data analytics</a>
plays a huge role in this. Data moves at incredible speeds, and it’s the
ability to process and respond to this data in real-time that can elevate a
lender's product offering. </p><p>The advent of cloud computing and open banking has
drastically changed access, allowing vast amounts of data to be processed
almost instantaneously. This real-time access offers unparalleled
flexibility in adjusting offers and funding support based on a company's
day-to-day performance.  <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/ai/">AI</a> and machine learning
(read: Large Language Models) will be a pivotal part of business financing in
the future. </p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">In the future of banking and securities, data engineering will revolutionize operations. AI, cloud computing,.. <a href="https://t.co/xBIv29JpFw">https://t.co/xBIv29JpFw</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MotivityLabs?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MotivityLabs</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mcloud?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Mcloud</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DataEngineering?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DataEngineering</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Banking?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Banking</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Securities?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Securities</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AI</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bigdata?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bigdata</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Finance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Finance</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DataAnalytics?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DataAnalytics</a> <a href="https://t.co/lOcxTh5gkE">pic.twitter.com/lOcxTh5gkE</a></p>— Motivity Labs Inc (@motivitylab) <a href="https://twitter.com/motivitylab/status/1779861915864293874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 15, 2024</a></blockquote><p>The vision will develop tools that can synthesise vast
amounts of data into comprehensible, actionable insights. Imagine being able to
feed financial data into an AI model and receive instant analysis on a
company's financial health, risks, and opportunities. This is where we are
headed, a future where data <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/a/analytics/" class="terms__main-term" id="0cd41468-7088-4154-93a3-bf5c46f15957">analytics</a> not only support but enhance every
aspect of business financing.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Treasuries enhance operations through AI-driven data analytics<a href="https://t.co/XWBINfPZ95">https://t.co/XWBINfPZ95</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Finance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Finance</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AI</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DataAnalytics?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DataAnalytics</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Technology?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Technology</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Treasury?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Treasury</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/APAC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#APAC</a></p>— The Asset (@TheAssetMag) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheAssetMag/status/1781200841862697357?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 19, 2024</a></blockquote><p>I’ve seen first-hand the power of data analytics in
real-time decision-making. We had a repeat customer who hit a rough patch, and
our tools flagged this financial downturn, meaning we could communicate with
them on the fly, adjusting our approach to lending while maintaining full
transparency. This is the kind of agility that data analytics enables, a far
cry from traditional models where assessments could be outdated by months if
not years.    </p><p>The Problem with Data </p><p>Of course, data analysis does come with its own challenges.
One significant hurdle for us is managing data duplication and ensuring its
reliability. In the world of global finance, where we deal with multiple
currencies and languages, data interpretation becomes complex. Take, for
instance, our operations across the UK and Australia. </p><p>When we refresh data at midnight in the UK, it’s already
midday in <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/australia/">Australia</a>.
This time difference can split a single business day's data across two days,
complicating our analysis and decision-making process.  Then there’s the fact that the sheer volume
of data we handle doesn't automatically translate to effective decision-making.
</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Finance Data Analysis: How Is Data Analytics Used In Finance? <a href="https://t.co/yjNhfOApHR">https://t.co/yjNhfOApHR</a></p>— Pankaj Kumar (@P4NKAJKUMAR) <a href="https://twitter.com/P4NKAJKUMAR/status/1779732371891195913?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 15, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Without wanting to sound like a broken record, it's not just
about collecting vast amounts of data; it’s about converting this data
into an easily interpretable format that informs sound financial decisions.
The information needs to be not only accurate and up-to-date but also presented in a way
that is comprehensible and actionable; there’s a real problem with the
standardisation of data if it is collected from multiple sources.</p><p>Without repeating the same point, the focus isn't solely on gathering extensive data but rather on transforming it into a format that facilitates informed financial choices. Data accuracy and currency are essential, but equally critical is how it's presented: clear and actionable. The challenge arises when data from various origins lacks standardization.</p><p>Open banking is a prime example of this; it’s incredible
that statements and accounts can be presented in so many different formats.
This process of translating raw data into meaningful insight is as crucial as
the data collection itself, and it's a challenge we continuously strive to
perfect.  The future of modern financing looks healthy. </p><p>As data points become ever more connected and automated,
there is a huge opportunity for lenders to enhance their decision-making
processes and offer more measured, sustainable, and tailored lending to
customers. The challenge, as outlined above, will be how we make sense of it
all.</p>

This article was written by Alan Lin at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Coinbase, eToro, NAGA and More: Executive Moves of the Week]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/coinbase-etoro-naga-and-more-executive-moves-of-the-week/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/coinbase-etoro-naga-and-more-executive-moves-of-the-week/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Hazan]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/moves/coinbase-etoro-naga-and-more-executive-moves-of-the-week</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This week witnessed a notable rise in executive appointments within the forex, crypto, and fintech industries, showing a slight difference compared to last week's activity.</p><p>The executive moves of the week encompass a diverse range of appointments within the financial sector. This includes the following changes: Nana Murugesan has assumed the role of President at Matter Labs; Louise Unger has transitioned to the Financial Markets Authority as the Executive Director for Response and Enforcement; Loukia Matsia joined NAGA as Head of Compliance; Mark Evans has taken on the role of Head of Corporate Development at IG Group; Martin Grant joins Binance.US's Board of Directors; James Hardcastle has become the Vice President and Head of Sales for the Asia Pacific region at Options Technology; Qianyue Dai has been promoted to VP and Senior Manager Retail for China and Japan at StoneX; Jeffrey Navarro has bid farewell to Taurex as Head of LATAM; and finally, Shalom Berkovitz concluded his directorship at eToro (UK) Limited after seven years. These moves reflect strategic advancements and leadership transitions across various firms in the financial industry, shaping their trajectories in the global market.</p><p>Discover the ever-changing landscape of executive shifts within the realms of forex, cryptocurrency, and fintech through our weekly summary. Take a closer look at the developing scene of leadership transitions within the financial technology industry.</p><p>Executive Moves of the Week</p><p>Coinbase's Former Executive Nana Murugesan Named President of Ethereum Scaling Firm</p><p>Nana Murugesan, the former Vice President at Coinbase, has assumed the role of President at Matter Labs, a leading Ethereum scaling solution firm. Murugesan's extensive experience, including leadership roles at Snap and Samsung Electronics, positions him to spearhead Matter Labs' operations, focusing on marketing, communication, finance, and legal aspects. Alex Gluchowski, Matter Labs' Co-Founder and CEO, emphasized Murugesan's pivotal role in advancing blockchain scalability: "His expertise will be instrumental in advancing our vision to scale
blockchain technology to a mainstream audience, powered by zero-knowledge
technology."</p><p>Murugesan's diverse background in electrical engineering, computer engineering, and business administration equips him to drive engineering solutions at Matter Labs. With over 60 employees spanning 35 countries, Murugesan aims to accelerate blockchain adoption, particularly through Matter Labs' zero-knowledge technology, facilitating secure and scalable transactions. Murugesan expressed enthusiasm for the opportunity, highlighting the significance of zkSync in enabling practical blockchain applications and expanding the ecosystem globally. </p><p>Investigate more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/coinbases-former-executive-nana-murugesan-named-president-of-ethereum-scaling-firm/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">Nana Murugesan's mission to advance blockchain scalability</a> and foster the ongoing financial revolution at Matter Labs.</p><p>After 12 Years at Bank of New Zealand, Financial Expert Joins FMA</p><p>The Financial Markets Authority (FMA) has appointed Louise Unger as the Executive Director for Response and Enforcement, tapping into her extensive experience in financial services law and regulation. Transitioning from her role as the General Manager of the Credit branch at the Commerce Commission, Unger brings a wealth of expertise in overseeing the implementation of regulatory acts and leading risk and compliance teams. </p><p>The FMA has reinforced its enforcement efforts with Unger's appointment amidst a rise in financial crimes, particularly impostor schemes targeting unsuspecting individuals. While overall scam reports decreased, the surge in imposter websites necessitates heightened vigilance. Recent incidents, including imposters posing as the UK's Financial Conduct Authority, underscore the need for caution. In response, the FMA has warned against unregulated platforms like AxonExchange and suspends Equitise Pty Ltd's crowdfunding license, signaling its commitment to safeguarding investors and maintaining market integrity. </p><p>Find out more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/moves/after-12-years-at-bank-of-new-zealand-financial-expert-joins-fma/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">Louise Unger's pivotal role in enhancing FMA's enforcement capabilities</a> and the regulator's proactive measures to address emerging financial threats.</p><p>NAGA Welcomes Former Tickmill Leader Loukia Matsia as New Head of Compliance</p><p>Loukia Matsia has assumed the role of Head of Compliance and Anti-Money Laundering (AML) at NAGA, expressing her enthusiasm for this career transition on LinkedIn. With extensive experience at Tickmill Europe Ltd where she served as Head of Compliance and AML, Matsia brings a wealth of expertise to her new position. Her tenure at Tickmill was marked by effective management of compliance operations and a commitment to upholding AML regulations. </p><p>Before her leadership role at Tickmill, Matsia served as a Compliance Officer, focusing on AML compliance for over three years. Her dedication to regulatory standards earned her recognition within the industry. With a background spanning various roles in reputable financial institutions, including the Account Manager at 24option and the Head of Administration and HR at CommexFX, Matsia demonstrated versatile skills and leadership capabilities. </p><p>Identify more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/naga-welcomes-former-tickmill-leader-loukia-matsia-as-new-head-of-compliance/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">NAGA's recent leadership transition</a> and its implications for the company's compliance operations and regulatory strategy.</p><p>IG Group Appoints Mark Evans as Head of Corporate Development</p><p>IG Group has named Mark Evans as its Head of Corporate Development, transitioning him from his previous role as Head of Consumer Insights and Strategy. With over six years of experience within the London-based forex and CFD trading firm, Evans brings a wealth of knowledge to his new position. His extensive career includes stints at prominent institutions such as Barclays Bank and BDO UK LLP, reflecting a robust background in finance and business advisory roles. </p><p>The appointment of Evans follows a series of significant changes within IG Group's leadership team, including the recent appointments of Jody Dunn as the Chief Operating Officer and Sarah Gore Langton as the Chief Risk Officer. These shifts occur as Charlie Rozes and Jon Noble, the former Chief Financial Officer and the Chief Operating Officer, respectively, depart from their roles. Rozes and Noble's exits coincide with Breon Corcoran's ascension to the CEO role earlier this year, as the company navigates both leadership transitions and stable financial performance.</p><p>Expose more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/ig-group-appoints-mark-evans-as-head-of-corporate-development/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">IG Group's strategic leadership changes</a> and the implications for its corporate development amidst stable financial results.</p><p>Binance.US Enlists New York's Former Fed Compliance Chief for Board</p><p>Binance.US has appointed Martin Grant, the former Chief Compliance and Ethics Officer of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, to its Board of Directors. With over three decades of regulatory expertise, Grant's tenure at the New York Fed underscores his deep understanding of compliance frameworks. Norman Reed, Binance.US' Interim CEO, emphasized Grant's addition as a testament to the company's commitment to compliance and integrity, crucial in navigating regulatory complexities. Grant expressed enthusiasm about shaping the future of the American digital asset industry through Binance.US. </p><p>Amid regulatory challenges, Binance.US faces layoffs and financial losses, stemming from legal actions by the SEC. Accusations of mishandling customer funds and offering unregistered securities have led to operational disruptions. Grant's appointment signals Binance.US's strategic response to regulatory pressures, aiming to reinforce compliance measures and position the platform for sustainable growth. </p><p>Learn more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/binanceus-enlists-new-yorks-former-fed-compliance-chief-for-board/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">Binance.US's regulatory challenges and strategic appointments</a> amidst the evolving landscape of digital assets.</p><p>18 Years of Fidessa Experience Lands Industry Veteran Top Job at Options Technology</p><p>Options Technology, a leading provider of capital markets infrastructure solutions, has named James Hardcastle as its new Vice President and Head of Sales for the Asia Pacific (APAC) region. With over 25 years of industry expertise, including 18 years at Fidessa, Hardcastle brings a wealth of knowledge to his role. He has a proven track record in software SaaS, hardware, infrastructure IaaS, and managed services, spanning both traditional finance and emerging finance markets. </p><p>Hardcastle's appointment underscores Options Technology's commitment to expanding its presence in the APAC region. He will leverage his extensive experience to drive sales growth and enhance the company's market position. Danny Moore, the President and CEO of Options, expressed confidence in Hardcastle's ability to deliver exceptional results, citing his successful track record in complex sales environments. </p><p>Discover more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/moves/18-years-of-fidessa-experience-lands-industry-veteran-top-job-at-options-technology/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">James Hardcastle's strategic role</a> in spearheading Options Technology's sales growth and market expansion across the APAC region.</p><p>StoneX Promotes Qianyue Dai as VP, Senior Manager Retail for China and Japan</p><p>StoneX, the FX and CFD brokerage firm, elevates Qianyue Dai to VP and Senior Manager of Retail for China and Japan. Dai, with over three years at StoneX, previously held roles such as Manager for Sales and Client Management and Senior Manager of Retail for China. With a background in GAIN Capital, Dai brings valuable industry experience to her new position. </p><p>StoneX Group's Q1 in the fiscal year 2024 showcased robust performance, with $74.6 million in operating revenue from forex and CFD offerings, marking an uplift of 53% year-over-year (Y-o-Y). Retail sales of FX and CFD contracts contributed significantly, reaching $66 million, a rise of 68% Y-o-Y. Despite a decline of 15% in average daily volume, profitability per trade surged 73% to $109, reflecting positive financial outcomes. StoneX's recent expansion into retail FX and CFD industry, facilitated by the acquisition of GAIN Capital, positions the firm as a significant industry player. </p><p>Display more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/stonex-promotes-qianyue-dai-as-vp-senior-manager-retail-for-china-and-japan/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">StoneX's strategic moves and Qianyue Dai's elevated role</a> in shaping the firm's presence in China and Japan.</p><p>This Regulator Bids Farewell to Long-Serving Top Executives</p><p>The Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC) has undergone significant leadership changes to drive its ongoing transformation. Notably, ASIC's CEO, Warren Day, has transitioned to the Commonwealth Director of Public Prosecutions on secondment, while Greg Yanco assumed the Interim CEO role. Tim Mullaly, the Executive Director of Enforcement and Compliance, announced his retirement, marking the end of his instrumental 25-year tenure. ASIC acknowledged their pivotal roles and has initiated searches for new Executive Directors to continue its evolution. </p><p>Amidst these changes, ASIC celebrates a milestone victory in combating greenwashing, reinforcing its commitment to regulatory integrity. Additionally, ASIC has strengthened its executive team with new appointments and restructuring, highlighting its dedication to modernization and strategic alignment. The departure of longstanding leaders marks a new chapter for ASIC, as it seeks exceptional talent to propel its transformative journey forward. </p><p>Reveal more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/this-regulator-bids-farewell-to-long-serving-top-executives/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">ASIC's leadership transitions</a> and strategic advancements amidst its commitment to regulatory excellence.</p><p>GCEX Strengthens UAE Team with New Sales Director</p><p>GCE Exchange FZE (GCEX), a digital prime brokerage and part of the GCEX Group, has reinforced its presence in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) by appointing Katina Messinis as the Sales Director for the region. With a robust background in cultivating strong client relationships across the Middle East, Africa, Southeast Asia, and Latin America, Messinis brings a wealth of experience to her new role.</p><p>In her capacity as Sales Director, Messinis will be stationed at GCEX's Dubai office, focusing on expanding the firm's client base. This includes catering to a diverse clientele comprising brokers, hedge funds, family offices, and professional traders. Leveraging her expertise, Messinis will provide clients with access to deep liquidity in digital assets and a comprehensive suite of proprietary technology solutions. Notably, this appointment comes at a pivotal moment for GCEX, following its recent acquisition of an Operational Virtual Asset Service Provider license from Dubai's Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority.</p><p>Investigate more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/moves/gcex-strengthens-uae-team-with-new-sales-director/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">GCEX's strategic moves</a> in enhancing its UAE operations and expanding its clientele with Messinis at the helm.</p><p>Taurex's Head of LATAM Jeffrey Navarro Announces Departure</p><p>Jeffrey Navarro, the Head of LATAM (Latin America) at Taurex, bid farewell to the company after over two years in the role. Navarro expressed gratitude to his colleagues, marking his departure on LinkedIn. He has transitioned to a new professional phase, highlighting Taurex's exceptional LATAM team performance. </p><p>Navarro's departure coincides with Taurex's rebranding from Zenfinex, along with a $15 million Series B funding round led by Oscar Hilt Tatum IV. The investment aims to enhance proprietary technology, including a mobile app and web platform slated for 2024 release. Funds will also fuel team expansion, regulatory compliance, and marketing efforts. This underscores Taurex's commitment to growth amidst significant revenue increase and ongoing technology investments. </p><p>Find out more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/taurexs-head-of-latam-jeffrey-navarro-announces-departure/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">Jeffrey Navarro's departure</a> and Taurex's strategic investment for future growth.</p><p>eToro UK Concludes Directorship of Shalom Berkovitz after Seven Years</p><p>eToro (UK) Limited has bid farewell to Shalom Berkovitz, concluding his seven-year tenure as one of its directors. Berkovitz, boasting three decades of professional experience, retired in February 2023 but continues to serve as a director for several subsidiaries within the eToro Group. Prior to his time at eToro, Berkovitz held esteemed leadership roles, including CEO positions at DSNR Media Group and d-Group, along with notable stints at Golden Pages Israel and Eurocom Communications.</p><p>In a strategic move to bolster its global operations, eToro has appointed seasoned professionals to key positions and secured regulatory approval in vital markets. In France, Inès de Dinechin joins as a Special Adviser, leveraging her extensive boardroom experience. Meanwhile, Massimo Citoni's promotion to Regional Manager strengthens eToro's presence in Italy.</p><p>Identify more about <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/director-shakeup-etoro-terminates-shalom-berkovitzs-appointment/" target="_blank" rel="follow" data-article-link="true">eToro's strategic initiatives</a> and Berkovitz's legacy amidst its global expansion efforts.</p>

This article was written by Tom Hazan at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Breaking: Bitcoin Halving is Sealed after Mining of Block 840,000]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/breaking-bitcoin-halving-is-sealed-after-mining-of-block-840000/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/breaking-bitcoin-halving-is-sealed-after-mining-of-block-840000/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/breaking-bitcoin-halving-is-sealed-after-mining-of-block-840000</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Bitcoin halving just took place at block number 840,000. This event today reduced the mining reward for each block to 3.125 Bitcoins from 6.25 Bitcoins. New Bitcoins are introduced into circulation through these mining rewards.</p><p>Another Bitcoin Halving</p><p>Halving is one of the most significant events in the cryptocurrency world and occurs approximately every four years, specifically after every 210,000 blocks. It greatly reduces the supply of Bitcoin, thus helping to control inflation by maintaining scarcity.</p><p>Bitcoin was created on 3 January 2009. Initially, the reward for mining each block was 50 Bitcoins. The <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/m/mining-reward/" class="terms__main-term" id="f35f95eb-324a-4053-84c5-59f754c15f9e">mining reward</a> was first halved on 28 November 2012 in the first halving event. The next halving event took place on 9 July 2016, reducing the mining reward to 12.5 Bitcoins per block, while the third halving on 11 May 2020 reduced it further to 6.25 Bitcoins.</p><p>Now, the reward for mining each <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/bitcoin/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="261088a9-0f41-4202-a73c-31f75ba6bd93">Bitcoin</a> block is 3.125 Bitcoins.</p><p>The Cap of 21 Million Bitcoins</p><p>Bitcoin operates on a <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/education-centre/proof-of-stake-vs-proof-of-work-the-differences-explained/">proof-of-work consensus mechanism</a>, and according to the algorithm, a halving must occur every 210,000 blocks until all 21 million Bitcoins are mined. It is estimated that the next Bitcoin halving will happen in 2028.</p><p>To alter this pre-set algorithm, a majority of Bitcoin miners, more than 50 percent, must agree, which is nearly impossible given Bitcoin's decentralized and extensive network.</p><p>Currently, around 19 million Bitcoins have already been mined, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/bitcoin-nears-depletion-only-nine-months-supply-ahead-of-halving/">leaving only 2 million more to be mined</a>.</p><p>The halving of Bitcoin supply has a significant impact on the cryptocurrency's price. Historically, it has been one of the major price drivers, with Bitcoin prices surging around the event. The event affects Bitcoin miners' operations, as a reduction in the reward by half without a corresponding significant price increase, affects the cash flow of the mining operations.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[FCA Flags Suspected Clone Firm Impersonating Legitimate Forexeze Limited]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/fca-flags-suspected-clone-firm-impersonating-legitimate-forexeze-limited/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/fca-flags-suspected-clone-firm-impersonating-legitimate-forexeze-limited/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 20:18:47 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/fca-flags-suspected-clone-firm-impersonating-legitimate-forexeze-limited</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The UK's financial services regulator has warned of a
suspected clone firm claiming to be affiliated with a previously registered entity. In a notice published today (Friday), the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) mentioned that it had not authorized forexeze.com and forex-eze.com to offer its services.</p><p>The FCA added that the suspected clone entity has been
reaching out to individuals, presenting itself as a legitimate financial
service provider.</p><p>Identifying the Clone Firm</p><p>Clone firms use various deceptive tactics, mimicking
authorized entities' details to appear genuine. They often replicate authorized firms' names, email addresses, and websites, making it challenging for individuals
to notice their fraudulent nature. Forexeze.com and forex-eze.com utilize email addresses such as info@forexeze.com and support@forex-eze.com,
the regulator noted.</p><p>However, the details of the authentic firm are
Forexeze Limited, which holds the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/fca/" target="_blank" rel="follow">FCA</a> Firm Reference Number 809435 and operates
from the Scottish Provident House in Harrow, Middlesex. The firm's telephone
number is +442088613040, and its email address is aliatrakji@yahoo.com.</p><p>Risks Associated with Dealing with Clone Firms</p><p>The FCA has warned users that engaging with <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/c/clone/" class="terms__main-term" id="c02bac54-0735-474c-8969-06d3fdb49589">clone</a>
firms exposes individuals to significant risks. Unlike authorized entities,
clone firms do not offer regulatory protection or access to dispute resolution
mechanisms like the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/financial-ombudsman-service/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Financial Ombudsman Service</a>. Additionally, clients are not
covered by the Financial Services Compensation Scheme.</p><p>Besides that, the regulator has urged users to verify the authorization status of any firm they wish to deal with through the FCA's Financial Services Register
before engaging in any transactions.</p><p>Elsewhere, the Financial Markets Authority (FMA) of
New Zealand is fighting against fraudulent activity and scams within the
financial markets. Recently, the regulator <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/regulation/fma-cracks-down-on-these-two-companies-amid-fraud-concerns-in-new-zealand/" target="_blank" rel="follow">took significant actions</a> to
safeguard consumers and maintain market integrity.  </p><p>The FMA canceled Equitise Pty Ltd's <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/c/crowdfunding/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="123c62c4-dab0-4489-b3e1-9961cb08abb5">crowdfunding</a>
license and issued a warning against AxonExchange, a cryptocurrency trading
provider. Equitise, a licensed equity crowdfunding service provider since 2014,
faced license cancellation for the alleged breach of compliance obligations. The company reportedly failed to provide financial reports and presented late annual confirmation filing.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Brazil Leads Financial Inclusion in Latin America: Records 70% Debit/Credit Card Usage]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/brazil-leads-financial-inclusion-in-latin-america-records-70-debitcredit-card-usage/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/brazil-leads-financial-inclusion-in-latin-america-records-70-debitcredit-card-usage/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:11:13 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/brazil-leads-financial-inclusion-in-latin-america-records-70-debitcredit-card-usage</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In Latin America, Brazil leads in financial inclusion with 70% adoption of debit or credit cards. The country has recorded 55% card usage and an outstanding level of real-time payments.
This positive trend is contributed by the elimination of barriers to payment
infrastructure in the country. </p><p>These are the findings of a joint study between Nubank
and Mastercard, which highlighted the path individuals pursue toward financial
inclusion. The study, which is based on data from 3.6 million Nubank's
customers, also highlighted the impact of financial inclusion and long-term economic
growth.</p><p>Unlocking Financial Inclusion</p><p>Speaking about the report, Cristina Junqueira, the Co-Founder and Chief Growth Officer of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/nubank/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Nubank</a>, mentioned: "Although access to financial services in and of itself has had a major impact, advancing the literacy journey on these topics brings greater and more sustainable benefits not only to individuals but to the community as a whole."</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">.<a href="https://twitter.com/nubank?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Nubank</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/Mastercard?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Mastercard</a> Exclusive Study Reveals Path to Advancing Beyond Access Toward Financial Health.Read more: <a href="https://t.co/2V1jHJKfVo">https://t.co/2V1jHJKfVo</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/study?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#study</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/fintech?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#fintech</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/finance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#finance</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FinancialIT?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FinancialIT</a></p>— Financial IT (@financialit_net) <a href="https://twitter.com/financialit_net/status/1781260676285231343?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 19, 2024</a></blockquote><p>The study noted that Brazil has significantly
progressed in financial inclusion compared to other countries in <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/latin-america/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Latin America</a>. The World Bank Global
Findex shows that the country has 70% card penetration and a growing trend in
real-time payment usage.</p><p>Additionally, the report underscored the importance of
providing financial access to underserved populations. Remarkably, 60% of
Nubank's customers transitioned from access to usage within 24 months,
irrespective of income level. Notably, prepaid cards have enabled most users
to access loan products and investments.</p><p>Addressing Barriers</p><p>However, despite this progress in financial inclusion, there
are barriers. While 84% of adults in Brazil have access to financial accounts,
many lack the necessary financial literacy to maximize the benefits. In order
to address this challenge, the study recommended active product usage and
financial education initiatives.</p><p>Mastercard's Division President for Brazil, Marcelo
Tangioni, added: "The journey to financial security and health is
non-linear and full of obstacles – the only way to accelerate this journey is
by understanding the barriers and then building and deploying inclusive digital
solutions."</p><p>"Through this study, we have clear evidence that
frequent, consistent, and responsible use of digital payment tools is critical
to building trust and putting people on a path towards a more sustainable
financial health."</p><p>Last year, Brazil's largest cryptocurrency exchange, Mercado Bitcoin, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/brazils-largest-crypto-exchange-gains-payments-license/" target="_blank" rel="follow">secured a payment institution license</a> from the country's central bank. This approval allows the exchange to operate as a payment institution and electronic money issuer. As a licensed payments provider, the exchange
offers a range of digital banking services. </p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving and Geopolitics: The Liquidity Conundrum]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/bitcoin-halving-and-geopolitics-the-liquidity-conundrum/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/bitcoin-halving-and-geopolitics-the-liquidity-conundrum/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 17:54:41 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victor Golovtchenko]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/bitcoin-halving-and-geopolitics-the-liquidity-conundrum</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The long-awaited day of the 4th phase of Bitcoin's halving is looming in the cryptocurrency sector. The
countdown to this event shows that it could happen around the final hours of Friday evening if
you are located in the Americas or Saturday morning if you are in Asia or
Europe.</p><p>According to the market metrics, the event is much anticipated and should be discounted well in advance of its actual occurrence. In contrast to unpredictable overnight barrages of rockets in the heat of the Middle East, the halving event has a clear outcome—the amount of BTC rewards
that miners get for completing a block will be reduced in half to 3.125 BTC
from the current 6.25.</p><p>This will inevitably lead to less supply from miners, but
does it change the liquidity of the overall market? We will attempt to answer that question in the coming paragraphs, and while at it, we
will also highlight some challenges related to the current geopolitical
landscape and the resulting jittery market conditions we have recently observed.</p><p>Are Previous Halvings Linked to Liquidity Squeezes?</p><p>Every time 210,000 blocks are mined, the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/bitcoin/" class="terms__main-term" id="261088a9-0f41-4202-a73c-31f75ba6bd93">Bitcoin</a> network's protocol <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/bitcoin-halving-countdown-why-it-may-not-guarantee-price-surge/" target="_blank" rel="follow">cuts in half</a> the amount of new rewards. As highlighted by the institutional research team at Coinbase, this means that the newly
minted supply will drop from 900 Bitcoins per day to 450 Bitcoins per day. At
current market prices ($65,000 per BTC), this equates to roughly $30,000,000
worth of new supply per day or $900,000,000 per month.</p><p>These figures are rather low compared to the average daily trading volumes across crypto exchanges, especially since the launch of BTC ETF trading, which triggered increased interest in the asset
class.</p><p>The amount of tradable Bitcoin has also been on the rise
during the recent bull run that accelerated since early Q4 2023. According to
the team at Coinbase Institutional Research, active BTC supply, defined as Bitcoin moved in the past three months, rose to 1.3 million. This figure is in comparison to 150,000, which was
mined during that time.</p><p>In a statement shared with <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Finance Magnates</a>, Coinbase's Research
Analyst, David Han, mentioned that the decline in BTC mining issuance
could create new supply-side dynamics that are constructive in the longer term.</p><p>Han expressed his doubts as to whether that can result in
an imminent supply crunch: “We find that the largest contributors to increased
BTC supply during bull markets come from long-term wallets beginning to
activate instead of from newly mined BTC.”</p><p>Crypto and Fiat Liquidity Cycles – the Signal and the Noise</p><p>A widely held belief in the cryptocurrency community is that
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/bitcoin-halving-countdown-what-is-ahead/" target="_blank" rel="follow">halving</a> events are usually followed by a significant rally in the value of
their digital assets. While there is some historical correlation to corroborate
this notion, science has long established - correlation does not imply
causation.</p><p>The logical fallacy where two events that occur at a similar
time have a cause-effect relationship is at the center of spurious
relationships - two events can be correlated, but that connection may not be
causal.</p><p>With only three <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/h/halving/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="4334a48f-5b44-4f38-9d1f-c304dfdd6c40">halving</a> events behind us and a fourth one
brewing, one can observe correlations, but not necessarily cause-effect
relationships. Halving events don’t perfectly coincide with central bank
liquifying cycles, but as the chart below shows, there is some food for thought
for risk-management teams and traders alike.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Less than 7 hours to the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a> halving ⏳Where do you see the price of <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$BTC</a> going next?Catch the countdown here: <a href="https://t.co/hBaJI9Juo9">https://t.co/hBaJI9Juo9</a> <a href="https://t.co/BfrAfkBh3I">pic.twitter.com/BfrAfkBh3I</a></p>— CoinGecko (@coingecko) <a href="https://twitter.com/coingecko/status/1781393838244048938?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 19, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Around the first halving in 2012, the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/fed/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Fed</a> launched the third
chapter of its post-financial crisis quantitative easing program (QE3), shortly
followed by the first US debt ceiling crisis and the loss of the reserve
currency issuer’s AAA rating.</p><p>The second one, in 2016, was followed by the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/bank-of-england/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Bank of England</a>’s post-Brexit ramp-up of bond buying in tandem with the ECB’s asset purchase program. Fast-forward to 2020, and we all remember the central bank and fiscal policy bazookas firing left and right with fiat liquidity so ample that it ultimately caused the sharpest spike in inflationary pressures globally since the 1970s.   </p><p>Geopolitical Blocks</p><p>It was an early morning in the Middle East, as a
well-telegraphed attack by Iran had been unleashed upon Israel. With all other
financial markets closed, it was up to crypto to reflect the current state of
mind (or compute).</p><p>The old Wall Street saying, “up the stairs, down the
elevator,” came to mind as <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/btc/" target="_blank" rel="follow">BTC</a> and ETH dropped in tandem in rapidly dwindling liquidity conditions. That night, Coinbase registered about $2 billion worth of liquidations, the company’s institutional research team
highlighted in a recent weekly market call.</p><p>In contrast to the rather gradual price action that unfolded in the aftermath of the October 7th attack on Israel by Hamas, the Iranian attack, despite being well-telegraphed before the weekend, did result in material price action across the crypto market.</p><p>At one point, Pax Gold, a crypto token supposed to be fully backed by gold, spiked about $1000 at a time when the physical gold market, which is underpinning the coin's value, wasn’t open. The magnitude
of the attack certainly surprised market participants, while some automatic
“stop trading” commands must have been unleashed across algorithmic trading
strategies.</p><p>Events centered around geopolitical stress have certainly caused some leveraged players to rethink, not only in the crypto market. Fed chair Powell’s higher rates for a longer period re-pivot raise questions about a widely expected easing of monetary policy.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Speech by Chair Powell on the economic outlook <a href="https://twitter.com/StanfordGSB?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@StanfordGSB</a>: <a href="https://t.co/y6oLUN0LYw">https://t.co/y6oLUN0LYw</a>Watch live: <a href="https://t.co/a0ApMRHum2">https://t.co/a0ApMRHum2</a></p>— Federal Reserve (@federalreserve) <a href="https://twitter.com/federalreserve/status/1775556726344839658?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 3, 2024</a></blockquote><p>To Bid, or Not to Bid</p><p>As the halving cycles come and go, the impact of these
events could lessen in time. Since most bitcoins have already been mined, the current market liquidity state is much more about the existing supply of BTC on the market than newly mined coins.</p><p>A supply crunch overnight is the least likely event, and if
very recent history is any guide, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/geopolitical-tension-is-crypto-following-traditional-markets/" target="_blank" rel="follow">geopolitical tensions</a> can create more
volatility or liquidity waves on cryptocurrency and traditional financial
markets.</p><p>Guided by risk-on and risk-off flows, cryptocurrencies have
been defying the trend occasionally, but at their core they remain a high-risk
asset with a digital store of value component behind it. Only time will tell whether or not that narrative has become a well-established characteristic, but so
far, so good.</p><p>As the halving event comes and passes us by, it is the
central banks that will have the ball in their court - ready to do whatever it
takes to address inflationary challenges or supply more fiat liquidity to the
monetary system.</p><p>With <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/bitcoin-etf/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Bitcoin ETFs</a> breaking new ground, the liquidity
situation for the king of crypto has significantly improved. As David Han outlines: “Net US spot ETFs inflows to date approximately offset the BTC that was
mined in the previous six months.”</p>

This article was written by Victor Golovtchenko at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Earned Wage Access: Friend or Foe in the War on Financial Tightropes?]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/earned-wage-access-friend-or-foe-in-the-war-on-financial-tightropes/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/earned-wage-access-friend-or-foe-in-the-war-on-financial-tightropes/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/earned-wage-access-friend-or-foe-in-the-war-on-financial-tightropes</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The fight over Earned
Wage Access (EWA) is the latest skirmish in <a href="https://hill.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=9295" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">the ongoing war for the wallets of
America's working class</a>. This seemingly innocuous service, allowing employees
to access a portion of their already-earned wages before payday, has ignited a
firestorm in the payments industry, pitting Democrats against Republicans and
revealing a fundamental disagreement about financial empowerment versus
predatory lending.</p><p>On one side, a chorus of
Republican lawmakers sings the praises of EWA, painting it as <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/house-bill/7428/text?s=1&amp;r=1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">a beacon of
financial freedom</a> for cash-strapped workers. They envision a world where a
leaky pipe or a car repair doesn't force someone into the clutches of a payday
loan with its exorbitant interest rates. EWA, they argue, empowers individuals
by giving them control over their finances, allowing them to bridge the gap
between paychecks without resorting to usurious lenders.</p><p>However, Democrats see a
wolf in sheep's clothing. They argue that EWA, with its potential for hidden
fees and unclear disclosures, can morph into a debt trap disguised as
convenience. They point to California's stricter regulations as a model,
highlighting the need for clear annual percentage rate (APR) disclosures to
ensure consumers understand the true cost of accessing their own money.</p><p>This debate exposes a
raw nerve in the American financial system: the lack of access to affordable
credit for low- and middle-income earners. Stuck between the rock of infrequent
paychecks and the hard place of sky-high interest rates, many workers find themselves
in a vicious cycle of debt. EWA, with its promise of immediate access to earned
wages, emerges as a potential solution, but the question remains – is it a
genuine lifeline or just another layer of financial quicksand?</p><p>The battle lines drawn
in the EWA debate echo a larger war being waged in the payments industry – the
fight between traditional credit, the burgeoning realm of Buy Now, Pay Later
(BNPL), and the desperate need for financial inclusion for the underbanked.
Traditional credit cards offer flexibility but can trap users in a cycle of
high-interest debt if not managed responsibly. BNPL, with its focus on smaller,
split payments, appears to offer a more manageable alternative. However,
concerns linger about the potential for overspending and a lack of the same
consumer protections as traditional credit cards.</p><p>EWA sits at a curious
intersection of these two worlds. Like <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/the-rise-of-buy-now-pay-later-services-and-their-influence-on-consumer-spending/">BNPL</a>, it provides immediate access to
funds, but with the potential for hidden fees and a reliance on already earned,
but not yet received, income. The question then becomes: Is EWA a responsible
innovation or a cleverly disguised form of predatory lending?</p><p>The answer likely lies
somewhere in between. EWA has the potential to be a valuable tool, particularly
for those struggling to make ends meet between paychecks. However, responsible
regulation and clear fee structures are crucial to prevent it from morphing
into a financial burden. Here's where lessons can be learned from the ongoing
evolution of BNPL. Regulatory frameworks that ensure transparency in fees and
responsible lending practices are essential to protect vulnerable consumers.</p><p>The fight for financial
stability is a complex one, with no single solution. EWA may not be the silver
bullet, but it can be a valuable tool in the arsenal for those struggling to
make ends meet. However, its success hinges on responsible regulation, clear
consumer protections, and a commitment to financial education. Only then can
EWA truly be a champion in the fight for financial well-being, not another
challenger pushing people to the edge.</p><p>The battle over EWA
isn't a zero-sum game. The victor shouldn't be a single political party or a
profit-driven industry.  The real winner
should be the American worker, finally equipped with the tools and resources to
navigate their financial reality with confidence.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Frictionless Finance: Why Fast Payment Systems Are the Cash Kings of Tomorrow]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/frictionless-finance-why-fast-payment-systems-are-the-cash-kings-of-tomorrow/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/frictionless-finance-why-fast-payment-systems-are-the-cash-kings-of-tomorrow/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/frictionless-finance-why-fast-payment-systems-are-the-cash-kings-of-tomorrow</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Cash may be king, but
it's a clunky monarch, weighed down by the burdens of physicality. The digital
age demands a more agile ruler, one that thrives in the realm of ones and
zeroes. Enter Fast Payment Systems (FPS), the fintech upstarts <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/uptake-use-and-inclusion-gains-fast-payment-systems-early-comparative-data" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">poised to dethrone
cash and usher in a new era of frictionless finance</a>.</p><p>FPS boast a simple yet
revolutionary proposition: instant transfers between bank accounts, 24/7, 365
days a year. No more waiting days for checks to clear or scrambling to find an
ATM on a Sunday afternoon. This streamlined efficiency has the potential to
reshape our financial interactions, impacting everything from how we split a
restaurant bill with friends to how small businesses manage their cash flow.</p><p>But <a href="https://www.nextradegroupllc.com/fast-payment-systems-and-inclusion" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">the true power of
FPS lies in their democratizing potential</a>. Unlike traditional banking systems,
which can often exclude unbanked or underbanked populations, FPS can operate
entirely on mobile phones. This opens the door for millions who have been locked
out of the formal financial system to participate in the digital economy.
Imagine a street vendor in a developing nation, previously limited to cash
transactions, now able to accept instant payments via their smartphone. The
implications for financial inclusion are vast.</p><p>However, the road to
becoming the king of the financial jungle isn't paved with good intentions
alone. There are challenges FPS must overcome before they can truly claim the
crown.</p><p>One major hurdle is
interoperability. Currently, many FPS function in silos, unable to seamlessly
connect with systems in other countries. This fragmentation creates a fractured
experience for users, hindering the potential for global e-commerce and cross-border
transactions. Imagine a freelancer in Argentina struggling to receive payment
from a client in Singapore because their respective FPS systems don't speak the
same digital language. Until a level of international cooperation fosters
interoperability, the true potential of FPS will remain unrealized.</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/the-double-edged-sword-of-faster-payments/">Security is another
concern</a>. The lightning-fast nature of FPS transactions necessitates robust
security measures to prevent fraud and cyberattacks. After all, a system
designed for instant transfers becomes equally adept at facilitating instant
theft. Balancing speed with security will be a crucial tightrope walk for FPS
providers.</p><p>There's also the
question of who gets to build and control these systems. Should the power lie
with governments, seeking to promote financial inclusion and stability? Or
should private companies take the lead, leveraging their expertise in
innovation and efficiency? The answer likely lies somewhere in between, with a
public-private partnership model fostering collaboration while ensuring
responsible governance.</p><p>Despite these
challenges, the momentum behind FPS is undeniable. Their convenience,
accessibility, and potential to empower the financially excluded make them a
compelling force in the evolving financial landscape. As these systems mature,
iron out their wrinkles, and establish a global network of interconnectivity,
they have the potential to become the cornerstone of a new financial era – one
where cash, the cumbersome king, finally gets dethroned.</p><p>This digital revolution
won't happen overnight. But with each tap, swipe, and instant transfer
facilitated by FPS, we inch closer to a world where financial transactions are
as seamless and ubiquitous as the internet itself. The future of finance may
not be entirely cashless, but it will undoubtedly be driven by the swift and
agile forces embodied by Fast Payment Systems.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[The Paper Chase: Can AI Outsmart Itself in the Battle Against Deepfakes?]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-paper-chase-can-ai-outsmart-itself-in-the-battle-against-deepfakes/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-paper-chase-can-ai-outsmart-itself-in-the-battle-against-deepfakes/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-paper-chase-can-ai-outsmart-itself-in-the-battle-against-deepfakes</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The realm of digital
identity has always been a precarious one, a constant dance between convenience
and security. In the past, a grainy webcam selfie and some hastily typed
information might have sufficed for verification. But in the age of deepfakes
and ever-evolving fraud tactics, the stakes have never been higher. The game of
digital deception has gotten a nightmarish upgrade, and the line between real
and fabricated blurs with every passing day.</p><p>Companies <a href="https://www.socure.com/news-and-press/socure-releases-multi-layered-ai-defense-system">like Socure </a>are wielding the double-edged sword of artificial intelligence (AI) in the fight
against identity theft. Their latest weapon? DocV, a document verification
solution that boasts the ability to pierce the veil of deepfakes and expose stolen
identities in a blink – all under two seconds. It's a David versus Goliath
scenario on a digital battlefield, with meticulously crafted AI on both sides.</p><p>But is this a fight AI
can truly win against itself? Can a technology designed to mimic and manipulate
be effectively countered by its own creation? The answer lies in understanding
the cunning of both sides.</p><p>On the one hand,
fraudsters <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/deepfakes-take-center-stage-in-financial-fraud/">have become Picassos of the digital realm</a>. They wield generative AI
tools to craft hyper-realistic deepfakes – not just faces, but entire
identities complete with fabricated documents and stolen personal information
(PII). These deepfakes are so convincing that they can bypass even the most
vigilant human eye, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/analysis/nearly-50-of-companies-targeted-by-ai-deepfakes-mastercard-report-reveals/">let alone legacy biometric and template-based security
systems</a>.</p><p>Socure, however, takes a
different approach. Instead of brute force pattern-matching, they've trained
their AI using a vast library of self-generated deepfakes. It's a sort of
inoculation – exposing their system to the very virus it's designed to combat.
By ingesting thousands of meticulously crafted deepfakes encompassing a
dizzying array of ethnicities, ages, and body types, Socure's AI learns to
recognize the subtle tells, the uncanny valley imperfections that betray the
artificial hand behind the mask. It's a constant game of chess: anticipating and adapting to the ever-shifting tactics of fraudsters.</p><p>The battleground extends
beyond faces and documents. Barcodes, once a reliable source of verification,
are now susceptible to manipulation. Here, too, Socure employs AI to identify
anomalies – inconsistencies in encoding or even the telltale signs of a machine-generated
barcode. It's a forensic analysis on a microscopic level, a detective story
unfolding in the digital realm.</p><p>But Socure's ambitions
go beyond mere document verification. They delve into the murky world of
identity graphs, analyzing the connections and correlations between seemingly
disparate pieces of information. This allows them to paint a holistic picture
of the person behind the ID, identifying suspicious patterns or red flags that
might otherwise go unnoticed. It's a web of trust and deceit laid bare, a map
that exposes the fraudulent footprints masquerading as legitimate identities.</p><p>The implications of this
AI arms race <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/the-dark-side-of-ai-how-taylor-swift-deepfakes-reveal-a-major-threat-to-banking-security/">extend far beyond the realm of finance</a>. Age verification for
online gaming, driver verification for ride-sharing services – the potential
applications are vast. It's a future where the very essence of who we are online
hinges on the ability of AI to discern truth from meticulously crafted lies.</p><p>Yet, a nagging question
remains. As AI becomes more sophisticated on both sides of the fence, can we
ever truly declare victory? Is this an endless duel destined to escalate with
each iteration? The answer, perhaps, lies not just in the technology itself,
but in the way we wield it.</p><p>Socure's success hinges
on transparency and continuous improvement. By making their AI development
process open for scrutiny, they build trust and invite collaboration. The fight
against deepfakes isn't a solitary endeavor; it requires a united front, a community
of experts constantly refining and updating the tools at our disposal.</p><p>The digital age has
ushered in an era of unprecedented convenience, but it has also opened doors
for those who seek to exploit its vulnerabilities. The battle against deepfakes
is a stark reminder that the line between progress and peril is razor-thin. But
as long as we leverage the power of AI not just for profit, but for the greater
good, we might just hold the edge in this never-ending game of digital
deception.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
</channel></rss>