<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<description>Neutral and Authentic News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:39:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cropped-Dark_CP_Symbol-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>AI Integration Propels Shanghai Schools to Global Recognition</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-integration-shanghai-schools-to-global/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emman Omwanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shanghai Schools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shanghai has become a model region in educational fields. This role is mostly related to the accomplishments of Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi. The school has been widely recognized for its innovative, technology-equipped teaching approach alongside its broad range of education subjects, setting a new bar in China and the rest of the world in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Shanghai has become a model region in educational fields. This role is mostly related to the accomplishments of Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi. The school has been widely recognized for its innovative, technology-equipped teaching approach alongside its broad range of education subjects, setting a new bar in China and the rest of the world in the field of educational standards.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Shanghai&#8217;s Dulwich College Puxi leads with innovative education</h2>



<p>The new campus of Dulwich College Shanghai, Puxi, which became operational in 2016, strives to serve the rapidly growing population in that area. The school had a commendable event. With a batch of learners from IB programs who made an excellent passage through the International Baccalaureate (IB) diplomas, the first graduation focused on learners&#8217; academic prowess unfazed by pressure. Most graduates have been rated the second-best IB School in China, and they have an average score of 37.7, which makes them capable of competing with other schools worldwide.</p>



<p>This success testifies to the school&#8217;s determination to uphold traditional academic techniques and willingness to follow the times. Dulwich Puxi pushes the limits of adopting AI and other state-of-the-art innovations in its student body. </p>



<p>Among the other schools, it was the first to adopt tools like the Alex Qbot chatbot and Century Tech learning platforms, which set a precedent for using advanced resources to enhance educational outcomes.</p>



<p>Artificially Intelligent Instruction and Innovation (AIAI) is one of the courses available among students in the high school years 10 to 11. Design Engineer Construction (DEC) is a core course for Grade 8 students. These courses, which aim to empower students with skills to explore and make sense of the multi-dimensional surface of technology, have been designed.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Transformational education at Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi</h2>



<p>The fundamental goal of extending the technological role in resolving actual world duplicities is at Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi. A noteworthy project is the upcoming Planet Hack hackathon, which was jointly organized by ANU and the college . This occasion is a platform for the students to combine  advanced environmental problems via research, ideas, and prototype designs that demonstrate how they have translated what they learned in the class into practical scenarios.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the school has been celebrated for its internationalism on a national and global level. Dulwich Puxi has been nominated for the 2024 Tes Awards for Best Use of Technology, which bears testimony to the school&#8217;s ability to ensure integrated tech usage in the classroom environment.</p>



<p>In the co-curricular club, students are encouraged to take part in sporting activities, music, and community work, which surface the endorphin hormone. Programs like the Duke of Edinburgh International Award and The Ignite: Swiss students are grateful for this program because it provides ample training for modern survival rather than just being academically good.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi&#8217;s vision for future education</h2>



<p>Paving the way for the rest, Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi led the way in implementing the digital future transformation model. Today&#8217;s existence proves that the concept is no longer just a theory but an actual reality.</p>



<p>The college provides instruction that encourages students&#8217; superior reasoning and problem-solving skills. Moreover, combining inventive approaches in technology will make the school effective in providing the necessary educational needs of its learners in the future. </p>



<p>The upcoming conference on The Future of Education, which will cover Dulwich Puxi, Dehong Shanghai, and Dulwich Pudong, will allow one to learn much about this leading educational institution.</p>



<p>In an era where things are quickly changing, and education is becoming more accessible, Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi leads the way by preparing their future generation to be the leaders who will lead them through bright and glorious days ahead.</p>



<p>News sourced from <a href="https://www.smartshanghai.com/articles/education/aitech-shanghai-education-dulwich-is-innovating" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Smart Shanghai</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Dulwich_College_Shanghai_Puxis_vision_for_future_educa_0-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Dulwich_College_Shanghai_Puxis_vision_for_future_educa_0-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Version of Mark Zuckerberg Showcased on YouTube: An Unusual Comparison</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-version-of-mark-zuckerberg-on-youtube/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Glory Kaburu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Trending News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To compare the AI version of Mark Zuckerberg from a YouTube perspective, the channel Breaking Even made a video entitled Artificial Intelligence of Mark Zuckerberg: What is the difference? This has led to discussion from people views about the similarities and differences between the two personalities of Mark Zuckerberg, an AI one, and the real [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To compare the AI version of Mark Zuckerberg from a YouTube perspective, the channel Breaking Even made a video entitled Artificial Intelligence of Mark Zuckerberg: What is the difference? This has led to discussion from people views about the similarities and differences between the two personalities of Mark Zuckerberg, an AI one, and the real one of Meta Platforms Inc. The video consists of a simulation of Zuckerberg, who interacts with the audience on various topics, e.g., producing threads of fictitious projects or taking part in different games like Rapid Fire and 2 Truths 1 Lie.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Performance of the AI Zuckerberg&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The audience of the video clearly recognized this because the presentation of this video took another direction. Zuckerberg was in some posture, which could have been plausibly the sitting or standing position, which made him visually distinct from the real Zuckerberg. However, despite efforts to make the AI sound more human in the blinking part, there were striking differences in its mannerisms in general. Nevertheless, the voice mimicry was very accurate when it came to Zuckerberg&#8217;s unique voice pattern in terms of pitch and intonation. Still, the AI&#8217;s response lacked some necessary level of understanding. </p>



<p>To exemplify, in the challenge that required to describe Meta on the thread and 1 hashtag in 20 seconds using merely an emoji, AI Zuckerberg clearly and succinctly answered that meta globe emoji is shaping up the social ties of the future in the metaverse. Join us at it thumbs-up emoji. However, this type of reply highlighted the common,</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cryptocurrency market insights&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Digital awareness also extends to cryptocurrency interactions, where investors have observed major differences in market movement. As current evidence shows, large-scale acquirers, often called crypto whales, are on the verge of re-entering the market due to growing interest. They are also presumed to be aggressively stocking up with a medium—to long-term view, solely presuming that Bitcoin will surely pass the $100k mark in 2024. This group is speculated to be aggressively stocking up with a medium to long-term view, solely presuming that Bitcoin will surge past the $100k mark in 2024.</p>



<p>The insights were top-notch, and Benzinga has recently launched a limited promotional push with a $7.95 fee that gives access to superior cryptocurrency research, stock tips, and crypto-related articles. This decision is made while traditional cryptocurrency investment progression is being seen to be limited after bull runs in 2020 and 2021.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Technology and personality: Film the thin red line.</h2>



<p>The video and the way it is becoming popular appeal to the prospect of artificial media sharing people’s personal experiences. While AI technologies have come to the extent where authentic-sounding conversations and personalized interactions can substitute human ones, a distinct difference is still obvious, especially in terms of tons of imponderability remaining in human relationships, such as genuine emotions, spontaneous attitudes, and so on.</p>



<p>The act of the AI Zuckerberg hanging out in the TechnoCard game 2 Truths 1 Lie shows such a gap. Unlike natural human interaction, the method of interacting with the game seemed quite similar to how a chatbot will process such prompts and respond, leading with a reply of Okay, 2 Truths, and a Lie, here we go, which could only be attested to the computer program. With the development of AI, human and machine figures both continue to have boundaries that are more and more indistinct while at the same time becoming more exciting to see.</p>



<p> Furthermore, artificial intelligence is now used in media platforms, such as YouTube. Because AI plays a major role in entertainment and communication, we are called to think about its future role in every aspect of our lives, including posing questions about authenticity, privacy, and human interaction in the age of digitalization. However, while investors are noticing the crypto market&#8217;s growth, they still introduce this technology to the financial market and try to predict players&#8217; actions in the future.</p>



<p>This article originally appeared in <a href="https://www.benzinga.com/news/24/04/38350350/ai-mark-zuckerberg-more-robotic-than-real-life-version-have-a-quick-peek-and-decide-for-yourself" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Benzinga</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_AI_Version_of_Mark_Zuckerberg_Showcased_on_YouTube_An_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_AI_Version_of_Mark_Zuckerberg_Showcased_on_YouTube_An_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Salvador Dal Museum Unveils AI-Powered Lobster Telephone</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-salvador-museum-unveils-ai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brenda Kanana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Innovators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI Salvador Dal Museum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI-Powered Lobster Telephone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dal Museum in Florida has presented an exhibition with an introduction to artificial intelligence, which now displays a holographic of the real-life person of Salvador. The historical touches are not limited to the exhibition of art pieces alone, one is also able to engage in conversation with a digital version of the artist through a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Dal Museum in Florida has presented an exhibition with an introduction to artificial intelligence, which now displays a holographic of the real-life person of Salvador. The historical touches are not limited to the exhibition of art pieces alone, one is also able to engage in conversation with a digital version of the artist through a replica of his famous &#8220;Lobster Telephone&#8221; sculpture.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Interactive experience</h2>



<p>This year, Museum guests will have a special chance to conduct a communication with an AI version of Salvador Dal. Thanks to the recreation, they can immerse themselves in the life and art of the mysterious artist. Participants can ask questions about The Lobster Phone, whether it be about Dal&#8217;s paintings or prints or advice about love and surrealism.</p>



<p>The AI Dal, which is a product of partnership between Goodby Silverstein &amp; Partners and the Dal Museum, exhibits cutting-edge artificial intelligence and allows for a virtual conversation with the revered surrealist painter. The robo-Dal robot powered by a large language model and implemented with Dal&#8217;s voice in it is expected to be a highly interactive and enjoyable experience for the museum visitors.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Talking to the AI Dal</h2>



<p>Visitors will be able to interact with the AI Dal by speaking to the receiver of the lobster telephone sculpture. The thorough inquiry will allow them to understand whether the Dal would work for them for pieces of paintings, prints, or even to get advice on different things. In its response, AI Dal is characterized by descriptions that are as overblown as the human Dal&#8217;s approach, sometimes discussing themes, such as surrealism, dreams and the human experience.</p>



<p>The emergence of AI counterparts of well-known persons opens unlimited opportunities for meetings and learning, while at the same time, it causes doubts about the ethical aspects of the technology. The concept of consent and how to save someone&#8217;s legacy after their death started questioning the digital realm. On the other hand, enthusiasts view digitization of artists&#8217; likenesses, such as Dal, as the best method through which people can get to understand more about their work, and more so to preserve their legacy in the digital age.</p>



<p>As technology progresses, the AI capability of creating the likeness of historical characters and celebrities is also expected to become popular. However, this is a double-edged sword, it can stimulate education and leisure, but the world needs to take into account ethical issues. Going ahead, the major task for the artist and the organization will be to navigate these hurdles with care and ethics so that the artists’ integrity is maintained and the individuals in the era will be treated with respect.</p>



<p>This article first appeared on the ASK DALI<a href="https://youtu.be/4e-3fq5y6A4?si=FyxhMgOQrauMMugq" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> YouTube video</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Dal_Museum_in_Florida_has_presented_an_exhibition_with_0-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Dal_Museum_in_Florida_has_presented_an_exhibition_with_0-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Windraces and Purdue University Announce AI Aviation Center</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/windraces-purdue-announce-ai-aviation-center/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aamir Sheikh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Innovators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI Aviation Center]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Windracers has partnered with Perdue University to establish the world’s first center for AI for aviation. Windracers is a UK-based cargo vehicle operator that provides service globally and is a leader in the autonomous air transportation industry. The Center on AI for Digital, Autonomous, and Augmented Aviation (AIDA3) was announced recently, which is a major [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Windracers has partnered with Perdue University to establish the world’s first center for AI for aviation. Windracers is a UK-based cargo vehicle operator that provides service globally and is a leader in the autonomous air transportation industry. The Center on AI for Digital, Autonomous, and Augmented Aviation (AIDA3) was announced recently, which is a major move for advancing progress on technologies related to unmanned aerial vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI Aviation Center AIDA3</h2>



<p>Purdue University is working on making aerial transportation systems safe, scalable, and efficient and has launched a center for integrating artificial intelligence and machine learning into them. The executive vice president for research at Perdue, Karen Plaut, said</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“Purdue is very proud to partner with Windracers because AIDA3 is focused on solving pressing societal needs.”</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>He also said,&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“What we develop in the laboratory will be designed to make a difference when put into real-world practice. Purdue’s research strengths and success in aviation and AI — linked with Windracers’ expertise in transportation of the future — makes for a powerful innovation engine.”</em></p>
<cite>Source: Purdue University.</cite></blockquote>



<p>According to the university, AIDA3 will help in providing innovative solutions for UAVs and other autonomous vehicle systems, and their focus will be on scaling up these solutions as the demand grows in the industry.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From the crossroads to the smart crossroads of America</h2>



<p>On the project page of Purdue’s website, the university says that Indiana is considered the crossroads of America, and they are striving to make it the smart crossroads of America. As according to estimates, over 1 million commercial <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-drones-revolutionize-crop-harvesting/" data-type="post" data-id="378417">UAVs</a> will be flying across the US performing more duties than just delivering packages by 2027. These unmanned systems will be used in fighting wildfires, defense, humanitarian services, and also emergency services.</p>



<p>It is due to this demand, which is expected in the near future, that the university has launched the center. Whatever smart solution will be developed in the center will be put to the test in real life. Mentioning AIDA3 as the first major progress of Purdue’s Institute for Physical Artificial Intelligence (IPAI), Sabine Brunswicker, director of the center, said,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“With IPAI, we focus on practical innovations that bring together the ‘bytes of AI’ and the ‘atoms of what we grow, make and move,’ and AIDA3 will make this reality in the realm of aviation transportation. We are thrilled to be undertaking this journey with our partners at Windracers.”</em></p>
<cite>Source: Purdue University.</cite></blockquote>



<p>The combination of Windracers and Perdue is a match well made, as Windracers is a champion of low-cost logistic solutions and will provide a real-life experience that they gained from their business operations based on their patented autopilot system for the Royal Navy, British Antarctic Survey, and Royal Mail. While Perdue boasts an extensive research profile across many fields of engineering, science, and arts. Windracers will also bring two of their long-range, fixed-wing UAVs to support the research and development work of AIDA3.</p>



<p>The university&#8217;s project page can be seen <a href="https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2024/Q2/purdue-launches-worlds-first-center-pioneering-use-of-ai-to-innovate-tomorrows-modes-of-autonomous-aviation-transportation.html" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/7769f65e-8ad7-4aea-a4fd-69094dd7f004-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/7769f65e-8ad7-4aea-a4fd-69094dd7f004-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surveillance Law, signed by Biden Stirring Privacy and Security Debates</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/surveillance-law-biden-stir-privacy-concern/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emman Omwanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surveillance Law]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden enacted the continuation and amendment of Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA), up to the addition of two years to American surveillance practice. While true supporters described the legislation as good in the hour of need, there were quite a few challengers to it, even from the group of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>President Joe <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/cryptocurrency-policies-a-comparative/">Biden</a> enacted the continuation and amendment of Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA), up to the addition of two years to American surveillance practice. While true supporters described the legislation as good in the hour of need, there were quite a few challengers to it, even from the group of privacy advocates and some of the politicians who believed it could go against Americans&#8217; basic rights.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">New surveillance law, Privacy, and Security Concerns</h2>



<p>The bill, Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act, has received overwhelming support from bipartisan representatives, Sullivan added as a National Security Adviser. It is hoped that it will provide a further constitutional check on the use of Section 702 to prevent national security risks. </p>



<p>Such an inheritance gives rise to all intelligence and law enforcement agencies, such as the NSA, the FBI, and the CIA, being able to examine foreign communications without a warrant, which some suppose could eventually lead to direct surveillance of U.S. citizens. Thus, this raises the concern of privacy and security.</p>



<p>A distinct divide between the two prominent factors of national security and personal privacy rights was well-illustrated by a legislative process. Although the bill drew widely spread backing mainly because it served as a means to fight terrorism and protect national security, opponents <a href="https://twitter.com/LizaGoitein/status/1781546937675657392" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">claimed</a> that the bill had the possibility of abusing the powers of surveillance activities. The most notable among the critics was Elizabeth Goitein from the Brennan Center for Justice, who found the bill&#8217;s nominal reform inadequate for defending civil rights.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It’s over (for now). A majority of senators caved to the fearmongering and bush league tactics of the administration and surveillance hawks in Congress, and they sold out Americans’ civil liberties. Section 702 has been reauthorized, not just without any meaningful reforms… 1/10</p>&mdash; Elizabeth Goitein (@LizaGoitein) <a href="https://twitter.com/LizaGoitein/status/1781546937675657392?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 20, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Impacts of the Law on Internet Service Providers&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The bill <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/house-votes-renew-fisa-spying-tool-earlier-republican-revolt-rcna147557" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">passed</a> the House; nonetheless, it generated dispute; an amendment that asked security agencies to obtain a warrant for internet-based surveillance occasionally failed in the House. This move was a visible reflection of the ever-growing challenges that must be overcome to achieve the right balance between the need for safety and privacy.</p>



<p>As the implications of Internet service providers and privacy regulations continue to evolve, the need for robust surveillance policies and rigorous implementation of these safeguards becomes increasingly prominent. Under Section 702 renewal, the U.S. intelligence agencies may also demand providers like Google or Verizon to display internet users’ data for investigative purposes, thus expanding data collection techniques from their national criteria.</p>



<p>This capability raises concerns for consumer rights activists, who fear that the new law would require many internet service providers whose duties are unclear to pivot to government spying.</p>



<p>For this reason, the White House says that this very specific act, the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act, has included the smartest and most powerful set of changes concerning oversight, privacy, and civil liberties. These initiatives are designed to balance the rising demand for intelligence with the desire to respect individual privacy rights.</p>



<p>After the law is implemented, discussions on the right balance between national security and privacy will continue, raising several areas of concern like policy, governance, and citizen rights. This continuing dialogue is highly likely to impact the making of laws and, as a result, judicial decisions related to privacy in the United States.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Surveillance_Law_signed_in_usa_Stirring_Privacy_and_Se_0-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Surveillance_Law_signed_in_usa_Stirring_Privacy_and_Se_0-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardano Price Prediction 2024-2033: Is ADA a good investment?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/cardano-price-prediction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wamugoir Annh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto Price Predictions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency trading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=45038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cardano Price Predictions 2024-2033 Cardano stands out as a project with remarkable potential beyond its role as a tradable asset. Rooted in scholarly peer-reviewed research, it has cultivated a robust community over time. Here, we delve into the essence of Cardano and offer a projection for the future value of ADA. How Much is ADA [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Predictions 2024-2033</h4>



<ul>
<li><a href="#Cardano ADA Price Prediction 2024">Cardano Price Prediction 2024 &#8211; up to</a><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=45038&amp;action=edit#Cardano%20ADA%20Price%20Prediction%202024"> $1.02</a></li>



<li><a href="#Cardano-Price-Prediction-2027" data-type="internal" data-id="#Cardano-Price-Prediction-2027">Cardano Price Prediction 2027 &#8211; up to </a><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=45038&amp;action=edit#Cardano-Price-Prediction-2027">$3.15</a></li>



<li><a href="#Cardano-Price-Prediction-2030" data-type="internal" data-id="#Cardano-Price-Prediction-2030">Cardano Price Prediction 2030 &#8211; up to </a><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=45038&amp;action=edit#Cardano-Price-Prediction-2030">$10.03</a></li>



<li><a href="#Cardano-ADA-Price-Prediction-2033" data-type="internal" data-id="#Cardano-ADA-Price-Prediction-2033">Cardano Price Prediction 2033 &#8211; up to </a><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=45038&amp;action=edit#Cardano-ADA-Price-Prediction-2033">$31.67</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Cardano stands out as a project with remarkable potential beyond its role as a tradable asset. Rooted in scholarly peer-reviewed research, it has cultivated a robust community over time. Here, we delve into the essence of Cardano and offer a projection for the future value of ADA.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Much is ADA Worth?</h2>



<p><strong>Cardano price today</strong> is $0.511, with a 24-hour trading volume of $378,570,443. Cardano is up 0.72% in the last 24 hours. The current CoinMarketCap ranking is #10, with a market cap of $18,212,596,113 USD. It has a circulating supply of 35,625,937,071 ADA coins and a max. supply of 45,000,000,000 ADA coins.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Analysis: ADA Consolidates Upwards with a $0.51. Will Bullish pressure mount more pressure?</h2>



<ul>
<li>Cardano price analysis shows an uptrend</li>



<li>Support for ADA/USD is present at $0.4916</li>



<li>Resistance ADA/USD is present at $0.5152</li>
</ul>



<p>The digital asset has seen a recent uptrend in the last 24 hours, with a high gain of 0.72%. ADA is currently trading at $0.5104. Cardano price analysis shows an uptrend as the coin trades above the $0.5 support level.  ADA/USD faces rejection at $0.52, but a break above this could lead to a bullish target of $0.55 resistance level. The support level to watch for ADA/USD is $0.5, and if bearish pressure pushes the coin below this level, further support can be found at $0.45.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Analysis: ADA Moves into a Narrow Consolidation Zone on a Daily Chart</h3>



<p>On the 24-hour candlestick chart for Cardano price analysis, the price can be seen forming an uptrend after a distinct decline in yesterday&#8217;s market. The uptrend has led ADA/USD to move into a narrow consolidation zone between the $0.5152 resistance level and the $0.4916 support level. Currently, the Relative Strength Index (RSI) for Cardano is at 33.76, indicating that ADA may be nearing oversold levels and potentially poised for a bullish breakout.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/qzQ0bojLCfXpjHQblC4NoCZmZ1hefHOVe5TSL0Gfj9qJijXDEF1vTq2ePi7vMWpEzcQnJE-vv13sowNNmlYkxCtBKibtWbeFUUTwyk6EGwjE6qam-JBKb6aepb72FRtOJf1kSGssjry8VEGM47yGnMQ" alt="" /></figure>



<p>ADA/USD 1-day price chart By <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/HPO3y1cf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></p>



<p>The moving averages (MAs) on the daily chart for ADA/USD show that the 50-day MA is below the 100-day MA, indicating a bearish sentiment in the short term. However, if ADA breaks above $0.51resistance, it could lead to further upward momentum and potentially a bullish crossover of the MAs. The Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD) for Cardano shows a bearish crossover, indicating that the coin may see some downward pressure in the short term.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano 4-hour Price Chart: Recent Updates</h3>



<p>The 4-hour timeframe for the Cardano price analysis gives the lead to the buyers as well, as the price has been improving since the start of the trading session, following yesterday’s bearish lead. Overall, the bulls have been in the lead since the start of today, with some high spikes also recorded. The current scenario has been quite favorable for the bulls as they have cornered bears successfully.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/Rap5zDp7sFg5yXJtjczBE4aLoMPAlcC3k6kPxRcuuwwEwysrgPxALcoB8dPQU5D_HylwOa4svxJyuDhMGWj53A3NFHqU65BISgwk0VpAaeasFBmSSnIbMaLMsvjN9aL4lZSYDWhE6k0ixK9phWxmR_Y" alt="" /></figure>



<p>ADA/USD 4-hour price chart By <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/M4L1RQTG/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></p>



<p>The RSI indicator has been on an uptrend for the last few hours and has now reached an index of 51.92; it may push northward in the upcoming trading hours to touch overbought levels.  The MACD chart for ADA/USD shows a bullish crossover, as the signal line crosses above the MACD line, indicating bullish momentum in the short term.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Analysis Conclusion</h3>



<p>Cardano price analysis shows that ADA/USD is in a bullish trend, with a price struggling to gain a head. However, the coin faces some downward pressure in the short term and should be monitored for any signs of bearish reversal.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is Cardano a Good Investment?</h3>



<p>Cardano has made significant strides in the blockchain domain, notably integrating smart contract capabilities, enhancing its appeal for various applications from decentralized finance (DeFi) to non-fungible tokens (NFTs). This advancement underscores Cardano&#8217;s dedication to creating a scalable and secure proof-of-stake (PoS) ecosystem. </p>



<p>For investors, the allure of Cardano (ADA) lies in its technological progress and the potential for broad adoption. The platform&#8217;s ongoing developments and expanding ecosystem indicate a bright future. Cardano offers a strong investment proposition rooted in rigorous scientific research and diverse use cases, suggesting its viability for sustained growth.&nbsp;Our Cardano price prediction section will examine&nbsp;the potential ROI for investors over the coming years.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Recent News/Updates</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Sees Surge in Plutus V2 Contracts Amid Market Stabilization</h2>



<p>Cardano is currently <a href="https://lookerstudio.google.com/u/0/reporting/3136c55b-635e-4f46-8e4b-b8ab54f2d460/page/p_a6behjl6oc" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">experiencing</a> a notable increase in the adoption of its Plutus V2 smart contracts amid general market stabilization. As of April 14, the total number of Plutus scripts recorded was 41,743, a significant rise from earlier in the month. This includes both versions, Plutus V1 and Plutus V2, with the latter seeing a sharper spike in usage.</p>



<p>While the Plutus V1 contracts have seen only a slight increase, the V2 contracts have surged, indicating a robust preference for the newer, more advanced system. Specifically, April has seen the introduction of 1,211 new Plutus contracts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cardano shows signs of potential upward movement if market conditions improve, underlining the continuing development and adoption of its smart contract technology. This growth in Plutus V2 contracts is a positive signal for the network&#8217;s ongoing evolution and maturity.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2024-2033</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Price Predictions By Cryptopolitan&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Cardano (ADA) has undergone significant volatility throughout the year, and the recent price uptick has bolstered investor sentiment, with projections for ADA showing a bullish outlook. Against this dynamic financial landscape, we shall delve into an analysis of Cardano’s price trajectory from 2024 through 2033.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/6fC2HqS8qER6wETX_v2qCq5JrSLB9r-ZIuBhnuMDx4tU7eWr7Z24Ob5UAmE5pAUZoMSFUqU7uUeDZiAjaG7dN1V_XYlqX2OwUO31zIYjaeeJRFyMsZrJT0-UM42IIKTCIPqBD_ILDw3LSK76v3GZxT8" alt="" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td>Year</td><td>Minimum</td><td>Average</td><td>Maximum</td></tr><tr><td>2024</td><td>$0.8339</td><td>$0.8671</td><td>$1.02</td></tr><tr><td>2025</td><td>$1.24</td><td>$1.27</td><td>$1.47</td></tr><tr><td>2026</td><td>$1.83</td><td>$1.88</td><td>$2.14</td></tr><tr><td>2027</td><td>$2.69</td><td>$2.76</td><td>$3.15</td></tr><tr><td>2028</td><td>$3.95</td><td>$4.06</td><td>$4.55</td></tr><tr><td>2029</td><td>$5.86</td><td>$6.07</td><td>$6.91</td></tr><tr><td>2030</td><td>$8.51</td><td>$8.82</td><td>$10.03</td></tr><tr><td>2031</td><td>$12.58</td><td>$12.94</td><td>$14.51</td></tr><tr><td>2032</td><td>$17.97</td><td>$18.61</td><td>$21.35</td></tr><tr><td>2033</td><td>$26.11</td><td>$27.05</td><td>$31.67</td></tr></tbody></table><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Cardano price prediction</figcaption></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2024</h4>



<p>Cryptocurrency experts are ready to announce their forecast for the Cardano price in 2024. The minimum trading cost might be $0.8339, while the maximum might reach $1.02 during this month. On average, it is expected that the value of ADA might be around $0.8671.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2025</h4>



<p>Cardano’s price forecast for 2025 anticipates a minimum price of $1.24 for Cardano (ADA), with an average price of $1.27 and a maximum price of $1.47. This suggests a bullish trend continuing into the year, with ADA potentially seeing significant gains.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2026</h4>



<p>Cryptocurrency experts have carefully analyzed the range of ADA prices throughout 2026. Their forecast is the following: the maximum trading value of Cardano will be around $2.14, with a possibility of dropping to a minimum of $1.83. The average cost will be $1.88.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2027</h4>



<p>In 2027, Cardano price prediction suggests Cardano could reach new heights, with the minimum price forecasted at $2.69, the average price expected to be around $2.76, and the maximum price potentially hitting $3.15.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2028</h4>



<p>After the analysis of the prices of Cardano in previous years, it is assumed that in 2028, the minimum price of&nbsp; ADA will be around $3.95. The maximum expected ADA price may be around $4.55. On average, the trading price might be $4.06 in 2028.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2029</h4>



<p>In 2029, Cardano’s price prediction indicates a potential maximum price of $6.91, with a minimum price of $5.86 and an average price of $6.07. These projections suggest significant growth potential and continued investor interest in ADA.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2030</h4>



<p>As per the forecast price and technical analysis, In 2030 the price of Cardano is predicted to reach at a minimum level of $8.51. The ADA price can reach a maximum level of $10.03 with the average trading price of $8.82.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2031</h4>



<p>Based on the technical analysis by cryptocurrency experts regarding the prices of Cardano, in 2031, ADA is expected to have the following minimum and maximum prices: about $12.58 and $14.51, respectively. The average expected trading cost is $12.94.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2032</h4>



<p>Cardano price is forecast to reach a lowest possible level of $17.97 in 2032. As per our findings, the ADA price could reach a maximum possible level of $21.35 with the average forecast price of $18.61.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction 2033</h4>



<p>The price of Cardano is predicted to reach at a minimum level of $26.11 in 2033. The Cardano price can reach a maximum level of $31.67 with the average price of $27.05 throughout 2033.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ADA Price Prediction by Wallet Investor</h2>



<p>The value of ADA is expected to significantly plummet over the next year, according to Wallet Investor&#8217;s forecast, possibly falling as low as $0.496. Its long-term investment potential is seen in a negative light by this stance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ADA Price Prediction by Technewsleader</h2>



<p>According to Technewsleader&#8217;s projections, ADA might trade between $1.13 and $1.30 in 2025 and have a value of $0.8458 in 2024. According to their technical analysis, ADA is expected to have a bullish run that is mostly sustained, peaking at $2.97 in 2027, $6.17 in 2029, and $29.98 in 2033.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ADA Price Prediction by Digitalcoinprice<strong>&nbsp;</strong></h3>



<p>Digitalcoinprice anticipates considerable&nbsp;future price&nbsp;growth for Cardano (ADA) in the years to come. Their projections show ADA reaching $1.25 by the end of 2024, climbing to $2.07 by 2026, and further increasing to $2.61 by 2028.&nbsp; The average price for 2029 is predicted at $3.12. By 2031, ADA could range between $5.55 and $5.92. In 2033, the price might surpass $10, reaching a maximum price of $11.07.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price Prediction By Industry Experts</h2>



<p>The outlook for Cardano (ADA) in 2024 is increasingly optimistic as the cryptocurrency experiences significant growth, with its price surging by about 50% this year amid expanding adoption and a notable increase in the Total Value Locked (TVL) on its DeFi platforms. Currently, ADA is valued at $0.368, having appreciated over 4.6% in the last week. Analysts are forecasting a substantial rise for ADA in 2024.</p>



<p>Ali Martinez, a well-regarded analyst, has observed that Cardano&#8217;s present consolidation phase closely resembles the pattern from 2018 to 2020. If this trend continues, ADA might maintain its consolidation until July of the next year. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Cardano?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#Cardano</a>&#39;s current consolidation trend eerily mirrors the 2018-2020 phase!<br><br>🔴 If history repeats, <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24ADA&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$ADA</a> could stay in this consolidation phase until July 2024.<br><br>🟢 Barring unforeseen events like the COVID-19 crash, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ADA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#ADA</a> could break out as soon as December! 🚀 <a href="https://t.co/CNsulywN5z" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/CNsulywN5z</a></p>&mdash; Ali (@ali_charts) <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1712453816497672274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">October 12, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>However, Martinez anticipates a potential breakout as early as December, predicting that this consolidation could propel ADA towards the $10 mark in 2024. The surge in Cardano’s TVL in its DeFi ecosystem underscores this bullish sentiment, with <a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Cardano?currency=ADA" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">DeFiLlama</a> reporting a jump from under 200 million ADA at the year&#8217;s start to 682 million ADA.</p>



<p>The ecosystem&#8217;s growth is further evidenced by significant increases in TVL for projects like Indigo, a collateralized debt protocol, and Minswap, a decentralized exchange, each surpassing the $50 million mark in TVL due to growing adoption. Additionally, Cardano continues to lead in development activity, outpacing other significant projects like Polkadot ($DOT) and Kusama ($KSM), reinforcing its position at the forefront of blockchain innovation.</p>



<p>Lucid, another cryptocurrency analyst, has set an even more ambitious target, suggesting ADA could reach $30 next year, a potential increase of over 9,000% from its current price. This prediction hinges on the anticipation of the cryptocurrency market’s total capitalization exceeding $10 trillion, driven by global factors acting as catalysts for growth.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24ADA&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$ADA</a> is going to $30!👑<br><br>Bitcoin proved to the whole world that a $1 Trillion market cap is attainable! Even Ethereum with all its issues hit $500 billion! With inflation the crypto market as a whole will be worth $10 Trillion within the decade! Cardano is going for the 100x!👻🔱</p>&mdash; Lucid (@LucidCiC) <a href="https://twitter.com/LucidCiC/status/1719312590554517890?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">October 31, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>FieryTrading offers an even more optimistic forecast, projecting an increase of over 10,000% within the next two years. This prediction is based on ADA&#8217;s consistent upward trajectory within a parallel channel, indicating potential for the price to hit the $35 mark eventually. Despite these long-term bullish predictions, short-term forecasts remain moderately optimistic.</p>



<p>Institutional interest in Cardano also seems to be on the rise, as evidenced by <a href="https://blog.coinshares.com/volume-157-digital-asset-fund-flows-weekly-report-a8be1d5b3f85" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">data</a> from CoinShares’ latest Digital Asset Fund Flows report. Last week, Cardano-based investment products attracted over $800,000 in inflows, bringing their year-to-date total to $8 million. This institutional backing further solidifies the positive outlook for ADA in the near and extended future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Price History </h2>



<p>To understand the Cardano Price Forecast, it is imperative to look at the Cardano price movements historically.</p>



<p>Before its launch in 2017, ADA coins were already on sale as far back as 2015, and sales continued till January 2017, after which it was launched. Its first rise in price was in January 2018, when it reached a record high of $1.31 due to the cryptocurrency rally.</p>



<p>The price soon dropped to $0.15 by April, and by the end of the year, it was worth $0.04. it was worth only around $0.10 in 2019 and started increasing again in late 2020, finishing the year at $0.19.</p>



<p>The crypto rally at the beginning of 2021 had seen the value of Cardano cryptocurrency increase greatly, reaching recordord high of $1.49 by February 27, 2021. But, this was just the start, and ADA prices kept increasing.</p>



<p>Later, in May, a price of<strong> $2.46 was reached by ADA</strong>, and this was an all-time high. Thereafter, it continued to maintain its price within the range of $1.20 – $2.</p>



<p>On September 2, 2021, the Cardano (ADA) price reached a new ATH or <strong>all-time high at $3.10</strong> and has been the <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/best-crypto-to-buy-now/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best-performing coin in the crypto world</a> along with Solana, Algorand, Luna, and Tezos for the past month, experiencing a bullish trend.</p>



<p>The Cardano price analysis shows negative signs after a brief bullish turnaround. In the meantime, the bulls have lost control of the Cardano market, which could signal new lows for the cryptocurrency. Analysts are optimistic about the fortunes of the market, and ADA could experience a turnaround in 2024 as expected of the entire cryptocurrency market.</p>



<p>Cardano (ADA) has experienced a modest increase in its value, rising by $0.01. This uptick is part of a broader positive trend for ADA, which has seen its price increase by 5.23% over the last week, indicating a strong performance in the short term. Moreover, the past month has been particularly promising for Cardano, as it has registered an 8.16% increase in its price, with an average gain of $0.04 to its value. This steady upward movement suggests growing investor confidence and potential for Cardano in the cryptocurrency market.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on the Cardano (ADA) Ecosystem</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is Cardano?</h3>



<p>Cardano&nbsp;is the habitat for the ADA cryptocurrency, mainly used to send and receive digital funds, making direct transfers fast and possible through cryptography.</p>



<p>More than being a cryptocurrency, it is a technological platform that helps run the financial applications individuals and institutions use worldwide. The platform is being constructed in layers that allow for soft fork upgrades.</p>



<p>Cardano&nbsp;blockchain&nbsp;also runs decentralized applications and services that any third parties do not control. This is the first&nbsp;blockchain&nbsp;project designed by a global team of engineers and can be implemented on mission-critical systems such as aerospace and banking applications.</p>



<p>The Cardano Foundation has also declared the launch of the final version of the&nbsp;<a href="https://bitcoinexchangeguide.com/cardano-launches-latest-version-of-alonzo-testnet-dubbed-alonzo-white/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Alonzo Testnet</a>,&nbsp;which will feature smart contracts on the platform. The new upgrade is termed Alonzo White, and with this release, investors are attracted to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/cardano-founder-tesla-should-accept-ada/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cardano</a>. Along with this, the coin was also added to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/cardano-wins-big-as-grayscale-it-portfolio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Grayscale Trust</a>,&nbsp;and there are plenty of supporters of Cardano like&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/etoro-clients-prefer-cardano/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">eToro</a>.</p>



<p>Owing to the public’s increased interest in Cardano and smart contracts, the organization behind the currency, Input Output Hong Kong, has spun up the&nbsp;<a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/cardano-alonzo-purple-upgrade-imminent-115716725.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Alonzo Purple</a>&nbsp;testnet. The onboarding process has already been initiated, and the testnet will be made live once done.</p>



<p>It was created by Charles Hoskinson, ex-Ethereum&nbsp;Co-Founder, and is considered a third-generation&nbsp;blockchain&nbsp;behind the likes of&nbsp;Bitcoin&nbsp;and&nbsp;Ethereum. It was launched back in 2017 to compete with&nbsp;Ethereum.</p>



<p>The coin took over the number three spot after&nbsp;Ethereum&nbsp;after&nbsp;blockchain&nbsp;technology company IOHK developers of Cardano ADA announced the date for the Alonzo hard fork on the&nbsp;Cardano&nbsp;mainnet.&nbsp;Alonzo became live&nbsp;on the Cardano network on September 13, 2021, which might lead to a surge in Cardano prices.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Projects involving Cardano</h3>



<p>Cardano has been involved directly or indirectly in several projects since its launch. In April 2019, The company behind the Cardano&nbsp;Blockchain, IOHK, also launched Atala, which is an enterprise&nbsp;blockchain&nbsp;framework designed for the Ethiopian government and other African countries. Later on, in September of the same year, Cardano entered into a partnership with the athletic wear company, New Balance, enabling the company to use the blockchain to detect fake footwear.</p>



<p>In 2020, IOHK launched Project Atlas and Project Catalyst. Project Atlas aimed to improve users’ experience on the Cardano platform through service integration and more accessibility to its tools and products. On the other hand, Project Catalyst sought to accelerate community innovation and develop on-chain governance.</p>



<p>Recently, Cardano has partnered with&nbsp;<a href="https://iohk.io/en/blog/posts/2021/06/02/nervos-partnership-to-build-the-first-cross-chain-bridge-with-cardano/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Nervos token</a>&nbsp;and the integration of&nbsp;Marlowe on the Cardano&nbsp;blockchain can come in handy for trading ETFs.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano accelerating in NFT space</h4>



<p>Cardano-based NFTs are quite popular nowadays because of the surge in Ethereum gas fees. The rising congestion and gas fees make the Cardano ecosystem most suited for&nbsp;NFT&nbsp;tokens. Recently, we have seen a lot of partnerships between Cardano and NFT artists.</p>



<p>DJ Paul Oakenfold, a Grammy winner&nbsp;<a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" href="https://edm.com/news/paul-oakenfold-album-cardano-blockchain">EDM artist</a>, has teamed up with Cardano to launch his next album as NFTs. The digital asset album will be based on the Cardano blockchain and is named “Zombie Lobster.”</p>



<p>The plan is to focus on new NFT projects on Cardano; therefore, Starship Universe, an NFT project, deserves special mention. This project is being managed by Alon Shulman, who has partnered with Cardano to release thousands of NFT tokens under this new project.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Cardano Compatible Wallets</h4>



<p>There are available wallets to store your Cardano crypto assets; to do that, you need to have at least one of the following wallets;</p>



<ul>
<li>Binance</li>



<li>Coinbase</li>



<li>Gemini</li>



<li>Kraken</li>



<li>Trezor</li>



<li>Coinsmart</li>



<li>Ledger Nano</li>



<li><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" href="http://Cex.io">Cex.io</a></li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Over and over again, the cryptosphere has proven to be quite subject to speculations and market sentiment (whether positive or negative) &#8211; as made evident by BTC&#8217;s recovery back up to $42k, and ETH at $2.2k. Cardano is currently in a bullish phase, and the current Cardano price predictions are largely positive. Depending on the developments in the crypto market, we could see significant growth in market capitalization and price in 2024. You may buy Cardano ADA tokens at top-tier crypto markets like&nbsp;<a href="https://www.binance.com/en/markets?ref=16863683" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Binance</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.huobi.so/en-us/topic/invited/?invite_code=uvzw3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Huobi global</a>, and Bitfinex.</p>



<p>You must keep in mind that cryptocurrency markets are highly volatile and experience price fluctuations. Hence, before making a Cardano investment, always do your own research. Look at the latest Cardano crypto news, market trends, fundamental analysis, and market capitalization – including expert opinions – before making any decision.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9UQRXH2WNhc" medium="video" width="640" height="360">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9UQRXH2WNhc" />
			<media:title type="plain">Hoskinson on Elon Musk &amp; Twitter</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[The founder of the Cardano proof-of-stake blockchain, Charles Hoskinson opines on Musk’s Twitter takeover and how it should have been done.]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/hoskinson-on-elon-musk-twitter.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cardano2.png" medium="image"  type="image/png" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cardano2.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WEEKLY CRYPTO PRICE ANALYSIS: BTC, ETH, BNB, SOL, XRP, DOGE, And ADA</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/weekly-crypto-price-analysis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wamugoir Annh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptomarket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doge Coin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=462035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Weekly crypto price analysis for major tokens such as Bitcoin( BTC),  Ethereum (ETH), Binance(BNB), Solana(SOL), XRP, Cardano(ADA), and Dogecoin(DOGE) shows a promising outlook for the market. Most digital assets display sideways trend momentum and challenging resistance levels, with slight correction over the past 24-hours. Leading the pack, Bitcoin (BTC) has successfully maintained its position above [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Weekly crypto price analysis for major tokens such as Bitcoin( BTC),  <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/ethereum-eth/">Ethereum</a> (ETH), <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/binance-bnb/">Binance</a>(BNB), Solana(SOL), XRP, <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/cardano-ada/">Cardano</a>(ADA), and <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/dogecoin-doge/">Dogecoin</a>(DOGE) shows a promising outlook for the market. Most digital assets display sideways trend momentum and challenging resistance levels, with slight correction over the past 24-hours.</p>



<p>Leading the pack, <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/bitcoin-price-forecast/">Bitcoin</a> (BTC) has successfully maintained its position above the $66,000 mark, showing signs of a bullish momentum after the Bitcoin Halving. The broader market has mirrored this positive trend, with significant buying interest observed across several key cryptocurrencies.</p>



<p>The broader market has mirrored this positive trend, with significant buying interest observed across several key cryptocurrencies.<a href="https://chicksx.com/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> Crypto exchanges</a> are having a frenzy with cryptocurrency trading.</p>



<p>Ethereum (ETH), holding the title of the second-largest digital currency by market cap, has not been left behind. The past week saw <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ethereum-price-prediction/">Ethereum</a> breach the $3,200 barrier, a bullish signal reinforcing the positive market sentiment. Similarly, <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/binance-coin-price-prediction/">Binance Coin</a> (BNB) has shown remarkable stability, consistently trading above $600 and inching closer to overcoming the $600 resistance mark.</p>



<p>Solana (SOL), known for its efficiency and lower transaction costs, has seen a surge in price, with its price soaring past $150. XRP has also enjoyed a week of gains, climbing by over 4% and trading above $0.53. This upward movement has sparked conversations about its potential to reach the $0.6 mark. <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/cardano-price-prediction/">Cardano</a> has seen a notable surge, with ADA appreciating by more than 7%, while Dogecoin experienced a slight decrease of 4% in the past week.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Bitcoin(BTC)</strong></h2>



<p>Bitcoin (BTC) has shown a bullish trend in the recent weekly price analysis, consistently finding strong support above the $66,000 mark. This solid foundation sets the stage for an anticipated upward movement toward a $70,000 resistance level after Bitcoin halving.</p>



<p>Currently, Bitcoin <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/bitcoin/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">stands</a> at $66,208 after a slight dip from $63,000 levels. Bitcoin’s market capitalization crosses the $1.3 trillion threshold. Over the last week, Bitcoin has witnessed a slight decrease of over 0.24% in value, signaling a sideways trend.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1168" height="599" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-24.png" alt="" class="wp-image-509918" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-24.png 1168w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-24-300x154.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-24-768x394.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1168px) 100vw, 1168px" /></figure>



<p>Bitcoin price chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/ziVIZD6X/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></p>



<p>Technical indicators further reinforce the optimistic outlook for the BTC/USD pair, with a majority signaling a buy. The Relative Strength Index (RSI) demonstrates above-average readings, reflecting a potent buying pressure within the market. </p>



<p>Additionally, the Moving Averages Convergence Divergence (MACD) indicator has experienced a bullish crossover, suggesting the potential onset of a new bull market phase. The 20-SMA and 50-SMA underscore this bullish trend, with the 20-SMA providing sturdy support for Bitcoin’s price.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Ethereum (ETH)</strong></h2>



<p>Ethereum (ETH), the market’s second behemoth, mirrors this bullish sentiment, having peaked at over $3200 in the last week. The demand for ETH has been markedly strong, with the cryptocurrency securing second position on the coin market cap</p>



<p>Ethereum’s current trading price is $3,231, with a slight dip of 0.11% in the past week. With a market capitalization exceeding $387 billion.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/m6hTV_eHBDYeV4H297U5pFWfo6Zi0pRmpYNgobzqVb1vhcxgiJ8z5ZEGuexoQq060WgbnoQtkZTb6It4mZYG2YL2e25qj4H_YphZdoxlWj4kTXVJEO3Yvz-Iuc3cdgfzge7RNb9QnBrk66MYRKW0AC4" alt="" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ethereum-price-prediction/">Ethereum price</a> chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/PZskTvA2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></p>



<p>The technical landscape for ETH/USD is equally promising, with key indicators aligning on the bullish side of the spectrum. The RSI stands above the 67 mark, indicating vigorous market demand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The MACD’s bullish crossover points towards a continuing positive trend for Ethereum. Moreover, the 20-EMA and 50-EMA serve as significant support levels, bolstering Ethereum’s bullish posture in the market.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Binance Coin (BNB)</strong></h2>



<p>Binance Coin (BNB), the proprietary digital asset of the globally recognized Binance exchange, has showcased a bullish pattern over the recent week, reaching heights surpassing $600. The market’s demand for BNB has been notably robust, resulting in a valuation increase of over 9% within the last seven days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Presently, Binance Coin’s market capitalization stands impressively over $89 billion, positioning it as the fourth-largest cryptocurrency by market size. BNB’s trading price is $605, marking a 4% increase in the past 24 hours.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/NUR6NwcDXenYjTR_Xic07chgOtRtzkCrbfDk7MnPq9qtvwzzTdk31PvqK8SVuUrc_cR7PGEYPeaq6iN1guwro_uGjVq6Xdsj1oDg7VWbMVZj1MdQQs9cm1eXZjxh83YmpIqiSBg_bThglo_XmWNYI7c" alt="" /></figure>



<p>Binance price chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/T9NxgRpO/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tradingview</a></p>



<p>Technical indicators for the BNB/USD pairing suggest a trajectory for continued upward movement, with a consensus among indicators leaning towards a buy position. The Awesome Oscillator’s position above the zero line signals a continuing bullish momentum for Binance Coin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, the 20-SMA and 50-SMA serve as pivotal support levels that may catalyze the asset toward encountering new resistance thresholds. Both the RSI and MACD indicators align with a bullish future for BNB.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Solana (SOL)</strong></h2>



<p>Solana (SOL), marking its presence as one of the standout performers over the past year, has witnessed its price surge beyond $150, with a market correction from $160 levels. This <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/altcoin/">altcoin</a> has been on a bullish ascent, bolstered by increasing purchasing pressure and setting new yearly highs. Currently, <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/solana/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Solana</a> is priced at $155, with a notable surge of 2% increase over the last week and a monthly upturn of 5%.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/4UmFpQFzt7UvVpvBKYqeYl_V5SC_G-v54x8g3be-tybsISPFUzyYUfoO6n1Je9OHtNQgVf0zWY__v12GNZhuJ0RPLmC1DWnKRk4HV83MpFzTB4EiKC4aY3_LnAj7Dm2SVHkyw8Acek8dqVZeRO9cBEQ" alt="" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/solana-price-prediction/">Solana price</a> chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/C5d3yjld/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tradingview</a></p>



<p>Continued bullish momentum could see SOL challenging the $160 resistance level. Conversely, should the Bears stage a comeback, Solana will find substantial support at the $150 threshold. The technical outlook for SOL/USD hints at a promising uptrend, with most indicators advocating a buy. Venturing into the overbought territory, the RSI signifies intense market interest in Solana. The MACD echoes this bullish sentiment, while the 20-MA supports SOL’s current market position.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>XRP</strong></h2>



<p>XRP has recently embarked on a bullish journey after spending most of Aprill below the $0.6 mark. The XRP/USD pair broke past this level, oscillating around the $0.55 resistance point. The past week saw XRP amassing a growth of approximately 4%, with its current trading value at $0.5377.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/k-NrRBYYDXjzBdbDjQJIgGIyORUsDfVglgsap72dMeLdtwVwmDuJLPXm8ipsCZdnCr9rPNnnMBQG0lcN1F_gwbbOp2EP_ciCKfjebgzxhbKzlbKffnOYP4e--RVuQaRzUGl024F7pCELfZscjldinvY" alt="" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/xrp-price-prediction/">XRP price</a> chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/l8kxQOPA/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tradingview</a></p>



<p>If XRP’s momentum is sustained, breaking through the $0.55 barrier might set its sights on reaching $0.60, though this level presents a formidable challenge. Analytical indicators, including moving averages and oscillators for XRP/USD, endorse a bullish stance, with the majority signaling a buy. </p>



<p>The Relative Strength Index, below 50, underscores the strong market demand for XRP. The MACD indicator’s bullish crossover hints at the potential for further price ascension, with the 20-day EMA and 50-day SMA reinforcing XRP’s support base.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Cardano(ADA)</strong></h2>



<p>Weekly crypto market analysis shows that ADA/USD has been trading bullish over the past week, with green candlestick patterns dominating the charts. The token has gained more than 5% in value over the past seven days, reaching a high of over $0.55. ADA is <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/cardano/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">trading</a> at $0.5114, with a market capitalization of over $18 billion.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/_HRe8GHfPNGlKRuduj5JBZANmyOh857xM3QHat4Yo59GKKPdWjas381uVs6bX0zvUbafY5X2SteXVrk4fTshWxgfMBP4k5UQPBPy5fdoz_8ZYCVv5Kvji331mm2wo-PaahT1lviuvMt-JiSCjXZ3iFk" alt="" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/cardano-price-prediction/">Cardano price</a> chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/LfTgUTMv/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tradingview</a></p>



<p>Technical indicators for ADA/USD also support a bullish outlook, with most indicators showing a buy signal. The RSI is hovering above 50, indicating a strong buying pressure in the market. The MACD indicator has also formed a bullish crossover, showing potential for further upside in price. The 20-MA and 50-MA are acting as strong support levels for ADA.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Dogecoin(DOGE)</strong></h2>



<p>Dogecoin (DOGE), the meme-based cryptocurrency, has seen a slight decrease in price with slight decrease of 0.8% in the past 24-hours and a decrease of 2.92% in the past week, indicating market fluctuations. Currently, the Dogecoin is at $0.1624, with bullish and bearish struggling to gain momentum.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1141" height="564" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-89.png" alt="" class="wp-image-514633" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-89.png 1141w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-89-300x148.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-89-768x380.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1141px) 100vw, 1141px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/dogecoin-price-prediction/">Dogecoin price</a> chart: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/OFUYQxEr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tradingview</a></p>



<p>The technical indicators for DOGE also support a bullish sentiment. The MACD indicator has shown a bullish crossover, indicating strong buying pressure in the market. The RSI is hovering above 60 levels, indicating a neutral trend. The 20-day EMA is also above the 50-day SMA, supporting a bullish trend.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Weekly crypto price analysis conclusion</strong></h2>



<p>Weekly crypto price analysis of popular digital assets shows that most are showing bullish signs, with slight correction in the past week. The candlestick pattern of the most green coins on the weekly charts also suggests that buyers are in control and may continue to push prices higher. Technical indicators also support a bullish outlook, with buying pressure expected to continue in the coming weeks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Weekly-Crypto-Price-Analysis-1.png" medium="image"  type="image/png" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Weekly-Crypto-Price-Analysis-1.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria&#8217;s National Centre for AI and Robotics Relaunched with Enhanced Capabilities</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/nigeria-ai-and-robotics-relaunched/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brenda Kanana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria AI Integration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Minister of Communications, Innovation, and Digital Economy Dr. Bosun Tijani has announced a fundamental resuscitation of the dormant National Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Robotics (NCAIR) to aid in revitalizing the country&#8217;s digital terrain in accordance with an important decision. The refurbished center seeks to upgrade the country&#8217;s research and development endeavors in rapidly advancing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Minister of Communications, Innovation, and Digital Economy Dr. Bosun Tijani has announced a fundamental resuscitation of the dormant National Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Robotics (NCAIR) to aid in revitalizing the country&#8217;s digital terrain in accordance with an important decision. The refurbished center seeks to upgrade the country&#8217;s research and development endeavors in rapidly advancing technologies, such as AI, Robotics, and IoT.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Restating Nigeria&#8217;s commitment to technological innovation</h2>



<p>NCAIR relaunch comes right after the former Minister for Communication and Digital Economy, Prof. Isa Pantami, claimed that the center was launched by President Muhammadu Buhari. Although there are different arguments, the goal is still the same; that is, the conversion of the country into technological resources and the advancement of innovation in the digital domain.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The National Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Robotics has been built and commissioned in Nov 2020, almost 4 years ago. The first of its kind in Africa. It has been  very effective, and thousands of Nigerians have been trained and trained. Legacy is achieved, not claimed. <a href="https://t.co/wo5eNZk2yG" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://t.co/wo5eNZk2yG</a></p>&mdash; Prof. Isa Ali Ibrahim, CON (@ProfIsaPantami) <a href="https://twitter.com/ProfIsaPantami/status/1781366925211124190?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 19, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Led by Dr. Bosun Tijani, the NCAIR has also seen significant enhancements, and it is sponsored by the technology giant Cisco. At the moment, the capacity of the center has grown, having over 2,500 virtual CPUs that were provided as well as one petabyte of storage. The reforms are targeted at empowering local researchers and start-ups and easing AI implementation in different sectors of the government.</p>



<p>Moreover, NCAIR will oversee the management of new computational infrastructure for national interest projects and academic research. Moreover, an AI laboratory has been established to boost AI research projects in the state and enterprise, which enhances cooperation and innovation in this area.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Enabling nationwide collaboration and knowledge sharing</h2>



<p>Major development is the establishment of AI hubs and pods at various locations in the country, allowing remote access to the NCAIR’s high-performance computing power. This project is aimed at decentralizing technology innovation, making it borderless, and encouraging participation from all areas while promoting inclusivity in the AI ecosystem of Nigeria.</p>



<p>Furthermore, NCAIR has embraced open reporting and scholarly publication of all undertaken research projects to facilitate accountability and knowledge sharing within the research community. The reemergence of NCAIR also aligns with the achievements of the National AI Workshop of the Ministry, which was a consensus-building platform for the AI strategy of Nigeria. One of the achievements was when the country revealed its first Multilingual GPT-2-like Language Model, which was a milestone in linguistic research and development.</p>



<p>Nigeria has not only been able to align its National AI Strategy after four days of collaborative work with over 120 AI experts but has also created several key relationships which are all aimed at enhancing the country’s AI journey. This progress shows Nigeria’s determination to benefit from technological innovation as the growth and development that sustains.</p>



<p>This article first appeared as a press release in the <a href="https://fmcide.gov.ng/hon-minister-dr-bosun-tijani-wraps-up-artificial-intelligence-strategy-workshop-announces-groundbreaking-partnerships-with-cisco-21st-century-technologies-others/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Federal Ministry of Communications, Innovation, and Digital Economy. </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Nigerias_National_Centre_for_AI_and_Robotics_Relaunche_1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Nigerias_National_Centre_for_AI_and_Robotics_Relaunche_1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ApeCoin Price Prediction 2024-2033: Will APE Break $3 Resistance?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/apecoin-price-prediction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Koome]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto Price Predictions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptomarket]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=189466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ApeCoin Price Prediction 2024-2033 Will ApeCoin (APE) break the $3 resistance. The coin has already managed to break above $2.5 this month, with the market in a bull run, the coin is set to perform better. However, like most ‘meme’ tokens, APE registers high volatility. How much is ApeCoin (APE) worth? The current ApeCoin price [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2024-2033</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/apecoin-price-prediction/#ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2024"><u>ApeCoin Price Prediction 2024</u></a> – up to $3.05</li>



<li><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/apecoin-price-prediction/#ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2027"><u>ApeCoin Price Prediction 2027</u></a> – up to $9.31</li>



<li><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/apecoin-price-prediction/#ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2030"><u>ApeCoin Price Prediction 2030</u></a> – up to $29.20</li>



<li><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/apecoin-price-prediction/#ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2033"><u>ApeCoin Price Prediction 2033</u></a> – up to $87.99</li>
</ul>



<p>Will ApeCoin (APE) break the $3 resistance. The coin has already managed to break above $2.5 this month, with the market in a bull run, the coin is set to perform better. However, like most ‘meme’ tokens, APE registers high volatility.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How much is ApeCoin (APE) worth?</h3>



<p>The current ApeCoin price is $1.33. Here are more statistics at press time:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td>24 Hour Trading Volume</td><td>$69 million</td></tr><tr><td>Price change in 24 hours</td><td>0.99%</td></tr><tr><td>Market Capitalization</td><td>$807 million</td></tr><tr><td>Circulating supply</td><td>604,895,833</td></tr><tr><td>Maximum supply</td><td>1,000,000,000</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin price analysis</h2>



<p>TL; DR Breakdown</p>



<ul>
<li>APE has lost over 30% in the last 30 days.</li>



<li>This week, it rose above the $1.25 support.</li>
</ul>



<p>In 2023, APE’s decline accelerated in June, forcing it to trade below $2 multiple times. Positive market sentiment helped it hit the $1.434 mark in October; it continued rising this year, reaching a high of $2.5.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">APE price analysis 1-day chart</h3>



<p>During the ‘Bitcoin halving month,&#8217; many altcoins corrected from the recent bull cycle, including APE. The coin is down 30.04% in the last 30 days.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/KMDsUu0LtEQ18GHKG9STboxTMhznm5E42LN5aFgkztd5V2fGBQ0avsgSM9RP4GSXpJTo1iJ46suNVMHx_HQqtSuMAj_msZyx1jcCy_RcoB2Fup3ctEVHkByMEd6iwvFMCLFWJ4OTzYV7y9u2A1YhPEw" alt="" /></figure>



<p>APE registers negative momentum this week amidst high volatility. Currently, the RSI is within the 30-70 neutral zone, which indicates the price is trending neutral.</p>



<p>There is no divergence within the last four candles, which is no sign of price reversal at current levels.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">APE/USD 4-hour price chart</h3>



<p>The 4-hour chart highlights ApeCoin’s movement and ‘choppiness’ through April 2024.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/ed4OuBd0YJxcGj2sEpWDBCOOo-muvyCL_LwCqCQRod5TenfX6LaGlLIqlNbXkbJWcWbr6cpbmoP2sgAMSPlxbdLXpd57ddnOSLbGUSpakZvEjn2MrBzLw6em82ku1L2A6t6JrGJAjtZtpcsvOXlM5po" alt="" /></figure>



<p>The MACD indicator shows the coin’s positive momentum is slowing as it remains range-bound.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What to expect from APE price analysis next?</h3>



<p>The momentum on the charts suggests APE will remain range-bound in the short term.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recent News</h2>



<p>however,Kevin Hart, American actor and comedian, parted ways with his BAYC <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/nft/"><u>NFT</u></a> selling it at 13.2ETH. At the price, the APE lost about 80% of its purchase value. The recent decline in NFT valuations has affected the entire market as the craze on the digital presentations drop. The move, however has not prevented APE from scaling higher.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2024-2033</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction by Cryptopolitan</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://images.surferseo.art/6d101cb4-5d8e-4e0f-9469-0214aae8414c.png" alt="ApeCoin Price Prediction" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td>Year</td><td>Minimum Price $</td><td>Average Price $</td><td>Maximum Price $</td></tr><tr><td>2024</td><td><strong>2.69</strong></td><td><strong>2.77</strong></td><td><strong>3.05</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2025</td><td><strong>3.83</strong></td><td><strong>3.94</strong></td><td><strong>4.51</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2026</td><td><strong>5.51</strong></td><td><strong>5.67</strong></td><td><strong>6.63</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2027</td><td><strong>7.93</strong></td><td><strong>8.16</strong></td><td><strong>9.31</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2028</td><td><strong>11.41</strong></td><td><strong>11.74</strong></td><td><strong>13.61</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2029</td><td><strong>16.76</strong></td><td><strong>17.23</strong></td><td><strong>19.67</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2030</td><td><strong>24.17</strong></td><td><strong>25.03</strong></td><td><strong>29.20</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2031</td><td><strong>36.55</strong></td><td><strong>37.81</strong></td><td><strong>42.44</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2032</td><td><strong>50.95</strong></td><td><strong>52.84</strong></td><td><strong>63.83</strong></td></tr><tr><td>2033</td><td><strong>73.19</strong></td><td><strong>75.30</strong></td><td><strong>87.99</strong></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2024-">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2024&nbsp;</h4>



<p>APE will rise above $3 at its peak to reach $3.05. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $2.69 at its worst.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2025</h4>



<p>APE will trade at the $3.94 mark on average. It will rise above $4 at its peak to reach $4.51. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $3.83 at its lowest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2026</h4>



<p>APE will trade at $5.67 on average. It will rise above the 2025 resistannce at its peak to reach $6.63. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $5.51 at its worst.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2027">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2027</h4>



<p>APE will trade at the $8.16 mark on average. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $7.93 at its lowest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2028</h4>



<p>APE will trade at $11.74 on average. It will rise above the previous resistance at its peak to reach $13.61. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $11.41 at its lowest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2029</h4>



<p>APE will trade at the $17.23 mark on average. It will rise to $19.67 at its peak. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $16.76 at its lowest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2030">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2030</h4>



<p>APE will trade at the $25.03 mark on average. It will rise to $29.20 at its highest. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $24.17 at its worst.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2031</h4>



<p>APE will trade at the $37.81 mark on average. It will rise above $40 resistance at its peak to reach $42.44. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $36.55 at its lowest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2032</h4>



<p>APE will trade at the $52.84 mark on average. It will rise above $50 at its peak. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $63.83 at its worst.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="ApeCoin-Price-Prediction-2033">ApeCoin Price Prediction 2033</h4>



<p>ApeCoin&#8217;s price will trade at the $75.33 mark on average. It will rise above $80 at its peak. It will however drop below the mark, reaching $73.19 at its lowest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Predictions by WalletInvestor</h3>



<p>The platform gives ApeCoin a past performance index rating of C and adds that APE would make a bad one-year investment. It will average at $0.529 next year. The platform provides the predictions in terms of return on investment (ROI). The ROI is negative over the entire period and is in double digits. It ranges from -70% to -93% annually.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Predictions by CryptoPredictions</h3>



<p>The site scans a coin’s exchange prices and other historical market data and analyses it to provide APE price prediction. The CryptoPredictions platform is bullish on APE. IT indicates that it will have single digit gains over the next four years, ranging between $2 and $5. The maximum price for the entire period is $5.527 while the minimum is $1.499.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price Predictions by Digitalcoinprice</h3>



<p>Digitalcoinprice ApeCoin price forecast is also bullish. The maximum price for the period 2024-2033 is 36.96. It will break the $10 resistance in 2029, and $30 in 2033. Closer home, the coin will range between $4.07 and $4.92 in 2025. In 2027 it will range between $7.29 and $8.67.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Predictions By Industry Experts</h3>



<p>ApeCoin price predictions by <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/binance-bnb/"><u>Binance</u></a>, a leading crypto exchange,is bullish on APE&#8217;s average price over the next 6 years. The coins growth is modest, with 2033 averaging at $2.56. The average will cross $2 in 2025.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Overview</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td>MARKETCAP</td><td>CIRCULATING SUPPLY</td><td>ALL-TIME LOW</td><td>POPULARITY</td><td>ALL-TIME HIGH</td></tr><tr><td>$1.1 billion</td><td>604,895,833</td><td>$1.00</td><td>#93</td><td>$39.40</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ApeCoin Price History</h2>



<p>Yuga Labs founded<a href="https://apecoin.com/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u> Apecoin</u></a> to power the entire operation of their apps and services offered for them to be improved. During its laich, APE price fell to a low of $6.48 within an hour, and it remained in a sideways range between that figure and $9.35 for the rest of the afternoon. Many investors were concerned by the huge gaps in APE’s value, with several centralized exchanges claiming that ApeCoin had dropped 80%. The same discrepancy was evident after initial listings on larger exchanges. Binance for instance registered a high of $28, while <a href="http://Gate.io" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Gate.io</a> went as far as $214.</p>



<p>Yuga Labs has created an ecosystem where APE can be used as a governance and utility token. One example is the ‘Otherside metaverse.’</p>



<p>APE would proceed to register its highest price at $39.40. The lowest was at $1. Like the ApeCin, the Yuga Lab’s have NFTs have also registered high volatility, and have lost most of their initial value.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/ZG3YWSa2sZdEkJcxyvCMBE9LN95NbVkOesL88HuUSZppxK8K73_Fjac4a4eQXsp9Us1S8cmke78PO6dZF-f8STDM83de0_AUyjZ-K9_gcFmwy0HoTbSjPPNtgJHY-AoVNZy0MnxdatuyoBgn3Dzq2Ho" alt="" /></figure>



<p>Source: <a href="https://coinstats.app/coins/apecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://coinstats.app/coins/apecoin/</u></a></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on the Apecoin Network</h2>



<p>The Bored Ape Yacht Club, long renowned for its satire and humor in trading circles, was the basis for ApeCoin, a cryptocurrency named after a well-known animal. The APE token is a governance mechanism in the APE ecosystem.APE powers the community that is cryptocurrency development at the forefront of web3.</p>



<p>ApeCoin cryptocurrency holders can choose the ecosystem’s path and how the DAO spends its funds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many consider ApeCoin a meme token if not an excessively hyped currency. Some investors/ whales are firmly behind ApeCoin, while others believe its bubble will burst in months.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion&nbsp;</h2>



<p>APE bears testament to the unforgiving nature of the crypto market. The coin has ridden the initial wave of the NFT markets and experienced multiple bullish and bear runs. A consistent trend is its volatility. Despite these factors, APE has provided utility to the Yuga Labs family meaning it is much less of a meme token. This year, its has shown consistency moving along the market sentiment rather than internal factors. As the year proceeds it might as well trade higher provided the market does not reverse.</p>



<p>Future projections are bullish with the coin crossing above $10 in 2028 and $80 by 2033. Will APE crush? APE has proved volatile, while it might crush, it will recover to its former glory in preceding bull markets. The growth of the Yuga Labs ecosystem will also be integral in determining its future performance. Remember to include own research before putting your money into APE.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TWgm5CUnXow" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TWgm5CUnXow" />
			<media:title type="plain">APE Coin Realistic Price Prediction... Time To Face Reality</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[APE Coin Price prediction and analysis APE Coin Price Prediction and technical analysis#ape #apecoin #crypto #bitcoin 🔸My Fairdesk referral link ($5040 Bonu...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/ape-coin-realistic-price-predict.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cpn-2022-06-21T042531.306.png" medium="image"  type="image/png" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cpn-2022-06-21T042531.306.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How the Next Rugby World Cup Can Be Won with AI</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/how-next-rugby-world-cup-can-be-won-with-ai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aamir Sheikh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Explained]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rugby AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaking of professional sports, it will be necessary to take advantage of AI over the next decade, as the teams that don’t have this advantage, it will be used against them. AI has the ability to find patterns that are usually hidden from the human eye, or, let&#8217;s say they don’t make any sense to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Speaking of professional sports, it will be necessary to take advantage of AI over the next decade, as the teams that don’t have this advantage, it will be used against them. AI has the ability to find patterns that are usually hidden from the human eye, or, let&#8217;s say they don’t make any sense to humans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This capability is often helpful in identifying problems that are not in focus but related to the subject at hand. AI machines are predictive, and the more data you feed them, the better results they provide, as they are moving towards an intelligence level, which we can call that of a superhuman level.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI advantage in rugby</h2>



<p>Coming back to sports, one does not have to explain the rules of the game to an AI system. These models can learn all the rules by themselves just by watching, and by feeding more game footage spanning over years of matches, they will get an understanding of the sport which will be more than any human.</p>



<p>If rugby game footage is fed to an <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/clubs-big-money-as-ai-is-reshaping-sports/">AI system</a> in a larger quantity, it can find hidden patterns, as mentioned above, which will enable it to identify the weaknesses and vulnerabilities of any player. </p>



<p>If all the matches played by a player in his career are fed to the system, it will learn all the defenses they have made in a match, and how they reacted to tackle any given situation, and the technique they used. As this information will be generated in a short time, and it can be used to take advantage of much better strategies and planning.</p>



<p>It can suggest a better plan to identify the players with the most potential, and it can even come up with a plan to win against any player combination. The possibilities are beyond comprehension. Supposing there is a combination of teams in which one team loses the majority of the matches, AI will come up with a formula to win against the other team and will guide them on how to win.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Assessing the opponents and the next World Cup</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="695" height="486" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/as1111-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-514619" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/as1111-1.png 695w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/as1111-1-300x210.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 695px) 100vw, 695px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: <a href="https://www.theroar.com.au/rugby-union/world-rugby-rankings/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Theroar</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>While assessing the opponent, if the system is fed with a number of matches of the opposite team, it will point out weak points in their strategy, it will identify their techniques and tactics, and will also predict their next move they could make in their play with extreme accuracy.</p>



<p>On the other side, teams will have to find new strategies often as the tech gets adopted across all the teams, so the job of analysts will become easy, but the coaches who can’t keep up with the evolving trends will get eliminated.</p>



<p>The tech will also help in detecting minute changes in players&#8217; body language and their movements and may suggest if the player is fit or has any problems. With enough data, AI will even be able to predict if any injury is possibly happening to a player.</p>



<p>Very soon, AI will be a necessity for any team, as those who have it will be superior in performance to those who lack it. If a team is able to get hold of it now, they will have better chances of winning the 2027 World Cup, and the tech will be much more utilized by the 2031 World Cup.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AI cannot beat everything and win rugby matches for a team that is disproportionate, for example, in skills, power, conditioning of the players, and their physical attributes. Human decisions and skills will always win matches on the ground, as AI alone cannot win matches. This is the nature of the sport and will remain the same.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The original story can be seen <a href="https://www.rugbypass.com/news/the-ai-advantage-how-the-next-two-rugby-world-cups-will-be-won/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/4e0672ae-bff5-4a5f-b2e8-8f215bfcd593.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/4e0672ae-bff5-4a5f-b2e8-8f215bfcd593.jpg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
