<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"

	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.newsbtc.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/</link>
	<description>Bitcoin &#38; Cryptocurrency News Today</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 19:43:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/cropped-cropped-cropped-favicon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">221170450</site>	<item>
		<title>Nervos Network CKB Token: The Market Disruptor With 75% Uptrend, Outshining Top 100 Cryptos</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/nervos-network-ckb-token-the-market-disruptor-with-75-uptrend-outshining-top-100-cryptos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronaldo Marquez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin integration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CKB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CKBUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CKBUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nervos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nervos Network]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amid a widespread price correction affecting the majority of the top 100 cryptocurrencies, one digital asset has defied the trend, surging to impressive heights. Nervos Network, along with its native token CKB, has not only recorded significant gains but has also climbed to the 79th rank in the market, raising questions about the factors behind its surge. Nervos Network Decoded Nervos Network is a proof-of-work (PoW) Layer 1 (L1) blockchain designed to optimize application-specific Layer 2 chains. The network aims to establish its native asset, CKB, as a more sustainable store of value (SoV) compared to Bitcoin (BTC) while providing a more secure smart contract platform than Ethereum (ETH). Bitcoin&#8217;s capped supply and decreasing block rewards raise concerns about long-term economic incentives for miners.  Notably, the Nervos Network tackles this issue by introducing a fixed annual secondary issuance of CKBs and the base supply, providing long-term incentives for miners. Related Reading: Traders Forecast Massive Rally For Altcoins, But Why Is Sentiment “Down”? Nervos Network also addresses the potential security risk associated with Ethereum. In Ethereum, the value of its native asset, ETH, is not directly linked to the value of Layer 2 apps built on top of it.  Nervos Network aims to mitigate this risk by ensuring that CKB is used for transaction fees and storage, creating a stronger economic relationship between the native asset and the overall network. How Secondary Issuance And State Rent Drive Sustainability Nervos utilizes a perpetual secondary issuance model to increase CKB&#8217;s SoV properties. This model incentivizes users to continuously lock up CKB in proportion to the size of their applications.  Furthermore, locked CKBs are subject to &#8220;state rent&#8221; through inflation, which automates state rent payments and ensures a sustainable economic model. Nervos Network introduces a secondary market for chain space, enabling apps to unlock and sell CKBs without requiring relevant storage.  Investors can offset inflation by purchasing CKBs and depositing them into NervosDAO, a mechanism that receives a portion of the secondary issuance to counterbalance inflation. Interestingly, this resembles &#8220;treasury bonds&#8221; and offers potential investment opportunities. Approaching ATH Amidst Bitcoin Integration Announcement Having delved into the fundamentals, CKB has recently experienced a significant surge in value, breaking out of a long consolidation phase that lasted almost two years.  After trading in a range of $0.0024 to $0.0035, the cryptocurrency has broken through this price level since January 30th and has seen significant gains over the past few months. Currently trading at $0.032, CKB is close to its all-time high (ATH) of $0.043, which was reached in March 2021. The token has seen notable price increases of 47%, 69%, 75%, and 14% over the past fourteen days, seven days, and 24 hours, respectively. According to CoinGecko data, CKB has also seen a significant increase in trading volume, reaching $207 million in the last 24 hours, 9.7% from the previous day&#8217;s trading.  In addition, CKB&#8217;s market capitalization has increased significantly, nearly doubling from $740 million on April 2 to approximately $1.35 billion in just over a week. Related Reading: Uniswap Bloodbath: UNI Price Crashes 16% On SEC Lawsuit Fears The price spike can be attributed to the announcement that Nervos Network&#8217;s CKB token will join the Bitcoin network. The token&#8217;s introduction of smart contract functionality, along with its interoperability and modularity features scheduled for 2024, has created excitement among investors. As Bitcoin approaches the Halving that has historically increased its value, Nervos Network is well-positioned to benefit from its strong ties to the largest cryptocurrency in the market.  With its continued bullish momentum and the predicted increase in BTC&#8217;s price, CKB may be poised to reach new all-time highs soon. Featured image from iStock, chart from TradingView.com ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid a widespread price correction affecting the majority of the top 100 cryptocurrencies, one digital asset has defied the trend, surging to impressive heights. Nervos Network, along with its native token CKB, has not only recorded significant gains but has also climbed to the 79th rank in the market, raising questions about the factors behind its surge.</p>
<h2>Nervos Network Decoded</h2>
<p>Nervos Network is a proof-of-work (PoW) Layer 1 (L1) <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-to-go-ballistic-after-halving-says-top-analyst/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">blockchain </a>designed to optimize application-specific Layer 2 chains. The network aims to establish its native asset, CKB, as a more sustainable store of value (SoV) compared to Bitcoin (BTC) while providing a more secure smart contract platform than Ethereum (ETH).</p>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s capped supply and decreasing block rewards raise concerns about long-term economic incentives for miners. </p>
<p>Notably, the Nervos Network tackles this issue by introducing a fixed annual secondary issuance of CKBs and the base supply, providing long-term incentives for miners.</p>

<p>Nervos Network also addresses the potential security risk associated with Ethereum. In Ethereum, the value of its native asset, <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/ceo-throws-cold-water-on-may-ethereum-etf-approval-impact-on-price/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">ETH</a>, is not directly linked to the value of Layer 2 apps built on top of it. </p>
<p>Nervos Network aims to mitigate this risk by ensuring that CKB is used for transaction fees and storage, creating a stronger economic relationship between the native asset and the overall network.</p>
<h2>How Secondary Issuance And State Rent Drive Sustainability</h2>
<p>Nervos utilizes a perpetual secondary issuance model to increase CKB&#8217;s SoV properties. This model incentivizes users to continuously lock up CKB in proportion to the size of their applications. </p>
<p>Furthermore, locked CKBs are subject to &#8220;state rent&#8221; through inflation, which automates state rent payments and ensures a sustainable economic model.</p>
<p>Nervos Network introduces a <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/dogecoin-memecoins-doge-active-trader-count/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">secondary market</a> for chain space, enabling apps to unlock and sell CKBs without requiring relevant storage. </p>
<p>Investors can offset inflation by purchasing CKBs and depositing them into NervosDAO, a mechanism that receives a portion of the secondary issuance to counterbalance inflation. Interestingly, this resembles &#8220;treasury bonds&#8221; and offers potential investment opportunities.</p>
Approaching ATH Amidst Bitcoin Integration Announcement
<p>Having delved into the fundamentals, CKB has recently experienced a significant surge in value, breaking out of a long consolidation phase that lasted almost two years. </p>
<p>After trading in a range of $0.0024 to $0.0035, the cryptocurrency has broken through this price level since January 30th and has seen significant gains over the past few months.</p>
<p>Currently trading at $0.032, CKB is close to its all-time high (ATH) of $0.043, which was reached in March 2021. The token has seen notable price increases of 47%, 69%, 75%, and 14% over the past fourteen days, seven days, and 24 hours, respectively.</p>
<p>According to CoinGecko <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/nervos-network" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">data</a>, CKB has also seen a significant increase in trading volume, reaching $207 million in the last 24 hours, 9.7% from the previous day&#8217;s trading. </p>
<p>In addition, CKB&#8217;s market capitalization has increased significantly, nearly doubling from $740 million on April 2 to approximately $1.35 billion in just over a week.</p>

<p>The price spike can be attributed to the <a href="https://talk.nervos.org/t/rgb-protocol-light-paper/7733" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announcement </a>that Nervos Network&#8217;s CKB token will join the Bitcoin network. The token&#8217;s introduction of smart contract functionality, along with its interoperability and modularity features scheduled for 2024, has created excitement among investors.</p>
<p>As Bitcoin approaches the Halving that has historically increased its value, Nervos Network is well-positioned to benefit from its strong ties to the largest cryptocurrency in the market. </p>
<p>With its continued bullish momentum and the predicted increase in BTC&#8217;s price, CKB may be poised to reach new all-time highs soon.</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/6EJjyGaX/" alt="Nervos Network" width="1815" height="858" loading="lazy"/>
<p>Featured image from iStock, chart from TradingView.com </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/shutterstock_download-2-12.jpg?fit=390%2C260" width="390" height="260" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PEPE Preparing For A 54% Move? Analyst Thinks So</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/pepe/pepe-preparing-54-move-analyst-thinks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Keshav Verma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PEPE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PEPE Bullish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PEPE Memecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PEPE Move]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PEPE price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PEPE price prediction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PEPE Rally]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An analyst has explained how a PEPE daily close outside of a certain price range could lead its value to go on a rally of 54%. PEPE Symmetrical Triangle May Hint At The Next Move For The Memecoin In a new post on X, analyst Ali discussed the recent trend forming in the PEPE price. According to the analyst, the memecoin is currently forming a symmetrical triangle pattern on its one-day chart. The &#8220;symmetrical triangle&#8221; here refers to a pattern in technical analysis (TA) that, as its name suggests, looks like a triangle. In this pattern, there are two lines of interest between which the asset&#8217;s price consolidates for a period. Related Reading: Bitcoin Back Above $70,000 Despite Negative Taker Volume The upper line connects successive tops, while the lower one joins together bottoms. The main feature of the pattern is that these two lines approach each other at a roughly equal and opposite slope (hence the &#8220;symmetrical&#8221; in the name). There are other triangle patterns in TA, but those have either differently angled lines (as is the case with wedges) or one line parallel to the time-axis (ascending and descending triangles). Like other TA patterns that represent a consolidation phase, the lines of the symmetrical triangle also serve as a point of potential reversal for the price. The upper line usually offers resistance (meaning tops can occur), while the lower line may provide support (bottom formation). When a break takes place from either of these lines, the price may likely see sustained momentum in that direction. This implies that a break above the triangle could be a bullish signal, while one below may be bearish. The symmetrical triangle may be viewed as a phase of the market in which the bulls and bears are at a standstill, hence why the price is ranging sideways. During a break, one of these wins out, and price action follows in that direction. Naturally, as the lines converge towards a center point in this pattern, a breakout becomes increasingly probable the closer to the apex of the triangle the asset&#8217;s price gets. Now, here is the chart shared by Ali that highlights the symmetrical triangle pattern that PEPE has been trading inside recently: Looks like the asset's price is getting closer to the converging point of the pattern &#124; Source: @ali_charts on X As is visible in the graph, the 1-day price of PEPE has been approaching the triangle&#8217;s apex recently, implying that a break in a direction may be coming for the memecoin. Related Reading: Dogecoin Usurped: These Memecoins Overtake DOGE In Active Trader Count &#8220;Watch out for a daily close outside of the $0.00000793 &#8211; $0.00000664 range, which could lead to a 54% move for PEPE,&#8221; explains the analyst. Given the pattern that has been forming, it now remains to be seen how the asset&#8217;s price will play out from here. PEPE Price At the time of writing, PEPE is trading around $0.000006868072, up 3% over the past week. The price of the memecoin appears to have gone down recently &#124; Source: PEPEUSD on TradingView Featured image from Shutterstock.com, charts from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An analyst has explained how a PEPE daily close outside of a certain price range could lead its value to go on a rally of 54%.</p>
<h2>PEPE Symmetrical Triangle May Hint At The Next Move For The Memecoin</h2>
<p>In a new <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1778739589647122604/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">post</a> on X, analyst Ali discussed the recent trend forming in the PEPE price. According to the analyst, the memecoin is currently forming a symmetrical triangle pattern on its one-day chart.</p>
<p>The &#8220;<a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/matic-analysis/polygon-breaks-symmetrical-triangle-analyst-target/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">symmetrical triangle</a>&#8221; here refers to a pattern in technical analysis (TA) that, as its name suggests, looks like a triangle. In this pattern, there are two lines of interest between which the asset&#8217;s price consolidates for a period.</p>

<p>The upper line connects successive tops, while the lower one joins together bottoms. The main feature of the pattern is that these two lines approach each other at a roughly equal and opposite slope (hence the &#8220;symmetrical&#8221; in the name).</p>
<p>There are other triangle patterns in TA, but those have either differently angled lines (as is the case with <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/ethereum-price-tops-3100-mega-wedge-breakout/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">wedges</a>) or one line parallel to the time-axis (ascending and descending triangles).</p>
<p>Like other TA patterns that represent a consolidation phase, the lines of the symmetrical triangle also serve as a point of potential reversal for the price. The upper line usually offers resistance (meaning tops can occur), while the lower line may provide support (bottom formation).</p>
<p>When a break takes place from either of these lines, the price may likely see sustained momentum in that direction. This implies that a break above the triangle could be a bullish signal, while one below may be bearish.</p>
<p>The symmetrical triangle may be viewed as a phase of the market in which the bulls and bears are at a standstill, hence why the price is ranging sideways. During a break, one of these wins out, and price action follows in that direction.</p>
<p>Naturally, as the lines converge towards a center point in this pattern, a <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/shiba-inu/shiba-inu-shib-price-major-breakout/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">breakout</a> becomes increasingly probable the closer to the apex of the triangle the asset&#8217;s price gets.</p>
<p>Now, here is the chart shared by Ali that highlights the symmetrical triangle pattern that PEPE has been trading inside recently:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GK86E8DWcAQgnb_?format=jpg&amp;name=4096x4096" alt="PEPE Symmetrical Triangle" width="2198" height="1443" loading="lazy"/></p>

<p>As is visible in the graph, the 1-day price of PEPE has been approaching the triangle&#8217;s apex recently, implying that a break in a direction may be coming for the memecoin.</p>

<p>&#8220;Watch out for a daily close outside of the $0.00000793 &#8211; $0.00000664 range, which could lead to a 54% move for PEPE,&#8221; explains the analyst. Given the pattern that has been forming, it now remains to be seen how the asset&#8217;s price will play out from here.</p>
<h2>PEPE Price</h2>
<p>At the time of writing, PEPE is trading around $0.000006868072, up 3% over the past week.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium aligncenter" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/aOGFLzNn/" alt="PEPE Price Chart" width="1534" height="854" loading="lazy"/></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/shutterstock_2301408373.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602960</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will The Halving Send Bitcoin Price To $100,000? Analytics Platform Reveals What You Should Expect</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-halving-price-100000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 21:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hannah Phung, a lead analyst at on-chain analytics platform SpotOnChain, recently gave her opinion on the impact that Bitcoin Halving could have on the flaghsip crypto’s price. This adds to the ongoing debate on whether or not the Halving event could cause Bitcoin’s price to rise to $100,000.  Bitcoin’s Price Surge Might Not Come Immediately Phung mentioned during an interview with BeInCrypto that Bitcoin’s price tends to increase around 6 to 12 months after the Halving and not immediately. This is evident from the past Halving events, as Bitcoin’s significant price gains came about one year after the Halving had occurred. After the first Halving on November 28, 2021, Bitcoin saw a price increase of over 8,000% one year after the event. Related Reading: Crypto Analyst Predicts Shiba Inu Price Will Reach $0.0001 If This Happens Source: Milk Road &#160; Meanwhile, BTC saw a price increase of 284% and 559% one year after the second and third Halving events, which took place on July 9, 2016, and May 11, 2020, respectively. Phung further noted that Bitcoin’s price gains come from the reduction in Bitcoin miners’ supply, which helps increase scarcity and drive up its price, especially when demand is stable.  In February, NewsBTC reported that Bitcoin’s demand was far outpacing the miners’ supply. This led to several crypto analysts making bullish predictions that Bitcoin’s price could increase exponentially when miners’ rewards are further cut in half later this month. One such analyst was MacronautBTC, who raised the possibility of Bitcoin rising to $237,000.  This Bitcoin Halving Could Be Different Despite the crypto market being known to follow historical patterns, Phung emphasized that the market can also be unpredictable, opening the possibility of this Halving being different from past ones. Moreover, this cycle has already proven different, considering that for the first time, Bitcoin hit a new all-time high (ATH) before the Halving.  Furthermore, the analyst acknowledged that the Bitcoin market is “much larger and more established compared to earlier halvings.” However, Phung still expects a price increase after the halving, although she admitted that the exact timing is uncertain, meaning it could be earlier or even later than usual.  Crypto analyst Rekt Capital also echoed a similar sentiment about how things could be different this cycle when he shared his analysis of the five phases of the Bitcoin Halving. Specifically, he stated that the Re-accumulation phase “may not last very long before additional uptrend continuation” since this is the first time the Re-accumulation range will be around a new ATH.  Market Sentiment Could Determine Bitcoin’s Price Post-Halving Phung also elaborated on how the market sentiment after the halving could provide insights into Bitcoin’s future trajectory. She predicts that crypto investors will likely be bullish once the halving takes place, considering the significance of the event on Bitcoin’s supply.  Related Reading: The Era Of Flippenings: Can Dogecoin Take XRP’s Spot? However, once the excitement about the halving wears off, several metrics, such as price charts, trading volume, social media discussions, and on-chain data like active addresses or exchange supply, will need to be analyzed to determine whether or not investors are still bullish.  Meanwhile, Phung suggested that the price surge that occurs immediately after the Bitcoin halving may not be shortlived this time around since more institutional investors are now involved and have helped create a “more mature market.” BTC price rises to $70,700 &#124; Source: BTCUSD on Tradingview.com Featured image from Bitcoin News, chart from Tradingview.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hannah Phung, a lead analyst at on-chain analytics platform <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/solana-meme-coin-trader/" rel="nofollow">SpotOnChain</a>, recently gave her opinion on the impact that Bitcoin Halving could have on the flaghsip crypto’s price. This adds to the ongoing debate on whether or not the Halving event could cause <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-100000-cardano-dead/#:~:text=Why%20Cardano%20Is%20Dead,non%2Dexistent%E2%80%9D%20on%20it.">Bitcoin’s price to rise to $100,000</a>. </p>
<h2>Bitcoin’s Price Surge Might Not Come Immediately</h2>
<p>Phung mentioned during an <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-halving-influences-price-investors-sentiment/?__cf_chl_rt_tk=5x4N1Qh_uLHxyijJT7f1wF2_haCHlw4TpMPSgGsBysU-1712910311-0.0.1.1-1706" rel="nofollow">interview</a> with BeInCrypto that Bitcoin’s price tends to increase around 6 to 12 months after the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-bull-market-glassnode/" rel="nofollow">Halving</a> and not immediately. This is evident from the past Halving events, as Bitcoin’s <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-price-rise-above-57000/#:~:text=Bitcoin%20isn't%20showing%20signs,a%20bullish%20narrative%20for%20BTC." rel="nofollow">significant price gains</a> came about one year after the Halving had occurred. After the first Halving on November 28, 2021, Bitcoin saw a price increase of over 8,000% one year after the event.</p>

<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-602930 aligncenter" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_4fef0a.png?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C199" alt="Bitcoin" width="460" height="199" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_4fef0a.png?w=512 512w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_4fef0a.png?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C199 460w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, BTC saw a price increase of 284% and 559% one year after the second and third Halving events, which took place on July 9, 2016, and May 11, 2020, respectively. Phung further noted that Bitcoin’s price gains come from the reduction in <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-demands-exceeds-supply/">Bitcoin miners’ supply</a>, which helps increase scarcity and drive up its price, especially when demand is stable. </p>
<p>In February, NewsBTC <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-demands-exceeds-supply/">reported</a> that Bitcoin’s demand was far outpacing the miners’ supply. This led to several crypto analysts making bullish predictions that Bitcoin’s price could increase exponentially when miners’ rewards are further cut in half later this month. One such analyst was MacronautBTC, who raised the possibility of Bitcoin rising to $237,000. </p>
<h2>This Bitcoin Halving Could Be Different</h2>
<p>Despite the crypto market being known to follow <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/when-bitcoin-top-historical-pattern-provide-hints/" rel="nofollow">historical patterns</a>, Phung emphasized that the market can also be unpredictable, opening the possibility of this Halving being different from past ones. Moreover, this cycle has already proven different, considering that for the first time, Bitcoin hit a <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-breaks-through-69000-setting-new-record/" rel="nofollow">new all-time high (ATH</a>) before the Halving. </p>
<p>Furthermore, the analyst acknowledged that the Bitcoin market is “much larger and more established compared to earlier halvings.” However, Phung still expects a price increase after the halving, although she admitted that the exact timing is uncertain, meaning it could be earlier or even later than usual. </p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-troubles-far-from-over/">Crypto analyst Rekt Capital</a> also echoed a similar sentiment about how things could be different this cycle when he shared his <a href="https://x.com/rektcapital/status/1769656725341163692" rel="nofollow">analysis</a> of the five phases of the Bitcoin Halving. Specifically, he stated that the Re-accumulation phase “may not last very long before additional uptrend continuation” since this is the first time the Re-accumulation range will be around a new ATH. </p>
Market Sentiment Could Determine Bitcoin’s Price Post-Halving
<p>Phung also elaborated on how the market sentiment after the halving could provide insights into Bitcoin’s future trajectory. She predicts that <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/over-90-of-bitcoin-holders-profit-46000-break-data/" rel="nofollow">crypto investors</a> will likely be bullish once the halving takes place, considering the significance of the event on Bitcoin’s supply. </p>

<p>However, once the excitement about the halving wears off, several metrics, such as price charts, trading volume, social media discussions, and on-chain data like active addresses or <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-coinbase-9-year-low/">exchange supply</a>, will need to be analyzed to determine whether or not investors are still bullish. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, Phung suggested that the price surge that occurs immediately after the Bitcoin halving may not be shortlived this time around since more <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/institutional-buyers-of-bitcoin/">institutional investors</a> are now involved and have helped create a “more mature market.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/0JGNYOcu/" alt="Bitcoin price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530"/></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin-100000.jpeg?fit=460%2C259" width="460" height="259" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602928</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Litecoin (LTC) Breaks Records: 5 Million Long-Term Holders Signal Major Market Shift</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/litecoin/litecoin-ltc-breaks-records-5-million-long-term/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Edyme]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 20:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Litecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[litecoin market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litecoin Prediction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ltc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently, reports from IntoTheBlock revealed that the Litecoin (LTC) network has exceeded five million long-term holders. This achievement represents approximately 62.5% of all LTC addresses with a balance, underscoring Litecoin&#8217;s widespread adoption and long-term viability within the crypto community. Rising Long-Term Holder Trend Signals Optimism  The surge in long-term holders has been particularly noticeable in recent months, underscoring a growing inclination towards holding LTC for quite a long time. In February&#8217;s closing days alone, the number of long-term holders soared by 170,000, signaling robust investor confidence in Litecoin&#8217;s long-term prospects. Related Reading: From $90 To $400 Litecoin: Analysts Bullish On LTC Soaring Trajectory In tandem with this surge in long-term holders, the number of individuals holding LTC for more than a year has steadily risen, now totaling 2.54 million addresses. Apart from the numerical growth, the profitability of holding LTC over the long term adds another dimension of interest. Amazing milestone for Litecoin! 💎The network now counts over 5 million long-term holders of $LTC. 👉This figure represents 62.5% of all Litecoin addresses with a balance. pic.twitter.com/K5FHz3Ivjs — IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) April 12, 2024 According to on-chain data, roughly 67.67% of all LTC addresses currently stand in profit, collectively holding 49.76 million LTC. In contrast, approximately 26.8% of LTC holders, totaling 2.15 million addresses, are currently at a loss. Meanwhile, a smaller segment, constituting 5.53% of holders, is situated at breakeven, which means they are neither in a loss nor a profit. Bullish Sentiment Surrounds Litecoin Amidst Rumors of ETF Approval So far, Litecoin has seen relatively stable movement, experiencing a minor increase of 0.3% over the past week, followed by a slight downturn of 0.1% in the last 24 hours. As of the current writing, LTC is trading at $96.72. Despite the altcoin&#8217;s current stability in price, analysts such as World of Charts anticipate a potential surge in the coming months, with projections suggesting a climb to $400. This bullish momentum is fuelled by growing institutional interest, particularly surrounding rumors of a potential LTC Exchange-Traded Fund (ETF). Fox Business journalist Eleanor Terrett has hinted at institutional intrigue towards a Litecoin ETF, citing LTC&#8217;s functional similarities to Bitcoin as a potential factor in its approval by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). 🚨SCOOP (with fixed ticker) 🙂: Hearing rumblings on the institutional level about possible interest in a Litecoin ETF. The logic is that because of $LTC functional similarities to $BTC, the @SECGov may be more inclined to approve it, possibly even more so than $ETH. Last week,… https://t.co/nsrhE87OLm — Eleanor Terrett (@EleanorTerrett) March 26, 2024 Additionally, Coinbase Derivatives&#8217; recent launch of futures contracts for Litecoin further contributes to the buzz surrounding the cryptocurrency. Related Reading: Litecoin Price Prediction: LTC Rally Could Extend To $120 Renowned crypto analyst Luke Martin echoes this sentiment, suggesting that the approval of an Ethereum ETF could pave the way for other &#8220;old altcoins&#8221; like Litecoin to gain regulatory approval. Martin emphasizes that LTC and Dogecoin may have a stronger case for not being classified as securities, particularly in comparison to Ethereum. Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, reports from IntoTheBlock <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1778713110355788129?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">revealed</a> that the Litecoin (LTC) network has exceeded five million long-term holders. This achievement represents approximately 62.5% of all LTC addresses with a balance, underscoring Litecoin&#8217;s widespread adoption and long-term viability within the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/litecoin-soars-above-110-as-ltc-breaks-out-of-macro-downtrend-analysts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">crypto community</a>.</p>
<h2>Rising Long-Term Holder Trend Signals Optimism </h2>
<p>The surge in long-term holders has been particularly noticeable in recent months, underscoring a growing inclination towards holding LTC for quite a long time. In February&#8217;s closing days alone, the number of long-term holders soared by 170,000, signaling robust investor confidence in Litecoin&#8217;s <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/litecoin-soars-past-105-is-ltc-set-for-epic-rally-this-april/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">long-term prospects</a>.</p>

<p>In tandem with this surge in long-term holders, the number of individuals holding LTC for more than a year has steadily risen, now totaling 2.54 million addresses. Apart from the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/all/from-90-to-400-litecoin-analysts-bullish-on-ltc-soaring-trajectory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">numerical growth</a>, the profitability of holding LTC over the long term adds another dimension of interest.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Amazing milestone for Litecoin!</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f48e.png" alt="💎" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />The network now counts over 5 million long-term holders of <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24LTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$LTC</a>.
<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f449.png" alt="👉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />This figure represents 62.5% of all Litecoin addresses with a balance. <a href="https://t.co/K5FHz3Ivjs" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">pic.twitter.com/K5FHz3Ivjs</a></p>
<p>— IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1778713110355788129?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">April 12, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>According to on-chain data, roughly 67.67% of all LTC addresses currently stand in profit, collectively holding 49.76 million LTC. In contrast, approximately 26.8% of LTC holders, totaling 2.15 million addresses, are currently at a loss.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a smaller segment, constituting 5.53% of holders, is situated at breakeven, which means they are neither in a loss nor a profit.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-602984 size-large" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C250" alt="Addresses currently holding in Litecoin (LTC). " width="860" height="250" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=2734 2734w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C250 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-12-at-16.05.29.png?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1"/>
<h2>Bullish Sentiment Surrounds Litecoin Amidst Rumors of ETF Approval</h2>
<p>So far, Litecoin has seen relatively stable movement, experiencing a minor increase of 0.3% over the past week, followed by a slight downturn of 0.1% in the last 24 hours. As of the current writing, LTC is trading at $96.72.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/wAjMrbwA/" alt="Litecoin (LTC) price chart on TradingView" width="2770" height="1496"/>
<p>Despite the altcoin&#8217;s current stability in price, analysts such as World of Charts <a href="https://x.com/WorldOfCharts1/status/1772543150118031667" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">anticipate</a> a potential surge in the coming months, with projections suggesting a climb to $400. This bullish momentum is fuelled by growing institutional interest, particularly surrounding <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/litecoin/litecoin-etf-rumors-fuel-10-surge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">rumors of a potential LTC Exchange-Traded Fund (ETF)</a>.</p>
<p>Fox Business journalist Eleanor Terrett has hinted at institutional intrigue towards a Litecoin ETF, citing LTC&#8217;s functional similarities to Bitcoin as a potential factor in its approval by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />SCOOP (with fixed ticker) <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />: Hearing rumblings on the institutional level about possible interest in a Litecoin ETF. The logic is that because of <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24LTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$LTC</a> functional similarities to <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$BTC</a>, the <a href="https://twitter.com/SECGov?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">@SECGov</a> may be more inclined to approve it, possibly even more so than <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24ETH&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$ETH</a>.</p>
<p>Last week,… <a href="https://t.co/nsrhE87OLm" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">https://t.co/nsrhE87OLm</a></p>
<p>— Eleanor Terrett (@EleanorTerrett) <a href="https://twitter.com/EleanorTerrett/status/1772698347515556030?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">March 26, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Additionally, Coinbase Derivatives&#8217; recent launch of futures contracts for Litecoin further contributes to the buzz surrounding the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/ltc/litecoin-price-prediction-ltc-rally-120/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">cryptocurrency</a>.</p>

<p>Renowned crypto analyst Luke Martin echoes this sentiment, <a href="https://x.com/VentureCoinist/status/1770624938413580375" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">suggesting</a> that the approval of an Ethereum ETF could pave the way for other &#8220;old altcoins&#8221; like Litecoin to gain regulatory approval. Martin emphasizes that LTC and Dogecoin may have a stronger case for not being classified as securities, particularly in comparison to Ethereum.</p>
<p>Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Litecoin.jpeg?fit=460%2C329" width="460" height="329" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602972</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Traders Forecast Massive Rally For Altcoins, But Why Is Sentiment “Down”?</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/traders-forecast-massive-rally-for-altcoins-but-why-is-sentiment-down/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rubmar Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 19:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin Season]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoins Bears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins bulls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altseason]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Trader Sentiment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin’s correction at the start of Q2 dragged down the Altcoins market, and a “gloomy” sentiment appears to surround investors despite Q1 2024 registering one of the best performances for the crypto market. As prices recover momentum, traders and analysts suggest a brighter future might be around the corner. Related Reading: Bitcoin To Go ‘Ballistic’ After Halving, Says Top Analyst – Here’s Why Altcoins Next Stop: Altseason? On Friday, some traders shared optimistic forecasts for altcoins. According to investor Crypto Jelle, the altcoin market cap chart “looks primed to go on a massive rally in the coming months.” The investor highlights the similarities between the altcoin’s performance during the previous bull runs. Per the chart, after 2018’s all-time high (ATH) of $474.5 billion, the altcoin market consolidated under the resistance zone in “preparation” for the next bull run. Altcoins market cap sitting at $1.15 trillion. Source: CryptoJelle on X During the 2020-2021 bull market, altcoins’ market cap broke out and consolidated around a new support zone before continuing its upward trajectory to its last ATH of $1.7 trillion. As the investor highlighted, altcoins’ performance looks like that of the previous bull run. They are seemingly consolidating after a breakout from the resistance zone. If history were to repeat itself, then altcoins could “remind everyone what they’re capable of.” Another trader and analyst, Titan of Crypto, shared a similar prediction to Jelle’s. According to the analysts, he’s seen crypto community members believing that “there’ll never be another altseason.” To those in doubt, the trader suggests they “zoom out” to get a broader perspective on where the market is in the cycle. Per his chart, which excludes Ether (ETH), altcoins are at the “2 bullish monthly candles followed by consolidation” phase. Run up prediction for altcoins, excluding ETH. Source: Titan Of Crypto on X. The chart also suggests that the subsequent run-up could surpass the $1.13 trillion ATH and soar to a market cap of $3.25 trillion in the coming months. To the analyst, the “#Altseason2024 is inevitable.” Predictions Are Up, Why Is The Sentiment Down? Across different platforms, the sentiment seems to lean towards “negative” despite the optimistic forecasts. Follis, content creator and founder of Chroma Trading shared his experience on X this Thursday. According to the post, “sentiment at the moment is some of the worst” he’s seen during his years in the crypto community. Moreover, he considers “engagement is dead” as “everyone is quiet” across X, Discord, and Twitch. Sentiment at the moment is some of the worst I&#39;ve seen in my 3y in crypto Twitter, twitch, discord &#8211; everyone is quiet, engagement is dead$BTC only -6% from ath but lots of alts down -40% or more. No real bid to be found for a month or more, except on random rotations &#38;… &#8212; フ ォ リ ス (@follis_) April 11, 2024 The post opened a discussion as to what could be the reason. Follis suggested a combination of “over-leveraged top longers” and “traders who expected price to go up indefinitely.” Another user weighed in, suggesting traders lost significant money buying high and selling low on Solana and Base memecoins. Top crypto trader Ansem joined the discussion, disagreeing with the “depressing” take on the current market. The trader pointed out that BTC was at $70,000 and ETH at $3,500 at the time of his post. These prices represent a 129.8% and 82.5% increase in the past year. Similarly, he highlighted the performance of SOL compared to the bear market bottom and the remarkable performance of memecoins in the past six months. Many users agreed that drawdowns are usual during market cycles and ultimately suggested looking at the bigger picture. Related Reading: Crypto Analyst Unveils Top Altcoins For Biggest Returns This Cycle Altcoins market cap is at $1.15 trillion. Source: TOTAL2 on Tradingview Featured Image from Unsplash.com, Chart from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400">Bitcoin’s correction at the start of Q2 dragged down the Altcoins market, and a “gloomy” sentiment appears to surround investors despite <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-q1-performance-digest-69-price-surge-12b-etfs-inflows-and-127-growth-in-layer-tvl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Q1 2024</a> registering one of the best performances for the crypto market. As prices recover momentum, traders and analysts suggest a brighter future might be around the corner.</p>

<h2 style="font-weight: 400">Altcoins Next Stop: Altseason?</h2>
<p style="font-weight: 400">On Friday, some traders shared optimistic forecasts for altcoins. According to investor Crypto Jelle, the altcoin market cap chart “looks primed to go on a massive rally in the coming months.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">The investor <a href="https://twitter.com/CryptoJelleNL/status/1778713795952620000" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">highlights</a> the similarities between the altcoin’s performance during the previous bull runs. Per the chart, after 2018’s all-time high (ATH) of $474.5 billion, the altcoin market consolidated under the resistance zone in “preparation” for the next bull run.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-602976 aligncenter" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C440" alt="Altcoins, crypto" width="860" height="440" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C440 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9CxSKWEAE1b8x.jpeg?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>

<p style="font-weight: 400">During the 2020-2021 bull market, altcoins’ market cap broke out and consolidated around a new support zone before continuing its upward trajectory to its last ATH of $1.7 trillion.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">As the investor highlighted, altcoins’ performance looks like that of the previous bull run. They are seemingly consolidating after a breakout from the resistance zone. If history were to repeat itself, then altcoins could “remind everyone what they’re capable of.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">Another trader and analyst, Titan of Crypto, <a href="https://twitter.com/Washigorira/status/1778728674704892406/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">shared</a> a similar prediction to Jelle’s. According to the analysts, he’s seen crypto community members believing that “there’ll never be another altseason.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">To those in doubt, the trader suggests they “zoom out” to get a broader perspective on where the market is in the cycle. Per his chart, which excludes Ether (ETH), altcoins are at the “2 bullish monthly candles followed by consolidation” phase.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-602977 aligncenter" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C533" alt="altcoins, crypto" width="860" height="533" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=3324 3324w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C533 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=1140 1140w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK9QCLJWoAIqrAg.jpeg?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>

<p style="font-weight: 400">The chart also suggests that the subsequent run-up could surpass the $1.13 trillion ATH and soar to a market cap of $3.25 trillion in the coming months. To the analyst, the “#Altseason2024 is inevitable.”</p>
<h2 style="font-weight: 400">Predictions Are Up, Why Is The Sentiment Down?</h2>
<p style="font-weight: 400">Across different platforms, the sentiment seems to lean towards “negative” despite the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-healthy-btc-to-rally-above-74000/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">optimistic forecasts</a>. Follis, content creator and founder of Chroma Trading shared his experience on X this Thursday.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">According to the post, “sentiment at the moment is some of the worst” he’s seen during his years in the crypto community. Moreover, he considers “engagement is dead” as “everyone is quiet” across X, Discord, and Twitch.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sentiment at the moment is some of the worst I&#39;ve seen in my 3y in crypto</p>
<p>Twitter, twitch, discord &#8211; everyone is quiet, engagement is dead<a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BTC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$BTC</a> only -6% from ath but lots of alts down -40% or more. No real bid to be found for a month or more, except on random rotations &amp;…</p>
<p>&mdash; フ ォ リ ス (@follis_) <a href="https://twitter.com/follis_/status/1778502540805521626?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 11, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">The post opened a discussion as to what could be the reason. Follis suggested a combination of “over-leveraged top longers” and “traders who expected price to go up indefinitely.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">Another user weighed in, <a href="https://x.com/larpalt/status/1778599143805522390" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">suggesting</a> traders lost significant money buying high and selling low on Solana and Base memecoins.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">Top crypto trader Ansem joined the discussion, <a href="https://x.com/blknoiz06/status/1778611201594790251" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">disagreeing</a> with the “depressing” take on the current market. The trader pointed out that BTC was at $70,000 and ETH at $3,500 at the time of his post. These prices represent a 129.8% and 82.5% increase in the past year.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400">Similarly, he highlighted the performance of SOL compared to the bear market bottom and the remarkable performance of memecoins in the past six months. Many users agreed that <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-below-70000-is-80k-still-possible-or-is-the-rally-over/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">drawdowns</a> are usual during market cycles and ultimately suggested looking at the bigger picture.</p>

<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-602975 aligncenter" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL2_2024-04-12_08-11-53.png?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C415" alt="Altcoins, market cap" width="860" height="415" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL2_2024-04-12_08-11-53.png?w=1064 1064w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL2_2024-04-12_08-11-53.png?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL2_2024-04-12_08-11-53.png?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL2_2024-04-12_08-11-53.png?w=860&#038;resize=860%2C415 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/TOTAL2_2024-04-12_08-11-53.png?w=750 750w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/nathan-dumlao-qDbnNDF2jZ4-unsplash-e1712931958543.jpeg?fit=307%2C460" width="307" height="460" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602973</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shiba Inu Sell Pressure Is Dropping &#8211; Here’s What It Means For Price</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/shiba-inu/shiba-inu-sell-pressure-price/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 17:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIB news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIB price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIBUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIBUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The majority of Shiba Inu investors have been left confused about the crypto&#8217;s price trajectory in the past few weeks. While the crypto has experienced a period of stagnation in the past two weeks, recent on-chain data shows that the outlook might be looking bullish again, particularly as selling has slowed dramatically this week. At the same time, Shiba Inu has now crossed a major milestone in the number of addresses, which could mean an increase in the number of holders. Shiba Inu Sell Pressure Drops The price of Shiba Inu can easily be moved by selling and buying pressure from investors. Recent on-chain data, however, indicates that the selling pressure is currently decreasing, which could manifest in the price of the SHIB in the coming week. Particularly, IntoTheBlock&#8217;s historical active address by profitability shows the yearly average now shifting towards wallet addresses at the money. Related Reading: XRP Sees An Alarming 1,800% Surge In Liquidations, Whats Going On? Interestingly, this cohort of traders is now at almost 74.6%, meaning they contribute to the majority of the buying and selling action. However, their &#8220;at the money status&#8221; doesn&#8217;t give a clear path to their actions, as they could either be selling or increasing their holdings at the current price. On the other hand, this metric indicates better action among the active portion of addresses that are &#8220;in the money.&#8221; Interestingly, these &#8220;in the money&#8221; addresses have now seen their year-to-date activity average falling below 18%. This cohort of traders, who would normally be selling after reaching profits on their holdings, have failed to conduct a tangible number of transactions. Interestingly, this indicates they might be opting to hold right now in order to increase their unrealized profits. Similarly, on-chain data shows a substantial amount of SHIB moving out of the hands of short-term holders, contributing to a drop in selling pressure. About 4% of the entire circulating supply of SHIB has moved from short-term holders to mid-term holders in the past week. Mid-term holders hold their assets for more than a month to a year, in contrast to short-term holders, who are known for holding for less than a month before selling.  Source: IntoTheBlock What’s Next For SHIB? With decreasing sell pressure and a shift to longer holding times, SHIB is poised for a reversal and continued upward momentum. At the time of writing, SHIB is trading at $0.00002766, down by 1.1% in the past 24 hours and up by 4.65% in a larger 7-day timeframe. Related Reading: The Era Of Flippenings: Can Dogecoin Take XRP’s Spot? Shiba Inu recently attained a milestone of 4 million addresses, which could mean an increase in activity is on the horizon. A surge in activity could see SHIB repeating a bullish pattern from the 2021 bull run. According to crypto analyst Bunchhieng, if history were to repeat itself, a repeat of this pattern would see SHIB rising to $0.0001. SHIB price at $0.000027 &#124; Source: SHIBUSDT on Tradingview.com Featured image from Watcher Guru, chart from Tradingview.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The majority of Shiba Inu investors have been left confused about the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/shiba-inu/trading-strategy-shiba-inu/">crypto&#8217;s price trajectory</a> in the past few weeks. While the crypto has experienced a period of stagnation in the past two weeks, recent on-chain data shows that the outlook <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/shiba-inu/shiba-inu-shib-price-recover/">might be looking bullish again</a>, particularly as selling has slowed dramatically this week. At the same time, Shiba Inu has now crossed a major milestone in the number of addresses, which could mean an increase in the number of holders.</p>
<h2>Shiba Inu Sell Pressure Drops</h2>
<p>The price of Shiba Inu can easily be moved by selling and buying pressure from investors. Recent on-chain data, however, indicates that the selling pressure is currently decreasing, which could manifest in the price of the SHIB in the coming week. Particularly, <a href="https://app.intotheblock.com/coin/SHIB/deep-dive?group=financials&amp;chart=inAndOut" rel="nofollow">IntoTheBlock&#8217;s </a>historical active address by profitability shows the yearly average now shifting towards wallet addresses at the money.</p>

<p>Interestingly, this cohort of traders is now at almost 74.6%, meaning they contribute to the majority of the buying and selling action. However, their &#8220;at the money status&#8221; doesn&#8217;t give a clear path to their actions, as they could either be selling or increasing their holdings at the current price.</p>
<p>On the other hand, this metric indicates better action among the active portion of addresses that are &#8220;in the money.&#8221; Interestingly, these &#8220;in the money&#8221; addresses have now seen their year-to-date activity average falling below 18%. This cohort of traders, who would normally be selling after reaching profits on their holdings, have failed to conduct a tangible number of transactions. Interestingly, this indicates they might be opting to hold right now in order to increase their unrealized profits.</p>
<p>Similarly, on-chain data shows a substantial amount of SHIB moving out of the hands of short-term holders, contributing to a drop in selling pressure. About 4% of the entire circulating supply of SHIB has moved from short-term holders to mid-term holders in the past week. Mid-term holders hold their assets for more than a month to a year, in contrast to short-term holders, who are known for holding for less than a month before selling. </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-602912 aligncenter" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Shiba-Inu-2.png?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C306" alt="Shiba Inu" width="460" height="306" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Shiba-Inu-2.png?w=512 512w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Shiba-Inu-2.png?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C306 460w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>

<h2>What’s Next For SHIB?</h2>
<p>With decreasing sell pressure and a shift to longer holding times, SHIB is poised for a reversal and continued upward momentum. At the time of writing, SHIB is trading at $0.00002766, <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/dogecoin-shiba-inu-price-red/" rel="nofollow">down by</a> 1.1% in the past 24 hours and up by 4.65% in a larger 7-day timeframe.</p>

<p>Shiba Inu recently <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/shiba-inu-hits-milestone/" rel="nofollow">attained a milestone</a> of 4 million addresses, which could mean an <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/shiba-inu-burn-rate-48554/" rel="nofollow">increase in activity</a> is on the horizon. A surge in activity could see SHIB repeating a bullish pattern from the 2021 bull run. According to crypto <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/shiba-inu/shiba-inu-price-reach-0-0001/">analyst Bunchhieng</a>, if history were to repeat itself, a repeat of this pattern would see <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/shiba-inu/trading-strategy-shiba-inu/">SHIB rising to $0.0001</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/aF1Bulyq/" alt="Shiba Inu price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530"/></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Shiba-Inu-3.jpeg?fit=297%2C170" width="297" height="170" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602908</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogecoin Usurped: These Memecoins Overtake DOGE In Active Trader Count</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/dogecoin/dogecoin-memecoins-doge-active-trader-count/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Keshav Verma]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 16:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEGEN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE traders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin Dominance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin Traders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602915</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On-chain data suggests Dogecoin is no longer the dominant meme coin in terms of its weekly active trader count. Here are the coins above it. Dogecoin Has Been Surpassed In Trader Count By Other Memecoins According to data from the market intelligence platform IntoTheBlock, DOG and DEGEN are the two assets that have managed to surpass the original meme-based cryptocurrency in terms of weekly trader count. A &#8220;trader&#8221; here refers to an investor who has been holding onto their coins since less than 30 days ago. These investors generally tend to move their coins often, as they play the role of active traders in the market. They are certainly not the HODLers of the sector. Related Reading: Bitcoin Back Above $70,000 Despite Negative Taker Volume When the number of these traders goes up for any asset, it means that some fresh interest is potentially coming into the coin. Price actions like rallies are only sustainable when they have an ever-increasing fuel coming in, so the trader count going up can perhaps be a bullish indication in this direction. On the other hand, the metric going down implies traders either are losing interest in the cryptocurrency or have decided to hold onto it in the long term, thus maturing past the 30-day threshold. Whatever the case be, though, a drawdown in the indicator does suggest a lack of new hands coming into the market. Now, here is a chart that shows the trend in the number of traders for the various meme coins in the sector: The data for the number of traders for meme-based tokens over the past couple of years &#124; Source: IntoTheBlock on X As displayed in the chart, Dogecoin (in blue) has consistently remained number one in terms of the number of traders, which only makes sense as DOGE has generally been the most popular meme coin, as its market cap would indicate. Hype and excitement are usually the number one driver for attracting users to a cryptocurrency. It would appear, though, that DOGE has recently been falling off in this metric. &#8220;While DOGE has long dominated almost every metric in the memecoin market, it seems to be losing some of its dominance,&#8221; says the analytics firm. The interest behind the coin may thus not be at the same level anymore. As for which meme coins have overtaken the cryptocurrency so far, IntoTheBlock notes, &#8220;DEGEN currently leads with 129k active traders, followed by DOG with 126k.&#8221; Related Reading: Bitcoin 2 Months Through “Euphoria Wave,” How Long Was The Last One? Given this high interest in these memecoins, it&#8217;s possible they may be likely to go through some volatility in the near future as all these traders make moves at once. In theory, this volatility can take these coins in either direction, but as the intelligence platform explains, &#8220;a strong increase in traders usually coincides with bullish momentum.&#8221; DOGE Price Dogecoin had slipped below the $0.17 level last week, but the coin has since bounced back as it&#8217;s now trading just under $0.20. Looks like the price of the memecoin has gone stale since its recovery push &#124; Source: DOGEUSD on TradingView Featured image from Kanchanara on Unsplash.com, IntoTheBlock.com, chart from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On-chain data suggests Dogecoin is no longer the dominant meme coin in terms of its weekly active trader count. Here are the coins above it.</p>
<h2>Dogecoin Has Been Surpassed In Trader Count By Other Memecoins</h2>
<p>According to data from the market intelligence platform <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1778450828468035932/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IntoTheBlock</a>, DOG and DEGEN are the two assets that have managed to surpass the original meme-based cryptocurrency in terms of weekly trader count.</p>
<p>A &#8220;trader&#8221; here refers to an investor who has been holding onto their coins since less than 30 days ago. These investors generally tend to move their coins often, as they play the role of active traders in the market. They are certainly not the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/litecoin/litecoin-breaks-record-hodlers-network-exceed-5-million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">HODLers</a> of the sector.</p>

<p>When the number of these traders goes up for any asset, it means that some fresh interest is potentially coming into the coin. Price actions like rallies are only sustainable when they have an ever-increasing fuel coming in, so the trader count going up can perhaps be a bullish indication in this direction.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the metric going down implies traders either are losing interest in the cryptocurrency or have decided to hold onto it in the long term, thus maturing past the 30-day threshold. Whatever the case be, though, a drawdown in the indicator does suggest a lack of new hands coming into the market.</p>
<p>Now, here is a chart that shows the trend in the number of traders for the various meme coins in the sector:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone aligncenter" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GK5RiYlXUAAzV85?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Dogecoin Number of Traders" width="903" height="500"/></p>

<p>As displayed in the chart, Dogecoin (in blue) has consistently remained number one in terms of the number of traders, which only makes sense as DOGE has generally been the most popular meme coin, as its <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-market-cap-price-surgeretesting-2021-highs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">market cap</a> would indicate.</p>
<p>Hype and excitement are usually the number one driver for attracting users to a cryptocurrency. It would appear, though, that DOGE has recently been falling off in this metric.</p>
<p>&#8220;While DOGE has long dominated almost every metric in the memecoin market, it seems to be losing some of its dominance,&#8221; says the analytics firm. The interest behind the coin may thus not be at the same level anymore.</p>
<p>As for which meme coins have overtaken the cryptocurrency so far, IntoTheBlock notes, &#8220;DEGEN currently leads with 129k active traders, followed by DOG with 126k.&#8221;</p>

<p>Given this high interest in these memecoins, it&#8217;s possible they may be likely to go through some <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-volatility-713-carnage-crypto-futures/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">volatility</a> in the near future as all these traders make moves at once.</p>
<p>In theory, this volatility can take these coins in either direction, but as the intelligence platform explains, &#8220;a strong increase in traders usually coincides with bullish momentum.&#8221;</p>
<h2>DOGE Price</h2>
<p>Dogecoin had slipped below the $0.17 level last week, but the coin has since bounced back as it&#8217;s now trading just under $0.20.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium aligncenter" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/QN86hVo2/" alt="Dogecoin Price Chart" width="1534" height="854"/></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/kanchanara-LPKJJ3M87Ho-unsplash.jpg?fit=460%2C306" width="460" height="306" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602915</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple’s 500 Million XRP Escrow Unlock Threatens Price As Bulls Struggle To Hold $0.61</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/ripple-500-million-xrp-unlock/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripple news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrpusdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[XRP has struggled to a higher degree compared to the others in the top 10 cryptocurrencies by market cap and it seems like the bearish sentiment is far from over. Ripple just unlocked a massive amount of tokens from escrow, which could threaten the price further. Ripple Unlocks 500 Million XRP In the early hours of Friday, on-chain whale tracking platform Whale Alert posted two transactions carrying a notable number of XRP tokens. The first transaction saw 200 million tokens unlocked from the escrow wallet, worth $122.63 million at the time of the transfer. Related Reading: Cardano At Risk Of Crashing To $0.4 As Important Metrics Turn Bearish The second transaction came minutes later when a total of 300 million XRP tokens were also unclosed from escrow. This second tranche of tokens, being larger than the first, was worth $183.89 million at the time, bringing the total number of unlocked tokens to 500 million. Together, both transactions were worth over $300 million. These unlocks have, unsurprisingly, stirred concern in the Ripple community for a number of reasons. One of the reasons is that Ripple never does unlocks in the middle of the month. Rather, they do scheduled unlocks at the start of each month. So, these transactions have drawn the attention of the crypto community. Another cause for concern is the fact that Ripple could be selling these XRP tokens. Hence, putting more tokens in circulation and adding more selling pressure to the already struggling digital asset. However, Ripple has not shown any indication of what these unlocks could be for as there have been no transfer transactions since then, just the unlock transactions. Unlocks Can Send Price Crashing? XRP unlocks are not new to the Ripple community, as scheduled unlocks take place every month. These unlocks see 1 billion XRP tokens unlocked from the escrow according to schedule. But most times, the majority of the unlocked tokens are sent back to escrow. Related Reading: Crypto Analyst Predicts Shiba Inu Price Will Reach $0.0001 If This Happens Usually, these unlocks do not negatively affect the altcoin’s price, but that’s when the unlocks are expected. This time around, the unlocks are unplanned, leading to speculation as to why Ripple would be unlocking XRP tokens outside of the unlock schedule. So far, the XRP price seems to not be reacting to the unlock at all. It continues to trend around $0.61, with small losses of 0.91% in the last day. However, the altcoin is still seeing 4.74% gains in the last week, showing the positive upside that it saw earlier in the week. Token price at $0.6095 &#124; Source: XRPUSDT on Tradingview.com Featured image from Linqto, chart from Tradingview.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p2">XRP has struggled to a higher degree compared to the others in the top 10 cryptocurrencies by market cap and it seems like the bearish sentiment is far from over. Ripple just unlocked a massive amount of tokens from escrow, which could threaten the price further.</p>
<h2 class="p2">Ripple Unlocks 500 Million XRP</h2>
<p class="p2">In the early hours of Friday, on-chain whale tracking platform Whale Alert posted two transactions carrying a notable number of XRP tokens. The first <a href="https://x.com/whale_alert/status/1778650667122307122" rel="nofollow">transaction</a> saw 200 million tokens unlocked from the escrow wallet, worth $122.63 million at the time of the transfer.</p>

<p class="p2">The second <a href="https://x.com/whale_alert/status/1778651535376810010" rel="nofollow">transaction</a> came minutes later when a total of 300 million <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-heading-to-100-500-analyst-provides-speculated-timeframes/">XRP tokens</a> were also unclosed from escrow. This second tranche of tokens, being larger than the first, was worth $183.89 million at the time, bringing the total number of unlocked tokens to 500 million. Together, both transactions were worth over $300 million.</p>
<p class="p2">These unlocks have, unsurprisingly, stirred concern in the Ripple community for a number of reasons. One of the reasons is that Ripple never does unlocks in the middle of the month. Rather, they do scheduled unlocks at the start of each month. So, these transactions have drawn the attention of the crypto community.</p>
<p class="p2">Another cause for concern is the fact that Ripple could be selling these <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-price-bullish-streak-0-60/">XRP tokens</a>. Hence, putting more tokens in circulation and adding more selling pressure to the already struggling digital asset. However, Ripple has not shown any indication of what these unlocks could be for as there have been no transfer transactions since then, just the unlock transactions.</p>
<h2 class="p2">Unlocks Can Send Price Crashing?</h2>
<p class="p2">XRP unlocks are not new to the Ripple community, as <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/xrp-news/xrp-price-rally-threatened-as-ripple-unlocks-1-billion-tokens/">scheduled unlocks take place every month</a>. These unlocks see 1 billion XRP tokens unlocked from the escrow according to schedule. But most times, the majority of the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/ripple-return-xrp-tokens-escrow/">unlocked tokens are sent back to escrow</a>.</p>

<p class="p2">Usually, these unlocks do not negatively affect <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/price-surge-xrp-price-20/">the altcoin’s price</a>, but that’s when the unlocks are expected. This time around, the unlocks are unplanned, leading to speculation as to why Ripple would be unlocking XRP tokens outside of the unlock schedule.</p>
<p class="p2">So far, <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-1800-surge-in-liquidations/">the XRP price</a> seems to not be reacting to the unlock at all. It continues to trend around $0.61, with small losses of 0.91% in the last day. However, the altcoin is still seeing 4.74% gains in the last week, showing the positive upside that it saw earlier in the week.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/jOoV6Lol/" alt="XRP price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530"/></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_103303.jpeg?fit=275%2C183" width="275" height="183" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602885</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Halving RoadMap: Analyst Outlines 3 Phases For Market Dynamics</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-halving-roadmap-analyst-outlines-3-phases-for-market-dynamics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Godspower Owie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 13:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parabolic Uptrend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-Halving Retrace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Re-Accumulation Range]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rekt Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin is now hovering around the $70,000 threshold after a notable recovery it witnessed a few days ago. Due to the recent momentum, crypto enthusiasts are becoming less pessimistic about the digital asset&#8217;s growth prior to the halving event. With the fast approaching much-anticipated Bitcoin Halving, Rekt Capital, a well-recognized cryptocurrency analyst and aficionado, has offered his market insights mapping out three distinct stages of the event for investors. 3 Distinct Aspects Of The Bitcoin Halving Rekt Capital&#8217;s analysis delves into Bitcoin&#8216;s movement before and after the halving takes place, which is expected to happen this month. In the seven days leading up to the occurrence, the crypto analyst underscored three stages to observe for a successful outcome. Related Reading: Bitcoin To $150,000 Is “Programmed” With Halving Approaching: Analyst These three phases include the final pre-halving retrace, the re-accumulation phase, and the parabolic uptrend phase. Emphasizing on the first aspect, Rekt Capital noted that the pre-halving retrace is documented in the books and has already manifested. During this period, Bitcoin experienced an 18% pullback compared to 2016 and 2020&#8217;s retracement of 38% and 19%, respectively. The expert believes that the concluded pre-halving Retrace was the last chance to purchase a deal during the pre-halving phase. Following the conclusion of the retrace, Rekt Capital has confirmed the development has laid the groundwork for the Re-accumulation range. It is important to note that the aforementioned range occurs a few weeks ahead of the halving, and it ends with a breakout from it a few weeks later. Specifically, the period could last for several weeks and up to 150 days or five months. Given the manifestation of the range, sideways movement through the halving and beyond is the major purpose of BTC. Thus, the analyst has stressed the need to be patient around this phase, as many investors get frustrated, bored, and disappointed here because their Bitcoin investments lack significant returns. As a result, they lose confidence and get shaken out of the market before the event. BTC&#8217;s Post-Halving Rally Might Mirror Previous Trend As for the parabolic uptrend, Rekt Capital claims the phase will begin when Bitcoin breaks out from the re-accumulation range. He further stated that the price of BTC tends to grow more quickly and enters a parabolic upsurge during this stage. Related Reading: Bitcoin To Go ‘Ballistic’ After Halving, Says Top Analyst – Here’s Why According to the expert, this area has typically lasted about a year or a little more, particularly around 385 days in the past. However, with the possible accelerated cycle that is currently in development, the period could be halved within this bull market cycle. Rekt Capital&#8217;s key perspectives came amidst Bitcoin demonstrating strength to revisit its current all-time high of $73,000. BTC has managed to amass gains of more than 6% in the past few days. It recovered to the $70,000 level after plunging as low as $67,000 on Wednesday and is getting close to $71,000. At the time of writing, BTC was trading at $70,854, indicating over 6% increase in the past week. Its market capitalization is up by 1% and its trading volume has plummeted by more than 21% over the past day. Given the current trend in the coin market, BTC could be in a position to see even bigger gains in the months to come. Featured image from iStock, chart from Tradingview.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bitcoin is now hovering around the $70,000 threshold after a notable recovery it witnessed a few days ago. Due to the recent momentum, crypto enthusiasts are becoming less pessimistic about the digital asset&#8217;s growth prior to the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-halving-a-look-at-post-halving-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">halving event</a>. </strong>With the fast approaching much-anticipated Bitcoin Halving, Rekt Capital, a well-recognized cryptocurrency analyst and aficionado, has offered his market insights mapping out three distinct stages of the event for investors.</p>
<h2>3 Distinct Aspects Of The Bitcoin Halving</h2>
<p>Rekt Capital&#8217;s analysis delves into <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-hits-record-high-in-halving/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin</a>&#8216;s movement before and after the halving takes place, which is expected to happen this month. In the seven days leading up to the occurrence, the crypto analyst underscored three stages to observe for a successful outcome.</p>

<p>These three phases include the final pre-halving retrace, the re-accumulation phase, and the parabolic uptrend phase. Emphasizing on the first aspect, Rekt Capital noted that the pre-halving retrace is documented in the books and has already manifested.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-602945" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C325" alt="Bitcoin" width="460" height="325" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=1794 1794w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C325 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=120 120w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rekt-Capital-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" data-recalc-dims="1"/>
<p>During this period, Bitcoin experienced an 18% pullback compared to 2016 and 2020&#8217;s retracement of 38% and 19%, respectively. The expert believes that the concluded pre-halving Retrace was the last chance to purchase a deal during the pre-halving phase.</p>
<p>Following the conclusion of the retrace, Rekt Capital has confirmed the development has laid the groundwork for the Re-accumulation range. It is important to note that the aforementioned range occurs a few weeks ahead of the halving, and it ends with a breakout from it a few weeks later.</p>
<p>Specifically, the period could last for several weeks and up to 150 days or five months. Given the manifestation of the range, sideways movement through the halving and beyond is the major purpose of BTC.</p>
<p>Thus, the analyst has stressed the need to be patient around this phase, as many <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/ultra-wealthy-investing-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">investors</a> get frustrated, bored, and disappointed here because their Bitcoin investments lack significant returns. As a result, they lose confidence and get shaken out of the market before the event.</p>
<h2>BTC&#8217;s Post-Halving Rally Might Mirror Previous Trend</h2>
<p>As for the parabolic uptrend, Rekt Capital claims the phase will begin when Bitcoin breaks out from the re-accumulation range. He further stated that the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-resumes-upside-why-btc-could-soon-hit-new-ath/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">price of BTC</a> tends to grow more quickly and enters a parabolic upsurge during this stage.</p>

<p>According to the expert, this area has typically lasted about a year or a little more, particularly around 385 days in the past. However, with the possible accelerated cycle that is currently in development, the period could be halved within this bull market cycle.</p>
<p>Rekt Capital&#8217;s key perspectives came amidst Bitcoin demonstrating strength to revisit its current all-time high of $73,000. BTC has managed to amass gains of more than 6% in the past few days.</p>
<p>It recovered to the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-70000-despite-negative-taker-volume/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">$70,000</a> level after plunging as low as $67,000 on Wednesday and is getting close to $71,000. At the time of writing, BTC was trading at $70,854, indicating over 6% increase in the past week.</p>
<p>Its market capitalization is up by 1% and its trading volume has plummeted by more than 21% over the past day. Given the current trend in the coin market, BTC could be in a position to see even bigger gains in the months to come.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/uPdwXGHG/" alt="Bitcoin" width="2273" height="1351"/>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/iStock-1296910866.jpg?fit=460%2C283" width="460" height="283" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602938</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardano (ADA) Prints ‘Undeniable Bull Run’ Signal: Crypto Analyst</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/cardano/cardano-ada-prints-undeniable-bull-run-signal-crypto-analyst/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cardano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADA Bull Run]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADA price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adausd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano Bull Run]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano Price Prediction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=602879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The price of Cardano (ADA) has experienced a decline in recent weeks. Following a peak at a 23-month high at $0.808 on March 11, the price of ADA has fallen by over 28%, and it is now hovering just below the $0.60 level. Notably, Cardano has underperformed compared to its competitors, slipping to the 10th position among the largest cryptocurrencies by market cap. However, a crypto analyst, known as Trend Rider (@TrendRidersTR) on X, has declared that ADA is showing clear signs of a bull run based on technical analysis of its Relative Strength Index (RSI) and Simple Moving Average (SMA) crossovers. What This Means For Cardano Price According to Trend Rider&#8217;s recent post on X, Cardano&#8217;s current market behavior mirrors a rare pattern in the one month chart (ADA/USD) observed only once before, which led to a significant price surge from $0.05 to $3.00. Related Reading: Cardano At Risk Of Crashing To $0.4 As Important Metrics Turn Bearish The analyst emphasized, &#8220;ADA&#8217;s undeniable bull run is here. With its second RSI crossover in history, it&#8217;s reminiscent of when prices soared from $0.05 to $3. This rare event, marking a potential trend shift as the RSI crosses its SMA, has flawlessly predicted past cycles shifts at it&#8217;s early stages.” The analysis presented by Trend Rider focuses on the RSI, a momentum oscillator that measures the speed and change of price movements, and its crossover with the SMA, a common trading signal interpreted as a potential bullish or bearish market indicator. The post details three critical phases in Cardano’s recent market activity. The first crossover occurred shortly after the COVID-19 pandemic onset when ADA traded at $0.19, marked by a substantial price increase following the crossover event. At the end of the 2021 bull run, a bearish crossover took place that heralded a prolonged bear market. “Notice how perfect the bearish crossover anticipated the bear market. This is an extremely strong validation for this indicator. Making it very relevant to predict ADA long term cycles,” the analyst states. The second bullish crossover of the RSI with the SMA occurred in October and November 2023, this event was initially met with market rejection a few months earlier, adding credibility to the indicator&#8217;s reliability in predicting long-term market trends. Related Reading: “Where It Should Be”: Crypto Analyst Remains Firm On $1.7 Prediction For Cardano (ADA) Trend Rider concludes, &#8220;The RSI and its SMA crossovers are an extremely reliable source to identify ADA bull runs and bear markets at its early stages.&#8221; This analysis suggests that Cardano is currently entering a bull market phase, reinforcing the optimistic outlook for ADA. Moreover, the analyst warned the one-month chart reflects a macro perspective for holders, “each candle represents one month, so you can expect huge volatility within each candle.” Furthermore, he cautioned of the inherent risks in crypto investments, noting the importance of a personalized investment strategy to navigate potential market volatility and unforeseen events, often referred to as &#8216;black swan&#8217; events. &#8220;VERY IMPORTANT: Personally, these macro charts help me see the bigger picture, but I always use my own process to secure profits and protect myself from any black swan event,&#8221; Trend Rider added. If history is any indicator, the current patterns could spell a lucrative phase for Cardano holders, but as always in crypto markets, caution remains a critical companion to enthusiasm. Featured image from Biztech Africa, chart from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The price of Cardano (ADA) has experienced a decline in recent weeks. Following a peak at a 23-month high at $0.808 on March 11, the price of ADA has fallen by over 28%, and it is now hovering just below the $0.60 level. Notably, Cardano has underperformed compared to its competitors, slipping to the 10th position among the largest cryptocurrencies by market cap.</p>
<p>However, a crypto analyst, known as Trend Rider (@TrendRidersTR) on X, has <a href="https://twitter.com/TrendRidersTR/status/1778421636959490228" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">declared</a> that ADA is showing clear signs of a bull run based on technical analysis of its Relative Strength Index (RSI) and Simple Moving Average (SMA) crossovers.</p>
<h2>What This Means For Cardano Price</h2>
<p>According to Trend Rider&#8217;s recent post on X, Cardano&#8217;s current market behavior mirrors a rare pattern in the one month chart (ADA/USD) observed only once before, which led to a significant price surge from $0.05 to $3.00.</p>

<p>The analyst emphasized, &#8220;ADA&#8217;s undeniable bull run is here. With its second RSI crossover in history, it&#8217;s reminiscent of when prices soared from $0.05 to $3. This rare event, marking a potential trend shift as the RSI crosses its SMA, has flawlessly predicted past cycles shifts at it&#8217;s early stages.”</p>
<p>The analysis presented by Trend Rider focuses on the RSI, a momentum oscillator that measures the speed and change of price movements, and its crossover with the SMA, a common trading signal interpreted as a potential bullish or bearish market indicator.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-602933 size-full" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900" alt="Cardano price analysis" width="1600" height="900" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900?w=1600 1600w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GK45AMaWwAAPLbl.jpg?resize=1600%2C900?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/>
<p>The post details three critical phases in Cardano’s recent market activity. The first crossover occurred shortly after the COVID-19 pandemic onset when ADA traded at $0.19, marked by a substantial price increase following the crossover event.</p>
<p>At the end of the 2021 bull run, a bearish crossover took place that heralded a prolonged bear market. “Notice how perfect the bearish crossover anticipated the bear market. This is an extremely strong validation for this indicator. Making it very relevant to predict ADA long term cycles,” the analyst states.</p>
<p>The second bullish crossover of the RSI with the SMA occurred in October and November 2023, this event was initially met with market rejection a few months earlier, adding credibility to the indicator&#8217;s reliability in predicting long-term market trends.</p>

<p>Trend Rider concludes, &#8220;The RSI and its SMA crossovers are an extremely reliable source to identify ADA bull runs and bear markets at its early stages.&#8221; This analysis suggests that Cardano is currently entering a bull market phase, reinforcing the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/cardano/where-it-should-be-crypto-analyst-remains-firm-on-1-7-prediction-for-cardano-ada/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">optimistic outlook for ADA</a>.</p>
<p>Moreover, the analyst warned the one-month chart reflects a macro perspective for holders, “each candle represents one month, so you can expect huge volatility within each candle.” Furthermore, he cautioned of the inherent risks in crypto investments, noting the importance of a personalized investment strategy to navigate potential market volatility and unforeseen events, often referred to as <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/ripple-2/ripple-victory-black-swan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">&#8216;black swan&#8217; events</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;VERY IMPORTANT: Personally, these macro charts help me see the bigger picture, but I always use my own process to secure profits and protect myself from any black swan event,&#8221; Trend Rider added.</p>
<p>If history is any indicator, the current patterns could spell a lucrative phase for <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/cardano/cardano-holders-disappointed-over-initial-4-6-estimated-staking-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Cardano holders</a>, but as always in crypto markets, caution remains a critical companion to enthusiasm.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Cardano-ADA-Jumps-To-18-Month-High.png?fit=460%2C261" width="460" height="261" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">602879</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
