<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<description>Neutral and Authentic News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:36:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cropped-Dark_CP_Symbol-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Join Us at the ICP Global Townhall</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/join-us-at-the-icp-global-townhall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guest User]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What Is the ICP Global Townhall? The ICP Global Townhall is an innovative 24-hour online event happening on April 26th powered by ICP HUBS NETWORK. This unique gathering unites experts, enthusiasts, and new participants from around the world to explore the latest in Internet Computer technology.&#160; The Global Townhall is designed to share insights, foster [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Is the ICP Global Townhall?</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://lu.ma/icp-global-townhall-ep-1-6" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">ICP Global Townhall</a> is an innovative <strong>24-hour online</strong> <strong>event happening on April 26th </strong>powered by <a href="https://twitter.com/ICPHUBS" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><strong>ICP HUBS NETWORK</strong></a>. This unique gathering unites experts, enthusiasts, and new participants from around the world to explore the latest in Internet Computer technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Global Townhall is designed to share insights, foster collaboration, and showcase innovations pushing decentralized technology&#8217;s edge. Whether you&#8217;re looking to learn, network, or contribute, this event offers an inclusive platform to engage with the growing ICP community around the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bulgaria &amp; Poland Segment</h2>



<p><strong>From 1:00 PM to 3:00 PM GMT+2</strong>, join the ICP HUBS from Bulgaria and Poland for an insightful two-hour session dedicated to AI and effective strategies for community building within the ICP ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prominent Hub Leads Josip Vlah and Maciej Orłowski will host this segment and will feature discussions with industry leaders and community representatives.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Highlights of The Segment Include</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>AI on ICP </strong>&#8211; Discuss the current and future potential of AI technologies with ICP.</li>



<li><strong>Strengthening the Community </strong>&#8211; Learn about successful community engagement strategies and hear inspiring success stories.</li>



<li><strong>Cross-Collaboration in Blockchain </strong>&#8211; Explore impactful collaborations that help drive growth in the blockchain space.</li>



<li><strong>AI &amp; Community building &#8211; a perspective from Industry Leaders</strong> &#8211; Delve into the long-term relevance of AI in the Web3 environment with top voices from the industry.</li>



<li><strong>Highlighting ICP Innovations</strong> &#8211; Discover notable projects and contributions within the ICP ecosystem.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join the Event</h2>



<p>Ready to be part of this pioneering event? Register now at the <a href="https://lu.ma/icp-global-townhall-ep-1-6" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">ICP Global Townhall Luma page</a> to secure your spot. Also, make sure to follow <a href="https://t.co/CNmtBgQHkK" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ICP HUB Bulgaria</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/ICPHUB_PL" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">ICP HUB Poland</a> on our social platforms to stay updated with the latest news and event highlights.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t miss this opportunity to connect with leaders and visionaries in the ICP community and perhaps even win some exclusive perks and giveaways. See you there!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/KOL-3.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/KOL-3.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Floki Inu Price Prediction 2024-2033: Can FLOKI Surpass Previous ATH?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/floki-inu-price-prediction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Narmin Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto Price Predictions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency investment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=206004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Floki Inu Price Prediction 2024-2033 In case you&#8217;re wondering, here&#8217;s a bit of trivia: &#8220;Floki&#8221; means &#8220;heroic Viking,&#8221; and is said to be the name of the Viking who discovered, and named Iceland. In June 2021, Elon Musk tweeted that he would be naming his pet Shiba Inu “Floki.” This led to the birth of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2024-2033</h4>



<ul>
<li><a href="#Floki-Inu-Price-Prediction-2024">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2024 – up to <strong>$0.000010</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Floki-Inu-Price-Prediction-2027">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2027 – up to <strong>$0.000033</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Floki-Inu-Price-Prediction-2030">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2030 – up to <strong>$0.000104</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Floki-Inu-Price-Prediction-2033">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2033 – up to<strong> $0.000326</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>In case you&#8217;re wondering, here&#8217;s a bit of trivia: &#8220;Floki&#8221; means &#8220;heroic Viking,&#8221; and is said to be the name of the Viking who discovered, and named Iceland. In June 2021, Elon Musk tweeted that he would be naming his pet Shiba Inu “Floki.” This led to the birth of the Floki Inu coin. While starting out as a dog-meme coin, Floki has become more than that due to its community. </p>



<p><strong>What does the future hold for the token?</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How Much is Floki Inu Worth?</h4>



<p>Today, Floki Inu is priced at $0.000188, with a 24-hour trading volume of $387.92M. Its market capitalization stands at $1.80B, with a market dominance of 0.07%. Over the last 24 hours, the FLOKI price has decreased by -1.79%. Sentiment analysis suggests a bullish outlook for Floki Inu&#8217;s price prediction, while the Fear &amp; Greed Index indicates a score of 72 (Greed). Currently, there are 9.57 trillion FLOKI tokens in circulation out of a maximum supply of 20.00 trillion FLOKI. The yearly supply inflation rate is -1.46%, indicating a decrease of -141.41 billion FLOKI over the last year. In terms of market cap, Floki Inu holds the #2 position in the NFT Tokens sector and #5 position in the Meme Coins sector.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu price analysis: FLOKI shows bearish momentum at $0.000188</h2>



<p>TL;DR Breakdown</p>



<ul>
<li>Floki Inu price analysis confirms a bearish movement.</li>



<li>Resistance for FLOKI is present at $0.000223.</li>



<li>Current Price of FLOKI is $0.000188.</li>
</ul>



<p>On April 24, 2024, the Floki Inu market experienced significant fluctuations. The day started with a noticeable uptick, reaching a peak of $0.000203. However, this upward movement was short-lived, quickly followed by a decline to a new daily low of $0.000187. Despite this sudden drop, the price stabilized and remained relatively steady thereafter. Despite concerns about potential cryptocurrency market volatility, overall sentiment stayed largely optimistic. Technical analysis of Floki Inu&#8217;s current valuation suggests a consistent pattern, ultimately settling at $0.000188. Moreover, the recent upward price movement indicates a shift towards bullish sentiment, possibly signaling a positive market outlook in the near future.</p>



<p>Floki Inu encountered notable volatility, starting with an initial surge to $0.000203, swiftly followed by a decline to $0.000187. Despite this turbulence, the price stabilized and maintained a steady trajectory thereafter. Despite apprehensions about cryptocurrency market fluctuations, general sentiment remained optimistic, supported by a technical analysis revealing a consistent pattern and eventual settling at $0.000188. Additionally, recent upward price movements hinted at a shift towards bullish sentiment, potentially indicating a positive market outlook in the short term.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu price analysis for 1-hour</h3>



<p>In the current market environment, Floki Inu is navigating through a landscape marked by bearish tendencies, gradual declines, and heightened volatility, which have elicited mixed sentiments among traders and investors amid ongoing uncertainties. Notably, a resistance level at $0.000205, aligning with the upper boundary of the Bollinger Bands, presents a potential obstacle to significant upward price movements. Conversely, another resistance level at $0.000188 serves as a robust defense against notable price declines, fostering an overall sense of stability. Close monitoring of these critical price levels is essential, as breaching the support level has historically resulted in increased market volatility, offering crucial insights into Floki Inu&#8217;s potential future trajectory and enabling market participants to make well-informed decisions amidst evolving market dynamics.</p>



<p>Floki Inu&#8217;s sustained negativity has garnered significant attention, with discussions revolving around the Moving Average trend sparking speculation about potential future price fluctuations for the cryptocurrency. Investors and traders are closely analyzing critical levels and indicators to assess Floki Inu&#8217;s resilience and anticipate shifts in market trends. The dynamic interaction between moving averages, resistance, and support has become a focal point in Floki Inu&#8217;s evolving market narrative, captivating traders as they devise decision-making strategies. It&#8217;s crucial to acknowledge that price movements are amplified by the market&#8217;s inherent volatility, further fueling the current environment of pronounced market fluctuation.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1200" height="544" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-103-1200x544.png" alt="" class="wp-image-515804" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-103-1200x544.png 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-103-300x136.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-103-768x348.png 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-103-1536x697.png 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-103.png 1788w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em><em>FLOKI/USD 1-hour price chart Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/FLOKIUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></em></em></figcaption></figure>



<p>With a Relative Strength Index (RSI) score of 41, indicating a relatively low level, the cryptocurrency market, as reflected by the observed price fluctuations in Floki Inu, appears to be stable. The pronounced downward trend in the RSI suggests a significant imbalance between buying and selling activity, with selling activities currently outweighing buying activities. However, despite this imbalance, prevailing market sentiment appears to favor bears, potentially influenced by recent news events or increasing investor confidence in the FLOKI cryptocurrency. This underscores the importance of maintaining a keen awareness of external variables and market dynamics when making investment decisions in this dynamic and ever-evolving financial landscape. By staying informed and vigilant, investors can better navigate uncertainty and capitalize on opportunities in the cryptocurrency market.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu 1-day price analysis: FLOKI bearish at $0.000188</h3>



<p>A detailed analysis of Floki Inu&#8217;s price performance unveils an underlying bearish market sentiment marked by a declining trend that maintains a generally steady trajectory, occasionally interspersed with minor price fluctuations. Despite these fluctuations, the cryptocurrency has demonstrated resilience by consistently remaining within the range indicated by the Moving Average. However, it&#8217;s prudent to exercise caution when assessing critical price levels, particularly given the notable resistance observed at $0.000223, which may hinder substantial upward price movements. Conversely, a secondary support level is identified around $0.000118. Breaching this level could precipitate heightened market volatility, underscoring the importance of vigilant observation and prudent decision-making in response to evolving market conditions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="545" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-104-1200x545.png" alt="" class="wp-image-515805" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-104-1200x545.png 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-104-300x136.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-104-768x349.png 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-104-1536x697.png 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-104.png 1787w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em><em>FLOKI/USD 1-day price chart Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/FLOKIUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TradingView</a></em></em></figcaption></figure>



<p>With a Relative Strength Index (RSI) score of 53 indicating stable dynamics, the observed price changes in Floki Inu suggest a balanced market sentiment. The downward trend in the RSI indicates more selling activity than buying, contributing to an overall sense of stability. This stability may be influenced by recent news events or fluctuations in investor confidence in the FLOKI cryptocurrency. It underscores the importance of comprehending external factors and market dynamics when making investment decisions in the dynamic financial landscape. To effectively navigate the inherent volatility, investors should remain vigilant and adapt their strategies in response to evolving market conditions and external influences.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What to Expect from the Floki Inu Price Analysis</h3>



<p>The way that the Floki Inu market performs is a good representation of the landscape&#8217;s moods and price movements, which are influenced by a variety of factors such as market dynamics, technical indicators, and outside news. Floki Inu has demonstrated stability and resilience in the face of unpredictability and unfavorable trends. It has attracted interest from traders and investors while remaining within significant price ranges. Relative Strength Index (RSI) and moving averages are two significant levels and indicators that are regularly examined to offer analytical data about the cryptocurrency market and assist investors in making informed decisions. In order to effectively manage risks and capitalize on possibilities in the always evolving cryptocurrency market, investors must remain vigilant and adapt their strategies as the market grows.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recent News on Floki Inu</h2>



<p>In order to effectively manage risks and capitalize on possibilities in the always evolving cryptocurrency market, investors must remain vigilant and adapt their strategies as the market grows. In order to earn points for their different clans, players are advised to cooperate in order to complete missions and in-game activities. There is going to be a competitive element where different clans are vying for power. Visit the game&#8217;s official website by clicking the provided link for more details. Additionally, channels for community participation on Telegram and Discord are available for discussion. The entire message seeks to promote interaction, strategic discussions, and participation in the scheduled time-limited event, with #Valhalla linking the content to the game or subject.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is FLOKI a good investment?</h2>



<p>Based on our price analysis, investing in Floki Inu presents potential opportunities but also significant risks. While the analysis indicates periods of stability and resilience, the cryptocurrency market, including FLOKI, is inherently volatile and subject to fluctuations influenced by various factors. Factors such as bearish momentum, resistance levels, and ongoing market uncertainties underscore the need for careful consideration and risk management. Investors should conduct thorough research, assess their risk tolerance, and diversify their investment portfolio before considering FLOKI or any other cryptocurrency. Seeking advice from financial professionals can provide valuable insights tailored to individual circumstances and goals, helping investors make informed decisions in the dynamic cryptocurrency market landscape.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2024 – 2033</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Predictions by Cryptopolitan</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/pMUkegYD0Luii8OJQbrb8G3C0QvL2QnZ04lNaCA9ejeuhm1tdWF_CQ83C6hiOQkYnDegiMlJNx-qtdqey4fcJNr7w_Dzic4mgfy5TWEXMMlS_yjIAiU0SU5YXglNjfa9Q_1iX4ZJqTYNmyadAVNHmwU" alt="" title="Points scored" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>YEAR</strong></td><td><strong>MINIMUM</strong></td><td><strong>AVERAGE</strong></td><td><strong>MAXIMUM</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>2024</strong></td><td>$0.000009</td><td>$0.000009</td><td>$0.000010</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2025</strong></td><td>$0.000013</td><td>$0.000013</td><td>$0.000015</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2026</strong></td><td>$0.000019</td><td>$0.000019</td><td>$0.000022</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2027</strong></td><td>$0.000027</td><td>$0.000028</td><td>$0.000033</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2028</strong></td><td>$0.000041</td><td>$0.000042</td><td>$0.000048</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2029</strong></td><td>$0.000060</td><td>$0.000062</td><td>$0.000071</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2030</strong></td><td>$0.000087</td><td>$0.000090</td><td>$0.000104</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2031</strong></td><td>$0.000130</td><td>$0.000135</td><td>$0.000150</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2032</strong></td><td>$0.000188</td><td>$0.000194</td><td>$0.000221</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2033</strong></td><td>$0.000274</td><td>$0.000284</td><td>$0.000326</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2024</h4>



<p>In our Floki Inu price prediction 2024, we anticipate a potential upward trend in its trajectory. There is a possibility for Floki Inu to reach a <strong>peak price of $0.000010</strong>. However, on its way to this level, the cryptocurrency could encounter a potential minimum price floor of $0.000009 to buy FLOKI. According to our projections, we expect the average price of FLOKI to hover around $0.000009. It&#8217;s important to note that cryptocurrency markets are inherently unpredictable, and various factors such as market cap can influence price movements in the crypto market, so these forecasts should be approached with caution.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2025</h4>



<p>In the anticipated Floki Inu price prediction for the year 2025, there is a notable inclination for the cryptocurrency to uphold a minimum value, aiming to remain above $0.000013. Furthermore, an envisioned scenario suggests the possibility of Floki prices reaching a <strong>peak price of $0.000015</strong>. This upward trajectory is expected to align with the cryptocurrency sustaining an average trading price, with projections hovering around $0.000013 throughout the entirety of the year.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2026</h4>



<p>In our 2026 Floki Inu price prediction, we foresee a notable level of volatility in the FLOKI market valuation. The potential for Floki&#8217;s price to attain <strong>its peak at $0.000022</strong> suggests significant opportunities for growth. Additionally, our average price projection for Floki Inu in 2026 revolves around $0.000019. At the lower end of this spectrum, our expectation positions the minimum projected price at approximately $0.000019.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2027</h4>



<p>In our Floki Inu price prediction for 2027, we anticipate the cryptocurrency potentially reaching a <strong>peak value of $0.000033.</strong> The mean price projection suggests a value of approximately $0.000028, indicating substantial growth potential. Within our projected range, the lower boundary is estimated at around $0.000027. This expectation underscores the likelihood of significant fluctuations in the cryptocurrency&#8217;s valuation, with an overall trajectory indicating a potential upward momentum.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2028</h4>



<p>In our Floki Inu price prediction for 2028, there exists the potential for the cryptocurrency to achieve its highest point with a <strong>peak price of $0.000048</strong>. Additionally, we anticipate a minimum trading price of $0.000041, indicating a plausible support level for the FLOKI coin. The expected average market value is foreseen to exhibit relative stability, maintaining a position around $0.000042. This forecast outlines a scenario where the cryptocurrency could undergo both peak performance and establish a resilient baseline, contributing to a comprehensive outlook for the upcoming year.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2029</h4>



<p>In our Floki Inu price prediction for 2029, there is an anticipation that the cryptocurrency may reach a <strong>peak price of $0.000071</strong>, indicating potential growth compared to the preceding year. Throughout the year, the coin is also expected to encounter a minimum price point of $0.000061. Additionally, the average trading price is forecasted to demonstrate relative stability, sustaining a level in the vicinity of $0.000062 throughout the duration of the period. This forecast illustrates a landscape where Floki Inu exhibits both the potential for upward momentum and a resilient baseline, contributing to an overall comprehensive outlook for the upcoming year.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2030</h4>



<p>In our FLOKI price prediction for 2030, we anticipate the cryptocurrency potentially reaching its peak with a <strong>maximum price of $0.0000104</strong>. Conversely, our forecast indicates a minimum price of $0.000090, suggesting a potential support level for the cryptocurrency. Additionally, our analysis suggests the possibility of intermittent price retracements, ultimately contributing to price stability with an average value resting at approximately $0.000087. This projection outlines a scenario where Floki Inu may experience fluctuations but maintains a relatively stable average value over the course of the year.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2031</h4>



<p>In our Floki Inu price prediction for the year 2031, we anticipate a favorable trajectory for the FLOKI token, surpassing its current levels. Our projections highlight a minimum expected price of $0.000135, underscoring a potential support level for the cryptocurrency. The estimated average price for the year hovers around $0.000135, signaling a stable trading range. Additionally, we envision the coin&#8217;s <strong>maximum price potentially reaching $0.000150</strong>. These projections collectively suggest the potential for a dual scenario, encompassing both price growth and stability within the Floki Inu cryptocurrency throughout the year 2031.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2032</h4>



<p>In our Floki Inu price prediction for the year 2032, we foresee a widening price range for Floki Inu, with the potential to reach a <strong>maximum price of $0.000221.</strong> This suggests a continuation of the bullish trend observed in the previous year. Additionally, our projection indicates a minimum price of $0.000188, signifying a potential support level. The average price projection for Floki Inu in 2032 is estimated to be approximately $0.000194, highlighting the potential for price stability within this range. These forecasts imply the possibility of both price expansion and periods of stability within the Floki Inu cryptocurrency in 2032.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2033</h4>



<p>In our Floki Inu price prediction for 2033, we envision an expanding price range for the cryptocurrency, potentially reaching a <strong>maximum of $0.000326</strong>. This signals a continuation of the positive trend observed in the preceding year. Additionally, our projection suggests a minimum price of $0.000274, indicating a potential support level. The average price estimate for Floki Inu in 2033 stands at approximately $0.000284, emphasizing the potential for price stability within this range. These Floki Inu price predictions indicate the likelihood of both price expansion and periods of stability within the Floki Inu cryptocurrency during the year 2033.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Predictions by CoinCodex</h4>



<p>By May 6, 2024, the price of Floki Inu is expected to increase by 230.27% and reach $0.000649, based on CoinCodex&#8217;s current price estimate. Technically speaking, the mood is currently bearish, with the Fear &amp; Greed Index reading 75 (Greed). Over the previous 30 days, Floki Inu achieved 17/30 (57%) green days and 11.40% price volatility. The Floki Inu forecast indicates that this is not a good time to purchase Floki Inu.&nbsp; The 2025 Floki Inu price prediction for the annual low is $0.000196. In the meantime, it&#8217;s expected that in 2026, the cost of Floki Inu could reach as high as $0.000525. The Floki Inu price estimate for 2030, based on the same criteria, is $0.000503 at lowest and $0.000816 at highest.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Predictions by DigitalCoinPrice</h4>



<p>According to DigitalCoinPrice&#8217;s forecasts, the price of Floki Inu is expected to rise during the next ten years. The price is predicted to rise significantly, with a range of $0.000173 to $0.000426 by 2024. This pattern is expected to persist through 2027, with a range of $0.000746 to $0.000887. The predicted price is expected to continue growing, with levels between $0.00130 and $0.00145 by 2030. With values ranging from $0.00363 to $0.00377, the price is predicted to climb little in 2033, indicating possibly slower growth in the future.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price Predictions by PricePredictions.net</h4>



<p>Based on PricePrediction.net&#8217;s study of Floki Inu&#8217;s price trajectory, consistent rise is anticipated over the next several decades. Prices are predicted to remain stable in 2024, ranging from $0.000009 to $0.000010. Values are expected to rise dramatically by 2027, from $0.000027 to $0.000033, indicating a discernible rising trend. Prices are predicted to range from $0.000087 to $0.000104 by 2030, indicating further increase and growing trust. Prices are predicted to rise to between $0.000274 and $0.000326 by 2033, indicating sustained high performance. A significant increase in value is anticipated in 2040, ranging from $0.0042 to $0.0053, indicating market maturity. Last but not least, prices are predicted to fluctuate between $0.0068 and $0.0079 by 2050, indicating ongoing optimism about Floki Inu&#8217;s long-term prospects.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Overview</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Popularity</strong></td><td>#58</td><td><strong>Market Cap</strong></td><td>$1,940,686,875</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price Change (24 hours)</strong></td><td>3.35%</td><td><strong>Trading Volume (24 hours)</strong></td><td>$197,085,080</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price change (7 days)</strong></td><td>-20.89%</td><td><strong>Circulating Supply</strong></td><td>9,558,727,875,277 FLOKI</td></tr><tr><td><strong>All-time low </strong>(Aug 09, 2021)</td><td>$0.00000002</td><td><strong>All-time high </strong>(Nov 04, 2021)</td><td>$0.0003437</td></tr><tr><td><strong>From ATL</strong></td><td>+1014538.61%</td><td><strong>From ATH</strong></td><td>-40.95%</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Price History</h2>



<p>Floki Inu was initially released to the public on Gate.io startup. 2B Floki were offered for the crowdsale, and 8,365 users participated, with 99.51% of the orders completed successfully. $23M was committed for sale, and each user got about 242072.13749697 Floki tokens. Floki Inu commenced trading on Sep 16th, AM 08:30 UTC on the cryptocurrency market.</p>



<p>CoinMarketCap indicates the first Floki Inu price of $0.000004. In October 2021, the Floki Inu price surged with a high trading volume. The high uptake pushed Floki to its all-time high price of $0.0003437 on 4 November 2021. The Floki Inu price today is 96% below its ATH.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/tgMntl0ze0pr0OdM6-ymlEUOVC-VXmxhA4VEZVlUH3KLpjSMps5EpKXdwgS-XJ5vLL80-tgEsA5HYPfLzasi4VQ-eSvEL2NzoHAgVjQHStQz33yW6kBj16XGpQ1pWtnN5fjcBjelRUj9MQ2ywMQXoio" alt="" /></figure>



<p>This year, Floki opened at $0.000111. Floki broke the support 4 days later to a continuous bear run. Floki is down 90% from the year’s opening price.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/QbvCDvQJnewrbm15yTA6Cj2NHnpwSWdD-MpodudlnUMx1u7zU6eF4f0J1kMrLg1Lop6u0Ga0Nqr6UZ6exCeR4uGvyQPf37JV-mqefjJN0W3yAPWKfk0oCrBNzJh9ef3qAvm8svW8l0fDJs6SB5s3Q4k" alt="" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on Floki Inu Network</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is Floki Inu?</h3>



<p>Floki Inu is part of a family of meme coins that are community owned. Floki Inu stands out from other meme coins because it creates utility for its community, i.e., Floki Vikings. Floki Inu follows the footsteps of the famous Shiba Inu, which has a significant and active community.</p>



<p>Floki Inu gives power and opportunities to the people instead of hedge funds and venture capitalists. Floki plans to become the most popular and utilized coin in the crypto space.</p>



<p>Floki Inu&nbsp;reached its highest price on&nbsp;Nov 4, 2021,&nbsp;when it was trading at its all-time high of&nbsp;$ 0.000342. The lowest price since its ATH was&nbsp;$ 0.000005&nbsp;(cycle low). The highest&nbsp;FLOKI&nbsp;price since the last cycle low was&nbsp;$ 0.000012&nbsp;(cycle high).&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How Does Floki Inu Work?</h3>



<p>The Floki coin is the native token of the Floki Inu ecosystem. The coin is available on the Ethereum blockchain and the Binance smart chain; the cross-compatibility enables Floki users to leverage the strengths of both blockchains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Floki Inu has a maximum supply of 10 trillion, with 9,071,605,014,287 Floki tokens in circulation. There is a 3% tax on every Floki coin trade; the tax is used for development, adoption initiatives, charity, marketing, and partnerships.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Team behind Floki Inu</h3>



<p>Floki is community led with plans to adopt a decentralized autonomous organization (DAO). Floki members are referred to as Floki Vikings. Floki team Core members include Dr. Amanda Kavner, Mr. Brown Whale, and Jackie Xu.</p>



<p>Floki Inu has over 400,000 token holders and 320,000+ followers on Twitter. Floki Inu’s success is attributed to its thriving community, like Shiba Inu.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu Ecosystem</h3>



<p>The Floki Inu ecosystem uses the Floki token and aims to provide utility to Floki Vikings.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/floki-ecosystem-1-1200x675.png" alt="floki ecosystem 1" class="wp-image-232547" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/floki-ecosystem-1-1200x675.png 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/floki-ecosystem-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/floki-ecosystem-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/floki-ecosystem-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/floki-ecosystem-1.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: Floki.com</figcaption></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>Valhalla</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Valhalla is a turn-based blockchain combat game in the metaverse. The game currently runs on L2 optimism Kovan testnet. The innovative technology makes it possible to verify stats on the chain and use Veras &#8211; unique upgradable Non Fungible tokens NFTs. Veras can be traded on the platform&#8217;s NFT marketplace.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Floki Places</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Floki places is a planned merchandise and NFT store that enables the crypto community to trade NFTs and merchandise for crypto.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Floki University</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Floki University is an education platform on everything cryptocurrency, metaverse, NFT, and blockchain. It is a beginner-friendly place to learn how blockchain technology affects real life and how retail clients and programmers benefit from it.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Decentralized Finance (DeFi</strong>)</li>
</ul>



<p>Floki is using strategic partnerships to bring Defi down to the people. A partnership with Chain Link gives Floki access to tamper-proof quality price feeds transmitted over the blockchain.</p>



<p>Floki Defi offerings include Inverse finance for Floki collateral and staking and BarnBridge for trading leverage.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Floki Inu 3 Pillars</h3>



<p>The Floki Inu pillars strengthen its commitment to its community. These include Charity, meme culture, and Utility.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Floki Meme Culture</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Floki Vikings thrive on memes. The community views memes as the only way to mainstream cryptocurrencies and enable adoption through the power of memes. Memes appeal to everyone poor, rich, old, young, small, and great.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Utility</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Floki Inu has a strong roadmap that focuses on utility. The utility makes the Floki token more than just a joke coin; Floki Inu provides opportunities and equality to the community.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Charity</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Top of the list is Floki’s aim to build a school on every continent and then in every underdeveloped nation in the world. Floki makes life easier for us and contributes to the world&#8217;s well-being.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Our Floki Inu price prediction has provided a comprehensive analysis of Floki Inu&#8217;s future price forecast for the period 2024 &#8211; 2033. The token&#8217;s utilities look promising, and its new NFT marketplaces and metaverse games are expected to promote user adoption further. According to our prediction, the coin is a good investment for the future. Our long-term price forecast for this coin is $0.000314, with a minimum price of $0.000263. Even though we are bullish on this token, we expect you to research it before investing in it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V4RMVjGdSj4" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V4RMVjGdSj4" />
			<media:title type="plain">Floki Inu Price Prediction 2022, 2025, 2030 — FLOKI Predictions</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we&#039;ll look at the Floki Inu price forecasts for 2022, 2025, and 2030, based on the following assumptions. One of the most significant aspects to exami...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/floki-inu-price-prediction-2022-.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Floki-Inu-Price-Prediction.png" medium="image"  type="image/png" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Floki-Inu-Price-Prediction.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung Galaxy S25 to Feature Google’s Next-Gen AI Model</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-to-googles-ai-model/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Palmer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Galaxy S 25 series function of Samsung is already been apt for the exhibit market, which is carried out by its relationship with Google which integrated the Gemini Nano 2 AI model. This is how Samsung reinforces its brand philosophy as an innovative market leader, making its signature smartphones richer, better, and more representative [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Galaxy S 25 series function of Samsung is already been apt for the exhibit market, which is carried out by its relationship with Google which integrated the Gemini Nano 2 AI model. This is how Samsung reinforces its brand philosophy as an innovative market leader, making its signature smartphones richer, better, and more representative of elite technology performance that other brands haven’t been able to come close to.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Partnership with google&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The reports indicate that it is Google&#8217;s Nano 2 AI engine that will play a significant role in facilitating the introduction of the new Galaxy S25 lineup of smartphones by Samsung, one of the first ones with such an innovation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This association signifies a business agreement that is setting the pace both for Samsung and Google to stay in competition through the utilization of AI for mobile product development. Cho Cheol-min, who presents as the managing director of Samsung Electronics&#8217; LSI division team, announces this.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This was during the semiconductor forum on 17/4 when he was presenting about the addition of the Gemini nano 2 to the Galaxy S25 range of smartphones a territory related to modem AI that will be unblocked for buyers.&nbsp; Building on a cornerstone of the highly successful Gemini Nano, which was featured as a new AI model in Pixel 8 Pro and Galaxy S24 Unit, the AI chip has now been predicted to deliver higher efficiency and performance. Google&#8217;s AI has always been high on its agenda so it will be impossible to keep up with Gemini Nano 2’s achievement in the on-device processing of data which every mobile user can enjoy.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ramping up AI development with Exynos chips&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The list of its plans to expand the size of its Exynos AI Studio and Exynos AI Stack teams, the agility of Samsung in AI research and development is also manifest., With a workforce size of 200 now, these teams are no doubt, a critical force that pushes the boundaries of AI technology that are utilized on Samsung&#8217;s Exynos chips. Providing for the acceleration of development efforts and an upgrade of the next generation features the plani of the Exynos will involve increasing its AI workforce to make future Exyonos chips a reality among them including the Exynos 2500 expected to power the Galaxy S25 series in the subsequent year. The role of Samsung in the semiconductor chip market is explored in-depth in the bulk of this discussion.</p>



<p>Thus Samsung&#8217;s chip strategy combination with the latest AI features in flagship smartphones can also influence itself. Although Samsung deployed the Snapdragon 8 chips for the Galaxy S23 range, it is looking to use its own Exynos 2400 chip for the Samsung S24 model, again. The move of AI priorities in Exynos chips shows that Samsung might go for branded processors&#8217; reputation and as a result, Samsung&#8217;s ecosystem might get more Galaxy devices with Exynos chips in the long run.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Release and announcement timeline</h2>



<p>Samsung’s partnership with Google and the subsequent introduction of the Gemini Nano 2 processors are not just the news of the day but are what make people’s curiosity continue to build up the official announcement of the Galaxy S25 series of smartphones that will be launched sooner than what we are expecting. Following last year&#8217;s announcement of the first-generation AI model known as Gemini Nano, speculations are mounting that Google may introduce Gemini Nano 2 along with the Pixel 9 series which are rumored to hit the stores in October.&nbsp; The 2025 flagship of Samsung, the Galaxy S25 is expected to exhibit the maximum efficiency that the Gemini Nano 2 can offer, hence being an example of AI-enabled smartphones&#8217; future for years to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The upcoming release of the Samsung Galaxy S25 series is built to utilize Google’s Gemini Nano 2. Artificial Intelligence technology is indeed a breakthrough in smartphone technology evolution. Featuring superior AI at the heart of its technology, the Galaxy S25 will surpass your wildest imaginations of what a mobile device can do by integrating a powerful user experience that defies limits known in today&#8217;s world of smartphones. During the process of AI development and strategic partnerships, Samsung holds a firm stand as a breakthrough performer. It creates a revolution in the mobile industry through the launch of the Galaxy S25 with a clear intent to simply stay head above the rest.</p>



<p>This article originally appeared in <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-might-launch-with-google-next-gen-ai-model/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Android Police</a> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Samsung_Galaxy_S25_to_Feature_Googles_NextGen_AI_Model_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Samsung_Galaxy_S25_to_Feature_Googles_NextGen_AI_Model_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s Behind the Hedera Hashraph HBAR Rally: Black Rock MMF Token Hosted by Archax</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/whats-behind-the-hedera-hashraph-hbar-rally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hristina Vasileva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[archax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hbar rally]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hedera (HBAR), the token behind Hedera Hashgraph, held a spectacular rally at the start of the new week. HBAR peaked at $0.18, its highest price for the past two years, doubling its price overnight. Investors in HBAR saw rumors that the Hedera blockchain carried one of BlackRock&#8217;s tokenized assets. Reportedly, Hedera carried a token linked [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hedera (HBAR), the token behind Hedera Hashgraph, held a spectacular rally at the start of the new week. HBAR peaked at $0.18, its highest price for the past two years, doubling its price overnight.</p>



<p>Investors in HBAR saw rumors that the Hedera blockchain carried one of BlackRock&#8217;s tokenized assets. Reportedly, Hedera carried a token linked to one of BlackRock’s Money Market Funds (MMF).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today we witness <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RWA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#RWA</a> history as <a href="https://twitter.com/BlackRock?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@BlackRock</a>’s ICS US Treasury money market fund (MMF) is tokenized on <a href="https://twitter.com/hedera?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@Hedera</a> with <a href="https://twitter.com/ArchaxEx?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@ArchaxEx</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/OwneraIO?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@OwneraIO</a>, marking a major milestone in asset management by bringing the world’s largest asset manager on-chain 🏦 <a href="https://t.co/1Kye8cjAJx" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/1Kye8cjAJx</a></p>&mdash; HBAR Foundation (@HBAR_foundation) <a href="https://twitter.com/HBAR_foundation/status/1782759384742813951?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 23, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>After the initial hype, HBAR retreated again to $0.13, potentially extending the slide. HBAR has mostly moved horizontally in the past two years and has not reached its previous peak.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">BlackRock Not Directly Involved in Token Generation on Archax Platform<gwmw style="display:none;"></gwmw></h2>



<p>After the 100% rally, it became clear that BlackRock is not using Hedera directly. However, a Hedera-linked project, Archax, explained it stands behind the new asset listing. Real-world asset listing is technologically possible for any blockchain, but in this case, HBAR spiked due to the belief that the BlackRock fund was directly involved.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">“Archax, today announced the expansion of fund shares it offers in tokenised form with the <a href="https://twitter.com/BlackRock?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@BlackRock</a> ICS US Treasury MMF. This builds on its launch of tokenised access to <a href="https://twitter.com/abrdn_plc?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@abrdn_plc</a> MMFs last year, created on both the <a href="https://twitter.com/hedera?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@hedera</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Ethereum?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#Ethereum</a>&quot;<a href="https://t.co/p1rdYuPi75" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://t.co/p1rdYuPi75</a></p>&mdash; Archax (@ArchaxEx) <a href="https://twitter.com/ArchaxEx/status/1782763536919286120?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 23, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Archax has already tokenized money market funds linked to the US dollar, as well as to GBP and EUR. Archax aims to popularize its trading platform, offering a relatively easy on-ramp for new investors.</p>



<p>On its side, BlackRock has experimented with digital assets and tokenization. But its tokenized assets would arrive through a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-03-19/blackrock-files-with-sec-to-offer-fund-with-tokenization-firm-securitize%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1713969194039123%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw0DH3aLDh6T12m5PNHt8Qqg&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1713969194051520&amp;usg=AOvVaw17fq5u_ibSA-JKvT83Bxb5" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">partnership with Securitize</a>. Through Securitize, BlackRock aims to enter the market for real-world asset (RWA) tokenization, bridging the gap between mainstream investors and decentralized finance.</p>



<p>After a period of meme coin creation, vaporware and NFT hype, the recent HBAR rally showed the market may be ready for real utility and added mainstream acceptance. Various attempts have been made to tokenize real-world assets, including niche assets and shares as well as physical items.</p>



<p>So far, stablecoins like Tether and USD Coin have been the best applications of real-world value tied up in tokens. Recently, gold-backed assets have also had a field day, even trading above the market price of physical gold at one point.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is HBAR Safe to Trade?<gwmw style="display: none; background-color: transparent;"></gwmw></h2>



<p>The dust has not settled yet for HBAR, as the asset trades with anomalous daily volumes. In the past day, HBAR trades peaked at $3.14B, which is a record for the token.</p>



<p>In the past day, more than 62% of the token’s supply changed hands in a trading frenzy. HBAR may slip fast, as the 2% liquidity depth on Binance is still relatively low at $838K. The token&#8217;s liquidity scores are relatively low, below 700 on CoinMarketCap. This means that its price could be very unstable.</p>



<p>HBAR may return to a lower range before establishing a more sustainable trend based on chart analysis. The token is widely used, with more than 71% of the supply in active circulation. The goal of HBAR is utility, but the Hedera community has been hoping for a higher price range during the new bull cycle.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Looking for something like this after completing a nice 5 wave impulse off the lows.<br><br>Note the first step is a break in lower timeframe market structure to kick things into gear.<br><br>After that if we can print a higher low we should be able to run it back to the highs.<a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24HBAR&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">$HBAR</a> <a href="https://t.co/1aCnnkinHl" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://t.co/1aCnnkinHl</a> <a href="https://t.co/CJ97RVtD0g" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/CJ97RVtD0g</a></p>&mdash; CrediBULL Crypto (@CredibleCrypto) <a href="https://twitter.com/CredibleCrypto/status/1783067730020594026?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 24, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>HBAR has been a speculative bet over the past few years. Hedera aimed to place itself as an alternative to Ethereum, bringing a graph-like structure instead of a blockchain. However, once the novelty wore out, HBAR also fell out of favor with investors.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://www.coinglass.com/funding/HBAR%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1713969194043488%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw3El3_TWIJ41u1Cmrwawtdn&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1713969194052543&amp;usg=AOvVaw12IPygvOynlUSUCvENMiCF" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Coinglass funding rate</a>&nbsp;for HBAR continues to be negative, as holders of short positions must pay to continue the shorting. At this point, HBAR may return to its pre-pump levels or continue trading anomalously in the case of a short squeeze.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/hbar.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/hbar.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flow Coin Price Prediction 2024-2033: Is FLOW a Good Investment?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/flow-coin-price-prediction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Narmin Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto Price Predictions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency trading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=129511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Flow Coin Price Prediction 2024-2034 The advice provided by seasoned traders, often referred to as the 50-35-15 rule, suggests allocating 50% of a crypto portfolio to Bitcoin (BTC), 35% to a selection of large-cap coins, and the remaining 15% to smaller projects with high growth potential. This strategy is grounded in the perceived stability of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2024-2034</h4>



<ul>
<li><a href="#Flow-Coin-Price-Prediction-2024">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2024 &#8211; up to<strong> $1.87</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Flow-Coin-Price-Prediction-2027">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2027 &#8211; up to <strong>$6.25</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Flow-Coin-Price-Prediction-2030">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2030 &#8211; up to <strong>$17.39</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Flow-Coin-Price-Prediction-2033">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2033 &#8211; up to <strong>$55.58</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>The advice provided by seasoned traders, often referred to as the 50-35-15 rule, suggests allocating 50% of a crypto portfolio to Bitcoin (BTC), 35% to a selection of large-cap coins, and the remaining 15% to smaller projects with high growth potential. This strategy is grounded in the perceived stability of Bitcoin, the reliability of established large-cap coins, and the potential for significant returns from smaller, riskier projects.</p>



<p>In the context of Flow Coin, the analysis emphasizes the ongoing development and innovation within the Flow ecosystem, even amidst challenges faced by similar organizations. The mention of achievements in Q1 underscores the potential of Flow as a layer 1 blockchain for building and scaling mainstream innovations. This positive outlook suggests that Flow is actively contributing to the blockchain space, which may attract interest from investors seeking promising projects.</p>



<p>One notable factor contributing to the increased interest in Flow is a listing announcement on Coinbase, a prominent cryptocurrency exchange. The &#8220;Coinbase effect&#8221; refers to the potential impact on a cryptocurrency&#8217;s price and visibility after being listed on the Coinbase platform. Such listings often lead to increased accessibility and exposure, potentially influencing investor sentiment and driving demand.</p>



<p>Before delving into the Flow Coin price prediction, the narrative emphasizes a positive perception. This may be attributed to the ongoing developments in the Flow ecosystem, achievements in Q1, and the significant Coinbase listing. The positive tone sets the stage for a more optimistic assessment of Flow Coin&#8217;s future performance.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>In 2024, the cryptocurrency market is maturing, elevating its status to be on par with more traditional asset classes. Despite navigating through a year of economic uncertainties, Bitcoin and Ethereum are standing out and gaining popularity as sought-after alternatives to conventional stocks and bonds. They are proving their resilience and attractiveness in the evolving financial landscape.</p>
<cite>Cryptopolitan</cite></blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How Much is Flow Worth?</h3>



<p>Today, Flow is priced at $0.998, with a 24-hour trading volume of $92.66M and a market capitalization of $1.50B, commanding a market dominance of 0.06%. Over the past day, the FLOW price has risen by 5.49%. Sentiment towards Flow&#8217;s price prediction is currently bullish, with the Fear &amp; Greed Index at 72 (Greed). Flow has a circulating supply of 1.50B FLOW out of a maximum supply of 1.37B FLOW. The yearly supply inflation rate stands at 44.94%, resulting in the creation of 465.68M FLOW over the last year. In terms of market cap rankings, Flow holds the #4 position in the NFT Tokens sector and #34 in the Layer 1 sector.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin price analysis: FLOW obtains a long-term bullish momentum at $0.998</h2>



<p><strong>TLDR Breakdown</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>FLOW price analysis is bullish today.</li>



<li>The strongest resistance is present at $1.357.</li>



<li>Current Flow price is $0.998 at the time of writing.</li>
</ul>



<p>Flow cryptocurrency initiated a noticeable ascent on April 24, 2024, starting from its initial value of $0.936. Despite encountering intermittent fluctuations, it gradually rose to a peak of $1.026 before stabilizing at a significantly higher level. Following this peak, Flow continued its upward trajectory, consistently hovering around the $0.998 range. This ability to sustain its price amid market fluctuations highlighted Flow&#8217;s resilience, strength, and adaptability. Investors observed with confidence as Flow demonstrated its robustness, indicating a positive outlook for the cryptocurrency despite market uncertainties.</p>



<p>Flow cryptocurrency experienced a significant increase in value when it began at a price of $0.936. Despite encountering some ups and downs along the way, it gradually climbed to a high point of $1.026 before stabilizing at a higher level than its initial value. Even after reaching this peak, Flow continued to maintain its upward trend, consistently staying around the $0.998 range. This ability to sustain its price despite fluctuations in the market indicates that Flow is resilient and adaptable. Investors observed this behavior with confidence, suggesting that Flow&#8217;s positive performance could continue even in uncertain market conditions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin price analysis for 1-hour: Recent developments</h3>



<p>The Flow Coin has been steadily climbing, although recent signs suggest a potential slowdown in its upward momentum. Notably, a significant hurdle lies at $1.013, acting as a strong resistance level. Conversely, a robust support zone is emerging around the lower boundary of the Bollinger Band at $0.928, crucial for reinforcing the coin&#8217;s upward trend and mitigating downward pressures. Furthermore, the price is trying to surpass the resistance level, signaling a market breakout. Although this breakout might lead to a reversal, a favorable outcome could involve the resistance level retracing, ideally to a higher position.</p>



<p>The Moving Average analysis suggests a bearish trend, indicating a likelihood of further downward price movements. Traders are advised to remain vigilant and adaptable to shifts in market sentiment. The current price trend is consistent with this bearish outlook, as prices fall within the upper and lower thresholds of the Bollinger Bands. A decisive breach of the upper threshold could signal a reversal, potentially leading to significant price gains. Given these conditions, maintaining a heightened level of awareness is crucial. This enables traders to promptly identify any deviations from the prevailing trend. By taking a proactive approach, traders can make informed decisions in response to evolving market dynamics, optimizing their trading strategies for maximum effectiveness.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="544" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-1200x544.png" alt="" class="wp-image-515780" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-1200x544.png 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-300x136.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-768x348.png 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-1536x696.png 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101.png 1787w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>FLOW/USD 1-hour price chart Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/FLOWUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TradingView</a></em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Currently, the Relative Strength Index (RSI) for Flow Coin stands at 58, indicating a phase of market stability marked by a significant balance between buying and selling activities, suggesting potential market equilibrium. However, the downward trajectory of the RSI signals the decreasing price of FLOW and the discrepancy between selling pressure and buying action, implying the continuation of Flow Coin&#8217;s unstable trend. Despite ongoing selling pressure, maintaining a vigilant stance and prioritizing the identification of potential market risks is crucial. Consistently monitoring the RSI and staying keenly attuned to shifts in buying and selling dynamics will be essential for traders to make well-informed decisions amidst evolving market conditions. This cautious approach is highly recommended for effectively navigating potential fluctuations and uncertainties in the market landscape.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin 1-day price analysis: FLOW bullish at $0.998</h3>



<p>Assessing the value of Flow Coin involves navigating a complex landscape of bullish and bearish factors contributing to observable price fluctuations in the volatile cryptocurrency market. The Bollinger Bands model is a crucial tool in this assessment, indicating a significant resistance level at $1.357 for Flow Coin. Surpassing this barrier could initiate an upward trajectory. Additionally, technical analysis identifies a strong support level at $0.712, acting as a price floor where seller interest reignites and defending against sharp price declines. This intricate interplay between resistance and support levels underscores the nuanced evaluation of Flow Coin&#8217;s value within the dynamic cryptocurrency market, highlighting the delicate balance of market forces in play.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="542" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-102-1200x542.png" alt="" class="wp-image-515781" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-102-1200x542.png 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-102-300x136.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-102-768x347.png 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-102-1536x694.png 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-102.png 1788w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>FLOW/USD 1-day price chart Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/FLOWUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TradingView</a></em></figcaption></figure>



<p>A detailed analysis of Flow Coin&#8217;s price dynamics reveals that the current Relative Strength Index (RSI) level of 44 indicates a phase of market stability. However, the observed pattern in the RSI suggests a potential shift towards an unstable market sentiment, marked by the emergence of an upward trend where buying activity exceeds selling activity. This upward momentum reflects increased engagement from buyers, actively influencing market direction. This dynamic interaction highlights an ongoing market battle, with participants vying to shape Flow Coin&#8217;s price movements. The balanced RSI and the downward trend pattern denote a fluid market environment, necessitating vigilant monitoring for potential shifts in market dynamics.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What to Expect from the Flow Price Analysis</h3>



<p>Based on our analysis of its price dynamics, a mix of positive and negative factors are influencing Flow Coin&#8217;s future in the volatile cryptocurrency market. The coin has shown itself to be strong and flexible, staying steady in the face of market volatility, even though current patterns suggest that its upward trajectory may be slowing down. The Bollinger Bands model and technical analysis help traders navigate the market by highlighting critical resistance and support levels. Flow Coin&#8217;s performance remains dynamic and susceptible to ongoing market conflicts despite many hurdles such as negative trends from moving averages and potential instability from the RSI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is FLOW a good investment?</h2>



<p>Flow (FLOW) presents a compelling investment opportunity based on its current market performance and positive indicators. With a bullish sentiment, market stability, and resilience against price fluctuations, Flow demonstrates potential for significant gains. Its upward trajectory, reinforced by technical analysis and support levels, indicates a promising outlook for investors. However, as with any investment in the cryptocurrency market, there are inherent risks, including volatility and uncertainty. Therefore, investors should conduct thorough research, assess their risk tolerance, and seek professional advice before making any investment decisions in Flow or any other cryptocurrency.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recent news on Flow Coin</h2>



<p>FLOW Blockchain reports the introduction and deployment of the Crescendo Previewnet. Stated differently, an environment for scaling Ethereum virtual machines (EVMs) is offered by the Crescendo Previewnet. They highlight Crescendo&#8217;s alleged potential to offer mainstream scalability in addition to a smooth integration with the FLOW ecosystem. Recall that this is merely a prototype version of Crescendo; testing and development for the final version are probably not too far off. Users are encouraged to begin experimenting with the platform since FLOW Blockchain is compatible with the Ethereum virtual machine (EVM), allowing developers to use their existing Ethereum tools within the FLOW ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Predictions for 2024-2033</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Price Predictions by Cryptopolitan</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/qpi3JRrjfI8ychjXJ1lvKgT_auUcrj08F9QxcaS-wyHIdY2qApummUekMk75MtRUs99h_CvwpC_4gZNXy7I2lA0ZQdZa-H34VTI96ml8jUX-zrzDq_0PoomziooDu-ViTP_dqsss5bGqQpCUKWcbKnw" alt="" title="Points scored" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center"><strong>YEAR</strong></td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center"><strong>MINIMUM</strong></td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center"><strong>AVERAGE</strong></td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center"><strong>MAXIMUM</strong></td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2024</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$1.59</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$1.64</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$1.87</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2025</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$2.43</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$2.50</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$2.79</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2026</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$3.57</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$3.70</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$4.26</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2027</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$4.92</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$5.07</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$6.25</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2028</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$7.38</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$7.58</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$8.49</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2029</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$10.29</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$10.60</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$12.73</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2030</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$15.17</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$15.70</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$17.39</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2031</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$22.19</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$22.81</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$26.71</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2032</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$32.00</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$33.14</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$38.13</td></tr><tr><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">2033</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$46.50</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$48.16</td><td class="has-text-align-center" data-align="center">$55.58</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2024</h4>



<p>Our Flow Coin price prediction in 2024<strong> suggests a potential peak at $1.87</strong>, accompanied by an average valuation projected at $1.64 and a minimum estimate of $1.59. The prevailing outlook indicates a predominantly bullish trend for the token, especially if Flow&#8217;s ecosystem forms strategic partnerships with influential industry investors and prominent blockchain networks. Such collaborative efforts hold the promise of yielding positive outcomes for investors, positioning Flow as an attractive investment option.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2025</h4>



<p>In our 2025 price prediction Flow price movements suggest a <strong>potential peak at $2.79</strong>, with a projected low of $2.43 and an average valuation of $2.50. These predictions underscore the potential for significant price escalation, particularly as blockchain-driven applications utilizing Flow&#8217;s technology gain widespread adoption, promising improved future outcomes.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2026</h4>



<p>Looking ahead to 2026, our Flow price forecast indicates a prevailing bullish market sentiment, with a<strong> projected peak at $4.26 </strong>and a minimum at $3.57. Additionally, our analysis anticipates an average market price stabilizing around $3.70. These projections underscore the potential for substantial price expansion, signaling increasing confidence among investors in Flow Coin&#8217;s prospects for the year 2026.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2027</h4>



<p>According to our 2027 Flow Coin price prediction, there seems to be considerable profit potential for investors. Our projection envisions the cryptocurrency reaching a <strong>peak price of $6.25</strong>, maintaining an average price of $5.07, and sustaining a minimum price of $4.92. These forecasts suggest the possibility of attractive returns and promising investment prospects in the Flow Coin crypto market in 2027 despite past performance.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2028</h4>



<p>In our 2028 Flow Coin price prediction, we anticipate substantial price growth, with a projected <strong>maximum trading price of $8.49</strong>. Additionally, our expectations include an average price reaching $7.58, while the minimum forecasted price stands at $7.38. These projections collectively depict a promising scenario for Flow within the cryptocurrency market, indicating an expected high demand for the token and a substantial increase in its price. The bullish outlook reflects a positive sentiment among investors, underscoring the potential for significant value appreciation and market recognition for Flow Coin in the year 2028.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2029</h4>



<p>Looking ahead to 2029, our forecast for Flow Coin indicates a noteworthy appreciation in value, with a projected<strong> peak price of $12.73</strong>. Furthermore, our prediction suggests that the cryptocurrency is expected to maintain an average trading value of $10.60, with no anticipated depreciation below $10.29 throughout the year. These projections emphasize a substantial potential for both upward price momentum and stability in the Flow Coin market in 2029. The forecast reflects a positive outlook, indicating a robust market performance and showcasing investor confidence in the inherent value proposition of Flow Coin.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2030</h4>



<p>As we peer into the prospective landscape of 2030, our Flow Coin price prediction offers an optimistic perspective, with a<strong> maximum projected price of $17.39</strong> signaling substantial growth potential. Additionally, we anticipate a strengthened price support level, establishing a minimum price of $15.17. The envisaged average market price for Flow in 2030 orbits around $15.70, underscoring the potential for sustained positive performance and potential advancements in the cryptocurrency&#8217;s value. These projections indicate a promising trajectory for Flow Coin, aligning with potential advancements in its ecosystem and increasing market demand. Investors may find the forecasted prices reflective of an optimistic outlook for Flow Coin in the year 2030.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2031</h4>



<p>As we explore the potential scenarios for 2031, our Flow Coin price prediction outlines a primarily bullish trajectory, emphasizing a <strong>maximum projected price of $26.71</strong>. This projection signals significant growth compared to the current market value. Additionally, we anticipate an average price of $22.81, complemented by a minimum projected price of $22.19. These predictions highlight the potential for substantial price appreciation and an overall positive performance in the Flow Coin market throughout 2031. The projected prices suggest a favorable outlook for Flow Coin, indicating potential advancements, heightened demand, and positive sentiment among investors during the year 2031.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2032</h4>



<p>In our 2032 Flow Coin price prediction, an optimistic scenario unfolds, highlighting the cryptocurrency&#8217;s potential to achieve a <strong>maximum price of $38.13</strong>. Furthermore, our projection places the average trading price for the coin at around $33.14, with no expected dip below $32.00. These predictions offer a positive outlook for Flow, suggesting the possibility of growth and market resilience within the specified timeframe. The forecasted prices indicate a buoyant market sentiment, reflecting potential investor confidence, increased demand, and a positive trajectory for Flow Coin in the year 2032.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction 2033</h4>



<p>In our 2033 Flow Coin price prediction, an optimistic scenario unfolds, emphasizing the cryptocurrency&#8217;s potential to reach a <strong>maximum price of $55.58</strong>. Additionally, our projection positions the average trading price for the coin at approximately $48.16, with no anticipated dip below $46.50. These predictions present a positive outlook for Flow, indicating the possibility of substantial growth and market resilience within the specified timeframe. The forecasted prices convey a buoyant market sentiment, suggesting potential investor confidence, heightened demand, and a positive trajectory for Flow Coin in the year 2033.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction by CoinCodex</h4>



<p>According to CoinCodex&#8217;s current Flow price prediction, the price of Flow is forecasted to increase by 228.25% and reach $4.13 by May 6, 2024. Their technical indicators suggest a bullish sentiment, while the Fear &amp; Greed Index is at 78 (Extreme Greed). Flow has experienced 16 out of 30 (53%) green days with a price volatility of 8.01% over the last 30 days. Based on this Flow forecast, it appears to be a favorable time to consider buying Flow.</p>



<p>For 2025, the yearly low Flow price prediction is estimated at $1.259097, while the price of Flow is predicted to reach as high as $3.34 in 2026. Looking further ahead, the Flow price prediction for 2030 suggests a maximum of $5.15 and a minimum of $3.18.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction by DigitalCoinPrice</h4>



<p>DigitalCoinPrice&#8217;s FLOW price predictions showcase a consistent upward trajectory over the specified years, with significant growth anticipated in 2024, 2027, 2030, and 2033. In 2024, the forecast suggests a substantial increase from a minimum price of $1.10 to a maximum of $2.75, indicating a potentially lucrative investment opportunity within a relatively short timeframe. This upward trend continues into 2027, with the minimum price projected to rise to $4.81 and the maximum reaching $5.75, reflecting a steady progression in value. By 2030, DigitalCoinPrice anticipates even greater growth, with minimum prices expected to surpass $8 and maximum prices reaching up to $9.28, indicating a significant maturation of the FLOW market. Finally, in 2033, the forecast predicts a further surge in value, with minimum prices projected to exceed $23 and maximum prices reaching $24.16, suggesting continued bullish sentiment and substantial potential returns for investors. Overall, DigitalCoinPrice&#8217;s FLOW price predictions paint a promising picture of sustained growth and profitability over the coming years, making it an attractive asset for long-term investment strategies.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price Prediction by PricePrediction.net</h4>



<p>PricePrediction.net&#8217;s FLOW price predictions offer a comprehensive outlook on the cryptocurrency&#8217;s trajectory over the coming decades, showcasing a steady upward trend in its value. The projections highlight significant growth potential, particularly evident in key milestone years such as 2024, 2027, 2030, 2033, 2040, and 2050. In 2024, FLOW is anticipated to range between $1.59 and $1.87, indicating a promising start with notable gains expected. By 2027, the projected price range of $4.92 to $6.25 suggests a substantial increase, reflecting growing investor confidence and adoption. Looking further ahead, the estimates for 2030, ranging from $15.17 to $17.39, and for 2033, ranging from $46.50 to $55.58, underscore FLOW&#8217;s potential for exponential growth over the next decade. The forecast for 2040, with prices ranging from $811.95 to $1,004, and for 2050, with prices ranging from $1,077 to $1,240, signify FLOW&#8217;s evolution into a significant player within the cryptocurrency landscape, potentially becoming a prominent asset class for investors seeking long-term growth opportunities.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Overview of Flow Coin</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Popularity</strong></td><td>#63</td><td><strong>Market Cap</strong></td><td>$1,880,592,673</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price Change (24 hours)</strong></td><td>1.50%</td><td><strong>Trading Volume (24 hours)</strong></td><td>$32,755,495</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price change (7 days)</strong></td><td>-5.97%</td><td><strong>Circulating Supply</strong></td><td>1,499,068,196 FLOW</td></tr><tr><td><strong>All-time low (5 months ago)</strong></td><td>$0.3921</td><td><strong>All-time high (April 5, 2021)</strong></td><td>$46.16</td></tr><tr><td><strong>From ATL</strong></td><td>+220.59%</td><td><strong>From ATH</strong></td><td>-97.28%</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Price History</h2>



<p>The year 2021 was marked by significant milestones and challenges for Flow Coin. In December 2021, the cryptocurrency&#8217;s price ranged from $11.48 to $15.78, closing the month at $12.42. The trading volume for December was $115.24 million, contributing to a market cap of $4.10 billion. This period reflected heightened investor interest and increased market capitalization, indicating Flow Coin&#8217;s growing prominence within the cryptocurrency landscape.</p>



<p>The transition from 2021 to 2022 presented a dynamic period for Flow Coin. In January 2022, the cryptocurrency opened at $8.80 and reached a high of $9.45. The closing value was $6.87, with a trading volume of $94.09 million and a market cap of $2.28 billion. This transition period highlighted fluctuations in market sentiment and price dynamics, setting the tone for the cryptocurrency&#8217;s performance in the subsequent months.</p>



<p>The year 2022 witnessed both highs and lows for Flow Coin. In December 2022, the cryptocurrency&#8217;s price fluctuated between $0.641314 and $1.161304, closing the month at $0.651922. The trading volume for December was $36.83 million, contributing to a market cap of $922.86 million. This phase indicated a balance between upward and downward price movements, reflecting the broader market dynamics during that period.</p>



<p>The transition from 2022 to 2023 showcased varied market conditions for Flow Coin. In January 2023, the cryptocurrency opened at $0.651922, reaching a high of $1.270412 during the month. The closing value was $1.061271, with a trading volume of $99.29 million and a market cap of $962.09 million. This period marked a shift from the previous year&#8217;s closing values, illustrating the evolving nature of Flow Coin in response to market dynamics.</p>



<p>Throughout 2023, Flow Coin showcased dynamic price movements, responding to various market forces. In December 2023, the cryptocurrency experienced notable volatility, starting the month at $0.643764 and reaching a high of $1.033405. The closing value for December settled at $0.911751, indicating a range of price fluctuations within the month. The trading volume during December was $129.72 million, contributing to a market capitalization of $1.21 billion. This month&#8217;s performance reinforced the cryptocurrency&#8217;s resilience and adaptability to market dynamics. The positive momentum observed in the closing months of 2023 suggested an optimistic outlook for Flow Coin, highlighting its potential for growth and stability in the evolving cryptocurrency landscape.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on Flow Coin (FLOW)</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is Flow Coin?</h3>



<p>Flow is a leading blockchain project that seeks to become a better alternative to Ethereum. It is a<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/is-proof-of-stake-secure/" data-type="post" data-id="82230"> Proof-of-Stake platform</a> that has faster speeds and lower transaction costs than Ethereum. As a result, its developers hope that it will become the go-to platform for web 3.0 deployments. The platform was created by the team that built CryptoKitties.</p>



<p>The decision by Yuga Labs on ApeCoin deployment and the ongoing permissionless contract development progress could trigger FLOW price action. The upgrade, which is expected to be launched soon, will focus n code-hardening, professional audits, and a bug bounty program.</p>



<p>Developed by Dapper Labs in 2018, Flow is a fast and decentralized layer-one blockchain infrastructure designed to function as the base protocol for NewGen applications, games, and digital assets. The Flow blockchain is created from scratch and intended for applications and internet-scale protocols that demand distinctive customer experience. It&#8217;s reputed to be the only blockchain-based technology that incorporates user-experience improvement features into its protocol layer.</p>



<p>The team behind the development of this project is renowned for consistently delivering top-notch blockchain consumer experiences with products like Dapper Wallet, NBA Top Shot, and CryptoKitties.</p>



<p>The Flow ecosystem is developer-friendly and has continued to attract top developers and some blockchain enthusiast brands, already building products on the network. Also, Flow has established collaborations with top-tier game developers, including nWay and Animoca Brands; entertainment brands, including LaLiga, NFL, Warner Music, NBA, and UFC; leading crypto platforms, including Binance; development studios, such as Samsung and Ubisoft, and a couple of NexGen high-growth startups like Opensea.</p>



<p>The native <u>cryptocurrency</u> token that fuels the Flow ecosystem is FLOW. It is utilized by developers, validators, participants, and applications on the network. FLOW token is designed to serve several purposes, including network fees, rewards, payment method, and a reserve asset in the long run.</p>



<p>Features that make the Flow network unique include upgradeable smart contracts, in-built logging support, consumer-friendly onboarding, and high throughput without<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/the-jax-network-sharding-solution-how-is-it-different/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> <u>sharding</u></a>. It leverages Cadence, a resource-oriented programming language for developing app assets and smart contracts.</p>



<p>Now that you&#8217;re familiar with the Flow network and its features, do you think its highlighted developments and future potential can make FLOW a valuable cryptocurrency both in the short-term and long term?</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Flow Coin Partnerships</h3>



<p>The Flow Network is continually looking at partnerships. Cheese announced that they would be partnering with the Flow blockchain. Cheeze is a photography-based NFT Media and Entertainment company. They will help to promote the recent NFT development of Flow.</p>



<p>If you remember, on 14 September 2021, Flow announced a partnership with Google Cloud’s power. The collaboration is expected to bolster the connection between consumers and app developers globally.</p>



<p>On 1 January 2022, Think Fund, in collaboration with Blocto App, announced a partnership with emerald DAO, the first DAO built on the Flow blockchain.</p>



<p>Flow blockchain started the year by introducing the customers to Flowverse, a new project in the ecosystem.</p>



<p>FLOW has several essential characteristics that make it the ideal currency for a new generation of games, consumer applications, and the digital assets that will power them. Let&#8217;s delve into more details of the Flow ecosystem, its functions, unique features, technical analysis, and price predictions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Flow is a good cryptocurrency with good projects behind it. However, investing in this cryptocurrency largely depends on your risk appetite. As you can see from our Flow price forecast, we expect the coin to reach $35.25. Despite being bullish on this cryptocurrency, we advise you do your own research before investing in it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CgVVCuizR0Y" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CgVVCuizR0Y" />
			<media:title type="plain">FLOW WILL DO A 9000% AFTER THIS?? - FLOW PRICE PREDICTION 2023</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[FLOW WILL DO A 9000% AFTER THIS?? - FLOW PRICE PREDICTION 2023Warning : The Indications that have been revealed in this video are unique and only for educati...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/flow-will-do-a-9000-after-this-f.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Flow-coin.png" medium="image"  type="image/png" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Flow-coin.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NBA playoffs to feature Coinbase&#8217;s new $15 million campaign</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/nba-playoffs-to-feature-coinbases-new-15-m/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mutuma Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase is allegedly launching a nationwide mega ad campaign. The company will use $15 million for the TV ads that will air during the NBA playoffs, which are expected to kick off on Wednesday. Coinbase ads highlight banking flaws with Pizza The campaign consists of two separate commercials: one 30-second video and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. cryptocurrency exchange <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/kathryn-haun-to-resign-from-coinbase-board/">Coinbase </a>is allegedly launching a nationwide mega ad campaign. The company will use $15 million for the TV ads that will air during the NBA playoffs, which are expected to kick off on Wednesday.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Coinbase ads highlight banking flaws with Pizza</strong></h2>



<p>The campaign consists of two separate commercials: one 30-second video and the other 60 seconds. These <a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/money/coinbase-dunks-traditional-payment-methods-15m-nba-ad-spend" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">commercial ads</a> will be featured on four major channels: ESPN, ESPN2, TNT, and ABC. The sole purpose of these ads Is to build awareness among the crypto market on sports fans. By implementing a strangulate storyline involving pizza, Coinbase seeks to clarify the complexity generally found in traditional payment systems.</p>



<p>The commercial used the analogy of a pizza undergoing tests and approval, as in the case of a regular bank transaction. The goal is to clarify the complications and charges associated with conventional banking and credit card utilization. The ads will air until June 9, during which time they will receive heavy coverage.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the core message of this ad?</strong></h2>



<p>The main visual is the pizza, symbolizing funds traveling the arteries passing through today’s financial systems. The analogy of the pizza moving through the various stages and getting all those &#8216;bites&#8217; by players representing the financial middlemen becomes a poignant symbol here. The art here is used to show the commission taken in each phase of a normal transaction.</p>



<p>In the final scene, the pizza is delivered to a door with a ‘surcharge’ signage on it, which is a typical extra charge that comes with using credit card transactions. Another message follows from the delivery guy, who emphasizes the need for an updated system that is better, faster, and convenient. Perhaps through the cryptocurrency alternative, such a system should be the order of the day. The second part of the ad highlights the effectiveness and direct influence of crypto transactions on their traditional ways.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Business philosophy and further goals</strong></h2>



<p>Coinbase Chief Policy Officer <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/coinbase-and-crypto-heavyweights-political-donations/">Faryar Shirzad</a> and VP of Engineering have both stated their objectives for the next set of commercials. They observed frequent beliefs among users that instant transactions occur through e-payments, such as credit card or Venmo applications. Nevertheless, these are an intricate part of a complex system that operates seamlessly with the digital interface considered as a whole.</p>



<p>While cryptocurrency transactions are known for their simplicity, Coinbase&#8217;s contrast helps to frame it as a leader in finance going forward. It underlines the value of consumers having their financial interactions without intermediaries as necessary, so transactions take place as quickly as the internet. Through this campaign, Coinbase keeps up with the improvement of public knowledge of how cryptocurrencies can work as a more convenient in the 21-st century alternative to traditional ways of money management.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Generate_an_image_of_Coinbase_logo_which_is_C_with_a_b_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Generate_an_image_of_Coinbase_logo_which_is_C_with_a_b_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experts Anticipate Declining Prices for AI Services Amidst ICT Sector Trends</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/declin-prices-for-ai-amid-ict-sector-trends/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emman Omwanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515744</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to experts, the increasingly fast-paced world of artificial intelligence (AI) technology is expected to shift toward more accessible platforms. This speedier problem is handled based on data accumulation tendencies within the information technology and communication industry (ICT), where prices have decreased over time. Historical trends in the ICT sector The Information and Communication Technology [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>According to experts, the increasingly fast-paced world of artificial intelligence (AI) technology is expected to shift toward more accessible platforms. This speedier problem is handled based on data accumulation tendencies within the information technology and communication industry (ICT), where prices have decreased over time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Historical trends in the ICT sector</h2>



<p>The Information and Communication Technology (ICT) sector has undergone a big shift in price reduction through the years, with a major decrease in the prices of the different components, with hardware, i.e., mobile phones, computers, and mobile communication, being a highlight. </p>



<p>The decrease in chip price is due to leadership in the semiconductor manufacturing sector; this manufacturing directly follows Moore’s law. Currently, the semiconductor industry is experiencing a downward trend in terms of pricing. </p>



<p>A notable impact is the increasing affordability of PCs, tablets, and mobile phones for home users. This trend has been magnified and embraced by projects powered by free services such as open source or by other advertising-driven models; hence, it is no wonder that democracy has invaded technology, too. </p>



<p>As more AIs are trained on microchips, pricing for semiconductor production will also be influenced, causing similar effects for AI overall. The fall in semiconductor prices might also be seen as the imminent decrease in AI infrastructure prices, leading to cheaper AI services for businesses and other consumers worldwide.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">OpenAI&#8217;s GPT-4 turbo: A case in point</h2>



<p>By the end of November, the AI&#8217;s OpenAI developers created GPT-4 Turbo, a model with a batch size of 128 people who can do the job of 512 people but at a very low cost compared to the preceding GPT-4. </p>



<p>This decision of OpenAI represents one of the major trends in the market regarding the use of affordable AI systems to deliver products to customers. As with the GPT-4 Turbo&#8217;s initial price, though it may have been set higher initially, it conforms to the broader trend of falling prices in parts of the ICT sector.</p>



<p>Despite that, companies hold the enthusiasm and produce more advanced stuff even if they do not have a reduction in their price tags. In contrast, the announcement of the next release of a text-based AI tool called GPT-5, made by OpenAI in the summer of 2024, demonstrates the ever-changing nature of this tool. However, AI applications focus on more complex models that are also likely to be costly. They demonstrate the sustained investment in AI infrastructure and technology.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Future outlook</h2>



<p>AI specialists continue to be confident about the presence of cost-effective AI services in the near future. With the declining costs of computing equipment and engineers optimizing AI algorithms, AI services will effectively reach a climax of becoming cheaper. </p>



<p></p>



<p>Additionally, AI has become part of different industries that increase efficiency and automation and decrease the expenses connected with graphic user interface design, tech support, and financial division.</p>



<p>A review of the IT industry&#8217;s long-run trajectory and the recent innovations in AI technologies illustrate an AI future that is increasingly cost-competitive and widely accessible. Although OpenAI and other companies are more at the forefront of the battle with the use of cost-effective strategies, future research and advancements in semiconductor technology are also expected to lower costs to a considerable extent. </p>



<p>As enterprises and individuals can use AI to solve sophisticated problems and ignite innovativeness, this is the initial step towards a more accessible future of technology among the people.</p>



<p>News sourced from:<a href="https://think.ing.com/articles/ai-services-will-become-more-affordable-over-time/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">THINK</a> economic and financial analysis</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_ICT_0-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_ICT_0-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Credential Theft is On the Rise and the Target is Core Cybersecurity Administrators</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/credential-theft-on-the-rise-cybersecurity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aamir Sheikh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Explained]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Credential Theft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Your identity has been stolen. It sounds so chilling to hear something like this, along with a sudden feeling of anxiety and helplessness in the situation and the fact that you don’t even know who stole your credentials. Things get muddier if the information stolen were your administrative credentials for your central cybersecurity system. As [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Your identity has been stolen. It sounds so chilling to hear something like this, along with a sudden feeling of anxiety and helplessness in the situation and the fact that you don’t even know who stole your credentials. Things get muddier if the information stolen were your administrative credentials for your central cybersecurity system.</p>



<p>As credential theft cases are increasing in number with insider based attacks, the infrastructure that protects your data is now the main target of hackers, as they are no longer just going after production or outer systems. According to a report, credential theft losses are estimated to be $20 billion in the US in 2023 and have affected 15.4 million folks.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="816" height="478" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/asw2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-515767" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/asw2.png 816w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/asw2-300x176.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/asw2-768x450.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 816px) 100vw, 816px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: <a href="https://www.mcafee.com/learn/a-guide-to-identity-theft-statistics/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Mcafee</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Credential theft is not new</h2>



<p>Credential theft is not a new problem to break on our heads, it&#8217;s been a problem for very long. Back in 2022, the BBC broke a story about a man in India who impersonated as the missing son of a landlord family in India. He deceived them for 41 years. Using their son’s ID, the man got a national identity card, paid taxes, went to college, and even got a gun license. He also sold 37 acres of the family’s property.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Looking at the lucrative benefits, you now have an idea why impersonators do it in the first place. But the guy finally went to jail, so not everything that shines is gold. And yes, no online hackers were involved in this case.</p>



<p>In this cyber age, no one is coming to break in, they don’t even need to apply clever tricks and hacks, Just a password and a username, and the data is gone. Especially data admins in companies have become the primary target of impersonators.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Artificial intelligence is also here to pour some fuel on the fire, as with its assistance, hackers can design more sophisticated approaches to attack and deploy them more efficiently. It can be anything like some phishing schemes based on generative AI, some new tricks of impersonation, or using deep fakes, but convincing the victim by luring them into something is the most favorite and easy way of getting credentials as you hand them over unintentionally. Remember the news when a British Parliamentarian provided the phone numbers and email addresses of his colleagues to a honey trapper?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="761" height="447" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/asw1-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-515763" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/asw1-1.png 761w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/asw1-1-300x176.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 761px) 100vw, 761px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: <a href="https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/34-Cybersecurity-Statistics-to-Lose-Sleep-Over-in-2020" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">techtarget</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cost of cybercrime</h2>



<p>Coming to our core topic, with most of our data now available online, from healthcare databases to dating sites that your wife may not know, securing all this is important. Nowadays, hackers are after passwords, names, and financial records, which they may use themselves or sell on the dark web. Supply chain attacks are perhaps the biggest in the history of cyberattacks in recent years. Gartner, which is an analyst firm, has said that by 2025, 45% of organizations will be impacted in one way or another by supply chain attacks globally.</p>



<p>According to US Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technologies, Anne Neuberger, the average cybercrime cost annually is expected to be more than $23 trillion for the year 2027. It is to be mentioned that just a year ago, in 2022, the figure was $8.4 trillion.</p>



<p>A Verizon report named “2023 Data Breach Investigation Report” mentions that the human factor is the most prevalent threat vector and the reason for 74% of cases of <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/combatting-phishing-with-mfa/" data-type="post" data-id="508480">data breach</a>. Humans are also behind stealing credentials and phishing attacks. The latter one is mostly carried out through emails in hopes that someone will provide information or at least click a link that can lead to further misuse. </p>



<p>The consequences of cyberattacks on businesses can last for years from the time they were first initiated. For a clear understanding, take into account criminal investigations, lawsuits, media backlash, and increases in insurance rates, altogether, these elements can bankrupt any firm.</p>



<p>The source of inspiration for this news can be seen <a href="https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/34-Cybersecurity-Statistics-to-Lose-Sleep-Over-in-2020" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/2fdf6ac2-8d23-41f6-a25b-c670d23e7aa2-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/2fdf6ac2-8d23-41f6-a25b-c670d23e7aa2-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meta’s Smart Glasses Get a Pretty Cool AI Uplift</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/metas-smart-glasses-get-ai-uplift/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ibiam Wayas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Trending News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meta AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meta Smart Glasses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meta’s smart glasses have gotten a major AI uplift that seems pretty cool. The glasses called “Ray Ban” now support video calling on WhatsApp and Messenger and can “look and tell” you the details of what you’re seeing. “That means you can do more with your glasses because now they can see what you see,” [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Meta’s <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/what-makes-meta-smart-glasses-stand-out/" data-type="post" data-id="504228">smart glasses</a> have gotten a major AI uplift that seems pretty cool. The glasses called “Ray Ban” now support video calling on WhatsApp and Messenger and can “look and tell” you the details of what you’re seeing.</p>



<p>“That means you can do more with your glasses because now they can see what you see,” Meta said.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Meta&#8217;s Smart Glasses Can See What You See</h2>



<p>The smart glasses are able to understand and process visual surroundings through a new upgrade called multimodal AI, which Meta has been testing with some early users since December 2023.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2024/04/new-ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-styles-and-meta-ai-updates/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">the announcement Tuesday</a>, Meta said the feature is now being made widely available in beta, starting with customers in the US and Canada.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Multimodal Meta AI is rolling out widely on Ray-Ban Meta starting today! It&#39;s a huge advancement for wearables &amp; makes using AI more interactive &amp; intuitive.<br><br>Excited to share more on our multimodal work w/ Meta AI (&amp; Llama 3), stay tuned for more updates coming soon. <a href="https://t.co/DLiCVriMfk" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/DLiCVriMfk</a></p>&mdash; Ahmad Al-Dahle (@Ahmad_Al_Dahle) <a href="https://twitter.com/Ahmad_Al_Dahle/status/1782803345914413453?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 23, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Some video clips that came out during the early test phase of the multimodal AI feature showed that the Ray Ban glass could look and suggest ways to save a dying plant, for instance. It can also give information about things like a landmark or even translate in real-time if you&#8217;re looking at foreign a text.</p>



<p>“Say you’re traveling and trying to read a menu in French. Your smart glasses can use their built-in camera and Meta AI to translate the text for you, giving you the info you need without having to pull out your phone or stare at a screen,” Meta said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Users Can Now Video Call with Meta’s Glasses</h2>



<p>Meta Ray Ban smart glasses have also gotten the ability to stream live surroundings on WhatsApp and Messenger video calls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The update completely removes the hassle of having to point your phone camera at things, or maybe items at the grocery store, to share your view or get recommendations on what to buy during video calls.</p>



<p>All the new features are built atop the pre-existing tech on the smart glasses. They are packed with an ultra-wide 12 MP camera. The glasses also come with Meta AI for those in the US and Canada. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="960" height="720" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-edited.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-515726" style="width:840px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-edited.jpg 960w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-edited-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-101-edited-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: Meta</figcaption></figure>



<p>Meta AI is an intelligent assistant that works similarly to Siri and Google Assistant, except that it’s powered by AI technology. It can generate texts, control the device through voice, and even get access to real-time information.</p>



<p>You could tell many are finding the Ray Ban glasses helpful, with Meta saying, “they’re selling out faster than we can make them.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-2024-04-24T131337.772.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-2024-04-24T131337.772.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Changpeng Zhao writes an apology letter to the Judge as he faces jail time</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/zhao-writes-an-apology-letter-to-judge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jai Hamid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Changpeng "CZ" Zhao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOJ]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=515713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Changpeng &#8220;CZ&#8221; Zhao, the founder and former CEO of Binance, has officially apologized for his past decisions in a comprehensive letter to the judge overseeing his trial. This apology came just days before his sentencing, scheduled for April 30, following a plea deal with the U.S. Department of Justice in late 2023. Despite previously waiving [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Changpeng &#8220;CZ&#8221; Zhao, the founder and former CEO of <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/us-wants-cz-in-prison-for-at-least-3-years/" data-type="post" data-id="515624">Binance</a>, has officially apologized for his past decisions in a comprehensive letter to the judge overseeing his trial. This apology came just days before his sentencing, scheduled for April 30, following a plea deal with the U.S. Department of Justice in late 2023. </p>



<p>Despite previously waiving his right to appeal any sentence under 18 months, the Department of Justice is now <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.328570/gov.uscourts.wawd.328570.78.0.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">pushing</a> for a three-year term.</p>



<p>Zhao&#8217;s letter to Judge Richard A. Jones of the Western District of Washington openly admits his failure to implement crucial compliance measures at Binance and promises that this legal trouble will be his last. </p>



<p>Furthermore, Zhao outlines his future intentions, which include supporting biotechnological innovations and youth initiatives. His plea was accompanied by 161 letters from various supporters, advocating for leniency due to his character and contributions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Zhao&#8217;s Wide Circle of Support</h2>



<p>The range of individuals backing Zhao is extensive. </p>



<p>His sister, Jessica Zhao, a former Managing Director at Morgan Stanley, commended him for his ongoing efforts to do good despite his errors. She highlighted his prudent management during the FTX crisis to ensure that Binance never misappropriated customer funds. </p>



<p>Yi He, a co-founder of Binance and the mother of Zhao’s three children, compared him to a &#8220;guardian of the wilderness&#8221; in the chaotic cryptocurrency industry.</p>



<p>CZ&#8217;s wife, Yang Weiqing, with whom he shares two children, cited their philanthropic efforts, including a substantial donation to Japan&#8217;s disaster-affected areas in 2018. His US-based university student children, Rachel and Ryan Zhao, portrayed him as a supportive father, urging the judge to view their father beyond this solitary incident.</p>



<p>From within the academic industry, Zhao received backing from Professor Jeremy R. Cooperstock of McGill University and Associate Professor Ronghui Gu of Columbia University, both highlighting his contributions to technology and innovation.</p>



<p>Further support came from Tigran Gambaryan, Head of Financial Crime Compliance at Binance, who despite being detained in Nigeria due to a separate issue, spoke highly of Zhao’s business acumen and philanthropic efforts. </p>



<p>U.S. figures like former Senator and Ambassador Max S. Baucus, and business leaders like Morgan Stanley Managing Director Sean Yang, also submitted letters vouching for Zhao&#8217;s character and professional integrity. Even members of the ruling family in the United Arab Emirates provided their endorsements, reflecting Zhao&#8217;s broad and positive impact on a global scale.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Legal Arguments and Defense Strategy</h2>



<p>Zhao&#8217;s legal team is strongly defending his unawareness of any illegal transactions on his platform, highlighting that these transactions were a minuscule fraction of the exchange’s total activity and therefore unlikely to have been deliberately facilitated by him. </p>



<p>They argue for probation, citing his non-repetitive breach and lack of prior knowledge about the specific illegalities. The defense also emphasized the international aspect of Binance’s operations, explaining that as a non-U.S. entity, Binance was not barred from servicing users in U.S.-sanctioned countries. </p>



<p>This point underscores the novel legal challenge Binance faces, where its automated systems inadvertently enabled transactions between these users and those in the U.S., a scenario not previously adjudicated.</p>



<p>In their plea agreement, Zhao and Binance consented to severe consequences beyond potential prison time. Binance has agreed to pay a $4.3 billion fine and will operate under a court-appointed monitor, a position yet to be filled.</p>



<p>The legal proceedings have affected Zhao’s personal life big time. Originally slated for sentencing in late February, the proceedings were delayed until April 30. Since appearing in court in Seattle, Zhao has been blocked from returning to Dubai, where he lives with his family.</p>



<p>Throughout the defense filings, Zhao was described as being uninformed of the transactions involving criminal funds, directly challenging the idea that he deliberately engaged in sanction violations. </p>



<p>The sanctions-related charge, a narrow and first-time application against Binance, claimed that an algorithmic matching engine unknowingly breached U.S. sanctions law by pairing users from sanctioned countries with U.S. users, a minute part of Binance’s trading volume.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-24-13.00.22-A-somber-and-reflective-image-for-an-article-titled-Changpeng-Zhao-writes-an-apology-letter-to-the-Judge-as-he-faces-jail-time.-The-image-features-a.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-24-13.00.22-A-somber-and-reflective-image-for-an-article-titled-Changpeng-Zhao-writes-an-apology-letter-to-the-Judge-as-he-faces-jail-time.-The-image-features-a.webp"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
