<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"

	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.newsbtc.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/</link>
	<description>Bitcoin &#38; Cryptocurrency News Today</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:34:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/cropped-cropped-cropped-favicon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">221170450</site>	<item>
		<title>Analysts Identify Key Scenario For Bitcoin Hitting $100,000</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/analysts-identify-key-scenario-for-bitcoin-hitting-100000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Godspower Owie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ark invest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Exchange-Traded Funds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Captain Faibik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cathie Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETFs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exponential Moving Average]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relative Strength Index]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RSI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prior to the Bitcoin Halving event, BTC&#8217;s price saw considerable instability, but it has since rebounded, reaching the $66,000 level, triggering bullish predictions from top crypto analysts regarding the coin&#8217;s future path. Captain Faibik, a crytocurrency analyst and trader, has emerged with an intriguing prediction, underscoring a narrative that could potentially propel the price of Bitcoin to the coveted $100,000 mark in the upcoming months. Bitcoin Poised For A Notable Rally To $100,000  According to Captain Faibik, Bitcoin has managed to hold the $60,000 support level in the wake of bullish investors in the market. As a result, the largest crypto asset by market cap is currently making a strong comeback. Related Reading: Is The Bitcoin Bloodbath Over? Analysts Say $60,000 Is The Cycle’s Bottom These bullish investors, according to Faibik must reclaim the crucial $72,000 resistance level in order to see a major rally to the $100,000 price level. This scenario acts as a ray of hope for the cryptocurrency community, igniting speculations and influencing projections about Bitcoin&#8217;s potential for future growth. Given the anticipated impact of the Bitcoin Halving and bulls, the $72,000 level could be realized in the short term. The expert previously highlighted that the Bitcoin weekly candle closed above the Exponential Moving Average (EMA) 10, demonstrating that the bulls are still very much in charge of the market. Following the Descending Channel break out in October last year, BTC Bulls has firmly secured the weekly EMA10, prompting the crypto analyst to put his next price target for the digital asset at $100,000. Faibik also noted that the daily Relative Strength Index (RSI) for Bitcoin has emerged from a falling wedge pattern. This breakout suggests that a 15% to 20% bullish rally in Bitcoin&#8217;s value is on the horizon. Meanwhile, in the daily timeframe, a bullish flag formation is underway, and in the event of an upward breakout from the bullish flag, Faibik anticipates a new all-time high for Bitcoin by May. Is A $1.5 million Price Level Possible For BTC? One of the most bullish predictions for Bitcoin this year came from Ark Invest Chief Executive Officer (CEO) Cathie Wood. The CEO foresees the digital asset to rise by over 2,000% reaching a whopping $1.5 million by 2030. Related Reading: ARK Invest Pivots To Bitcoin As Cathie Wood Expects BTC Price To Explode During an interview in Hong Kong, Wood reiterated her projections for BTC, which were supported by a thorough investigation that included institution surveys and evaluations of market volatility. She stated: I have been asked this question from different angles, and our analysis from multiple perspectives indicates that by 2030, Bitcoin could rise to $1.5 million. This price prediction is based on a survey of institutions, using a discount rate and volatility analysis. Initially, Wood&#8217;s forecast for Bitcoin was estimated at $600,000 in the next six years. However, considering the effect of the Bitcoin Spot Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs), she now believes the coin has the potential to hit $1.5 million. Featured image from iStock, chart from Tradingview.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to the Bitcoin Halving event, BTC&#8217;s price saw considerable instability, but it has since rebounded, reaching the $66,000 level, triggering bullish predictions from top crypto analysts regarding the coin&#8217;s future path.</p>
<p>Captain Faibik, a crytocurrency analyst and trader, has emerged with an intriguing <a href="https://x.com/CryptoFaibik/status/1782607799559627136" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">prediction</a>, underscoring a narrative that could potentially propel the price of Bitcoin to the coveted $100,000 mark in the upcoming months.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Poised For A Notable Rally To $100,000 </h2>
<p>According to Captain Faibik, Bitcoin has managed to hold the $60,000 support level in the wake of bullish investors in the market. As a result, the largest crypto asset by market cap is currently making a strong comeback.</p>

<p>These bullish investors, according to Faibik must reclaim the crucial $72,000 resistance level in order to see a major rally to the $100,000 price level. This scenario acts as a ray of hope for the cryptocurrency community, igniting speculations and influencing projections about Bitcoin&#8217;s potential for future growth. Given the anticipated impact of the Bitcoin Halving and bulls, the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/is-a-72k-bitcoin-surge-on-the-horizon-glassnodes-analysis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">$72,000 level</a> could be realized in the short term.</p>
<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-604904" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C220" alt="Bitcoin" width="460" height="220" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=2531 2531w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=460&#038;resize=460%2C220 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart-1.jpg?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" loading="lazy" data-recalc-dims="1"/>
<p>The expert previously highlighted that the Bitcoin weekly candle closed above the Exponential Moving Average (EMA) 10, demonstrating that the bulls are still very much in charge of the market. Following the Descending Channel break out in October last year, BTC Bulls has firmly secured the weekly EMA10, prompting the crypto analyst to put his next price target for the digital asset at $100,000.</p>
<p>Faibik also noted that the daily Relative Strength Index (RSI) for <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-pump-66k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin</a> has emerged from a falling wedge pattern. This breakout suggests that a 15% to 20% bullish rally in Bitcoin&#8217;s value is on the horizon.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in the daily timeframe, a bullish flag formation is underway, and in the event of an upward breakout from the bullish flag, Faibik anticipates a new all-time high for Bitcoin by May.</p>
<h2>Is A $1.5 million Price Level Possible For BTC?</h2>
<p>One of the most bullish predictions for Bitcoin this year came from Ark Invest Chief Executive Officer (CEO) <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/cathie-wood-bitcoin-cash-gold/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Cathie Wood</a>. The CEO foresees the digital asset to rise by over 2,000% reaching a whopping $1.5 million by 2030.</p>



<p>During an <a href="https://wublock.substack.com/p/cathie-wood-iinterview-in-hk-bitcoin?r=jbpop&amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;triedRedirect=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">interview </a>in Hong Kong, Wood reiterated her projections for BTC, which were supported by a thorough investigation that included institution surveys and evaluations of market volatility.</p>
<p>She stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>I have been asked this question from different angles, and our analysis from multiple perspectives indicates that by 2030, Bitcoin could rise to $1.5 million. This price prediction is based on a survey of institutions, using a discount rate and volatility analysis.</p></blockquote>
<p>Initially, Wood&#8217;s forecast for Bitcoin was estimated at $600,000 in the next six years. However, considering the effect of the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/beyond-bitcoin-etfs-there-are-other-players/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin Spot Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs)</a>, she now believes the coin has the potential to hit $1.5 million.</p>
<img decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/Md0sxrGj/" alt="Bitcoin" width="2273" height="1351" loading="lazy"/>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/iStock-1347306105.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604902</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solana Market Cap Skyrockets $11 Billion As Price Jumps 17% &#8211; Details</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/solana/solana-market-cap-skyrockets-11-billion-as-price-jumps-17-details/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sol]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solana, like many Proof-of-Stake (PoS) cryptocurrencies, relies on a decentralized network of validators who secure the network by staking their SOL coins. In exchange for staking, validators earn rewards. However, as Solana&#8217;s price began its recent ascent, a noticeable decline in staked SOL was observed. This suggests that some validators are choosing to unstake their coins, potentially to capitalize on the price surge and book some early profits. Solana Market Cap And Price Soar Meanwhile, on Tuesday, Solana enjoyed a stellar day, surging 17% and adding over $11 billion to its market capitalization, which now stands at over $70 billion. This impressive performance saw Solana outperform industry giants like Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH), which remained entangled in their own price gyrations. With its market capitalization now totaling an impressive $80.7 billion, Solana&#8217;s surge has caught the attention of the crypto world. Related Reading: Solana Meme Coin Massacre: 12 Projects Gone In 30 Days, $27 Million Vanished This unstaking activity has drawn the attention of analysts, with the unstaked amount reaching a significant 5 million SOL over the past week. With Solana currently trading around $157 per coin, this translates to roughly $780 million worth of tokens re-entering the market. The influx of such a large volume in a short period could lead to a temporary oversupply situation on exchanges. SOL price action in the last 24 hours. Source: Coingecko Pullback Or Power Through? The potential impact of unstaked SOL on the price is a matter of debate. Without a corresponding surge in demand to absorb this additional supply, there&#8217;s a risk of an initial price correction in the coming days. This could see Solana retreat from its current perch and settle around the $150 mark before potentially resuming its upward trajectory towards $200. Total crypto market cap currently at $2.3 trillion. Chart: TradingView The $200 Target The coming days will be crucial for Solana. The bulls need to maintain strong buying pressure to absorb the unstaked coins and push the price above the $160 resistance zone. If successful, this could propel Solana towards its $200 target. However, a failure to do so, coupled with a large-scale sell-off from unstaked SOL, could trigger a correction down to $150. Related Reading: Bullish On Polkadot: Analyst Sees DOT Hitting $15 Soon Solana Breakpoint 2024 In another development, Solana Breakpoint 2024 is set to take place in Singapore, from September 20 to September 21. This event will provide attendees with full access to the heart of the Solana community, including insightful talks and exclusive events. Special subsidized rates are available for developers, creators, artists, and students, ensuring that a diverse range of individuals can participate in this transformative event. The Solana Campus, located just a short 15-minute journey from downtown Amsterdam, offers a variety of stages for insightful talks, networking areas to build connections, and complimentary transportation for attendees&#8217; convenience. Solana Breakpoint is an important event for the Solana community, providing a platform for developers, validators, and other ecosystem participants to discuss the latest developments, share insights, and showcase their achievements. The annual conference highlights the network&#8217;s potential and its role in the broader blockchain space, with a focus on performance, reliability, and innovation. Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Solana, like many Proof-of-Stake (PoS) cryptocurrencies, relies on a decentralized network of validators who secure the network by staking their SOL coins. In exchange for staking, validators earn rewards.</p>
<p>However, as Solana&#8217;s price began its recent ascent, a noticeable decline in staked SOL was observed. This suggests that some validators are choosing to unstake their coins, potentially to capitalize on the price surge and book some early profits.</p>
<h2><strong>Solana Market Cap And Price Soar</strong></h2>
<p>Meanwhile, on Tuesday, Solana enjoyed a stellar day, surging 17% and adding over $11 billion to its market capitalization, which now stands at over $70 billion. This impressive performance saw Solana outperform industry giants like Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH), which remained entangled in their own price gyrations. With its market capitalization now totaling an impressive $80.7 billion, Solana&#8217;s surge has caught the attention of the crypto world.</p>

<p>This unstaking activity has drawn the attention of analysts, with the unstaked amount reaching a significant 5 million SOL over the past week. With Solana <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/solana" rel="nofollow">currently trading around $157</a> per coin, this translates to roughly $780 million worth of tokens re-entering the market. The influx of such a large volume in a short period could lead to a temporary oversupply situation on exchanges.</p>

<h2><strong>Pullback Or Power Through?</strong></h2>
<p>The potential impact of unstaked SOL on the price is a matter of debate. Without a corresponding surge in demand to absorb this additional supply, there&#8217;s a risk of an initial price correction in the coming days. This could see Solana retreat from its current perch and settle around the $150 mark before potentially resuming its upward trajectory towards $200.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/QtNZp2XG/" width="1835" height="883"/></p>

<b>The $200 Target</b>
<p>The coming days will be crucial for Solana. The bulls need to maintain strong buying pressure to absorb the unstaked coins and push the price above the $160 resistance zone. If successful, this could propel Solana towards its $200 target. However, a failure to do so, coupled with a large-scale sell-off from unstaked SOL, could trigger a correction down to $150.</p>

<strong>Solana Breakpoint 2024</strong>
<p>In another development,<a href="https://solana.com/breakpoint" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> Solana Breakpoint 2024</a> is set to take place in Singapore, from September 20 to September 21. This event will provide attendees with full access to the heart of the Solana community, including insightful talks and exclusive events.</p>
<p>Special subsidized rates are available for developers, creators, artists, and students, ensuring that a diverse range of individuals can participate in this transformative event. The Solana Campus, located just a short 15-minute journey from downtown Amsterdam, offers a variety of stages for insightful talks, networking areas to build connections, and complimentary transportation for attendees&#8217; convenience.</p>
<p>Solana Breakpoint is an important event for the Solana community, providing a platform for developers, validators, and other ecosystem participants to discuss the latest developments, share insights, and showcase their achievements. The annual conference highlights the network&#8217;s potential and its role in the broader blockchain space, with a focus on performance, reliability, and innovation.</p>
<p><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_f77ed6.jpg?fit=460%2C297" width="460" height="297" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604860</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solana Memecoins WIF And BONK Explode By Double Digits: Key Reasons</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/solana-memecoin-wif-bonk-explode-by-double-digits/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BONK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BONK price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogwifhat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WIF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WIF Price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two Solana-based memecoins, Bonk (BONK) and Dogwifhat (WIF), have registered substantial gains over the past 24 hours. BONK recorded a 35% increase, while WIF climbed by 19%, positioning them among the top three gainers in the top 100 cryptocurrencies by market cap today. Only Hedera Hashgraph (HBAR) surpassed them, with a notable 44% rise during the same period. Resolution Of Solana’s Congestion Issues Spurs Memecoins The significant uptick in these Solana memecoins is closely linked to the recent improvements in the Solana network&#8217;s performance. A tweet from SolanaFloor earlier today indicated, &#8220;BREAKING: Solana&#8217;s congestion issues have been completely resolved, with block production back to normal. Transactions confirming in under 2 seconds.&#8221; This announcement marks a pivotal moment for the network which had been plagued by congestion issues. Source A: https://t.co/2TVnbaPNlHSource B: https://t.co/GfHxy8dC1B &#8212; SolanaFloor &#124; Powered by Step Finance (@SolanaFloor) April 24, 2024 On April 15, Solana developers rolled out crucial updates designed to alleviate these problems, urging validators to adopt version v1.17.31. This version introduces changes in the treatment of validators based on their stakes. Further enhancements are anticipated with the release of version v1.18 next month, which will include a new scheduler, albeit disabled by default. Related Reading: Solana Meme Coin Massacre: 12 Projects Gone In 30 Days, $27 Million Vanished Andrew Kang, founder of Mechanism Capital, remarked a few days before the fix, &#8220;Let’s also not forget that the Solana congestion issues have weighed down SOL and Solana-based memecoins significantly. It’s not a question of if but when the network is significantly improved. That’s your springboard.&#8221; Kang&#8217;s comments now seem prophetic as the resolution of network issues has indeed acted as a springboard for memecoin valuations. Specifics On Rally Of Dogwifhat (WIF) And BONK The price of WIF soared to a 24-hour high of $3.43 on April 24, buoyed by an impressive 96% increase in trading volume. This influx was fueled by notable acquisitions from whales like Ansem, who capitalized on the positive market sentiments. Related Reading: Solana Price Jumps 7% On Bitcoin And Ethereum ETF Approvals, Network Congestion Update The breakout above the resistance level at $3.18, after a week of sideways trading between $1.97 and $3.18, was a significant trigger. WIF formed a two-week-long ascending triangle, a bullish chart pattern that indicated a continuation of the previous upward trend. The breakout was widely discussed in the crypto community, with trader Bluntz Capital confirming the pattern&#8217;s resolution and sparking further bullish sentiment. 2 week long ascending triangle forming here on $WIF, i think the breakout is imminent pic.twitter.com/S0OZWBsq6u — Bluntz (@Bluntz_Capital) April 24, 2024 BONK is registering a dramatic 35% rise, with a remarkable 304% increase in trading volume. The price action successfully breached the 0.236 Fibonacci retracement level at $0.000020727, and continued its upward trajectory to the 0.5 Fibonacci level, signaling strong buying interest and bullish momentum. This rally probably gained additional support from the recent listing of BONK by the global neobank Revolut, which was announced on April 22. This inclusion in Revolut’s trading platform, which features over 150 digital currencies, provided significant exposure and legitimacy, further enhancing investor interest and market activity around BONK. Featured image from Shutterstock, chart from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two Solana-based memecoins, Bonk (BONK) and Dogwifhat (WIF), have registered substantial gains over the past 24 hours. BONK recorded a 35% increase, while WIF climbed by 19%, positioning them among the top three gainers in the top 100 cryptocurrencies by market cap today. Only Hedera Hashgraph (HBAR) surpassed them, with a notable 44% rise during the same period.</p>
<h2>Resolution Of Solana’s Congestion Issues Spurs Memecoins</h2>
<p>The significant uptick in these Solana memecoins is closely linked to the recent improvements in the Solana network&#8217;s performance. A tweet from SolanaFloor earlier today indicated, &#8220;BREAKING: Solana&#8217;s congestion issues have been completely resolved, with block production back to normal. Transactions confirming in under 2 seconds.&#8221; This announcement marks a pivotal moment for the network which had been plagued by congestion issues.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Source A: <a href="https://t.co/2TVnbaPNlH" rel="nofollow">https://t.co/2TVnbaPNlH</a>Source B: <a href="https://t.co/GfHxy8dC1B" rel="nofollow">https://t.co/GfHxy8dC1B</a></p>
<p>&mdash; SolanaFloor | Powered by Step Finance (@SolanaFloor) <a href="https://twitter.com/SolanaFloor/status/1783039301678489778?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 24, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>On April 15, Solana developers <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/solanafirst-mainnet-update-tackle-congestion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">rolled out</a> crucial updates designed to alleviate these problems, urging validators to adopt version v1.17.31. This version introduces changes in the treatment of validators based on their stakes. Further enhancements are anticipated with the release of version v1.18 next month, which will include a new scheduler, albeit disabled by default.</p>

<p>Andrew Kang, founder of Mechanism Capital, <a href="https://twitter.com/Rewkang/status/1781162435032072422" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">remarked</a> a few days before the fix, &#8220;Let’s also not forget that the Solana congestion issues have weighed down SOL and Solana-based memecoins significantly. It’s not a question of if but when the network is significantly improved. That’s your springboard.&#8221; Kang&#8217;s comments now seem prophetic as the resolution of network issues has indeed acted as a springboard for memecoin valuations.</p>
Specifics On Rally Of Dogwifhat (WIF) And BONK
<p>The price of WIF soared to a 24-hour high of $3.43 on April 24, buoyed by an impressive 96% increase in trading volume. This influx was fueled by notable acquisitions from whales like <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/the-next-dogecoin-top-trader-this-memecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Ansem</a>, who capitalized on the positive market sentiments.</p>

<p>The breakout above the resistance level at $3.18, after a week of sideways trading between $1.97 and $3.18, was a significant trigger. WIF formed a two-week-long ascending triangle, a bullish chart pattern that indicated a continuation of the previous upward trend. The breakout was widely discussed in the crypto community, with trader Bluntz Capital confirming the pattern&#8217;s resolution and sparking further bullish sentiment.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">2 week long ascending triangle forming here on <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24WIF&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$WIF</a>, i think the breakout is imminent <a href="https://t.co/S0OZWBsq6u" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/S0OZWBsq6u</a></p>
<p>— Bluntz (@Bluntz_Capital) <a href="https://twitter.com/Bluntz_Capital/status/1782964005797302421?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 24, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/solana/solanas-memecoin-bonk-reaches-1-6-billion-market-cap-witnesses-explosive-100-price-rally/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">BONK</a> is registering a dramatic 35% rise, with a remarkable 304% increase in trading volume. The price action successfully breached the 0.236 Fibonacci retracement level at $0.000020727, and continued its upward trajectory to the 0.5 Fibonacci level, signaling strong buying interest and bullish momentum.</p>
<p>This rally probably gained additional support from the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/floki-and-bonk-drop-5-after-revolut-listing-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">recent listing</a> of BONK by the global neobank Revolut, which was announced on April 22. This inclusion in Revolut’s trading platform, which features over 150 digital currencies, provided significant exposure and legitimacy, further enhancing investor interest and market activity around BONK.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-604899 size-full" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673" alt="BONK price" width="3628" height="1673" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3628 3628w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1140 1140w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BONKUSD_2024-04-24_13-08-27.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/1500x500.jpg?fit=460%2C239" width="460" height="239" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bullish On Polkadot: Analyst Sees DOT Hitting $15 Soon</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/altcoin/bullish-on-polkadot-analyst-sees-dot-hitting-15-soon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 09:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Altcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polkadot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[price analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Polkadot (DOT), the interoperable blockchain platform designed for connecting different blockchains, is currently caught in a tug-of-war between technical indicators suggesting a potential price dip and bullish predictions from some analysts. Recent price movements paint a somewhat gloomy picture. DOT breached the lower boundary of its ascending trend channel, a technical indicator often interpreted as a sign of weakening momentum. Related Reading: Solana Meme Coin Massacre: 12 Projects Gone In 30 Days, $27 Million Vanished Trading volume also leans bearish, with sellers dominating the market and putting downward pressure on the price. Support seems to be holding around $6.30, but resistance sits stubbornly at $9.40, hindering any upward movement. Polkadot Consolidation Or Correction? However, not everyone is ready to count DOT out. Proponents point to a bullish flag pattern, suggesting a consolidation phase. This consolidation, they argue, is a healthy pause after recent fluctuations and allows for accumulation before the next significant price move. This interpretation finds support from prominent crypto analysts like World of Charts. They believe the current price action is a bullish flag, a technical pattern often seen as a precursor to a breakout. Should this breakout occur, they predict a surge in value, with DOT potentially reaching $15 in the coming weeks. $Dot#Dot Consolidating In Bullish Flag In H4 Timeframe Expecting Upside Breakout &#38; Incase Of Successful Breakout Expecting Move Towards 15$ In Coming Weeks #Crypto pic.twitter.com/nZkfjMoeDL — World Of Charts (@WorldOfCharts1) April 22, 2024 Uncertain Future For Polkadot? The conflicting technical signals make Polkadot&#8217;s future trajectory difficult to predict. The short-term outlook appears shaky, with potential for a price dip in the coming days or weeks. However, the long-term picture remains more optimistic. Polkadot&#8217;s core technology offers a compelling solution for blockchain interoperability, a major hurdle in the crypto industry. If the project continues to develop and gain traction, a significant price increase in the future remains a possibility. Total crypto market cap currently at $2.3 trillion. Chart: TradingView While the potential for a $15 price tag in the coming weeks is enticing, the current technical indicators suggest caution. Ultimately, the price of Polkadot, like all cryptocurrencies, remains highly volatile and susceptible to unforeseen events. The coming weeks will be crucial in determining whether the bulls or the bears will prevail in this ongoing battle. Polkadot JAM Protocol: Integrating Ethereum Smart Contracts, Boosting DOT&#8217;s Potential In another development, Polkadot has been at the forefront of blockchain innovation, drawing significant attention from industry stakeholders with recent developments and promising future prospects. A notable milestone is the unveiling of the Join-Accumulate Machine (JAM) Gray Paper, representing a fusion of Polkadot and Ethereum protocols. Related Reading: XRP: 600 Million Token Influx As Whales Make Their Presence Felt This protocol, as explained by the team, aims to establish a global singleton permissionless object environment akin to Ethereum&#8217;s smart-contract ecosystem, while also integrating secure sideband computation parallelized across a scalable node network, a concept pioneered by Polkadot. Moreover, the JAM protocol introduces a crucial service supporting existing parachains, allowing developers to continue utilizing Substrate for blockchain deployment. This integration of Polkadot&#8217;s infrastructure with Ethereum&#8217;s smart contract capabilities and its commitment to DOT underscores a strategic alignment towards interoperability and scalability, potentially reshaping the landscape of decentralized applications and blockchain development. Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:243">Polkadot (DOT), the interoperable blockchain platform designed for connecting different blockchains, is currently caught in a tug-of-war between technical indicators suggesting a potential price dip and bullish predictions from some analysts.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="5:1-5:422">Recent price movements paint a somewhat gloomy picture. DOT breached the lower boundary of its ascending trend channel, a technical indicator often interpreted as a sign of weakening momentum.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="5:1-5:422">Trading volume also leans bearish, with sellers dominating the market and putting downward pressure on the price. Support seems to be holding around $6.30, but resistance sits stubbornly at $9.40, hindering any upward movement.</p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="7:1-7:41"><strong>Polkadot Consolidation Or Correction?</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:301">However, not everyone is ready to count DOT out. Proponents point to a bullish flag pattern, suggesting a consolidation phase. This consolidation, they argue, is a healthy pause after recent fluctuations and allows for accumulation before the next significant price move.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:320">This interpretation finds support from prominent crypto analysts like World of Charts. They believe the<a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/polkadot" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> current price action</a> is a bullish flag, a technical pattern often seen as a precursor to a breakout. Should this breakout occur, they predict a surge in value, with DOT potentially reaching $15 in the coming weeks.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24Dot&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$Dot</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Dot?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#Dot</a> Consolidating In Bullish Flag In H4 Timeframe Expecting Upside Breakout &amp; Incase Of Successful Breakout Expecting Move Towards 15$ In Coming Weeks <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Crypto?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#Crypto</a> <a href="https://t.co/nZkfjMoeDL" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/nZkfjMoeDL</a></p>
<p>— World Of Charts (@WorldOfCharts1) <a href="https://twitter.com/WorldOfCharts1/status/1782354685741126122?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-604819" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580" alt="" width="1024" height="580" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580?w=1552 1552w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_ce0df4.png?resize=1024%2C580?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="13:1-13:33"><strong>Uncertain Future For Polkadot?</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:494">The conflicting technical signals make Polkadot&#8217;s future trajectory difficult to predict. The short-term outlook appears shaky, with potential for a price dip in the coming days or weeks.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:494">However, the long-term picture remains more optimistic. Polkadot&#8217;s core technology offers a compelling solution for blockchain interoperability, a major hurdle in the crypto industry. If the project continues to develop and gain traction, a significant price increase in the future remains a possibility.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:494"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/tUfYNja0/" width="1835" height="883"/></p>

<p data-sourcepos="17:1-17:377">While the potential for a $15 price tag in the coming weeks is enticing, the current technical indicators suggest caution. Ultimately, the price of Polkadot, like all cryptocurrencies, remains highly volatile and susceptible to unforeseen events. The coming weeks will be crucial in determining whether the bulls or the bears will prevail in this ongoing battle.</p>
<strong>Polkadot JAM Protocol: Integrating Ethereum Smart Contracts, Boosting DOT&#8217;s Potential</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="19:1-19:241">In another development, Polkadot has been at the forefront of blockchain innovation, drawing significant attention from industry stakeholders with recent developments and promising future prospects. A notable milestone is the unveiling of the Join-Accumulate Machine (JAM) Gray Paper, representing a fusion of Polkadot and Ethereum protocols.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="19:1-19:241">This protocol, as explained by the team, aims to establish a global singleton permissionless object environment akin to Ethereum&#8217;s smart-contract ecosystem, while also integrating secure sideband computation parallelized across a scalable node network, a concept pioneered by Polkadot.</p>












<p>Moreover, the JAM protocol introduces a crucial service supporting existing parachains, allowing developers to continue utilizing Substrate for blockchain deployment.</p>
<p>This integration of Polkadot&#8217;s infrastructure with Ethereum&#8217;s smart contract capabilities and its commitment to DOT underscores a strategic alignment towards interoperability and scalability, potentially reshaping the landscape of decentralized applications and blockchain development.</p>
<p><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>












]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_defd8d.jpg?fit=460%2C297" width="460" height="297" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604814</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Outperform In Crypto: Arthur Hayes&#8217; &#8216;Left Curve&#8217; Strategy</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/how-to-outperform-crypto-arthur-hayes-left-curve/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arthur Hayes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arthur Hayes Left Curve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In his latest essay, Arthur Hayes, the former CEO of crypto exchange BitMEX, introduced a bold investment philosophy he calls the &#8220;Left Curve.&#8221; This strategy diverges sharply from traditional investment approaches typically adopted during bull markets in the crypto world. Hayes&#8217; essay serves not only as an investment manifesto but also as a critique of conventional financial wisdom, encouraging investors to maximize their returns by embracing more aggressive tactics. Crypto Bull Run Just Got Started Hayes begins by criticizing the common investor mentality that prevails during bull markets, particularly the tendency to revert to conservative strategies after initial gains. He argues that many investors, despite having made profitable decisions, fail to capitalize fully on bull markets by selling their holdings too soon—particularly when they convert high-performing cryptocurrencies into fiat currencies. &#8220;Some of you think you are masters of the universe right now because you bought Solana sub $10 and sold it at $200,&#8221; he states, challenging the notion that such actions demonstrate market mastery. Instead, Hayes promotes a strategy of sustained investment and accumulation, particularly in Bitcoin, which he refers to as &#8220;the hardest money ever created.&#8221; Related Reading: Akash Network (AKT) Leads Crypto Top 100 With 46% Rise Today: Here’s Why A central thesis of Hayes&#8217; argument is the critique of fiat currency as a safe haven for profits taken from cryptocurrency investments. &#8220;If you sold shitcoins for fiat that you don’t immediately need for living expenses, you are fucking up,&#8221; Hayes bluntly asserts. He discusses the inherent weaknesses of fiat money, primarily its susceptibility to inflation and devaluation through endless cycles of printing by central banks. &#8220;Fiat will continue to be printed ad infinitum until the system resets,&#8221; he predicts, suggesting that fiat currencies are inherently unstable storage of value compared to cryptocurrencies. Hayes extends his analysis to the macroeconomic factors influencing cryptocurrency markets. He describes how major economies like the US, China, the European Union, and Japan are debasing their currencies to manage national debt levels. This macroeconomic maneuvering, according to Hayes, is inadvertently setting the stage for cryptocurrencies to rise. He points out the increasing adoption of Bitcoin ETFs in the US, UK, and Hong Kong markets as a tool for institutional and retail investors to hedge against fiat depreciation. Related Reading: ‘More Upside Is Coming’: Crypto Market Set For 350% Growth, Predicts Glassnode Cofounders This part of his analysis underscores a broader acceptance of cryptocurrency as a legitimate asset class in traditional investment circles, powered by the realization that traditional financial systems are struggling under the weight of unsustainable fiscal policies. Hayes also delves into the strategic aspects of market timing, particularly around events known to influence market dynamics, such as US tax payment deadlines and Bitcoin halving. He notes: As we exit the window of weakness that I forecasted would occur due to April 15th US tax payments and the Bitcoin halving, I want to remind readers why the bull market will continue and prices will get sillier on the upside. This observation suggests that understanding these cyclic events can provide strategic entry and exit points for maximizing investment returns. Emphasizing psychological resilience, Hayes encourages investors to adopt a mindset that resists the conventional impulse to cash out during brief market rallies. &#8220;At this moment, I will resist the urge to take chips off the table. I will encourage myself to add more to the winners,&#8221; he advises, promoting a long-term view of investment in cryptocurrencies. This approach, according to Hayes, is essential for realizing the full potential of crypto investments, particularly in a market characterized by high volatility and rapid gains. In conclusion, Hayes&#8217; &#8220;Left Curve&#8221; philosophy is more than just an investment strategy; it is a comprehensive approach that encompasses understanding macroeconomic trends, psychological resilience, and strategic market timing. His essay serves as a guide for investors looking to navigate the complexities of crypto markets with a bold, assertive strategy that challenges traditional financial doctrines. At press time, BTC traded at $66,789. Featured image created with Bloomberg, chart from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In his latest <a href="https://cryptohayes.medium.com/left-curve-ef2e1e187027" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">essay</a>, Arthur Hayes, the former CEO of crypto exchange BitMEX, introduced a bold investment philosophy he calls the &#8220;Left Curve.&#8221; This strategy diverges sharply from traditional investment approaches typically adopted during bull markets in the crypto world. Hayes&#8217; essay serves not only as an investment manifesto but also as a critique of conventional financial wisdom, encouraging investors to maximize their returns by embracing more aggressive tactics.</p>
<h2>Crypto Bull Run Just Got Started</h2>
<p>Hayes begins by criticizing the common investor mentality that prevails during bull markets, particularly the tendency to revert to conservative strategies after initial gains. He argues that many investors, despite having made profitable decisions, fail to capitalize fully on bull markets by selling their holdings too soon—particularly when they convert high-performing cryptocurrencies into fiat currencies.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some of you think you are masters of the universe right now because you bought <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/solana/market-expert-reveals-why-solana-price-is-poised-to-go-higher/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Solana</a> sub $10 and sold it at $200,&#8221; he states, challenging the notion that such actions demonstrate market mastery. Instead, Hayes promotes a strategy of sustained investment and accumulation, particularly in Bitcoin, which he refers to as &#8220;the hardest money ever created.&#8221;</p>

<p>A central thesis of Hayes&#8217; argument is the critique of fiat currency as a safe haven for profits taken from cryptocurrency investments. &#8220;If you sold shitcoins for fiat that you don’t immediately need for living expenses, you are fucking up,&#8221; Hayes bluntly asserts.</p>
<p>He discusses the inherent weaknesses of fiat money, primarily its susceptibility to inflation and devaluation through endless cycles of printing by central banks. &#8220;Fiat will continue to be printed ad infinitum until the system resets,&#8221; he predicts, suggesting that fiat currencies are inherently unstable storage of value compared to cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>Hayes extends his analysis to the macroeconomic factors influencing cryptocurrency markets. He describes how major economies like the US, China, the European Union, and Japan are debasing their currencies to manage national debt levels.</p>
<p>This macroeconomic maneuvering, according to Hayes, is inadvertently setting the stage for cryptocurrencies to rise. He points out the increasing adoption of <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/all-quiet-on-the-bitcoin-etf-front-should-you-be-paranoid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin ETFs in the US</a>, UK, and <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/spot-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-approved-hong-kong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Hong Kong</a> markets as a tool for institutional and retail investors to hedge against fiat depreciation.</p>

<p>This part of his analysis underscores a broader acceptance of cryptocurrency as a legitimate asset class in traditional investment circles, powered by the realization that traditional financial systems are struggling under the weight of unsustainable fiscal policies.</p>
<p>Hayes also delves into the strategic aspects of market timing, particularly around events known to influence market dynamics, such as US tax payment deadlines and Bitcoin halving. He notes:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>As we exit the window of weakness that I forecasted would occur due to April 15th US tax payments and the Bitcoin halving, I want to remind readers why the bull market will continue and prices will get sillier on the upside.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>This observation suggests that understanding these cyclic events can provide strategic entry and exit points for maximizing investment returns. Emphasizing psychological resilience, Hayes encourages investors to adopt a mindset that resists the conventional impulse to cash out during brief market rallies. &#8220;At this moment, I will resist the urge to take chips off the table. I will encourage myself to add more to the winners,&#8221; he advises, promoting a long-term view of investment in cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>This approach, according to Hayes, is essential for realizing the full potential of crypto investments, particularly in a market characterized by high volatility and rapid gains. In conclusion, Hayes&#8217; &#8220;Left Curve&#8221; philosophy is more than just an investment strategy; it is a comprehensive approach that encompasses understanding macroeconomic trends, psychological resilience, and strategic market timing.</p>
<p>His essay serves as a guide for investors looking to navigate the complexities of crypto markets with a bold, assertive strategy that challenges traditional financial doctrines.</p>
<p>At press time, BTC traded at $66,789.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-604815 size-full" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673" alt="Bitcoin price" width="3628" height="1673" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3628 3628w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1140 1140w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-24_08-48-54.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/1x-1-1.jpg?fit=460%2C259" width="460" height="259" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604798</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>XRP: 600 Million Token Influx As Whales Make Their Presence Felt</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-600-million-token-influx-as-whales-make-their-presence-felt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 06:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[price analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cryptocurrency market continues to grapple with volatility, and XRP has been no exception. After a promising start to the year, the price of XRP has mirrored the broader market slump triggered by Bitcoin&#8217;s correction. However, amidst the bearish sentiment, a different story is unfolding underwater – one involving deep-pocketed investors, or &#8220;whales,&#8221; accumulating the altcoin at a significant clip. Related Reading: Solana Meme Coin Massacre: 12 Projects Gone In 30 Days, $27 Million Vanished XRP Whales Accumulate Millions Despite Price Drop While the price of XRP has dipped considerably from its highs in March, whale addresses have been quietly going on a buying spree. According to data from market intelligence platform Santiment, analyzed by market researcher Ali Martinez, addresses holding between 10 million and 100 million XRP have been steadily adding to their holdings since early April. This buying frenzy intensified after XRP&#8217;s sharp price drop in mid-April, with whales capitalizing on the lower prices in a classic &#8220;buy-the-dip&#8221; strategy. $XRP dropped from $0.62 to $0.41, and #crypto whales took notice. They&#8217;ve bought over 31 million #XRP in just the past week! pic.twitter.com/3FCA3PR3hi — Ali (@ali_charts) April 23, 2024 The data reveals that these whales have scooped up a staggering 30 million XRP tokens in the past week alone, bringing their cumulative holdings to a hefty 6.75 billion units. This buying spree indicates a potential shift in sentiment among these large investors, who seem unfazed by the short-term price fluctuations and might be betting on XRP&#8217;s long-term prospects. Deeper Dive: Whale Activity Hints At Bullish Sentiment Taking a deeper dive, latest data suggests that this accumulation trend began even earlier, on April 5th. Interestingly, this coincides with the tail end of a selling period by these same whales, where they offloaded some of their holdings. However, since April 5th, the buying spree has been relentless, with whales amassing over 600 million XRP in just two weeks. This significant accumulation suggests a renewed confidence in XRP, potentially signaling a bullish outlook from these key market players. Total crypto market cap currently at $2.391 trillion. Chart: TradingView Further bolstering this notion is the recent surge in the number of addresses holding at least 1 million XRP. These &#8220;mid-tier whales&#8221; have been steadily increasing, with their ranks reaching a near-record high of 2,013 on Tuesday. This broader participation from various tiers of large investors adds weight to the idea that XRP might be undervalued at its current price point. 🐳 The price of #XRP has jumped ahead of the #altcoin pack, jumping +6% and as high as $0.5687 today. The amount of wallets, 2,013, holding at least 1M $XRP has been surging over the past six weeks (rising 3.1%), and is within 1 wallet of the #AllTimeHigh. https://t.co/2ZfC9v79x9 pic.twitter.com/rqKgcOYJJx — Santiment (@santimentfeed) April 22, 2024 XRP Outperforms Other Altcoins Meanwhile, Santiment disclosed that XRP is outpacing the other altcoins in terms of wallet size. Wallets holding 1 million or more coins have increased, with a 3% gain over the last six weeks. The increase of significant XRP holdings indicates that investors&#8217; interest and confidence are rising. Related Reading: The Cardano $1 Dream: Is A Price Explosion Coming Or Just Deja Vu? While whale activity can be a significant indicator of sentiment, it shouldn&#8217;t be the sole factor driving investment decisions. However, the recent buying spree by XRP whales is a noteworthy development, suggesting a potential shift in sentiment and a possible turning point for the coin&#8217;s price. Featured image from Pixabay, chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:396">The cryptocurrency market continues to grapple with volatility, and XRP has been no exception. After a promising start to the year, the <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/xrp" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">price of XRP</a> has mirrored the broader market slump triggered by Bitcoin&#8217;s correction. However, amidst the bearish sentiment, a different story is unfolding underwater – one involving deep-pocketed investors, or &#8220;whales,&#8221; accumulating the altcoin at a significant clip.</p>

<h2 data-sourcepos="5:1-5:53"><strong>XRP Whales Accumulate Millions Despite Price Drop</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:484">While the price of XRP has dipped considerably from its highs in March, whale addresses have been quietly going on a buying spree. According to data from market intelligence platform Santiment, analyzed by market researcher Ali Martinez, addresses holding between 10 million and 100 million XRP have been steadily adding to their holdings since early April.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:484">This buying frenzy intensified after XRP&#8217;s sharp price drop in mid-April, with whales capitalizing on the lower prices in a classic &#8220;buy-the-dip&#8221; strategy.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24XRP&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$XRP</a> dropped from $0.62 to $0.41, and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/crypto?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#crypto</a> whales took notice. They&#8217;ve bought over 31 million <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XRP?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#XRP</a> in just the past week! <a href="https://t.co/3FCA3PR3hi" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/3FCA3PR3hi</a></p>
<p>— Ali (@ali_charts) <a href="https://twitter.com/ali_charts/status/1782702831973085397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:366">The data reveals that these whales have scooped up a staggering 30 million XRP tokens in the past week alone, bringing their cumulative holdings to a hefty 6.75 billion units. This buying spree indicates a potential shift in sentiment among these large investors, who seem unfazed by the short-term price fluctuations and might be betting on XRP&#8217;s long-term prospects.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="9:1-9:366"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-604783" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464" alt="" width="1024" height="464" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464?w=1621 1621w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_543230.png?resize=1024%2C464?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
<h2 data-sourcepos="11:1-11:58"><strong>Deeper Dive: Whale Activity Hints At Bullish Sentiment</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="13:1-13:521">Taking a deeper dive, latest data suggests that this accumulation trend began even earlier, on April 5th. Interestingly, this coincides with the tail end of a selling period by these same whales, where they offloaded some of their holdings.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="13:1-13:521">However, since April 5th, the buying spree has been relentless, with whales amassing over 600 million XRP in just two weeks. This significant accumulation suggests a renewed confidence in XRP, potentially signaling a bullish outlook from these key market players.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:381"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/2KI6kmZa/" width="1835" height="883"/></p>

<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:381">Further bolstering this notion is the recent surge in the number of addresses holding at least 1 million XRP. These &#8220;mid-tier whales&#8221; have been steadily increasing, with their ranks reaching a near-record high of 2,013 on Tuesday. This broader participation from various tiers of large investors adds weight to the idea that XRP might be undervalued at its current price point.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f433.png" alt="🐳" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> The price of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XRP?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#XRP</a> has jumped ahead of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/altcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#altcoin</a> pack, jumping +6% and as high as $0.5687 today. The amount of wallets, 2,013, holding at least 1M <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24XRP&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$XRP</a> has been surging over the past six weeks (rising 3.1%), and is within 1 wallet of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AllTimeHigh?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#AllTimeHigh</a>. <a href="https://t.co/2ZfC9v79x9" rel="nofollow">https://t.co/2ZfC9v79x9</a> <a href="https://t.co/rqKgcOYJJx" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/rqKgcOYJJx</a></p>
<p>— Santiment (@santimentfeed) <a href="https://twitter.com/santimentfeed/status/1782524613987320181?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<strong>XRP Outperforms Other Altcoins</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:381">Meanwhile, Santiment disclosed that XRP is outpacing the other altcoins in terms of wallet size. Wallets holding 1 million or more coins have increased, with a 3% gain over the last six weeks. The increase of significant XRP holdings indicates that investors&#8217; interest and confidence are rising.</p>

<p data-sourcepos="19:1-19:578">While whale activity can be a significant indicator of sentiment, it shouldn&#8217;t be the sole factor driving investment decisions. However, the recent buying spree by XRP whales is a noteworthy development, suggesting a potential shift in sentiment and a possible turning point for the coin&#8217;s price.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="19:1-19:578"><em>Featured image from Pixabay, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_7fadfc.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604781</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>XRP Price Reclaims $0.50 and Indicators Suggest Fresh Surge To $0.70</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-price-reclaims-0-50/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aayush Jindal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 05:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPBTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrpusdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604778</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[XRP price is recovering higher above the $0.500 resistance. The price is signaling a positive bias and might rally above the $0.580 and $0.600 levels. XRP is attempting a recovery wave above the $0.50 zone. The price is now trading above $0.5150 and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours). There was a break above a key bearish trend line with resistance at $0.5220 on the 4-hour chart of the XRP/USD pair (data source from Kraken). The pair could gain bullish momentum if there is a close above the $0.580 resistance. XRP Price Aims Higher After a sharp decline, XRP price found support near the $0.3880 zone. It formed a base and started a fresh increase above the $0.450 resistance, like Bitcoin and Ethereum. The bulls were able to push the price above the $0.50 resistance. The price climbed above the 50% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $0.6420 swing high to the $0.3875 low. Besides, there was a break above a key bearish trend line with resistance at $0.5220 on the 4-hour chart of the XRP/USD pair. The price is now trading above $0.5150 and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours). Immediate resistance is near the $0.5650 level. The next key resistance is near $0.5820 or the 76.4% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $0.6420 swing high to the $0.3875 low. Source: XRPUSD on TradingView.com A close above the $0.5820 resistance zone could spark a strong increase. The next key resistance is near $0.620. If the bulls remain in action above the $0.620 resistance level, there could be a rally toward the $0.680 resistance. Any more gains might send the price toward the $0.700 resistance. Another Drop? If XRP fails to clear the $0.5820 resistance zone, it could start another decline. Initial support on the downside is near the $0.540 level. The next major support is at $0.5150. If there is a downside break and a close below the $0.5150 level, the price might accelerate lower. In the stated case, the price could retest the $0.4650 support zone. Technical Indicators 4-Hours MACD – The MACD for XRP/USD is now gaining pace in the bullish zone. 4-Hours RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for XRP/USD is now above the 50 level. Major Support Levels – $0.540, $0.5150, and $0.4650. Major Resistance Levels – $0.5650, $0.5820, and $0.6200.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>XRP price is recovering higher above the $0.500 resistance. The price is signaling a positive bias and might rally above the $0.580 and $0.600 levels.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>XRP is attempting a recovery wave above the $0.50 zone.</li>
<li>The price is now trading above $0.5150 and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours).</li>
<li>There was a break above a key bearish trend line with resistance at $0.5220 on the 4-hour chart of the XRP/USD pair (data source from Kraken).</li>
<li>The pair could gain bullish momentum if there is a close above the $0.580 resistance.</li>
</ul>
<h2>XRP Price Aims Higher</h2>
<p>After a sharp decline, XRP price found support near the $0.3880 zone. It formed a base and started a fresh increase above the $0.450 resistance, like <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-eyes-70k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin</a> and <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-holds-support-3000/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Ethereum</a>. The bulls were able to push the price above the $0.50 resistance.</p>
<p>The price climbed above the 50% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $0.6420 swing high to the $0.3875 low. Besides, there was a break above a key bearish trend line with resistance at $0.5220 on the 4-hour chart of the XRP/USD pair.</p>
<p>The price is now trading above $0.5150 and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours). Immediate resistance is near the $0.5650 level. The next key resistance is near $0.5820 or the 76.4% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $0.6420 swing high to the $0.3875 low.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604779" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461" alt="XRP Price" width="1024" height="461" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1835 1835w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP_Price_754d13.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/XRPUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">XRPUSD on TradingView.com</a></p>
<p>A close above the $0.5820 resistance zone could spark a strong increase. The next key resistance is near $0.620. If the bulls remain in action above the $0.620 resistance level, there could be a rally toward the $0.680 resistance. Any more gains might send the price toward the $0.700 resistance.</p>
<h2>Another Drop?</h2>
<p>If XRP fails to clear the $0.5820 resistance zone, it could start another decline. Initial support on the downside is near the $0.540 level.</p>
<p>The next major support is at $0.5150. If there is a downside break and a close below the $0.5150 level, the price might accelerate lower. In the stated case, the price could retest the $0.4650 support zone.</p>
<p>Technical Indicators</p>
<p>4-Hours MACD – The MACD for XRP/USD is now gaining pace in the bullish zone.</p>
<p>4-Hours RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for XRP/USD is now above the 50 level.</p>
<p>Major Support Levels – $0.540, $0.5150, and $0.4650.</p>
<p>Major Resistance Levels – $0.5650, $0.5820, and $0.6200.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/shutterstock_170515580.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604778</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum Price Holds Support – Why ETH Could Soon Rally 5%</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-holds-support-3000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aayush Jindal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 04:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethbtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ethereum price is holding gains above the $3,120 resistance zone. ETH could soon rally if it clears the $3,280 resistance zone. Ethereum extended its increase above the $3,220 resistance zone. The price is trading above $3,165 and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average. There is a key bullish trend line forming with support at $3,170 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD (data feed via Kraken). The pair could continue to move up if it clears the $3,280 resistance zone. Ethereum Price Aims Higher Ethereum price remained in a positive zone above the $3,000 level, like Bitcoin. ETH extended its increase above the $3,150 and $3,165 resistance levels. It even spiked above the $3,250 resistance. It traded to a new weekly high at $3,263 and recently corrected lower. There was a minor decline below the $3,220 level. Ether dipped below the 50% Fib retracement level of the recent wave from the $3,154 swing low to the $3,263 high. However, the bulls were active above the $3,200 level. The 61.8% Fib retracement level of the recent wave from the $3,154 swing low to the $3,263 high acted as a support. Ethereum is now trading above $3,200 and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average. There is also a key bullish trend line forming with support at $3,170 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD. Immediate resistance is near the $3,250 level. The first major resistance is near the $3,280 level. Source: ETHUSD on TradingView.com The next key resistance sits at $3,350, above which the price might gain traction and rise toward the $3,500 level. A close above the $3,500 resistance could send the price toward the $3,550 resistance. If there is a move above the $3,550 resistance, Ethereum could even test the $3,750 resistance. Any more gains could send Ether toward the $3,880 resistance zone in the coming days. Another Drop In ETH? If Ethereum fails to clear the $3,280 resistance, it could start a downside correction. Initial support on the downside is near the $3,200 level. The first major support is near the $3,180 zone and the trend line. The main support is near the $3,120 level. A clear move below the $3,120 support might increase selling pressure and send the price toward $3,030. Any more losses might send the price toward the $2,850 level in the near term. Technical Indicators Hourly MACD – The MACD for ETH/USD is gaining momentum in the bullish zone. Hourly RSI &#8211; The RSI for ETH/USD is now above the 50 level. Major Support Level – $3,120 Major Resistance Level – $3,280]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Ethereum price is holding gains above the $3,120 resistance zone. ETH could soon rally if it clears the $3,280 resistance zone.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Ethereum extended its increase above the $3,220 resistance zone.</li>
<li>The price is trading above $3,165 and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average.</li>
<li>There is a key bullish trend line forming with support at $3,170 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD (data feed via Kraken).</li>
<li>The pair could continue to move up if it clears the $3,280 resistance zone.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Ethereum Price Aims Higher</h2>
<p>Ethereum price remained in a positive zone above the $3,000 level, like <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-eyes-70k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin</a>. ETH extended its increase above the $3,150 and $3,165 resistance levels. It even spiked above the $3,250 resistance.</p>
<p>It traded to a new weekly high at $3,263 and recently corrected lower. There was a minor decline below the $3,220 level. Ether dipped below the 50% Fib retracement level of the recent wave from the $3,154 swing low to the $3,263 high.</p>
<p>However, the bulls were active above the $3,200 level. The 61.8% Fib retracement level of the recent wave from the $3,154 swing low to the $3,263 high acted as a support.</p>
<p>Ethereum is now trading above $3,200 and the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-reversal-3400/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">100-hourly Simple Moving Average</a>. There is also a key bullish trend line forming with support at $3,170 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD. Immediate resistance is near the $3,250 level. The first major resistance is near the $3,280 level.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604775" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461" alt="Ethereum Price" width="1024" height="461" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1835 1835w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_294fa7.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ETHUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ETHUSD on TradingView.com</a></p>
<p>The next key resistance sits at $3,350, above which the price might gain traction and rise toward the $3,500 level. A close above the $3,500 resistance could send the price toward the $3,550 resistance. If there is a move above the $3,550 resistance, Ethereum could even test the $3,750 resistance. Any more gains could send Ether toward the $3,880 resistance zone in the coming days.</p>
<h2>Another Drop In ETH?</h2>
<p>If Ethereum fails to clear the $3,280 resistance, it could start a downside correction. Initial support on the downside is near the $3,200 level. The first major support is near the $3,180 zone and the trend line.</p>
<p>The main support is near the $3,120 level. A clear move below the $3,120 support might increase selling pressure and send the price toward $3,030. Any more losses might send the price toward the $2,850 level in the near term.</p>
<p>Technical Indicators</p>
<p>Hourly MACD<strong> – </strong>The MACD for ETH/USD is gaining momentum in the bullish zone.</p>
<p>Hourly RSI<strong> &#8211; </strong>The RSI for ETH/USD is now above the 50 level.</p>
<p>Major Support Level – $3,120</p>
<p>Major Resistance Level – $3,280</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/iStock-935533896.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604774</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Price Eyes Next Breakout As The Bulls Aim For $70K</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-eyes-70k/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aayush Jindal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 03:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xbtusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604771</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin price climbed above the $66,000 resistance zone and started consolidation. BTC is now eyeing the next move above the $67,200 resistance zone. Bitcoin is eyeing a decent increase above the $67,200 resistance zone. The price is trading above $65,500 and the 100 hourly Simple moving average. There is a connecting bullish trend line forming with support at $65,900 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair (data feed from Kraken). The pair could gain bullish momentum if it clears the $67,200 resistance zone. Bitcoin Price Eyes More Upsides Bitcoin price started a fresh increase above the $65,500 and $66,000 resistance levels. BTC even climbed above the $67,000 level. It traded as high as $67,200 and is currently consolidating gains. There was a minor decline below the $66,500 level, but the price remained stable above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $64,280 swing low to the $67,200 low. Bitcoin price is still trading above $65,500 and the 100 hourly Simple moving average. There is also a connecting bullish trend line forming with support at $65,900 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair. The trend line is near the 50% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $64,280 swing low to the $67,200 low. Immediate resistance is near the $67,000 level. The first major resistance could be $67,200. A clear move above the $67,200 resistance might send the price higher. The next resistance now sits at $68,500. If there is a clear move above the $68,500 resistance zone, the price could continue to move up. In the stated case, the price could rise toward $70,000. Source: BTCUSD on TradingView.com The next major resistance is near the $70,500 zone. Any more gains might send Bitcoin toward the $72,000 resistance zone in the near term. Are Dips Limited In BTC? If Bitcoin fails to rise above the $67,000 resistance zone, it could start a downside correction. Immediate support on the downside is near the $66,200 level. The first major support is $66,000 or the trend line. If there is a close below $66,000, the price could start to drop toward $65,400. Any more losses might send the price toward the $64,200 support zone in the near term. Technical indicators: Hourly MACD – The MACD is now losing pace in the bullish zone. Hourly RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for BTC/USD is now above the 50 level. Major Support Levels – $66,200, followed by $66,000. Major Resistance Levels – $67,000, $67,200, and $68,500.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Bitcoin price climbed above the $66,000 resistance zone and started consolidation. BTC is now eyeing the next move above the $67,200 resistance zone.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Bitcoin is eyeing a decent increase above the $67,200 resistance zone.</li>
<li>The price is trading above $65,500 and the 100 hourly Simple moving average.</li>
<li>There is a connecting bullish trend line forming with support at $65,900 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair (data feed from Kraken).</li>
<li>The pair could gain bullish momentum if it clears the $67,200 resistance zone.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Bitcoin Price Eyes More Upsides</h2>
<p>Bitcoin price started a <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-extends-increase-67k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">fresh increase</a> above the $65,500 and $66,000 resistance levels. BTC even climbed above the $67,000 level. It traded as high as $67,200 and is currently consolidating gains.</p>
<p>There was a minor decline below the $66,500 level, but the price remained stable above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $64,280 swing low to the $67,200 low. Bitcoin price is still trading above $65,500 and the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-pump-66k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">100 hourly Simple moving average</a>.</p>
<p>There is also a connecting bullish trend line forming with support at $65,900 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair. The trend line is near the 50% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $64,280 swing low to the $67,200 low.</p>
<p>Immediate resistance is near the $67,000 level. The first major resistance could be $67,200. A clear move above the $67,200 resistance might send the price higher. The next resistance now sits at $68,500. If there is a clear move above the $68,500 resistance zone, the price could continue to move up. In the stated case, the price could rise toward $70,000.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604772" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461" alt="Bitcoin Price" width="1024" height="461" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1835 1835w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_0576e3.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">BTCUSD on TradingView.com</a></p>
<p>The next major resistance is near the $70,500 zone. Any more gains might send Bitcoin toward the $72,000 resistance zone in the near term.</p>
<h2>Are Dips Limited In BTC?</h2>
<p>If Bitcoin fails to rise above the $67,000 resistance zone, it could start a downside correction. Immediate support on the downside is near the $66,200 level.</p>
<p>The first major support is $66,000 or the trend line. If there is a close below $66,000, the price could start to drop toward $65,400. Any more losses might send the price toward the $64,200 support zone in the near term.</p>
<p>Technical indicators:</p>
<p>Hourly MACD – The MACD is now losing pace in the bullish zone.</p>
<p>Hourly RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for BTC/USD is now above the 50 level.</p>
<p>Major Support Levels – $66,200, followed by $66,000.</p>
<p>Major Resistance Levels – $67,000, $67,200, and $68,500.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/shutterstock_1069524017.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604771</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is A $72K Bitcoin Surge On The Horizon? Glassnode&#8217;s Latest Analysis Points To An Answer</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/is-a-72k-bitcoin-surge-on-the-horizon-glassnodes-analysis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Edyme]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 02:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin prediction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto asset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glassnode]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recent insights from Glassnode&#8217;s cofounders, shared under their X (formerly Twitter) account &#8216;Negentrophic&#8217; have sparked interest in Bitcoin market dynamics, leading to a promising stabilization and possible price surge. Related Reading: ‘More Upside Is Coming’: Crypto Market Set For 350% Growth, Predicts Glassnode Cofounders Market Sentiments And EMA Trends With Bitcoin&#8217;s value recently wavering below the $70,000 mark, a detailed analysis from the cofounders suggests that a strong support level around the $62,000 50-day Exponential Moving Average (EMA) could set the stage for a significant rebound. This crucial support level indicates a strong buying sentiment, indicating the market&#8217;s confidence in the cryptocurrency&#8217;s value and a potential resistance against further declines. Using the strategic placement of the 50-day EMA as a support point, the analysis suggests that investors might see the current price levels as a solid base, preventing significant downward movements. #BTC potential trajectory may offer Buy-the-dips Opportunities BTC&#8217;s 50-day EMA near $62k provides potential support, targeting $72k for a rebound. Shorter EMAs signal a tendency to buy, while longer EMAs suggest a preference for selling. Given BTC’s recent significant gains… pic.twitter.com/3NjUUqa001 — 𝗡𝗲𝗴𝗲𝗻𝘁𝗿𝗼𝗽𝗶𝗰 (@Negentropic_) April 23, 2024 This perspective is reinforced by recent price movements, where despite a pre-halving general dip, Bitcoin has experienced a 7.1% increase in value over the past week, and the same uptick continued in the last 24 hours. Further analysis by the Glassnode cofounders delves into the behavior of EMAs over different durations. Short-term EMAs indicate a growing inclination among investors to buy, while longer-term EMAs lean towards selling. This contrasting behavior between short and long-term EMAs sheds light on the current phase of the market, which seems to be in a period of consolidation after the notable 92% increase in Bitcoin’s price over six weeks earlier in the year. Such insights are vital as they offer a deeper understanding of the underlying market forces and investor behavior during volatile periods. Meanwhile, Glassnode’s team&#8217;s analytical approach extends beyond simple price movements. Yesterday, they compared the current market conditions to the early 2021 &#8220;strong correction,&#8221; which they term &#8220;wave 4&#8221; of the ongoing market cycle. This historical perspective provides a lens through which current trends can be evaluated, suggesting a cyclic return to bullish conditions reminiscent of past market behaviors. Bitcoin Bullish Projections And Market Dynamics Bitfinex analysts have highlighted significant activities around Bitcoin withdrawals, supporting the optimistic outlook on Bitcoin. The current levels, echo those of January 2023, suggest that investors are increasingly moving their Bitcoin to cold storage—a sign that many anticipate further price increases. Related Reading: Analyst Reveals Bitcoin’s Bull Market Breakthrough: Here’s What You Need To Know Veering back to Glassnode’s projections yesterday based on their indexes and Fibonacci levels, the cofounders were boldly optimistic, anticipating a potential 350% increase from current market levels. The #Crypto Bull Market Continues. &#8220;OTHERS&#8221; follows Crypto excl. the largest 10 Cryptos. Observe that we in early 2021 had a strong correction. We believe that was a wave 4. We now have a similar strong decline. More upside is coming. This index and our Fibonacci levels… pic.twitter.com/qKtIOSXneP — 𝗡𝗲𝗴𝗲𝗻𝘁𝗿𝗼𝗽𝗶𝗰 (@Negentropic_) April 22, 2024 Notably, this forecast highlights the expected financial trajectory and underscores a growing confidence among experts and market analysts in Bitcoin&#8217;s market performance and its foundational economic principles. Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recent insights from Glassnode&#8217;s cofounders, <a href="https://x.com/Negentropic_/status/1782721645175566404" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">shared</a> under their X (formerly Twitter) account &#8216;Negentrophic&#8217; have sparked interest in Bitcoin market dynamics, leading to a promising stabilization and possible price surge.</p>

<h2>Market Sentiments And EMA Trends</h2>
<p>With Bitcoin&#8217;s value recently wavering below the $70,000 mark, a detailed analysis from the cofounders suggests that a strong support level around the $62,000 50-day Exponential Moving Average (EMA) could set the stage for a significant rebound.</p>
<p>This crucial support level indicates a strong buying sentiment, indicating the market&#8217;s confidence in the cryptocurrency&#8217;s value and a potential resistance against further declines.</p>
<p>Using the strategic placement of the 50-day EMA as a support point, the analysis suggests that investors might see the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/conservative-projection-places-bitcoin-at-245000-in-5-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">current price levels</a> as a solid base, preventing significant downward movements.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://x.com/Negentropic_/status/1782721645175566404" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#BTC</a> potential trajectory may offer Buy-the-dips Opportunities</p>
<p>BTC&#8217;s 50-day EMA near $62k provides potential support, targeting $72k for a rebound.</p>
<p>Shorter EMAs signal a tendency to buy, while longer EMAs suggest a preference for selling.</p>
<p>Given BTC’s recent significant gains… <a href="https://x.com/Negentropic_/status/1782721645175566404" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">pic.twitter.com/3NjUUqa001</a></p>
<p>— 𝗡𝗲𝗴𝗲𝗻𝘁𝗿𝗼𝗽𝗶𝗰 (@Negentropic_) <a href="https://x.com/Negentropic_/status/1782721645175566404" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">April 23, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>This perspective is reinforced by recent price movements, where despite a pre-halving general dip, Bitcoin has experienced a 7.1% increase in value over the past week, and the same uptick continued in the last 24 hours.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/90xKaONv/" alt="Bitcoin (BTC) price chart on TradingView" width="2770" height="1496"/>
<p>Further analysis by the Glassnode cofounders delves into the behavior of EMAs over different durations. Short-term EMAs indicate a growing inclination among investors to buy, while longer-term EMAs lean towards selling.</p>
<p>This contrasting behavior between short and long-term EMAs sheds light on the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/market-expert-predicts-new-paradigm-for-bitcoin-days-under-100000-numbered/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">current phase</a> of the market, which seems to be in a period of consolidation after the notable 92% increase in Bitcoin’s price over six weeks earlier in the year.</p>
<p>Such insights are vital as they offer a deeper understanding of the underlying market forces and investor behavior during volatile periods.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Glassnode’s team&#8217;s analytical approach extends beyond simple price movements. Yesterday, they <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/crypto-market-set-for-growth-predicts-glassnode-cofounders/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">compared the current market conditions to the early 2021 &#8220;strong correction,&#8221;</a> which they term &#8220;wave 4&#8221; of the ongoing market cycle.</p>
<p>This historical perspective provides a lens through which current trends can be evaluated, suggesting a cyclic return to bullish conditions reminiscent of past market behaviors.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Bullish Projections And Market Dynamics</h2>
<p>Bitfinex analysts have <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-market-dynamics-still-positive-post-halving-bitfinex-analysis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">highlighted significant activities</a> around Bitcoin withdrawals, supporting the optimistic outlook on Bitcoin. The current levels, echo those of January 2023, suggest that investors are increasingly moving their Bitcoin to cold storage—a sign that many anticipate further price increases.</p>

<p>Veering back to Glassnode’s projections yesterday based on their indexes and Fibonacci levels, the cofounders were boldly optimistic, anticipating a potential 350% increase from current market levels.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The <a href="https://x.com/Negentropic_/status/1782721645175566404" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#Crypto</a> Bull Market Continues.</p>
<p>&#8220;OTHERS&#8221; follows Crypto excl. the largest 10 Cryptos.</p>
<p>Observe that we in early 2021 had a strong correction. We believe that was a wave 4.
We now have a similar strong decline.</p>
<p>More upside is coming. This index and our Fibonacci levels… <a href="https://x.com/Negentropic_/status/1782721645175566404" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">pic.twitter.com/qKtIOSXneP</a></p>
<p>— 𝗡𝗲𝗴𝗲𝗻𝘁𝗿𝗼𝗽𝗶𝗰 (@Negentropic_) <a href="https://x.com/Negentropic_/status/1782721645175566404" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Notably, this forecast highlights the expected <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoins-next-move-revealed-trading-guru-reveals-this-cryptic-chart-pattern-heres-what-it-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">financial trajectory</a> and underscores a growing confidence among experts and market analysts in Bitcoin&#8217;s market performance and its foundational economic principles.</p>
<p>Featured image from Unsplash, Chart from TradingView</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/photo-1621501011941-c8ee93618c9a.jpg?fit=460%2C306" width="460" height="306" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604740</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
