<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Coin Republic</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/</link>
	<description>By the Coins, From the Coins, For the Coins</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 18:29:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/thecoinrepublic-logo_4dfefd11e401f10473b04f3db4d145f2-75x75.png</url>
	<title>The Coin Republic</title>
	<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>WOW Summit Hong Kong 2024 Concludes In Triumph, Cementing Its Position As A Blockchain Powerhouse</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/wow-summit-hong-kong-2024-concludes-in-triumph-cementing-its-position-as-a-blockchain-powerhouse/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/wow-summit-hong-kong-2024-concludes-in-triumph-cementing-its-position-as-a-blockchain-powerhouse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Serena James]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 03:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wow summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WOW Summit 2024]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="WOW Summit" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1.jpg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-750x422.jpg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-1140x641.jpg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p>The recently concluded WOW Summit Hong Kong 2024 (March 26-27) emerged as a resounding success, solidifying its place as a premier global Web3 event. WOW Summit Hong Kong brought together blockchain luminaries, industry leaders, and the future architects of the digital asset space from over 30 countries, showcasing the industry&#8217;s energy and innovation. The summit&#8217;s location in Hong Kong, Asia’s fintech hub, emphasized the growing role of digital assets in the global financial landscape. Attendees experienced an expansive range of activities, including panel discussions, side events, and exclusive networking opportunities.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/03/22/wow-summit-hong-kong-2024-unveils-stellar-lineup-of-speakers-partners-agenda-and-digital-art-exhibition-curated-by-sothebys/">WOW Summit</a> Hong Kong boasted an exceptional lineup of speakers, &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="WOW Summit" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1.jpg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-750x422.jpg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_9557-1-1140x641.jpg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<p>The recently concluded WOW Summit Hong Kong 2024 (March 26-27) emerged as a resounding success, solidifying its place as a premier global Web3 event. WOW Summit Hong Kong brought together blockchain luminaries, industry leaders, and the future architects of the digital asset space from over 30 countries, showcasing the industry&#8217;s energy and innovation. The summit&#8217;s location in Hong Kong, Asia’s fintech hub, emphasized the growing role of digital assets in the global financial landscape. Attendees experienced an expansive range of activities, including panel discussions, side events, and exclusive networking opportunities.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/03/22/wow-summit-hong-kong-2024-unveils-stellar-lineup-of-speakers-partners-agenda-and-digital-art-exhibition-curated-by-sothebys/">WOW Summit</a> Hong Kong boasted an exceptional lineup of speakers, featuring heavyweights like Sebastien Borget, Co-founder and COO of The Sandbox; Yat Siu, Chairman and Co-founder, Animoca Brands, Joseph Chan, Under Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury, The Government of Hong Kong SAR; John Cahill, COO, Asia, Galaxy Digital, Stacey-Ann Pearson, Head of Web3 &#8211; APAC, AWS; Bugra Celik, Director, Digital Assets, Global Private Banking and Wealth, HSBC. Their presence, alongside other esteemed figures, fostered a dynamic exchange of ideas and unparalleled insights.<br><br>Sotheby&#8217;s wowed attendees with a captivating digital art exhibition VENET EVENT (2024) – an exclusive, never-before-seen collection of 500 generative artworks by the esteemed conceptual artist Bernar Venet. Each piece is a testament to Venet’s visionary prowess and promises to captivate art enthusiasts worldwide. The highly anticipated release and public sales of this collection are scheduled for this June promising an unparalleled opportunity for collectors to acquire truly unique masterpieces.</p>



<p><strong>Viola Lukács, Digital art expert and Founder of Violuk Projects, </strong>introduced Bernar Venet’s six-decade exploration across diverse mediums, including sculpture, painting, and even sound, and how EVENT (2024) delves into the fascinating interplay of chance and unpredictability within the digital realm. Viola said: “Blockchain emerges as a medium for pushing the frontiers of art, offering dynamic platforms for the cultivation of generative art. Concurrently, the advent of web3 technologies heralds a transformative era in art presentation and distribution, amplifying both scalability and accessibility on a global spectrum. Within this landscape of innovation, WOW Summit Hong Kong 2024 emerges as a pivotal nexus, bridging the realms of art and technology, fostering a rich tapestry of cross-pollination and inspiring dialogue.”</p>



<p>Celebrating the event’s massive success, <strong>Ivan V. Ivanov, Global CEO, WOW Summit</strong>, said, “We were thrilled to have had this expanding, impressive roster of speakers and sponsors for WOW Summit Hong Kong, accompanied by extensive international media attention. The response has been unanimous – Asia stands at the forefront of innovation in digital assets and <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/10/all-about-metalcore-the-new-web3-game-on-zkevm-blockchain/">Web3</a>, with WOW Summit emerging as the premier platform for the global ecosystem to converge. The overall traction for the event has been extraordinary with several side events. We couldn&#8217;t be more excited for what&#8217;s to come.”</p>



<p>The meticulously curated agenda offered attendees a comprehensive exploration of the ever-evolving blockchain landscape. Panels and keynote presentations addressed thought-provoking topics. From the transformative power of asset-backed cryptos and the impact of Bitcoin ETFs to navigating complex regulatory landscapes and shaping long-term industry frameworks, the Summit delved into the most critical themes shaping the future.</p>



<p><strong>Bowie Lau, Co-host of WOW Summit Hong Kong</strong>, remarked: &#8220;The caliber of speakers and the depth of the discussions solidified WOW Summit Hong Kong as a must-attend event for anyone invested in the future of blockchain technology.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Summit&#8217;s success wouldn&#8217;t have been possible without the invaluable contributions of top-notch roster of sponsors, including Platinum Sponsors MMPro Trust, EXOLO, WOW Earn, Valhalla, InvestHK, LAK3, Zima Bank and Gold Sponsors Azbit, ivendPay, Chain Up, Custonomy, Market Making Pro, Tangem, VALR, all demonstrating their unwavering commitment to fostering a vibrant and cutting-edge blockchain landscape.</p>



<p>Pok Pok, a gamified options protocol using chicken <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/03/26/fractionalized-nfts-could-be-the-next-big-thing-pixelmon-ceo/">NFTs</a>, triumphed at the Startup Pitch Competition, captivating the judges with their creative approach to making options trading accessible. Congratulations to all participants who showcased their brilliance on stage: TokenSphere, FailSafe, ZKEX.com, b-cube.ai, AYDO, Iagent, One Click Crypto, Kleo Network, GitRoll, UniSRC-20, UniSell, and RealtyX. A special shoutout to RealtyX, who impressed Orthogonal Global Group with their innovative concept, earning them a coveted spot in Orthogonal&#8217;s accelerator program. This phenomenal event was made possible by the generous support of MMPRO, PWC, AWS, TaskOn, Charlton&#8217;s Law, Quantum Leap Strategy AG, and many more, whose dedication to fostering the next generation of industry leaders is deeply appreciated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>WOW Summit Hong Kong culminated with an unforgettable after-party, a night to remember at the iconic Tazmania Ballroom, LKF Tower. This exclusive event offered breathtaking, panoramic vistas and attracted a prestigious guest list, solidifying WOW Summit&#8217;s reputation for crafting extraordinary experiences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>WOW Summit is expanding globally and looking for local hosts and partners in Asia, the US, Australia, LATAM, and Europe. We are also inviting investors to indicate their interest in the investment in WOW Summit. For regional partnerships or investment opportunities, please contact us at <a href="mailto:partners@wowsummit.net" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">partners@wowsummit.net</a>&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>About WOW Summit:</strong></h4>



<p>WOW Summit is a premier Web3 event, where decision-makers in the global crypto ecosystem connect to exchange ideas, network and shape the industry. WOW Summit is a global meeting place for entrepreneurs, institutions, industry insiders, investors, builders and those with a strong interest in the crypto and blockchain industry. The Summit drives the innovative trajectory of Web3, covering cutting-edge trends and innovations in technology. It explores themes including the Web2 &#8211; Web3 transition, CBDCs, regulatory landscapes, asset tokenization, and the societal impact of blockchain and DLT technologies. Powered by<a href="https://marketmaking.pro/" rel="nofollow"> MarketMaking.Pro</a>, hosted by<a href="https://uvecon.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> Uvecon.VC</a> and co-hosted by MaGESpire, WOW Summit has a history of hosting distinguished speakers, government officials, and industry leaders. The event is supported by Hong Kong Government,<a href="https://www.investhk.gov.hk/en/home.html" rel="nofollow"> Invest Hong Kong</a>, Hong Kong Tourism Board, and <a href="https://www.fsdc.org.hk/" rel="nofollow"> Financial Services Development Council</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/wow-summit-hong-kong-2024-concludes-in-triumph-cementing-its-position-as-a-blockchain-powerhouse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEABW Reveals Exciting Speaker Lineup And Demo Day For Web3 Builders And Investors</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/seabw-reveals-exciting-speaker-lineup-and-demo-day-for-web3-builders-and-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/seabw-reveals-exciting-speaker-lineup-and-demo-day-for-web3-builders-and-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pratik Chadhokar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 02:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEABW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1.png" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1.png 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-750x422.png 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-1140x641.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><ul class="list-ic vertical">
    <li>
        <span>1</span>
        <a>SEABW is shaping up to be Thailand’s biggest Web3 gathering with unparalleled opportunities for networking, collaboration, and discussion</a>
    </li>
    <li>
        <span>2</span>
        <a>The event will give delegates unique insights into the Web3 adoption in the SEA region, regulations, and products from the local Web3 industry</a>
    </li>
 
</ul>



<p><strong><em>Bangkok, April XX, 2024 </em></strong>– Southeast Asia Blockchain Week (SEABW), a premier blockchain conference exploring the evolving landscape of Web3 in the Southeast Asia region, is thrilled to announce the speaker lineup for the main SEABW conference. The headline speakers include Aptos Co-Founder and CTO Avery Ching, Animoca Brands Co-Founder &#38; Chairman Yat Siu, SCBX Deputy CEO &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1.png" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1.png 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-750x422.png 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-127-1024x576-2-1-1140x641.png 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<ul class="list-ic vertical">
    <li>
        <span>1</span>
        <a>SEABW is shaping up to be Thailand’s biggest Web3 gathering with unparalleled opportunities for networking, collaboration, and discussion</a>
    </li>
    <li>
        <span>2</span>
        <a>The event will give delegates unique insights into the Web3 adoption in the SEA region, regulations, and products from the local Web3 industry</a>
    </li>
 
</ul>



<p><strong><em>Bangkok, April XX, 2024 </em></strong>– Southeast Asia Blockchain Week (SEABW), a premier blockchain conference exploring the evolving landscape of Web3 in the Southeast Asia region, is thrilled to announce the speaker lineup for the main SEABW conference. The headline speakers include Aptos Co-Founder and CTO Avery Ching, Animoca Brands Co-Founder &amp; Chairman Yat Siu, SCBX Deputy CEO Arak Sutivong, Hashed CEO &amp; Managing Partner Simon Kim, Nansen CEO Alex Svanevik, YGG Co-founder Gabriel Dizon, Wintermute Co-founder Yoann Turpin, and The Spartan Group Co-founder &amp; Managing Partner Kelvin Koh.</p>



<p>Moreover, <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/10/ethereum-etf-may-face-rejection-by-the-sec-says-jan-van-eck/">Ethereum </a>Co-founder Vitalik Buterin will also mark his presence with an online keynote session. There will be a total of over 135 innovators, entrepreneurs, decision-makers and thought leaders across the entire spectrum of the blockchain industry engaging in keynote sessions, panel discussions, fireside chats, and moderated debates.</p>



<p>The SEABW will explore the latest trends and developments in blockchain technology, investment opportunities, adoption and use cases, policy and regulations, as well as the unique Web3 landscape in SEA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The attendees are going to have unparalleled opportunities for networking, collaboration, and discussion. The world-class event will be a reflection of Southeast Asia’s increasingly vital role in Web3, expressed in terms of crypto adoption and the exciting startups originating from the region. Southeast Asia is home to more than 690 million people. Its young and tech-savvy population, underserved by the financial system, is open to using crypto. The region is witnessing unprecedented growth, particularly in the gaming sector. This surge signifies a potential tipping point for &#8216;Web3 mass adoption&#8217; in Southeast Asia.</p>



<p>Hojin Kim, CEO of ShardLab, said, “Through a comprehensive program featuring keynote speeches, exhibitions, <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2022/03/12/draftkings-a-23-billion-sports-gambling-business-serves-as-a-networking-verifier-for-polygon/">networking</a> sessions, Demo Day, and more, the SEABW aims to provide the region’s Web3-curious entrepreneurs and enterprises with an opportunity to learn from and network with some of the brightest Web3 minds worldwide. Moreover, we aim to not only present sessions and speeches but also provide real Web3 experiences, showing impactful real-life use cases of blockchain through our official web app. This app is designed for ordinary audiences who may not be familiar with blockchain Dapps. We seek to inspire actionable initiatives and projects that address pressing challenges and capitalize on emerging opportunities in Southeast Asia&#8217;s evolving blockchain landscape.”</p>



<p>The SEABW will be held on April 22-28 at the True ICON Hall in Bangkok, Thailand. While the main event will take place on April 24-25, there will be major side events throughout the week including ‘Token X Summit &#8211; TOKENIZATION’ on April 23rd, Game Day &amp; Demo Day on April 24-25th and ‘ONCHAIN 2024’ on April 26-28th.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>DEMO DAY TO SHOWCASE THE REGION’S INNOVATION</strong></h2>



<p>Besides the official VIP &amp; Speakers Night, After Party, and Game Day, the SEABW organizers are particularly focused on the Demo Day that will be held on April 24-25th. The Demo Day will spotlight 10 notable Web3 startups at the SEABW conference venue. It will cater to a broad audience including investors, founders, builders and others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Demo Day is organized in partnership with elite companies, <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2023/07/31/crypto-investors-cool-on-bitcoin-and-arbitrum-funds-vc-spectra-presale-success-attracts-the-entire-crypto-world/">VC funds</a> and accelerators including Hashed, Wintermute, SCB 10X, Saison Capital, Faction, and Krungsri Finnovate. Web3 builders have until April 5th to apply for the SEABW Demo Day. The startups will have an opportunity to present and connect with investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Top-tier entrepreneurs, developers, and builders will come together bringing their innovative products and services. It presents an opportunity for the attendees to get a sneak peek into the future of Web3 in Southeast Asia, network with the regional builders, create synergies and explore business opportunities.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>About SEABW</strong></h3>



<p>Southeast Asia Blockchain Week is the flagship conference for web3 developers, investors, and users. It brings together key figures from across the industry for seven days of panel discussions, keynotes, product demonstrations, and networking. From Web3 Games to RWAs, SEABW illuminates Southeast Asia’s most promising startups and web3 companies.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Learn more: <a href="https://seablockchainweek.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Website </a>| <a href="https://twitter.com/SEABWofficial" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> | <a href="https://t.me/SEABWofficial" rel="nofollow">Telegram</a></strong></h4>



<p><br><strong>&#8211; Buy</strong> <a href="https://seablockchainweek.org/?page=ticket" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tickets</a><br><strong>&#8211; Discover</strong> <a href="https://seablockchainweek.org/?page=partners" rel="nofollow">Sponsors</a> <br><strong>&#8211; Check out</strong> <a href="https://seablockchainweek.org/?page=agenda" rel="nofollow">Agenda </a> </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>About ShardLab</strong></h3>



<p>ShardLab is the innovation arm of Hashed, a leading global Web3 venture capital firm based in Asia. Beyond ideas, we actively build ecosystems and collaborations to bring innovative disruptions using Web3 technology. Our vision extends to fostering mass adoption of Web3 in Southeast Asia, making technology accessible, and empowering communities in this dynamic digital frontier.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>About Hashed</strong></h3>



<p>Hashed is a team of blockchain experts and builders based in Seoul, Singapore, Bengaluru, and Silicon Valley. We believe that decentralization can transform not only the global economy but the very fabric of the internet. Our mission is to accelerate the mass adoption of blockchain by investing our resources and empowering a new wave of entrepreneurs and innovators to create this future. We approach this work as builders, not just pickers. We participate as core technical contributors to global infrastructure, and we’ve built a network of projects and people that connect industry pioneers with the knowledge and resources necessary to unlock the potential of blockchain.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Media contact:&nbsp;</h4>



<p><a href="mailto:media@seablockchainweek.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">media@seablockchainweek.org</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/seabw-reveals-exciting-speaker-lineup-and-demo-day-for-web3-builders-and-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aptos Crypto Price Analysis: What Next In The Aptos Price?</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/aptos-crypto-price-analysis-what-next-in-the-aptos-price/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/aptos-crypto-price-analysis-what-next-in-the-aptos-price/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nancy J. Allen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aptos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aptos (APT)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Aptos" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><ul class="list-ic vertical">
    <li>
        <span>1</span>
        <a>Aptos price breaks below 20 and 50-day EMA levels showcasing bearishness on the daily chart.</a>
    </li>
    <li>
        <span>2</span>
        <a>APT price is down by 16.03%, showcasing that bulls are dominating.</a>
    </li>
 
</ul>






<p>Aptos (APT) is a blockchain token that operates on layer 1. It uses the Move programming language and serves various purposes within the Aptos network. Move is a smart contract programming language that was first developed by Meta to power the Diem blockchain. Aptos relies heavily on Move, which prioritizes safety and flexibility, to make the project more efficient.&#160;</p>



<p>Aptos utilizes a parallel data model and execution engine to improve the efficiency &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Aptos" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/apt-2-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<ul class="list-ic vertical">
    <li>
        <span>1</span>
        <a>Aptos price breaks below 20 and 50-day EMA levels showcasing bearishness on the daily chart.</a>
    </li>
    <li>
        <span>2</span>
        <a>APT price is down by 16.03%, showcasing that bulls are dominating.</a>
    </li>
 
</ul>






<p>Aptos (APT) is a blockchain token that operates on layer 1. It uses the Move programming language and serves various purposes within the Aptos network. Move is a smart contract programming language that was first developed by Meta to power the Diem blockchain. Aptos relies heavily on Move, which prioritizes safety and flexibility, to make the project more efficient.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Aptos utilizes a parallel data model and execution engine to improve the efficiency of its processes. Additionally, the network&#8217;s overall efficiency is boosted by its use of a variant of the Byzantine fault tolerance consensus mechanism.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Technical Analysis of The Aptos Crypto Price</strong></h2>



<!-- TradingView Chart BEGIN -->

<script type="text/javascript" src="https://s3.tradingview.com/tv.js"></script>

<script type="text/javascript">

var tradingview_embed_options = {};

tradingview_embed_options.width = '980';

tradingview_embed_options.height = '425';

tradingview_embed_options.chart = 'kWfga2Pg';

new TradingView.chart(tradingview_embed_options);

</script>

<p><a href="https://in.tradingview.com/chart/APTUSD/kWfga2Pg-APT/"></a> <a href="https://in.tradingview.com/u/writer12_gsm/"></a> <a href="https://in.tradingview.com/"></a></p>

<!-- TradingView Chart END -->



<p>The Aptos (APT) cryptocurrency has been experiencing a downward trend in its price action, with lower lows observed on the charts over the past few weeks. This has been accompanied by a decrease in investor interest, resulting in below-average trading volume.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, user activity for APT has declined, further contributing to negative sentiment towards the cryptocurrency and a bearish outlook on the charts. The cryptocurrency was in a corrective phase, making buyers cautious. Additionally, it trades below significant moving averages and aims to reach the 50-day EMA to maintain its gains.</p>



<p>At the time of writing, the Aptos <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/10/pancakeswap-price-prediction-where-will-cake-price-move-next/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">price</a> was trading at $ 11.91 with an intraday gain of 0.59%, bouncing from the lower trendline near the lower support mark. Moreover, the intraday trading volume increased is $167.09 Million and the market cap is $4.75 Billion.</p>



<p>At the time of publishing, Aptos crypto (USD: Aptos) is trading above the 50 and 20-day EMAs (Exponential moving averages), which do not support the price trend. The current value of RSI is 35.55 points. The 14 SMA is below the median line at 45.27 points which indicates that the Aptos crypto is bearish.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>APT Crypto Price vs Volume Analysis</strong></h2>



<iframe loading="lazy" title="Santiment Chart: Price (APT), Volume (APT)" width="1170" height="425" src="https://embed.santiment.net/chart?ps=aptos&#038;pt=APT&#038;df=2023-10-12T18%3A29%3A59.193Z&#038;dt=2024-04-12T18%3A29%3A59.193Z&#038;sat=shchcfg_Iay0qZnME0JM&#038;emcg=1&#038;emhwm=1&#038;wm=price_usd%3Bvolume_usd&#038;wax=0%3B1&#038;wc=%2326C953%3B%23435ed3&#038;ws=%7B%22interval%22%3A%221d%22%7D%3B" scrolling="no"></iframe>



<p>The volume and price graph displayed that the trading volume has decreased in the last few days and the price also declined. In the last few days, the price was down significantly. However, the price is expected to grow in the long term</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>APT Crypto Social Dominance vs Social Volume</strong></h2>



<iframe loading="lazy" title="Santiment Chart: Social Dominance (APT), Social Volume (APT)" width="1170" height="425" src="https://embed.santiment.net/chart?ps=aptos&#038;pt=APT&#038;df=2023-10-12T18%3A29%3A59.193Z&#038;dt=2024-04-12T18%3A29%3A59.193Z&#038;sat=shchcfg_Iay0qZnME0JM&#038;emcg=1&#038;emhwm=1&#038;wm=social_dominance_total%3Bsocial_volume_total&#038;wax=0%3B1&#038;wc=%23FF5B5B%3B%2368DBF4&#038;ws=%7B%22interval%22%3A%221d%22%7D%3B%7B%22interval%22%3A%221d%22%7D" scrolling="no"></iframe>



<p>According to the social dominance and social volume graph, there has been a decline in both social dominance and social volume over the past few months, which has had a negative effect on the price. Additionally, the momentum of the APT price may be influenced by changes in social dominance and volume dominance.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Summary</strong></h4>



<p>The Aptos (APT) cryptocurrency has been experiencing a downward trend in its price action, with lower lows observed on the charts over the past few weeks. This has been accompanied by a decrease in investor interest, resulting in below-average trading volume. Technical indicators such as MACD, RSI, and EMAs are emphasizing negative signs and imply that the downtrend may continue in the Aptos crypto price. The cryptocurrency was in a corrective phase, making buyers cautious.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Technical Levels</strong></h4>



<p>Support Levels: $10.39</p>



<p>Resistance Levels: $13.52</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Disclaimer</strong></h5>



<p>This article is for informational purposes only and does not provide any financial, investment, or other advice. The author or any people mentioned in this article are not responsible for any financial loss that may occur from investing in or trading. Please do your own research before making any financial decisions</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/aptos-crypto-price-analysis-what-next-in-the-aptos-price/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AXS Crypto Analysis Shows Rapid Price Drop, Can It Keep Up?</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/axs-crypto-analysis-shows-rapid-price-drop-can-it-keep-up/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/axs-crypto-analysis-shows-rapid-price-drop-can-it-keep-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anurag S]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AXS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AXS coin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AXS Crypto Price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201258</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="AXS" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><ul class="list-ic vertical">
    <li>
        <span>1</span>
        <a>Active addresses reflect user participation in transactions over time, showing a decline in activity and potential impact on AXS price.</a>
    </li>
    <li>
        <span>2</span>
        <a>The Axie Infinity price asset plunged below the 20-day and 50-day EMA bands, reliant on the sellers&#8217; surge could deteriorate more.</a>
    </li>
 
</ul>






<p>The price of AXS asset has been displaying bearish behavior and has been declining consistently on the daily chart, indicating a potential further downward trend. The asset&#8217;s performance was poor last week and last month, with a drop of -3.59% and -25.95%, respectively, which suggests a stable downtrend.</p>



<p>The price of Axie Infinity crypto has significantly dropped &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="AXS" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/AXS-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<ul class="list-ic vertical">
    <li>
        <span>1</span>
        <a>Active addresses reflect user participation in transactions over time, showing a decline in activity and potential impact on AXS price.</a>
    </li>
    <li>
        <span>2</span>
        <a>The Axie Infinity price asset plunged below the 20-day and 50-day EMA bands, reliant on the sellers&#8217; surge could deteriorate more.</a>
    </li>
 
</ul>






<p>The price of AXS asset has been displaying bearish behavior and has been declining consistently on the daily chart, indicating a potential further downward trend. The asset&#8217;s performance was poor last week and last month, with a drop of -3.59% and -25.95%, respectively, which suggests a stable downtrend.</p>



<p>The price of Axie Infinity crypto has significantly dropped in recent times. This decline was evident as the price plunged from a crucial level of approximately $13.50 on the chart.</p>



<p>AXS crypto is deteriorating at faster pace, as it meets the resistance level and could dive to new lows from the current price. The Axie Infinity price asset plunged below the 20-day and 50-day EMA bands.</p>



<p>Likewise, the AXS price asset is displaying bearish characteristics as MACD is below the zero line at -0.73 and the RSI is falling smoothly below the median line at 41.60, implying that the Axie Infinity asset is losing momentum and can achieve new depths in the coming sessions.</p>



<p>At press time, the AXS crypto had experienced a 1.99% decline in the last 24 hours to $9.36. Therefore, if the Axie Infinity price fails to stay above the $8.50 level, it could decline further and reach lower lows.</p>



<p>However, if the demand for the crypto remains high, the AXS asset price could bounce back from the current level by surpassing the below trendline. The next goal for Axie Infinity is to reach $11.0 and $12.0.</p>



<!-- TradingView Chart BEGIN -->

<script type="text/javascript" src="https://s3.tradingview.com/tv.js"></script>

<script type="text/javascript">

var tradingview_embed_options = {};

tradingview_embed_options.width = '980';

tradingview_embed_options.height = '425';

tradingview_embed_options.chart = 'Y8MyIEse';

new TradingView.chart(tradingview_embed_options);

</script>

<p><a href="https://in.tradingview.com/chart/AXSUSD/Y8MyIEse-AXS-crypto-is-deteriorating-at-faster-pace/"></a><a href="https://in.tradingview.com/u/Sam_TCR/"></a><a href="https://in.tradingview.com/"></a></p>

<!-- TradingView Chart END -->



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AXS Volume Analysis</strong></h2>



<p>Upon examining the AXS chart, it becomes evident that there was a surge in trading volume on or around March 10th, 2024. This increase in volume suggests that there was a notable uptick in both interest and market activity regarding the Axie Infinity token at that particular moment in time. It is worth noting that the volume had previously surpassed the $600 Million mark.</p>



<p>However, from March 11th, 2024 onwards, volume continued to fall, and a significant descent in AXS activity was observed which illustrated decreased demand and excitement about Axie Infinity price. The trading volume depleted from $600 Million to the low of $250 Million by April 8th on the chart.</p>



<iframe loading="lazy" title="Santiment Chart: Price (AXS), Volume (AXS)" width="1170" height="425" src="https://embed.santiment.net/chart?ps=pendle&#038;pt=PENDLE&#038;df=2024-01-06T00%3A00%3A00.000Z&#038;dt=2024-04-11T18%3A29%3A59.967Z&#038;sat=shchcfg_mlVp_SllsxIP&#038;emcg=1&#038;emhwm=1&#038;wm=%5B1%3Bprice_usd%3Baxie-infinity%3BAXS%5D%3B%5B1%3Bvolume_usd%3Baxie-infinity%3BAXS%5D&#038;wax=0%3B1&#038;wc=%23FF5B5B%3B%23FFCB47&#038;ws=%3B" scrolling="no"></iframe>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AXS Crypto Active Addresses Declining</strong></h2>



<p>The count of active addresses in the AXS refers to the number of unique addresses of Axie Infinity users who have participated in one or more transactions within a specific timeframe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Within the last hour, there were 31 transactions, in the past 24 hours, the number of transactions involving different addresses in Axie Infinity was 357, in the past 7 days were 1529, and in the last 30 days, there were 6907 transactions involving unique addresses in the AXS asset.</p>



<p>This data indicates that the number of people who are involved in using and trading the AXS is decreasing. As a result, the demand and value for the Axie Infinity <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/10/pancakeswap-price-prediction-where-will-cake-price-move-next/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">price</a> may also be decreasing due to the decreasing number of active addresses over time. These terms are used to highlight the short-term and long-term trends of AXS crypto&#8217;s activity and its adoption.</p>



<iframe loading="lazy" title="Santiment Chart: Active Addresses 30d (AXS), Active Addresses 7d (AXS), Active Addresses 24h (AXS), Active Addresses 1h (AXS)" width="1170" height="425" src="https://embed.santiment.net/chart?ps=pendle&#038;pt=PENDLE&#038;df=2024-01-06T00%3A00%3A00.000Z&#038;dt=2024-04-11T18%3A29%3A59.967Z&#038;sat=shchcfg_mlVp_SllsxIP&#038;emcg=1&#038;emhwm=1&#038;wm=%5B1%3Bactive_addresses_30d%3Baxie-infinity%3BAXS%5D%3B%5B1%3Bactive_addresses_7d%3Baxie-infinity%3BAXS%5D%3B%5B1%3Bactive_addresses_24h%3Baxie-infinity%3BAXS%5D%3B%5B1%3Bactive_addresses_1h%3Baxie-infinity%3BAXS%5D&#038;wax=0%3B1%3B2&#038;wc=%23FF5B5B%3B%23FFCB47%3B%235275FF%3B%23FF8450&#038;ws=%3B%3B%3B" scrolling="no"></iframe>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Summary</strong></h4>



<p>The AXS asset price is falling, showing bearish signs on the daily chart. Last week and last month saw poor performances with drops of 3.59% and 25.95%, indicating a stable downtrend.</p>



<p>From March 11th, 2024, AXS volume fell significantly, indicating decreased demand for Axie Infinity. Trading volume dropped from $600 Million to $250 Million by April 8th. Active addresses reflect user participation in transactions over time, showing a decline in activity and potential impact on AXS value.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Technical Levels</strong></h4>



<p><strong>Support Levels</strong>: $8.50</p>



<p><strong>Resistance Levels</strong>: $11.0</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Disclaimer</strong></h4>



<p>In this article, the views, and opinions stated by the author, or any people named are for informational purposes only, and they don’t establish the investment, financial, or any other advice. Trading or investing in cryptocurrency assets comes with a risk of financial loss.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/axs-crypto-analysis-shows-rapid-price-drop-can-it-keep-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto &#038; NASA: VR Metaverse &#038; Utilization Of Blockchain</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/crypto-nasa-vr-metaverse-utilization-of-blockchain/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/crypto-nasa-vr-metaverse-utilization-of-blockchain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Smith]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Metaverse" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p><em><strong>The latest buzz about NASA is the national space program’s VR metaverse to prepare astronauts.</strong></em></p>



<p>NASA and SpaceX astronauts are utilizing the metaverse to undergo training, for life on a space station known as &#8220;Gateway,&#8221; which is currently in the works. This space station is envisioned as a cutting-edge science laboratory solar-powered spacecraft and a home away from home for astronauts from around the world as detailed in a blog article by NASA.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Metaverse Is Changing The Cosmo Game</strong></h2>



<p>In the past astronauts typically trained for missions using computer-based simulators. However with the advent of virtual reality headsets and &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Metaverse" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/NASA-created-VR-metaverse-to-prep-astronauts-for-life-on-lunar-space-station-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<p><em><strong>The latest buzz about NASA is the national space program’s VR metaverse to prepare astronauts.</strong></em></p>



<p>NASA and SpaceX astronauts are utilizing the metaverse to undergo training, for life on a space station known as &#8220;Gateway,&#8221; which is currently in the works. This space station is envisioned as a cutting-edge science laboratory solar-powered spacecraft and a home away from home for astronauts from around the world as detailed in a blog article by NASA.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Metaverse Is Changing The Cosmo Game</strong></h2>



<p>In the past astronauts typically trained for missions using computer-based simulators. However with the advent of virtual reality headsets and advanced spatial computing technologies astronauts now have the opportunity to acquire the skills to operate and thrive in an immersive 3D environment.</p>



<p>The initial inhabitants of space will be the team for managing Gateway, which is being established as a crucial site for the Artemis program. The goal of this U.S.-led endeavor is to construct a manned outpost on the Moon. This will be part of humanity&#8217;s mission to send a human to Mars.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Gateway plays a role in the Artemis missions</strong></h3>



<p>According to NASA Gateway plays a role in the Artemis missions. Will serve as a versatile outpost orbiting the Moon. It will offer support for surface expeditions serve as a hub for scientific endeavors and acts as a launching point for further exploration, into deep space.</p>



<p>As per NASA, the astronauts assigned to the Gateway project will encounter the mission of becoming the crew of an orbital space station in deep space situated at a distance of around 386,243 kilometers from Earth. In contrast, astronauts aboard the International Space Station typically work at a distance of 400 kilometers, from Earth.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><a href="https://w3wc.io/?no"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/freecompress-1440x90-gif-1-1.gif" alt="" style="width:1450px;height:auto"/></a></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>NASA Planning to Utilize Blockchain Technology</strong></h2>



<p>NASA is teaming up with Lonestar and the Isle of Man to use blockchain technology for verifying and securing data storage on the moon during the upcoming Artemis missions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blockchain will be used to provide irrefutable proof of human landing on the moon during NASA&#8217;s Artemis 3 mission in 2025. Before that, Artemis 2 will launch in November 2024 with a crewed mission to orbit the moon and return to Earth.</p>



<p>As one of the scientific missions during the Artemis voyages, Lonestar and the Isle of Man will develop lunar storage systems that rely on solar power and require no additional infrastructure.</p>



<p>According to Roosen, the head of innovation at Digital Isle of Man, the island&#8217;s government-funded agency that supports its tech sector, &#8220;people often tell NASA: &#8216;You made up the moon missions,&#8217; and proving that they&#8217;re actually there is surprisingly difficult.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Blockchain Is Useful To NASA?</strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/03/24/details-of-upcoming-blockchain-expo-scheduled-on-june-5-6-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Blockchain </a>technology&#8217;s immutability is reliable for recording and verifying future lunar missions. This would provide real-time check-in mechanisms for lunar exploration and indisputable evidence of human presence on the moon&#8217;s surface, helping NASA dispel any conspiracy theories surrounding lunar landings.</p>



<p>This project marks a significant milestone in the evolving relationship between blockchain technology and space exploration, as blockchain-verified data storage solutions could authenticate historical space achievements and future lunar activities as NASA&#8217;s Artemis program progresses.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Summary</strong></h3>



<p>NASA and SpaceX astronauts are training in the metaverse for life on a space station called &#8220;Gateway&#8221;. Gateway is being built as a crucial site for the Artemis program, which aims to construct a manned outpost on the Moon as part of humanity&#8217;s mission to send a human to Mars. NASA, Lonestar, and Isle of Man will use blockchain to secure data storage on the moon during Artemis missions.</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Disclaimer</strong></h5>



<p>The views and opinions stated by the author, or any people named in this article, are for informational purposes only. They do not establish financial, investment, or other advice. Investing in or trading in stocks, cryptos or related indexes comes with a risk of financial loss.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/crypto-nasa-vr-metaverse-utilization-of-blockchain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>HashKey &#038; TON Foundation Join Hands, TON Airdrops 300k Toncoins</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/hashkey-ton-foundation-join-hands-ton-airdrops-300k-toncoins/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/hashkey-ton-foundation-join-hands-ton-airdrops-300k-toncoins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Shinoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 23:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TON]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Toncoins" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7.jpg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-750x422.jpg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-1140x641.jpg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p><em><strong>HashKey Globals and the TON Foundation have formed a partnership with a focus on Hong Kong for the initial phase.</strong></em></p>



<p>The crypto market is undergoing a massive evolution, and companies like HashKey Globals are expanding their services and plans. Investors&#8217; confidence in the market is evident in the current bull run.&#160;</p>



<p>Recently, HashKey Global launched its global crypto exchange in Bermuda, which has gained the attention of significant industry names like TON.&#160;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>HashKey Global Brief</strong></h2>



<p>HashKey Global presently provides spot trading services for 21 digital assets, including bitcoin (BTC), ether (ETH), Tether&#8217;s USDT, and Circle&#8217;s USDC. They plan to introduce &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Toncoins" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7.jpg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-750x422.jpg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Ton-7-1140x641.jpg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<p><em><strong>HashKey Globals and the TON Foundation have formed a partnership with a focus on Hong Kong for the initial phase.</strong></em></p>



<p>The crypto market is undergoing a massive evolution, and companies like HashKey Globals are expanding their services and plans. Investors&#8217; confidence in the market is evident in the current bull run.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Recently, HashKey Global launched its global crypto exchange in Bermuda, which has gained the attention of significant industry names like TON.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>HashKey Global Brief</strong></h2>



<p>HashKey Global presently provides spot trading services for 21 digital assets, including bitcoin (BTC), ether (ETH), Tether&#8217;s USDT, and Circle&#8217;s USDC. They plan to introduce futures trading product services in the coming weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The company, similar to Coinbase, has chosen Bermuda as its global exchange base, thanks to the nation&#8217;s regulatory regime that has proved to be very suitable for them to expand from, after seeing Coinbase&#8217;s success in Bermuda. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><a href="https://w3wc.io/?no"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/freecompress-1440x90-gif-1-1.gif" alt="" style="width:1450px;height:auto"/></a></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>TON &amp; Hashkey Partner Ship</strong></h3>



<p>Telegram initiated the TON <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/03/24/details-of-upcoming-blockchain-expo-scheduled-on-june-5-6-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blockchain</a> as an internal project in 2018. However, two years later, due to legal action by the SEC, the project was abandoned. Following this, the TON Foundation was formed by the community with Telegram&#8217;s backing, to carry on with the development of the project. </p>



<p>HashKey and the Foundation are focusing their partnership on Hong Kong in the first phase but said they will expand to other APAC markets should their initial efforts prove a success, according to an emailed announcement on Friday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Toncoin, the native token of TON, climbed approximately 1.7% in the hour following the announcement and was down nearly 4% in the last 24 hours. For comparison, the CoinDesk 20 Index (CD20), which shows a weighted measurement of the digital asset market, declined around 1.3% in the same timeframe.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>TON Foundation Distributed 300k Toncoins</strong></h3>



<p>The Open Network&#8217;s TON Foundation distributed 300,000 Toncoin to active meme coin traders on the DeDust and Ston.fi platforms, valued at roughly $2.19 Million. The airdrop targeted traders who engaged in transactions between March 4 and April 10. Participants needed to trade specific meme coins and accumulate points to qualify for the reward.</p>



<p>The distribution gave 90 free tokens per eligible wallet, excluding Sybil addresses to ensure fairness. Toncoin reached a new all-time high before the announcement, surging more than 14% to $7.65 per token. However, after the news, TON&#8217;s price fell by 5% to $7.22.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Summary</strong></h4>



<p>HashKey Global and the TON Foundation are partnering in Hong Kong, with plans to expand to other APAC markets. HashKey offers spot trading for 21 digital assets and will introduce futures trading soon. The TON Foundation distributed 300,000 Toncoin to active meme coin traders on DeDust and Ston.fi platforms, valued at $2.19 Million.</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Disclaimer</strong></h5>



<p>The views and opinions stated by the author, or any people named in this article, are for informational purposes only. They do not establish financial, investment, or other advice. Investing in or trading in stocks, cryptos or related indexes comes with a risk of financial loss.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/hashkey-ton-foundation-join-hands-ton-airdrops-300k-toncoins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embrace The Extraordinary: NFT Artist Gr8ful Gurl Elevates Emotional Intelligence Amidst Technological Innovation At “Summer of Love” Coachella Valley, CA With SpaceBlue &#038; Bitbasel</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/embrace-the-extraordinary-nft-artist-gr8ful-gurl-elevates-emotional-intelligence-amidst-technological-innovation-at-summer-of-love-coachella-valley-ca-with-spaceblue-bitbasel/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/embrace-the-extraordinary-nft-artist-gr8ful-gurl-elevates-emotional-intelligence-amidst-technological-innovation-at-summer-of-love-coachella-valley-ca-with-spaceblue-bitbasel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pratik Chadhokar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitbasel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceBlue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1.jpg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-750x422.jpg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-1140x641.jpg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p>Coachella Valley, CA. &#8211; April 11-12, 2024 &#8211; Brandi Veil, recognized by her moniker Gr8ful Gurl, isn&#8217;t just an <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/07/what-is-pfp-nft-how-is-it-related-to-profile-pictures/">NFT</a> artist—she&#8217;s a visionary on a mission to redefine the intersection of community, personal connection, and gratitude in the digital age. In an era dominated by the relentless march of technological advancement, Gr8ful Gurl stands as a beacon of Emotional Intelligence (EI), advocating for the importance of human-centric values in our ever-evolving world.</p>



<p>On February 22, 2024, Gr8ful Gurl etched her name in history as one of the pioneering 222 NFT artists chosen for the groundbreaking Spaceblue.club and partners Bitbasel mission &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1.jpg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1.jpg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-750x422.jpg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ImportedPhoto_1712944414692-1-1-1140x641.jpg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<p>Coachella Valley, CA. &#8211; April 11-12, 2024 &#8211; Brandi Veil, recognized by her moniker Gr8ful Gurl, isn&#8217;t just an <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/07/what-is-pfp-nft-how-is-it-related-to-profile-pictures/">NFT</a> artist—she&#8217;s a visionary on a mission to redefine the intersection of community, personal connection, and gratitude in the digital age. In an era dominated by the relentless march of technological advancement, Gr8ful Gurl stands as a beacon of Emotional Intelligence (EI), advocating for the importance of human-centric values in our ever-evolving world.</p>



<p>On February 22, 2024, Gr8ful Gurl etched her name in history as one of the pioneering 222 NFT artists chosen for the groundbreaking Spaceblue.club and partners Bitbasel mission to the moon. Amidst the awe-inspiring backdrop of Cape Canaveral, Florida, she joined forces with fellow creatives to push the boundaries of art and technology beyond Earth&#8217;s confines. &#8220;Gr8ful Gurl isn&#8217;t just about digital art—it&#8217;s about fostering connections, nurturing communities, and embracing the power of gratitude,&#8221; said Veil, reflecting on her journey. &#8220;In a world driven by the relentless pace of innovation, it&#8217;s crucial to remember the human element that binds us all together.&#8221; As the world eagerly anticipates the next frontier of metaverse projects, Gr8ful Gurl continues to push the envelope, infusing her work with boundless creativity and unwavering passion. From virtual galleries, comic book stories to immersive experiences, her vision knows no bounds. Join Gr8ful Gurl on her mission to the stars and beyond, where art, <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/02/17/the-coinbases-report-on-blockchain-technology-advantages/">technology</a>, and humanity converge in a symphony of innovation and inspiration.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>More about the Summer of Love Series and Lunarprise Moon Museum contact us.</strong></h4>



<p><strong>For media inquiries, please contact: </strong></p>



<p>Brandi Veil&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gr8ful Gurl NFT&nbsp;</p>



<p>Brandi@brandiveil.com&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="http://www.gr8fulgurl.com" rel="nofollow">www.gr8fulgurl.com</a></p>



<p>About Gr8ful Gurl&nbsp;</p>



<p>NFT:Gr8ful Gurl NFT is a pioneering force in the world of digital art, advocating for Emotional Intelligence (EI) amidst the rapid pace of technological innovation. Led by visionary artist Brandi Veil, Gr8ful Gurl is dedicated to fostering community, personal connections, and gratitude in the digital age.</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: Any information written in this press release or sponsored article does not constitute investment advice. Thecoinrepublic.com and all its authors do not, and will not endorse any information on any company or individual on this page. Readers are encouraged to do their research and take any actions based on their findings and not from any content written in this press release or sponsored article. Thecoinrepublic.com and all its authors do not and will not be responsible for any damage or loss caused directly or indirectly by the use of any content, product, or service mentioned in this press release or sponsored article.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/embrace-the-extraordinary-nft-artist-gr8ful-gurl-elevates-emotional-intelligence-amidst-technological-innovation-at-summer-of-love-coachella-valley-ca-with-spaceblue-bitbasel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain Life Event 2024: The Crypto Whales Meeting Platform</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/blockchain-life-event-2024-the-crypto-whales-meeting-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/blockchain-life-event-2024-the-crypto-whales-meeting-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adarsh ​​Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 22:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Event" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p><strong><em>Blockchain Life Event 2024, the 12th International Forum on Cryptocurrencies, Web3, and Mining is scheduled on 15 &#38; 16 April, in Dubai. </em> </strong></p>



<p>On April 15 &#38; 16, Blockchain Life 2024 will demonstrate that it is one of the main cryptocurrency events of the year bringing together investors, crypto traders, developers, entrepreneurs, miners, service providers, and many more. The event offers a unique platform to connect like-minded professionals for idea-sharing and an evolving landscape.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Blockchain Live Event Details</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Event Date: </strong>April 15th and 16th 2024</p>



<p><strong>Location: </strong>Al Badia Blvd, Dubai Festival City, Dubai</p>



<p><strong>Fields covered:</strong> Web3, Cryptocurrencies, Investments, Blockchain, Mining, Trading, &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Event" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Blockchain-life-Event-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<p><strong><em>Blockchain Life Event 2024, the 12th International Forum on Cryptocurrencies, Web3, and Mining is scheduled on 15 &amp; 16 April, in Dubai. </em> </strong></p>



<p>On April 15 &amp; 16, Blockchain Life 2024 will demonstrate that it is one of the main cryptocurrency events of the year bringing together investors, crypto traders, developers, entrepreneurs, miners, service providers, and many more. The event offers a unique platform to connect like-minded professionals for idea-sharing and an evolving landscape.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Blockchain Live Event Details</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Event Date: </strong>April 15th and 16th 2024</p>



<p><strong>Location: </strong>Al Badia Blvd, Dubai Festival City, Dubai</p>



<p><strong>Fields covered:</strong> Web3, Cryptocurrencies, Investments, Blockchain, Mining, Trading, Halving, Decentralized Finance (DeFi), Metaverse, and many more.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Day 1 (15 April) event list: </strong>How to drive crypto adoption through innovative approaches?, Long-term ecosystem development, The UAE in Web3: Achievements and next steps, Tokenization of Assets: Beyond Cryptocurrencies, Halving is coming, and many more.<strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><strong>Day 2 (16 April) event list: </strong>The impact of blockchain and Web3, Crypto decentralization, Tokenization victories, Investment in Web3 gaming, Diving into Artificial Intelligence, Official afterparty, and many more.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Official Afterparty: </strong>Live Concert, food, Alcohol Bar and Show, and Special guest Alan Walker.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The event will bring together 160+ speakers and 8000+ attendees from 120+ countries including UAE, Russia, USA, Germany, UK, China, India, Canada, Israel etc.   </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><a href="https://w3wc.io/?no"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/freecompress-1440x90-gif-1-1.gif" alt="" style="width:1450px;height:auto"/></a></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why Attend The Blockchain Life 2024 Event?</strong></h3>



<p>Blockchain Life is a place where you can meet your favorite opinion leaders, company owners, specialists, scientists, and crypto leaders from 120 countries. Take advantage of the opportunities offered by <a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2023/12/21/paybito-plans-to-expand-workforce-for-dubai-and-singapore-markets/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dubai </a>and UAE, which are becoming the meeting point for an expanding community of crypto people and visionaries.</p>



<p>Join the Bull Run event where expert speakers and panel discussions will cover the latest trends and strategies in the industry. By attending, participants can gain actionable insights that can help individuals achieve financial success.</p>



<p>Discover the true world of Web3, cryptocurrencies, and mining while enjoying luxurious networking with Crypto Whales. Over 150 booths featuring the most innovative companies are waiting to interact with groundbreaking teams and forge connections with CEOs.</p>



<p>Meet blockchain and crypto enthusiasts from around the world who share a passion for this industry.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Speakers And Attendees Details&nbsp;</strong></h3>



<p>The Blockchain Life 2024 event is about to connect 160+ speakers and 8000+ attendees from worldwide. Here are the attendee&#8217;s and speakers details.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Speakers: </strong>Sergey Nazarov, the co-founder of Chainlink, Paolo Ardoino CEO of Tether, and CTO of Bitfinex, H.E. Justin Sun, TRON founder, Ben Zhou, co-founder and CEO of Bybit, &amp; Rachel Conlan, CMO of Binance are some main speakers at the event.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Attendees: </strong>The event involves attendees from different countries including 18% from North America, 3% from Africa, 37% from Asia, 3% from South America, and 2% from Australia.</p>



<p>Furthermore, it is expected that 67% of investors, 34% of crypto traders, 31% of entrepreneurs, 30% of developers, 29% of miners, 26% of service providers, 24% of startups, and 4% of others will attend the event.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/blockchain-life-event-2024-the-crypto-whales-meeting-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chainlink Guarding Transaction With New Bridge App ‘Transporter’</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/chainlink-guarding-transaction-with-new-bridge-app-transporter/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/chainlink-guarding-transaction-with-new-bridge-app-transporter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Anderrson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 21:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chainlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chainlink (LINK) Price Prediction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Chainlink" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p><em><strong>Chainlink, a platform connecting public and private blockchains has launched a new bridge app ‘Transporter’ for making data and value transactions safer.  </strong></em></p>



<p>The issues related to security &#38; scalability have persisted in the blockchain technology since its launch and require an effective solution. Chainlink (LINK), a decentralized blockchain oracle network streaming on Ethereum, introduced a new bridge app ‘Transporter’ for safer data transfer. The Bridge app is available on a few of the blockchains including Arbitrum, Avalanche, Base, BNB Chain, Ethereum, Optimism, etc.&#160;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Chainlink’s New Bridge App Details</strong></h2>



<p>On Thursday, April 11, to mitigate the challenge of security, Chainlink introduced &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter.webp" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="Chainlink" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter.webp 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-300x169.webp 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-1024x576.webp 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-768x432.webp 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-1536x864.webp 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-750x422.webp 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Chainlink-Aims-to-Make-Transfers-Across-Blockchains-Safer-with-New-Bridge-App-Transporter-1140x641.webp 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<p><em><strong>Chainlink, a platform connecting public and private blockchains has launched a new bridge app ‘Transporter’ for making data and value transactions safer.  </strong></em></p>



<p>The issues related to security &amp; scalability have persisted in the blockchain technology since its launch and require an effective solution. Chainlink (LINK), a decentralized blockchain oracle network streaming on Ethereum, introduced a new bridge app ‘Transporter’ for safer data transfer. The Bridge app is available on a few of the blockchains including Arbitrum, Avalanche, Base, BNB Chain, Ethereum, Optimism, etc.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Chainlink’s New Bridge App Details</strong></h2>



<p>On Thursday, April 11, to mitigate the challenge of security, Chainlink introduced a new bridge app ‘Transporter’ for safer data and value transfer.</p>



<p>The new application will permit users to transfer the tokens and data across different blockchains without any security concerns and is available for individuals and institutions. The aim is to offer the best and most cost-effective way to make high-value token transfers effortless and secure.</p>



<p>The new bridge was developed on Chainlink&#8217;s Cross-Chain Interoperability Protocol (CCIP) technology, which is mainly used by SWIFT for shifting large token volumes and messages to other networks in a safe way. Additionally, the technology is used by banks for international money transfers.</p>



<p>Apart from top-notch security, the platform also supports real-time visual tracking to check the status of transfers between blockchains. The platform charges the regular fee for using the technology and includes the cost of executing the transaction on different blockchains and fees paid to CCIP service providers.</p>



<p>The Transporter application is currently available for blockchains including<a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/03/11/arbitrum-dao-removed-proposal-to-fund-tornado-cashs-legal-case/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Arbitrum</a>, Base, BNB Chain, Avalanche, Ethereum, Polygon, Optimism, and WEMIX.           </p>



<p>Sergey Nazarov, the co-founder of Chainlink addressed the new bridge app ‘Transporter’.</p>



<p>&#8220;Having a secure way to move both value and data across chains is something the blockchain industry has needed for years,”, Nazarov added.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bridges play a crucial role in interconnecting the individual blockchain rails, permitting the transaction of value and data in between.</p>



<p>According to DefiLlama data, the existing bridges have transferred around across different chains last month. However, all these bridges are the targets of exploits and hacks, holding chances of user data loss.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><a href="https://w3wc.io/?no"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/freecompress-1440x90-gif-1-1.gif" alt="" style="width:1450px;height:auto"/></a></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Chainlink’s Upcoming Events</strong></h3>



<p>Chainlink is a platform connecting the world of blockchains and is actively engaged in innovations and inventions. After the launch of ‘Transporter,’ the platform is ready to work on its upcoming projects like Chainlink SmartCon and Introducing the Chainlink Block Magic Hackathon.</p>



<p>Chainlink SmartCon is an event going to be organized in Hong Kong between October 30 and 31, 2024. The event involves digital asset leaders, DeFi pioneers, and on-chain builders who will come together to discuss technological topics and invent the future of global markets.</p>



<p>Another upcoming event on Chainlink is Block Magic, which is going to be organized from April to June and involves different events like Chainlink Bootcamp, workshops, Hackathon kick-off, and Project submission deadline.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to CoinMarketCap data, Chainlink is currently trading at $17.44 after an upsurge of 0.64% in the past 1 day and has a market cap of $10,236,002,394. The coin has a 24-volume of $277,908,962, a maximum supply of 1 Million, and a circulating supply of 587,099,970.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/chainlink-guarding-transaction-with-new-bridge-app-transporter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking News! ! ! Earn €500 A Day</title>
		<link>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/breaking-news-earn-e500-a-day/</link>
					<comments>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/breaking-news-earn-e500-a-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sam Chess]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 21:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud Mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/?p=201168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1.jpeg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1.jpeg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-768x432.jpeg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-1536x864.jpeg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-750x422.jpeg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-1140x641.jpeg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p>Economist David Rosenberg says there is an 85% chance the US economy will enter a recession in 2024. This is the model&#8217;s best performance since the 2008 financial crisis.</p>



<p>A recession could be on the way in 2024, and even a slight slowdown could send stocks tumbling as investors bulldoze their way into one of the most expensive markets in more than two decades.</p>



<p>This was announced by Paul Dietrich, chief investment strategist at B. Riley Wealth. U.S. stocks hit new highs again this week after chipmaker Nvidia posted a wildly upbeat earnings report. But the higher the stocks rise, &#8230;</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1.jpeg" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-article-image" alt="" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear:both;max-width: 100%;" link_thumbnail="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1.jpeg 1920w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-768x432.jpeg 768w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-1536x864.jpeg 1536w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-750x422.jpeg 750w, https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-33-1-1140x641.jpeg 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" />
<p>Economist David Rosenberg says there is an 85% chance the US economy will enter a recession in 2024. This is the model&#8217;s best performance since the 2008 financial crisis.</p>



<p>A recession could be on the way in 2024, and even a slight slowdown could send stocks tumbling as investors bulldoze their way into one of the most expensive markets in more than two decades.</p>



<p>This was announced by Paul Dietrich, chief investment strategist at B. Riley Wealth. U.S. stocks hit new highs again this week after chipmaker Nvidia posted a wildly upbeat earnings report. But the higher the stocks rise, the more likely they are to fall into a potential recession.</p>



<p>The economy will experience a mild recession, but even a moderate slowdown could trigger a stock market crash of up to 40%, sending the S&amp;P 500 down about 3,000 points. Various data indicate that there may be a global economic crisis in the future, so how can ordinary people save themselves from the economic crisis?</p>



<p>This article will tell you how smart investors can earn passive income through Blue Sky Miners and not be eliminated in the economic crisis!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What Is Cloud Mining?</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/03/20/bluestonemining-helps-earning-passive-income-through-innovative-cloud-mining-sign-up-and-get-10/">Cloud mining</a> is a method of producing cryptocurrency by renting processing resources from a service provider (cloud mining service provider). To become a member of a mining farm, miners need to purchase a certain amount of &#8220;computing power&#8221; from a service provider. In exchange, the provider rewards miners based on the hashing power they receive. Since mining is done in the cloud, miners don’t have to worry about noise, temperature, resource management or energy costs.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Benefits of cloud mining</strong></h3>



<p>Cloud mining appeals to savvy investors for a variety of reasons, each of which contributes to a simple and potentially lucrative investment path:</p>



<p>Ongoing income: regardless of investor activity, even if you are not working and sleeping,</p>



<p>Both provide the opportunity to passively accumulate Bitcoin income.</p>



<p>Risk reduction: Cloud mining service providers typically manage technical glitches and maintenance, thereby reducing risks associated with equipment failure.</p>



<p>No technical education required: Cloud mining is designed for user convenience and users can use it regardless of their technical knowledge.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The operations to participate in Bitcoin cloud mining are as follows.</strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://blueskyminer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">1. Click to enter: blueskyminer official website, and then start registration with one click. Sign up bonus $10</a></p>



<p>2. Account Registration: Provide the necessary information to create your personal account.</p>



<p>3. Package selection: Choose the cloud mining package that best suits your investment wishes and financial plan.</p>



<p>4. Start mining: With an active account, you can start accumulating Bitcoins immediately.</p>



<p>A custom cloud mining package for blueskyminer.</p>



<p>Check out our custom cloud mining options atsunminer:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/09/btcs-nearest-rival-eth-posted-its-biggest-jump-in-a-month/">BTC </a>entry-level computing power</p>



<p>Investment: $10</p>



<p>Guaranteed return: $10 plus $0.50 daily bonus</p>



<p>Get daily login rewards and steadily increase your mining income.</p>



<p>BTC increases computing power</p>



<p>Deposit: $100</p>



<p>Guaranteed return: $100 plus $6.60</p>



<p>Designed for those who want more powerful computing power and stable profits.</p>



<p>BTC Premier computing power</p>



<p>Investment: $300</p>



<p>Guaranteed return: $500 plus $42.70</p>



<p>Optimize your earning potential with our powerful cloud mining solutions.</p>



<p>Bitcoin cloud mining is an impactful strategy when looking to increase cryptocurrency revenue. Cloud mining is redefining digital currency investment strategies by offering ease of use, economic benefits, and the opportunity for consistent income.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Affiliate Program</strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/01/23/reality-spot-etf-blackrock-vanguard-will-control-bitcoin/">Blue Sky Miner</a> presents its users with several ways of making money, besides mining. One of the ways of making money via this platform is by joining its affiliate program. As a Blue Sky Miner affiliate, you get a unique code and link that you must share with your contacts.</p>



<p>A successful referral guarantees you a 3% commission on their spending. If your referral refers another user to the platform, you get a 1% commission. This is an excellent way of making money, especially if you are a pro salesperson.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Million Bounty</strong></h3>



<p>If you are active on social media, you can make extra money by creating groups and discussions revolving around Blue Sky Miner. The Million Bounty program allows you to make $1 to $500 by making such moves on platforms like Facebook, TikTok, Instagram and WhatsApp.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Customer Support</strong></h3>



<p>In case of a problem when using Blue Sky Miner, do not hesitate to contact customer support for assistance. You can reach the support team in many ways, like through the live chat, email, submitting an e-ticket, or via its social media handles. The response is swift and you will have your issues sorted promptly.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Final Thought</strong></h4>



<p>As the economic crisis approaches, I think you should choose a good investment project to prevent you from being harmed by the economic crisis.</p>



<p><a href="https://blueskyminer.com/" rel="nofollow">Start joining Blue Sky Miner now and increase your current income.</a></p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: Any information written in this press release or sponsored article does not constitute investment advice. Thecoinrepublic.com and all its authors do not, and will not endorse any information on any company or individual on this page. Readers are encouraged to do their research and take any actions based on their findings and not from any content written in this press release or sponsored article. Thecoinrepublic.com and all its authors do not and will not be responsible for any damage or loss caused directly or indirectly by the use of any content, product, or service mentioned in this press release or sponsored article.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecoinrepublic.com/2024/04/12/breaking-news-earn-e500-a-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
