<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<description>Neutral and Authentic News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:20:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cropped-Dark_CP_Symbol-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Shiba Inu lead hints ShibaSwap 1.75 before 2.0 launch</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/shiba-inu-lead-hints-shibaswap-1-75/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mutuma Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shibarium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ShibaSwap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shytoshi Kusama]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shytoshi Kusama, Shiba Inu&#8217;s leading developer, often shares about the forthcoming release of ShibaSwap 1.75, which would let the chain of events for the rumored ShibaSwap 2.0 clicking begins. Kusama is currently discussing with X tech gurus shortly on Shibarium’s Telegram channel, where he has exposed future progress. On April 20, Kusama shared that he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Shytoshi Kusama, Shiba Inu&#8217;s leading developer, often shares about the forthcoming release of ShibaSwap 1.75, which would let the chain of events for the rumored ShibaSwap 2.0 clicking begins. Kusama is currently discussing with X tech gurus shortly on Shibarium’s Telegram channel, where he has exposed future progress.</p>



<p>On April 20, Kusama shared that he and a respected figure were having ongoing primary-level talks about issues related to SHIB. The Shiba Inu community showed tremendous support when the influential artist mentioned the symbolism of “warm woof” in her work.</p>



<p>Regarding the issue raised by community member Karn about ShibaSwap 2.0, Kusama showcased that the thrilling upgrade is coming soon in &#8220;Pretty Soon.&#8221; However, they stressed that version 1.75 would be released beforehand to build up new partnerships or connections. &#8220;(ShibaSwap 2.0) is the real deal since that&#8217;s the time when all the fun activities begin, but from the start, I had to make some new friends, apparently,” told Kusama.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ShibaSwap?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#ShibaSwap</a> V1.75 coming “pretty soon” because “needed to make new frens first”… <br>… would it be <a href="https://twitter.com/Uniswap?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@Uniswap</a> ? 🤔<br>Let’s go <a href="https://twitter.com/ShytoshiKusama?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@ShytoshiKusama</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/kaaldhairya?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@kaaldhairya</a> , thank you for all you do!… <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Unleash?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#Unleash</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Shibaswap?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#Shibaswap</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Shibarium?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#Shibarium</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BONE?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">#BONE</a> <a href="https://t.co/moIgMb4dzX" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/moIgMb4dzX</a></p>&mdash; Jolt (@Jolt_yourday) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jolt_yourday/status/1782030578847519209?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 21, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Shiba Inu community awaits ShibaSwap 1.75 upgrade</strong></h2>



<p>The first Web3 decentralized exchange of the Shiba Inu ecosystem, ShibaSwap, debuted in July 2021. It enables trades and staking of ecosystem tokens budget gift cards in leu, including tokens like BONE, SHIB, and LEASH. Starting from scratch, SHIB caught the public&#8217;s attention. In January 2023, CertiK, a blockchain security group, ranked it number one among other decentralized exchanges (DEX).</p>



<p>The main criticism of ShibaSwap 1.0 was identifying areas for improvement within the DEX, so Shiba Swap 2.0 came into light in 2023. Integrating into the ShibaSwap 2.0 upgraded framework architecture, the new feature will utilize this to expand beyond the conventional token swap mechanism to embed a fully-fledged crypto gateway portal. The portal becomes a central place where anyone can track cryptocurrency numbers, charts, news, and trends, which, therefore, will improve its usage.</p>



<p>Then,<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/shiba-inu-nfts-sold-out-in-35-mins/"> ShibaSwap 2.0</a> is planned to introduce fresh and upgraded designs for implementation. The new user layout and operation are to be enhanced and of better quality. The ShibaSwap followers were recently handed some exciting news by their lead developer, who declared that ShibaSwap 1.75 is fixed to be released. This makes it quite evident that the ShibaSwap community anxiously looks forward to the yet-to-come advancements.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>ShibaSwap&#8217;s journey and success</strong></h2>



<p>After spending some time in the Shiba Swap community, the number of users on the platform has increased, with many coming back to use it because of its simplicity and strong offerings. DEX is a marvelous instrument for swapping and staking tokens that, overall, contribute to the growth of the Shiba Inu’s ecosystem.</p>



<p>The ShibaSwap<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/front-end-attacks-on-trader-joes-dex/"> DEX platform</a> has acquired Certik&#8217;s certificate, among others that were audited in January 2023 and has emerged as the platform that exceeds the competition compared to PancakeSwap and 1inch Network. This certification, therefore, makes it clear that the platform has stayed true to its word to keep user interaction safe by protecting transactions and integrating with other financial institutions.</p>



<p>However, unlike Dogecoin, which tends to stagnate, Shiba Inu&#8217;s developers actively make improvements and extend the platform. Recent versions of ShibaSwap 1.75 and ShibaSwap 2.0 represent new releases and mark the beginning of a new history of decentralized exchanges. The more the SHIB community expects new and improved features and functionalities from the Shiba Inu project, the sooner these development milestones will be reached, which will ultimately allow the ecosystem to flourish in its next development stage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Design_an_image_of_Shiba_Inu_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Design_an_image_of_Shiba_Inu_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Market in Japan to Benefit from SoftBank’s $960 Million Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-market-from-softbanks-million-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emman Omwanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SoftBank, a major Japanese telecommunications company, has announced that it will push the development of AI technologies with an investment plan of 150 billion yen ($960 million) by June of next year, and the venture&#8217;s investments mainly focus on boosting the company&#8217;s computing. This financial injection is the primary purpose of SoftBank to increase its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>SoftBank, a major Japanese telecommunications company, has announced that it will push the development of AI technologies with an investment plan of 150 billion yen ($960 million) by June of next year, and the venture&#8217;s investments mainly focus on boosting the company&#8217;s computing. This financial injection is the primary purpose of SoftBank to increase its capabilities of building and ultimately rendering the Japanese with specific AI model tests.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SoftBank&#8217;s AI investments and partnerships in Japan</h2>



<p>Soft bank, in this way, enables the high cost for the company to be visible, making Softbank competitive in Japan in computing power. It is the third largest investment into technological infrastructure, following a 20 billion yen expenditure on computing infrastructure last year. By the recent announcement, SoftBank has made its place in society as the leader in computational resources, filling it with its latest increase of hands that have also been lent to other companies for this facility.</p>



<p>This plan will specify the purchase of a new generation of graphics processing units (GPUs), which are the products of Nvidia, one of the biggest chip designers in the US. However, these GPUs are super critical for the perfect building of advanced generative AI and help achieve breakthroughs. It is not just about SoftBank but also about a network system where SoftBank can share all know-how and capacities with others and be nurtured by other firms.</p>



<p>To achieve its objectives by fiscal year 2024, SoftBank plans to finish a large language model with 390 billion parameters, a pitchstone in AI. They have just started; this model is supposed to be the first step towards a model with 1 trillion parameters, and it is expected to start work soon, which is the next step in this new and incredible technology. The world&#8217;s best AI model is the appointer, and the organization encourages its performance to follow OpenAI&#8217;s GPT 4 standard, the world benchmark of high-performance AI.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Economic impact and market outlook</h2>



<p>The investment is scheduled to take place at the right moment to gain from the Japanese generative AI market, which will be valued at almost $13 billion by 2030, exhibiting a 17-fold growth from the level of $750 million (estimated for 2023). These inherent landmines that AI adoption entails can lead to significant economic growth opportunities, stretching the application of AI to numerous industries.</p>



<p>SoftBank’s constantly innovating attitude in this regard seemed a winner, with investors who, through rising shares, are as high as of 2018. Such confidence is seen as the market brightness of AI perspective, which means AI can lead the business in the future.</p>



<p>Along with this, there is also the motivation to build national capabilities regarding AI, which illustrates other strategic and economic aspects related to the nation&#8217;s data security and sovereignty. Under the increased influence of global dynamics, Japan is seeking to diversify its supply chain, specifically technology advancement, as a way of building capabilities to combat sudden changes in the market or geopolitical tensions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SoftBank&#8217;s data center expansion</h2>



<p>Besides AI, Softbank has diversified by building up its infrastructure networks. The corporation is looking for new data centers within Japan and found them in Hokkaido as its key project, which is huge. These facilities are indispensable for processing data and will constitute a breakthrough in the era of AI-powered products.</p>



<p>The venture, which gives the company a broader strategic reach, reflects Softbank&#8217;s view that leadership in AI is an inevitable task in global AI takeoff. Furthermore, SoftBank, with those steps, does not just invest in technology but also forms the future Japanese market setting and its technological capabilities.</p>



<p>News sourced from<a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Tech/Semiconductors/SoftBank-to-spend-960m-to-boost-computing-power-for-generative-AI?utm_campaign=IC_asia_daily_free&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=NA_newsletter&amp;utm_content=article_link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> NIKKEI ASIA</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_SoftBank_a_major_Japanese_telecommunications_company_h_1-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_SoftBank_a_major_Japanese_telecommunications_company_h_1-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emergence of AI in the Workspace Requires Skills Development </title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-in-the-workspace-requires-skills/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Glory Kaburu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The ever-growing significance of AI in the workspace, and the automation of jobs renders the workers nervous. A current survey done at the University of Southern California and ESCP Business School claims that artificial intelligence will become a gatekeeper for a new kind of job, which requires both humans and machines to work effectively. Integrating [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The ever-growing significance of AI in the workspace, and the automation of jobs renders the workers nervous. A current survey done at the University of Southern California and ESCP Business School claims that artificial intelligence will become a gatekeeper for a new kind of job, which requires both humans and machines to work effectively.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Integrating human and machine capabilities&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The integration of AI in the workplace is not an easy task as it will not lead to the total reshuffling of humans with machines.&nbsp; Contrary to that, it is an occasion for reinventing human jobs being exempt by the outstanding skills of both humans and AI. The study may be made by the University of Southern California, which showed that while AI&nbsp; provides the best predictability and more efficiency and more efficiency, the human touch still helps ensure an excellent outcome. This combination of humans and robots is thought to align the best application of artificial intelligence in business environments.</p>



<p>According to ESCP Business School&#8217;s report, AI would make humans even more emotionally blind to the situation, which they would have to monitor and intervene with. Nevertheless, AI does admit that there can be efficiencies gained by the streamlining of processes plus it can in turn liberate human workers to deal with problems and contribute their emotions where it is most required. According to the report, work in the future will likely be categorized into three types: Even though intelligence might seem impervious to AI, this makes it vulnerable in three broad areas, namely, as an intelligent hand in physical work, an intelligent mind cognitive work, and an intelligent heart emotional work.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Future of technology and ethical concerns&nbsp;</h2>



<p>AI is a stepping stone in many ways and holds many positives, yet the development has its share of unwanted effects. The first issue is the risk that basic human abilities, such as memory, attention, and precision when handling objects, would be replaced.&nbsp; The ESCP paper highlights the importance of understanding and preserving human intelligence, which is structured into three levels: abilities such as the use of hands, problem examination and creativity, and the systemic approach and the level of holism.</p>



<p>There lies the difficulty in applying AI in a way that couples with the said human abilities, giving the technology a booster effect, not a displacing effect on the workforce. Organizations should create protocols that would coordinate integration between AI and human capabilities and also to some extent develop these skills within people.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Enhancing workforce skills for an AI-integrated future</h2>



<p>This demand is also heard from industry executives who call for education reform as they are convinced that while AI will certainly transform jobs, it does not mean that the jobs will be cut altogether. Hence, it is more critical to break up with traditional retraining and instead, tackle the issues of appropriate employment of humans in a world of robotics.</p>



<p>As the human-to-machine line keeps demanding, it is becoming clearer that the workforce needs to be better progressed and their knowledge needs to be advanced as well. Due care should be exercised while introducing such AI into the workplace to avoid the decrease of necessary human skills, allowing employees to have the capability of not only interacting with AI but of upgrading their skills through education and adaptation too.</p>



<p>The present change in the relational map of work is the result of the developing AI technology. That necessitates us to reconsider the skills development and the way they are implemented. In that sense, yielding the mutual advancement of human and machine intelligence, organizations can make the most of AI to increase effectiveness and enhance innovation. Alongside this, the development and multiplication of human skills will become the most pressing task for the workforce that is currently in the middle of a revolution.</p>



<p>The AI-enhanced prospects are required to adapt and conform the survive and prosper in this hi-tech world. Responding to job shifts that a growing AI role as a proprietor brings, both in business practices and educational facilities, is a necessity. Educational institutions, both schools, and universities, shall be geared towards knowledge transference instead of training students with skills pertinent to the promising and unprecedented technological development. Proactive and lifelong learning skills along with continuous skills development would be necessary for workers to remain on the top of the game in their line of business.</p>



<p>This article originally appeared in <a href="https://cybernews.com/editorial/skills-work-alongside-ai/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Cybernews</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Emergence_of_AI_in_the_Workspace_Requires_Skills_Devel_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Emergence_of_AI_in_the_Workspace_Requires_Skills_Devel_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Will AI Impact the Taxation Process?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/how-will-ai-impact-the-taxation-process/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aamir Sheikh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Explained]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taxation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Increased transparency is a requirement of tax authorities in recent times. They need transparent processes for sharing information, their jurisdictions, and also for firm approaches to management and tax collection processes. On the other end of the equation, this has overburdened businesses with the load of increased compliance. Businesses are also facing tax risk and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Increased transparency is a requirement of tax authorities in recent times. They need transparent processes for sharing information, their jurisdictions, and also for firm approaches to management and tax collection processes. On the other end of the equation, this has overburdened businesses with the load of increased compliance. Businesses are also facing tax risk and uncertainty.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tax and technology have interconnected to a greater extent, especially with the widespread of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML). Tax functioning is changing at a fast pace that has never been seen before, as tax authorities are digitizing.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tech tools for taxation&nbsp;</h2>



<p>As we know, business leaders are always on the hunt for knowledge as to how they can speed up their use of tech tools so that they can create more capability in their teams and use data to get more insights from it.</p>



<p>Compliance obligation never stops at one point and keeps expanding, and heads of tax departments are asked to meet the requirement at a much faster pace while maintaining the quality.</p>



<p>The point here is that how the tech is reshaping the tax future. And what must the tax heads do to utilize the potential that it offers?</p>



<p>Authorities around the world are sharing information with one another and adopting data analytics and digital operations, which is why they are provoking a shift towards progressive compliance from relying on hindsight. So we can say that the main drivers of tech disruption in the tax sector are may be these authorities. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="653" height="573" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/as1112.png" alt="" class="wp-image-514685" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/as1112.png 653w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/as1112-300x263.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 653px) 100vw, 653px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: <a href="https://www.pwc.no/no/publikasjoner/Digitalisering/artificial-intelligence-and-machine-learning-final1.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Pwc</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Role of leadership</h2>



<p>Take AI as an example, it can help professionals in the tax sector to know the savings hidden in their data and to identify the actual tax risks, and also stay updated on the most recent regulatory changes. AI solutions can also tell about how tax laws apply to a specific situation at hand with real-time insights.</p>



<p>AI can help free time and save the effort of tax teams for important strategic activities by automating this heavy lifting and streamlining the decision-making process.</p>



<p>Heads of tax must ensure some elements to get the most out of <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/dutch-skepticism-towards-ai/" data-type="post" data-id="511041">AI</a> and to integrate it effectively. A leadership role must be devoted to integrating and implementing digital tech in the functions of taxation.</p>



<p>The key duty of the leadership of tax tech will be strategy development, because it is very important that the taxation lead the tech. There are no shortcuts when it comes to technology deployment in the public sector due to its huge size and public impact, so the strategy must be based on a practical time frame, and clarify the coming changes to the processes and system as a whole, and must be evaluative of the fact that where the process stands and where it should be after the implementation.</p>



<p>The original story can be seen <a href="https://www.ft.com/partnercontent/kpmg/how-is-technology-shaping-the-future-of-tax.html" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/54fc651e-d623-4066-bb03-9ed084a9cc06.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/54fc651e-d623-4066-bb03-9ed084a9cc06.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bybit Kicks Off Trader’s Year of 2024 Interview Series with Anson Tan, Famous Quant Traders</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/bybit-kicks-off-traders-year-of-2024-interview-series-with-anson-tan-famous-quant-traders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guest User]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leading crypto exchange Bybit has started a captivating interview series where it questions famous traders on their journey and experience in trading crypto.&#160; Bybit said the series is a key component of the “Bybit Trader’s Year of 2024” initiative, which is aimed at grooming and elevating a community of crypto traders at every stage of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Leading crypto exchange Bybit has started a captivating interview series where it questions famous traders on their journey and experience in trading crypto.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bybit said the series is a key component of the “Bybit Trader’s Year of 2024” initiative, which is aimed at grooming and elevating a community of crypto traders at every stage of their development, with a reward pool of $4 million USDT.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first episode of the series happened in February 2024, featuring with Anson Tan, a famous quant trader and the host of the popular crypto YouTube channel, The Tradveller. In the interview, Tan shared his crypto journey, his experience, vision, and aspirations to achieve together with Bybit.</p>



<p><strong>How did you enter the crypto rabbit hole and why did you become a trader?</strong></p>



<p>I got to know Bitcoin when I was only 19, back when the hot topic was mining. However, being a student with limited funds, I couldn&#8217;t afford mining rigs or facilities. So, I turned to trading as a cost-effective alternative that allowed me to participate in the crypto market.</p>



<p><strong>Why did you choose to trade with Bybit?</strong></p>



<p>Of all my years in crypto trading, I found Bybit to offer a very smooth trading experience and a user-friendly platform. Bybit&#8217;s performance and stability during extreme market volatilities have always been robust and reliable. What impressed me the most was Bybit&#8217;s perpetual contracts, which are more sophisticated and smoother than those offered by other major exchanges. Additionally, Bybit&#8217;s customer service has been super supportive, always responsive and helpful. Their 24/7 support and chat in the community have been invaluable to me, especially during my early days as a trader.</p>



<p><strong>What’s your main goal this year?</strong></p>



<p>My main goal this year is focused on quantitative trading, education, empowerment, and investment to nurture young traders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I plan to create educational videos and explore offline sharing and seminars as a means of better engagement and communication. I believe certain aspects of the crypto industry cannot be adequately addressed through online interactions alone. Furthermore, I aim to collaborate with like-minded industry opinion leaders to foster growth and trust in the crypto field.</p>



<p><strong>What should we expect from Bybit Trader’s Year of 2024?</strong></p>



<p>In 2024, you can expect more sharing and interaction with the community, both within the crypto industry and the traditional world. The introduction of spot ETFs has brought about positive changes to the landscape, and it&#8217;s something we can look forward to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we continue to build our community, we constantly contemplate how industry practitioners, like myself, can contribute to the advancement of the crypto industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Personally, I&#8217;m always excited and inspired by Bybit&#8217;s annual VIP gathering, as it brings together a group of unnoticed masters, creating a &#8220;crouching tiger, hidden dragon&#8221; situation.</p>



<p>Besides the interview series, Bybit added that the year-long will feature a range of other activities, including monthly trading competitions, inspirational master classes conducted by industry experts and top traders, as well as a host of thrilling events and gatherings.</p>



<p>&#8220;In the ever-evolving realm of crypto trading, empowerment and education stand as pivotal pillars for success. &#8216;Bybit Trader of 2024&#8217; reflects our commitment to empowering Bybit users with essential knowledge and tools that will shape their trading journey,” said Ben Zhou, CEO of Bybit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/job-4131482_1280.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/job-4131482_1280.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fugitive Binance executive Nadeem Anjarwalla faces extradition to Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/fugitive-binance-executive-nadeem-anjarwalla/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mutuma Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nadeem Anjarwalla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Federal Police Service of Kenya is underway in extraditing Nadeem Anjarwalla, a high-ranking Binance official who escaped from custody in Nigeria. According to the authoritative source of the Nigerian government relayed by the International Criminal Police Organisation, the gangster money launderer Anjarwalla will be delivered to Nigerian authorities within the current week, Punch reports. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Federal Police Service of Kenya is underway in extraditing <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/operation-traces-binance-executive-in-kenya/">Nadeem Anjarwalla</a>, a high-ranking <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/nigerian-court-delays-binance-executive-bail/">Binance official</a> who escaped from custody in Nigeria. According to the authoritative source of the Nigerian government relayed by the International Criminal Police Organisation, the gangster money launderer Anjarwalla will be delivered to Nigerian authorities within the current week, Punch reports. The general service of the Kenyan police picked Anjarwalla because of his successful avoidance of capture in Nigeria.</p>



<p>The controversy centers on whether Anjarwalla has evaded taxes, speculated on currency, and washed $35.4 million through the bank. Olukoyede, the EFCC chairman, announced that the Commission had intensified its efforts for Anjarwalla&#8217;s capture and will return him to Nigeria to face justice. EFCC is now working along with other international law enforcement agencies to make sure that Anjarwalla is being repatriated. EFCC–a commission committed to fight financial crimes that may affect the Forex market through corruption or fraud in Nigeria–accused Anjarwalla.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>EFCC&#8217;s vigilance leads to Binance executive&#8217;s arrest</strong></h2>



<p>Close cooperation among the Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC), the International Criminal Police Organisation (Interpol), the Nigeria Police Force, and the Kenyan Police Service has increasingly focused on speeding up Anjarwalla&#8217;s extradition. This created the required international siege, which ended with the defendant’s extradition from Kenya. The emphasis of these discussions is on expediting her extradition process so that she can be returned to Nigerian detention as soon as possible, which is the purpose of such discussions.</p>



<p>The charge <a href="https://businessday.ng/news/article/kenya-police-to-extradite-fleeing-binance-executive-to-nigeria/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">extradition process for Anjarwalla</a>, who is a Binance executive, is a very big step for the alleged financial misconduct. Anjarwalla’s persecution by the EFCC shows how serious the commission is about not allowing economic crimes to become part of Nigeria’s economic fabric. However, with the arrest of Anjarwalla in Kenya and the soon-to-be extradition to Nigeria, authorities want justice, which is believed to involve the fraudster in a financial crime.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Legal proceedings and prosecution</strong></h2>



<p>The EFCC&#8217;s recent arrest and prepared extradition of Anjarwalla are linked to its work on Binance Holdings Limited and its officials. The same accusations, together with currency speculation and tax evasion, are attributed to Anjarwalla and Tigran Gambaryan. Although Gambaryan is already behind bars at this time, Anjarwalla&#8217;s extradition process is proceeding with great success. The EFCC&#8217;s aim in Anjarwalla’s case is in line with its mission to prevent crime in the financial sector and defend Nigeria’s economic integrity.</p>



<p>The return of Anjarwalla from another country emphasizes the need for the cooperation of countries internationally to combat transnational financial crimes. The EFCC&#8217;s fastidiousness and closeness with worldwide law enforcement agencies are signs of Nigeria&#8217;s seriousness in tackling unlawful financial activities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Generate_an_image_of_nigeria_flag_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Generate_an_image_of_nigeria_flag_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meta Rolls Out Llama 3 to Enhance AI Capabilities Across Social Media Platforms</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/meta-rolls-llama-3-to-enhan-ai-capability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emman Omwanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Explained]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Llama 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meta Platforms(META.O) has unveiled the version of its AI experiment, Llama 3, and the newest real-time image generator ‘IMAGINE’. AI development has always been driving the interest of companies like Meta as they look to match OpenAI &#8211; the leader of the Generative AI market. The new models are advanced technologies of The Meta AI [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Meta Platforms(META.O) has unveiled the version of its AI experiment, Llama 3, and the newest real-time image generator<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/imagine-meta-ai-feature-prompts-into-image/"> ‘IMAGINE’</a>. AI development has always been driving the interest of companies like Meta as they look to match OpenAI &#8211; the leader of the Generative AI market. The new models are advanced technologies of The Meta AI suite, which is declared as the first-class and free virtual assistant service, different from other competitors like Google and Mistral.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Meta AI Llama 3 developments across its platforms</h2>



<p>The updated version of Meta AI assistant will reach a larger audience due to the company&#8217;s integration into popular platforms, namely Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp, and Messenger. Meta has also launched a website, which is a standalone feature designed to provide users with interactive experiences like creating a packing list for a trip, doing a music quiz, or creating images of city skylines. In this case, Meta will compete against OpenAI from Microsoft, using limited resources to combat.</p>



<p>The change in Meta also implies a substantial change (or upgrade) of Meta&#8217;s computing infrastructure and the bringing together Meta&#8217;s research and product units. These adaptations are about to make the AI capabilities of the company more accessible yet efficient to its numerous users. </p>



<p>The company has taken a further step forward by releasing its Llama models to developers, providing a robust ML tool with the possibility to put under question the revenue models of its rivals. This transparency, however, has led to some reservations about the technology coming from potentially abusing the technology.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Meta AI development and&nbsp; strategic partnerships toward global expansion</h2>



<p>Meta equips Llama 3 with superior coding capability in addition to the new pictorial data in training, but now it produces text instead of images. Meta’s current and upcoming product developments in artificial intelligence are indeed very impressive, according to Meta’s Chief Product Officer, Chris Cox. He emphasized that high-level reasoning skills and dual-output generation of text and image will be included in future releases. The providers expect these new features to be gradually deployed from now on.</p>



<p>Other than that, Meta made a deal with Google to provide up-to-the-minute search results that assistants can use to answer inquiries. This also expanded a collaboration with Microsoft Bing, which is now available. According to Meta’s global AI agenda, this extension of services covers more than a dozen countries outside the US, including Australia, Canada, Singapore, Nigeria, Pakistan, and Europe, where plans are still being worked on due to stringent privacy laws.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Meta market position rises with new AI model</h2>



<p>The price of MetaShares bounced back in the afternoon after the statement, climbing by 1.8%. Llama 3’s 8 billion and 70 billion parameter models launched, the additional versions that already beat the performance of the famous free libraries located in the market. Roughly 400 billion weights are being trained in the largest model, which has many other settings to improve AI intelligence.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/gCSd88uMLGxEfVXwwWCTqmLnAbqFg_67lIIR9cFdGq47bHfjMWHSflon2y6ve7RIwA9YGEJeYdR1LEJxlDLTy6AK2y3lqx_FsVnRzm5I_1ua8RHEYmoIVy1Kp1Q0I-km84bGQc20mp3P8pdeCqjU9J4" alt="" /></figure>



<p>Source: Reuters</p>



<p>Meta’s decision to offer extra AI tools is a strategic decision that aims to position the tech company to compete in an industry where creativity and fast delivery are crucial. </p>



<p>The constantly changing and mercurial AI landscape allows Meta to boost its investments in advanced capabilities and strategic partners. However, with such a development, Meta could stand a better chance of getting a good field position.</p>



<p>News sourced from <a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/meta-llama-3/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">meta</a> blogpost</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Meta_Rolls_Social_Media_Platforms_IMPROVED_WITHTECH_1-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Meta_Rolls_Social_Media_Platforms_IMPROVED_WITHTECH_1-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Government crackdown: Thailand to block unregistered crypto platforms</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/thailand-block-unregistered-crypto-platform/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mutuma Maxwell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand SEC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thailand has declared that crypto exchanges that do not have permission are to be blocked from unauthorized digital asset platforms and that this act of government is to tighten the control over the crypto market. The decision made by the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Technology Crime Suppression Committee, and the government in a united [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Thailand has declared that crypto exchanges that do not have permission are to be blocked from unauthorized digital asset platforms and that this act of government is to tighten the control over the crypto market. The decision made by the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Technology Crime Suppression Committee, and the government in a united front depicts the government being substantially committed to fighting cybercrime. The services that steal people&#8217;s attention and are unregistered by the Ministry of Digital Economy and Society should be blocked. Due to this, people will be able to use services from trusted providers.</p>



<p>With a view to being considerate to users, the <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/thailand-government-savings-bond/">Thai government</a> plans a transitional period to allow the management of personal accounts and withdrawal of proceeds before the block is enforced. According to the SEC, the withdrawal of assets from the affected platforms must be immediately done to fulfill the regulatory directive and minimize disruption. This deliberate method demonstrates Thailand&#8217;s resolution to achieve the twin goals of regulations and protection of the stakeholders.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Transition period for users</strong></h2>



<p>While the system is still being developed, people can manage their accounts and withdraw their assets from the illegal crypto platforms in Thailand prior to access being restricted. The initiative is meant to help users transition seamlessly while at the same time ensuring the user interfaces are in line with the regulations of the SEC and other authorities. The Thai government sees this as a window for account management and asset withdrawals to minimize disruptions and have a regulatory measure.</p>



<p>Furthermore,<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/joint-status-report-reveals-ongoing-dispute/"> Binance Holdings Ltd</a>, the world&#8217;s biggest crypto trading platform, has decided to explore the possibility of a market presence in Thailand. Supporting Gulf Energy Development Pcl, Binance seeks to establish a cryptocurrency exchange platform in Thailand. Nevertheless, the project will be required to comply with the recently issued Thai authorities&#8217; requirements. This indicates the growing trend of crypto companies leading the industry in concentrating their attention on new markets such as Thailand because of the dynamic crypto space.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Thailand&#8217;s accomplishment of regulatory compliance</strong></h2>



<p>Thailand&#8217;s <a href="https://www.sec.or.th/TH/Pages/News_Detail.aspx?SECID=10732&amp;fbclid=IwZXh0bgNhZW0BMQABHfcwra1QtmXgckCBiPpfgG5OKOrRxpWY8tSF13jeQDi2qDks1El5_GsYKQ_aem_ASNhM3cWgGaZHUMVDkCdGUnbDIL2U3wt3oc9MbFlXn_BLI5zhNoT1-6f0q6k7mGKLVc" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">new regulatory</a> moves demonstrate that the country is dedicated to enhancing crypto development via investor protection and preservation of stable finance. By enforcing strict custodian standards and banning access to unauthorized platforms, Thai regulators are attempting to reduce the threats related to crypto while providing a secure digital asset ecosystem. These moves parallel world precedents and are examples of the Thai authority&#8217;s preventive actions to control the fast-moving crypto market.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Design_an_image_of_Thailand_flag_and_bitcoin_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Design_an_image_of_Thailand_flag_and_bitcoin_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Integration Propels Shanghai Schools to Global Recognition</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-integration-shanghai-schools-to-global/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emman Omwanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shanghai Schools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shanghai has become a model region in educational fields. This role is mostly related to the accomplishments of Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi. The school has been widely recognized for its innovative, technology-equipped teaching approach alongside its broad range of education subjects, setting a new bar in China and the rest of the world in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Shanghai has become a model region in educational fields. This role is mostly related to the accomplishments of Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi. The school has been widely recognized for its innovative, technology-equipped teaching approach alongside its broad range of education subjects, setting a new bar in China and the rest of the world in the field of educational standards.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Shanghai&#8217;s Dulwich College Puxi leads with innovative education</h2>



<p>The new campus of Dulwich College Shanghai, Puxi, which became operational in 2016, strives to serve the rapidly growing population in that area. The school had a commendable event. With a batch of learners from IB programs who made an excellent passage through the International Baccalaureate (IB) diplomas, the first graduation focused on learners&#8217; academic prowess unfazed by pressure. Most graduates have been rated the second-best IB School in China, and they have an average score of 37.7, which makes them capable of competing with other schools worldwide.</p>



<p>This success testifies to the school&#8217;s determination to uphold traditional academic techniques and willingness to follow the times. Dulwich Puxi pushes the limits of adopting AI and other state-of-the-art innovations in its student body. </p>



<p>Among the other schools, it was the first to adopt tools like the Alex Qbot chatbot and Century Tech learning platforms, which set a precedent for using advanced resources to enhance educational outcomes.</p>



<p>Artificially Intelligent Instruction and Innovation (AIAI) is one of the courses available among students in the high school years 10 to 11. Design Engineer Construction (DEC) is a core course for Grade 8 students. These courses, which aim to empower students with skills to explore and make sense of the multi-dimensional surface of technology, have been designed.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Transformational education at Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi</h2>



<p>The fundamental goal of extending the technological role in resolving actual world duplicities is at Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi. A noteworthy project is the upcoming Planet Hack hackathon, which was jointly organized by ANU and the college . This occasion is a platform for the students to combine  advanced environmental problems via research, ideas, and prototype designs that demonstrate how they have translated what they learned in the class into practical scenarios.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the school has been celebrated for its internationalism on a national and global level. Dulwich Puxi has been nominated for the 2024 Tes Awards for Best Use of Technology, which bears testimony to the school&#8217;s ability to ensure integrated tech usage in the classroom environment.</p>



<p>In the co-curricular club, students are encouraged to take part in sporting activities, music, and community work, which surface the endorphin hormone. Programs like the Duke of Edinburgh International Award and The Ignite: Swiss students are grateful for this program because it provides ample training for modern survival rather than just being academically good.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi&#8217;s vision for future education</h2>



<p>Paving the way for the rest, Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi led the way in implementing the digital future transformation model. Today&#8217;s existence proves that the concept is no longer just a theory but an actual reality.</p>



<p>The college provides instruction that encourages students&#8217; superior reasoning and problem-solving skills. Moreover, combining inventive approaches in technology will make the school effective in providing the necessary educational needs of its learners in the future. </p>



<p>The upcoming conference on The Future of Education, which will cover Dulwich Puxi, Dehong Shanghai, and Dulwich Pudong, will allow one to learn much about this leading educational institution.</p>



<p>In an era where things are quickly changing, and education is becoming more accessible, Dulwich College Shanghai Puxi leads the way by preparing their future generation to be the leaders who will lead them through bright and glorious days ahead.</p>



<p>News sourced from <a href="https://www.smartshanghai.com/articles/education/aitech-shanghai-education-dulwich-is-innovating" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Smart Shanghai</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Dulwich_College_Shanghai_Puxis_vision_for_future_educa_0-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Dulwich_College_Shanghai_Puxis_vision_for_future_educa_0-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Version of Mark Zuckerberg Showcased on YouTube: An Unusual Comparison</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-version-of-mark-zuckerberg-on-youtube/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Glory Kaburu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 09:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Trending News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=514656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To compare the AI version of Mark Zuckerberg from a YouTube perspective, the channel Breaking Even made a video entitled Artificial Intelligence of Mark Zuckerberg: What is the difference? This has led to discussion from people views about the similarities and differences between the two personalities of Mark Zuckerberg, an AI one, and the real [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To compare the AI version of Mark Zuckerberg from a YouTube perspective, the channel Breaking Even made a video entitled Artificial Intelligence of Mark Zuckerberg: What is the difference? This has led to discussion from people views about the similarities and differences between the two personalities of Mark Zuckerberg, an AI one, and the real one of Meta Platforms Inc. The video consists of a simulation of Zuckerberg, who interacts with the audience on various topics, e.g., producing threads of fictitious projects or taking part in different games like Rapid Fire and 2 Truths 1 Lie.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Performance of the AI Zuckerberg&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The audience of the video clearly recognized this because the presentation of this video took another direction. Zuckerberg was in some posture, which could have been plausibly the sitting or standing position, which made him visually distinct from the real Zuckerberg. However, despite efforts to make the AI sound more human in the blinking part, there were striking differences in its mannerisms in general. Nevertheless, the voice mimicry was very accurate when it came to Zuckerberg&#8217;s unique voice pattern in terms of pitch and intonation. Still, the AI&#8217;s response lacked some necessary level of understanding. </p>



<p>To exemplify, in the challenge that required to describe Meta on the thread and 1 hashtag in 20 seconds using merely an emoji, AI Zuckerberg clearly and succinctly answered that meta globe emoji is shaping up the social ties of the future in the metaverse. Join us at it thumbs-up emoji. However, this type of reply highlighted the common,</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cryptocurrency market insights&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Digital awareness also extends to cryptocurrency interactions, where investors have observed major differences in market movement. As current evidence shows, large-scale acquirers, often called crypto whales, are on the verge of re-entering the market due to growing interest. They are also presumed to be aggressively stocking up with a medium—to long-term view, solely presuming that Bitcoin will surely pass the $100k mark in 2024. This group is speculated to be aggressively stocking up with a medium to long-term view, solely presuming that Bitcoin will surge past the $100k mark in 2024.</p>



<p>The insights were top-notch, and Benzinga has recently launched a limited promotional push with a $7.95 fee that gives access to superior cryptocurrency research, stock tips, and crypto-related articles. This decision is made while traditional cryptocurrency investment progression is being seen to be limited after bull runs in 2020 and 2021.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Technology and personality: Film the thin red line.</h2>



<p>The video and the way it is becoming popular appeal to the prospect of artificial media sharing people’s personal experiences. While AI technologies have come to the extent where authentic-sounding conversations and personalized interactions can substitute human ones, a distinct difference is still obvious, especially in terms of tons of imponderability remaining in human relationships, such as genuine emotions, spontaneous attitudes, and so on.</p>



<p>The act of the AI Zuckerberg hanging out in the TechnoCard game 2 Truths 1 Lie shows such a gap. Unlike natural human interaction, the method of interacting with the game seemed quite similar to how a chatbot will process such prompts and respond, leading with a reply of Okay, 2 Truths, and a Lie, here we go, which could only be attested to the computer program. With the development of AI, human and machine figures both continue to have boundaries that are more and more indistinct while at the same time becoming more exciting to see.</p>



<p> Furthermore, artificial intelligence is now used in media platforms, such as YouTube. Because AI plays a major role in entertainment and communication, we are called to think about its future role in every aspect of our lives, including posing questions about authenticity, privacy, and human interaction in the age of digitalization. However, while investors are noticing the crypto market&#8217;s growth, they still introduce this technology to the financial market and try to predict players&#8217; actions in the future.</p>



<p>This article originally appeared in <a href="https://www.benzinga.com/news/24/04/38350350/ai-mark-zuckerberg-more-robotic-than-real-life-version-have-a-quick-peek-and-decide-for-yourself" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Benzinga</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_AI_Version_of_Mark_Zuckerberg_Showcased_on_YouTube_An_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_AI_Version_of_Mark_Zuckerberg_Showcased_on_YouTube_An_0.jpg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
