<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
            <rss version = "2.0"
                xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
                xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
                xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
                xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
                xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
                <channel>
                    <title>News &#8211; Finance Magnates | Financial and business news</title>
<atom:link href="https://www.financemagnates.com//feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//</link>
<description></description>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 05:38:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator></generator>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Mastercard's Executive Shuffle: A Sign of Things to Come?]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/mastercards-executive-shuffle-a-sign-of-things-to-come/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/mastercards-executive-shuffle-a-sign-of-things-to-come/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/mastercards-executive-shuffle-a-sign-of-things-to-come</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.mastercard.com/news/press/2024/april/positioning-mastercard-for-the-next-era-of-growth/">Mastercard's recent
leadership shakeup</a> signals a potential shift in their strategic vision. The
appointments of Jorn Lambert, Raj Seshadri, and Craig Vosburg to newly defined
C-suite roles highlight Mastercard's focus on three key areas: core payments, commercial
expansion, and data-driven services. This strategic realignment could position
Mastercard to compete more effectively in <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/payment-reports-2024-and-the-race-for-the-perfect-payment-experience/">a rapidly evolving payments industry</a>.</p><p>Doubling
Down on Core Payments: Jorn Lambert's move to Chief Product
Officer signifies the continued importance of Mastercard's traditional business
– facilitating secure and efficient card transactions. This focus ensures they
stay competitive against rivals like Visa and emerging players in the global
payments network.</p><p>Expanding
the Commercial Landscape: Raj Seshadri's appointment as Chief
Commercial Payments Officer reflects Mastercard's ambition to broaden its reach
beyond consumer credit cards. By placing a dedicated leader in charge of B2B
payments, bill payments, and remittances, Mastercard signals its intent to
capture a larger share of the commercial payments market. This focus on
business-to-business transactions could be a significant growth driver in the
coming years.</p><p>Data
and AI Take Center Stage: The creation of a new data and AI
organization under Craig Vosburg, the Chief Services Officer, is a strong
indicator of Mastercard's strategic direction. By placing data and AI at the
heart of its service offerings, Mastercard is well-positioned to leverage its
vast transaction data to provide valuable insights and solutions for its
partners and customers. This focus on data-driven services could unlock new
revenue streams and differentiate Mastercard in a crowded marketplace.</p><p>Mastercard's
Long Game: CEO Michael Miebach's comments about "long-term
growth" and "diversifying revenue streams" suggest Mastercard is
playing the long game. The leadership changes and corporate restructuring aim
to position the company for sustained success in a dynamic financial
environment. Whether this strategic shift proves successful remains to be seen,
but Mastercard's focus on core payments, commercial expansion, and data-driven
services provides a clear roadmap for the future.</p><p>Open
Questions: While the realignment appears well-defined, some questions
remain. How will Mastercard balance its traditional focus on consumer payments
with its push into the commercial space? Can the company successfully integrate
data and AI into its services to create real value for its customers? The
answers to these questions will ultimately determine the success of
Mastercard's strategic vision.</p><p>One thing is certain:
Mastercard is making a bold move. The coming months and years will reveal
whether this leadership shuffle and strategic realignment propel Mastercard to
a position of dominance in the world of payments.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[How UPI's Disruption Paves the Way for India's Digital Payment Dominance]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/how-upis-disruption-paves-the-way-for-indias-digital-payment-dominance/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/how-upis-disruption-paves-the-way-for-indias-digital-payment-dominance/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/how-upis-disruption-paves-the-way-for-indias-digital-payment-dominance</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Forget plastic and
forget cash. In the heart of India's digital payment revolution, a battleground
is emerging – the war of the wallets. The Reserve Bank of India's (RBI) <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/wealth/save/upi-rule-change-soon-use-money-in-phonepe-amzonpay-wallet-to-pay-via-paytm-other-upi-apps-check-rbi-new-rule/articleshow/109197156.cms?from=mdr">recent
decision</a> to allow third-party UPI apps to access prepaid payment instruments
(PPIs) has ignited a firestorm of potential, and the fight for customer loyalty
is about to get fierce.</p><p>This isn't your typical
corporate clash. The combatants here are a diverse bunch – established giants
like Paytm, scrappy fintech startups, and even brick-and-mortar retailers with
their own loyalty programs. Until now, PPIs operated in closed gardens, forcing
users to stick to the app provided by the issuer. This fragmented landscape
stifled competition and limited the reach of digital payments, especially for
smaller transactions.</p><p>The RBI's move
dismantles these walls, throwing the doors wide open for innovation. It's much like your local coffee shop's loyalty card morphing into your go-to
payment method for online shopping. Or a small business owner seamlessly
integrating their existing PPI system with a user-friendly UPI app, attracting a
wider customer base. Suddenly, the possibilities for seamless and convenient
digital payments explode.</p><p>This isn't just about
convenience, it's about power. The dominance of giants like Paytm, with its
staggering $19.1 billion GMV in FY23, is under threat. Smaller players now have
a fighting chance, offering unique features and experiences to woo users. Competition
breeds choice, and consumers stand to benefit with a wider array of options and
potentially lower fees.</p><p>But the real prize lies
in financial inclusion. By removing the restriction to a single app, the RBI is
making digital payments more accessible for millions. Small businesses, often
reliant on cash transactions, can now tap into the digital ecosystem with ease.
Individuals new to the digital realm no longer face the hurdle of navigating a
specific PPI issuer's app. This inclusivity can be a game-changer, driving
financial empowerment and propelling India's ambition to become a digital
payments powerhouse.</p><p>However, the war won't
be won without casualties. Security concerns need to be addressed to ensure a
safe environment for transactions across different platforms. User experience
will also be a battleground – clunky interfaces and a lack of interoperability
can quickly turn customers away.</p><p>The RBI's decision is a
bold move, but the true test lies in execution. <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/digital-horizons-the-e-rupees-rise-amid-global-currency-debates/">Can India create a robust
infrastructure</a> that fosters healthy competition while prioritizing security and
user experience? The answer will determine the victor in the war of the wallets,
but the ultimate winner will be India itself, paving the way for a future where
digital payments become the norm, not the exception. This disruption has the
potential to not just reshape India's financial landscape, but act as a
blueprint for other developing economies looking to embrace the future of
money. The war drums are beating, and the world is watching. The Great Wallet
War has just begun.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Crypto's Coming Out Party: From Fringe to Familiar on the Streets of Lugano]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/cryptos-coming-out-party-from-fringe-to-familiar-on-the-streets-of-lugano/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/cryptos-coming-out-party-from-fringe-to-familiar-on-the-streets-of-lugano/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/cryptos-coming-out-party-from-fringe-to-familiar-on-the-streets-of-lugano</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Lugano, a picturesque
Swiss town nestled amidst dramatic mountains and glistening lakes, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/with-lugano-joinin-the-crypto-revolution-is-mass-adoption-imminent/">is on the
cusp of a financial revolution</a>. Forget quaint cafes and charming cobblestone
streets; the real buzz surrounds something far more disruptive: cryptocurrency.
This once fringe technology is shedding its shadowy reputation and stepping
into the bright lights of everyday transactions, not just in Lugano, but with
the potential to transform our global financial landscape.</p><p>Lugano isn't just
dipping its toes in the crypto pool; <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/martinrivers/2022/04/19/could-luganos-plan-b-bring-bitcoin-to-the-masses/">it's diving headfirst</a>. The city has
embraced cryptocurrencies like a long-lost friend, allowing residents to pay
for everything from lattes to taxes using digital tokens. This isn't some pilot
program cobbled together with duct tape and optimism. Lugano has partnered with
cryptocurrency exchange Bitfinex to create a robust infrastructure that
supports payments in Bitcoin, Tether, and even their very own local token,
LVGA. The early results are promising – over 15% of Lugano's citizens have
already incorporated crypto into their daily routines.</p><p>But why Lugano? Why now?
The answer lies in a perfect storm of necessity and opportunity. Switzerland,
with its reputation for innovation and a progressive approach to finance,
provided fertile ground for the seeds of crypto adoption to take root. Lugano,
a city eager to boost its economy and attract new residents, saw crypto as a
golden ticket. By embracing this new financial frontier, they've positioned
themselves at the forefront of a movement that could redefine how we pay for
everything.</p><p>Convenience, the
cornerstone of successful payment methods, is a hurdle crypto needs to clear.
While tech-savvy early adopters scoff at the clunky interfaces and slow
transaction times of traditional banking, the average citizen craves a seamless
experience. Lugano's success hinges on making crypto as effortless to use as
swiping a debit card. Here, the city's partnership with Bitfinex proves
crucial. The exchange has developed a user-friendly platform that streamlines
payments, allowing residents to pay with a simple QR code scan. This eliminates
the complexities often associated with crypto transactions, making it a more
palatable option for the everyday user.</p><p>The fear of the unknown
is another hurdle crypto must overcome. Decentralized currencies, free from the
oversight of traditional financial institutions, can feel unsettling to some.
Lugano's approach directly addresses this concern. By partnering with a reputable
exchange like Bitfinex, they've instilled a sense of trust and legitimacy in
the system. Residents know their hard-earned crypto is in safe hands, paving
the way for wider acceptance.</p><p>Of course, Lugano isn't
the only place where crypto is making inroads into the mainstream. Crypto
credit cards are gaining traction, allowing users to spend their digital
currency at any store that accepts traditional cards. Forward-thinking
companies like Microsoft and even Wikipedia are now welcoming Bitcoin payments.
These baby steps, coupled with the success story unfolding in Lugano, paint a
compelling picture of a future where crypto becomes a familiar face at the
checkout counter.</p><p>But crypto's ascent to
financial stardom won't be without its share of drama. Regulation, the bane of
many an innovation's existence, will undoubtedly play a role. Governments will
grapple with how to integrate this disruptive technology into the existing
financial framework. Finding the right balance between fostering innovation and
protecting consumers will be a delicate dance.</p><p>The road ahead for
crypto is paved with both promise and peril. Challenges abound, but the
potential rewards are undeniable. Cities like Lugano are proving that crypto
can be more than just a speculative asset class; it can become a practical tool
that transforms how we manage our money. As crypto sheds its cloak of obscurity
and ventures into the public square, one thing is certain: the way we pay for
our daily lives is on the cusp of a fascinating metamorphosis. Lugano may be
the stage for the opening act, but the global financial drama is just
beginning.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[OpenAI Targets Fortune 500 Executives with Customized AI Solutions]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/openai-targets-fortune-500-executives-with-customized-ai-solutions/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/openai-targets-fortune-500-executives-with-customized-ai-solutions/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 15:41:57 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Institutional FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/openai-targets-fortune-500-executives-with-customized-ai-solutions</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI recently hosted hundreds of top executives from
Fortune 500 companies in San Francisco, New York, and London to pitch AI
services, according to a report by Reuters. At the center of this pitch is an enterprise-grade version of OpenAI's chatbot. This
offering aims to address specific needs across industries, including finance,
healthcare, and energy. </p><p>OpenAI's Corporate Push</p><p>Notably, OpenAI has assured corporate customers that
their data remains secure and won't be used to train its models. OpenAI is leveraging its expertise in AI to tap into
the corporate sector in a bid to diversify revenue streams. The latest
marketing efforts aim to expand the firm's services to new markets.</p><p>While some executives questioned the need for
additional services from <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/openai/" target="_blank" rel="follow">OpenAI</a>, Altman and COO Brad Lightcap highlighted the
value of customized solutions and direct engagement with the OpenAI team. With a valuation of $86 billion, OpenAI is reportedly on a
trajectory to meet its revenue targets, fueled by the success of
ChatGPT and strategic expansions into corporate markets.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Exclusive: OpenAI's Altman pitches ChatGPT Enterprise to large firms, including some Microsoft customers <a href="https://t.co/Whj4rwEIfb">https://t.co/Whj4rwEIfb</a> <a href="https://t.co/qvTxKyuw87">pic.twitter.com/qvTxKyuw87</a></p>— Reuters (@Reuters) <a href="https://twitter.com/Reuters/status/1778771379367620749?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 12, 2024</a></blockquote><p>The company's enterprise offerings, including ChatGPT
Enterprise and the Sora video creation tool, are expected to play a significant
role in driving future growth and market dominance. Beyond corporates, OpenAI is targeting Hollywood with
video creation tools.  However, despite the opportunities presented by the new technology, there are concerns regarding the reliability and copyright implications of AI.</p><p>Navigating Growth and Uncertainty</p><p>Last year, Altman was <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/openais-ceo-drama-ends-with-sam-altman-back-in-charge/" target="_blank" rel="follow">reinstated as the CEO</a> of the
OpenAI following a tumultuous journey of resignation, job offers from
Microsoft, and, ultimately, a return to his former position. Altman reclaimed his role as the CEO of OpenAI. The
reinstatement followed three days of uncertainty, during which Altman's future
with the company hung in the balance. </p><p>Altman's departure from OpenAI sparked speculation
about his next move. Reports emerged that Microsoft had extended a job offer to Altman and several of his colleagues. The situation escalated as it became apparent that a significant portion of OpenAI's workforce were behind its CEO.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Revolut India Expands Offerings with RBI Approval for Payment Instruments]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/revolut-india-expands-offerings-with-rbi-approval-for-payment-instruments/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/revolut-india-expands-offerings-with-rbi-approval-for-payment-instruments/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 15:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/revolut-india-expands-offerings-with-rbi-approval-for-payment-instruments</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Revolut India has recently announced that it has received an
in-principle authorization from the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to issue
Prepaid Payment Instruments, including prepaid cards and wallets. This
development adds to the company's existing authorization to operate as an ADII,
with permissions granted by the RBI for issuing multi-currency forex cards and
providing cross-border remittances.</p><p>Revolut India Achieves Authorization from RBI</p><p>This authorization marks a milestone for Revolut India, as
it enables the company to offer both international and domestic payment
solutions to Indian consumers through a single platform. Expressing gratitude
towards the RBI for the opportunity to operate in India, Revolut India's CEO, Paroma
Chatterjee, noted the honour of being selected among the 17 entities granted
this license.</p><p>“Over the last two years, we have been tirelessly building
the Revolut experience - for India, in India. Being fully compliant with all
regulatory requirements is our top priority. India is the only market where
Revolut has therefore undertaken the massive task of localising the global
tech-stack, in order to comply with local regulations,” she added.</p><p>Anticipating the introduction of its services to Indian
customers, Revolut India aims to bring the global Revolut experience to the
Indian market gradually. With over 175,000 prospective customers already on the
waitlist, the company looks forward to catering to the needs of Indian
consumers.</p><p>Revolut Expands with Banking License Approval in Mexico</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/revolut-gains-banking-licence-in-mexico-eyes-the-remittance-market/">Revolut
has expanded its operations by obtaining a banking license in Mexico</a>,
allowing it to establish itself as a bank in Latin America, as reported by <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/">Finance Magnates</a>. The approval from
Comisión Nacional Bancaria y de Valores enables Revolut to offer a wide range
of financial products and services to Mexican users. </p><p>The company plans to focus on cross-border remittances,
leveraging Mexico's lucrative market, where remittances reached a record $63.3
billion in 2023, predominantly from the United States. Additionally, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/revolut/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Revolut</a>
holds a banking license in the European Economic Area, granted by the central
bank of Lithuania, while operating with a payments institution license in the
UK as it awaits processing of its banking license application there.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Taurex's Head of LATAM Jeffrey Navarro Announces Departure]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/taurexs-head-of-latam-jeffrey-navarro-announces-departure/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/taurexs-head-of-latam-jeffrey-navarro-announces-departure/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 14:17:13 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/taurexs-head-of-latam-jeffrey-navarro-announces-departure</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jeffrey Navarro, the Head of LATAM (Latin America) at
Taurex, announced his departure from the company today (Friday). Navarro, who
has served in Taurex's operations in the Latin American region, conveyed his gratitude
to his colleagues and the company in a farewell message.</p><p>Announcing Departure and Career Transition</p><p>Expressing his sentiments on LinkedIn, Navarro marked the
occasion as his final day at Taurex, indicating his transition to a new
professional chapter. He shared: "Today marks my last day at Taurex. I
will now be another member of the company's worldwide fans cheering from
afar." </p><p>He expressed his gratitude to the entire <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/taurex/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Taurex</a> team,
emphasizing the exceptional resilience and excellence of the Taurex LATAM team,
which he regarded as among the top performers in the region.</p><p>Navarro held the position of Head of LATAM at Taurex for
over 2 years. Prior to this role, he served as the Regional Manager for LATAM
&amp; Spain at Tickmill for approximately 3 years. Preceding his tenure at
Tickmill, he worked as an Account Manager for Spain &amp; Latin America at
AxiCorp for over 2 years. Additionally, Navarro gained valuable experience as a
Business Development Manager at Fotrad LTD for approximately 3 years.</p><p>Zenfinex Rebrands to Taurex, Closes $15M Series B Funding</p><p>The Zenfinex Group now rebranded its retail arm to Taurex, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/brokers/excessive-zenfinex-group-secures-15-million-to-propel-proprietary-tech/">recently
closed its Series B funding round</a>, securing $15 million led by Oscar Hilt
Tatum IV, as reported by <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/">Finance
Magnates</a>. Operating as Taurex for B2C and Zenfinex for B2B, the company
plans to bolster its proprietary technology with the investment, including a
mobile app and web platform slated for release in 2024. </p><p>Besides technology, funds will support team expansion,
regulatory compliance, and marketing efforts. This round follows a $5 million
Series A led by Tatum IV. Originally a UK-based boutique brokerage, Taurex now
operates across multiple jurisdictions, experiencing significant revenue growth
but remaining at a loss due to substantial technology investments.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[XTX Markets to Boost Trading Capacity with Mega Data Center in Finland]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/xtx-markets-to-boost-trading-capacity-with-mega-data-center-in-finland/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/xtx-markets-to-boost-trading-capacity-with-mega-data-center-in-finland/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 13:41:28 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/xtx-markets-to-boost-trading-capacity-with-mega-data-center-in-finland</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The online trading firm XTX Markets plans to build a
substantial data center in Finland. This decision marks a significant departure
from the prevailing trend among financial institutions, which typically opt to
outsource their IT needs to major technology firms in Silicon Valley. </p><p>According to the Financial Times, The London-based
market maker will construct a data center with a 250-megawatt capacity in
Finland's Kajaani District. The first phase of this facility will be equipped
with computing capabilities totaling 22.5MW. </p><p>Strategic Nordic Location</p><p>XTX's decision to establish its data center in the
Nordic country is due to the affordable electricity and the cool climatic
conditions in the region. The Nordic countries have emerged as favorable destinations for
hosting data because there is less need for extensive cooling systems.</p><p>XTX's move to build its own data center reflects
the firm's decision to maintain autonomy over its technological infrastructure.
This approach contrasts with competitors like Citadel Securities, which have
opted to use the cloud services of companies like Google for data storage and
algorithm testing.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/5YALU6qrQK">https://t.co/5YALU6qrQK</a></p>— XTX Markets (@xtxmarkets) <a href="https://twitter.com/xtxmarkets/status/1778743261915464123?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 12, 2024</a></blockquote><p>XTX Markets relies heavily on processing power to
execute its algorithmic trading strategies. The company reportedly uses 25,000
graphics processing units (GPUs) computational resources to drive its
operations.</p><p>Joshua Leahy, XTX's Chief Technology Officer, told the FT that the company secured the Kajaani site to boost its computing capacity. In Europe, data center space is limited, with demand surpassing supply. The market maker already operates a supercomputer based in Iceland.</p><p>Exploring New Technology</p><p>In February, XTX Markets unveiled an AI program aimed at
advancing research in algorithmic trading by merging finance with AI technology. The initiative, situated in New York City, promised to be a hub for
the exploration of opportunities at the intersection of finance and machine
learning.</p><p>The AI Residency Program, spearheaded by XTY Labs, offers
two categories: Junior AI Residents and Senior AI Residents. These residents
undertake research projects spanning 6 to 12 months. The focus of the
program is to develop machine learning algorithms for the financial sector.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[FMAS:24 Session Spotlight – Strategies for Trading Mastery: Pitfalls & Solutions]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmas24-session-spotlight-strategies-for-trading-mastery-pitfalls-solutions/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmas24-session-spotlight-strategies-for-trading-mastery-pitfalls-solutions/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 11:26:07 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Patterson]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[FM-Events]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmas24-session-spotlight-strategies-for-trading-mastery-pitfalls-solutions</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The countdown to Finance Magnates Africa Summit (FMAS:24) is underway, with a little over one month to go until the premium event of the year. Now in its second year, FMAS:24 will once again be held in Sandton City, South Africa on May 20-22. Ahead of the event, prospective participants can familiarize themselves with some agenda highlights, featuring an extensive focus on the retail trading space.</p><p>As the year’s largest and most anticipated event in Africa, FMAS:24 will be eying a record attendance and engagement. This means more traders, brokers, brands, and attendees than ever before, coupled with an expanded content track.</p><p>Of particular note for attendees will be the launch of a second content stage, Trader Zone, dedicated to retail traders, a growing demographic at FMAS:24. This dynamic stage is the perfect hub for both new and existing traders, each of whom can learn from the industry’s most well-known talent, experts, and marquee traders.</p><p>This includes the upcoming session Strategies for Trading Mastery: Pitfalls &amp; Solutions. Prospective attendees are encouraged to explore the <a href="https://events.financemagnates.com/event/aad8d48a-17e5-426c-8e9f-8faedd80b023/websitePage:64aa44de-1e95-4947-b236-0f4f3191a96a">live agenda</a> as it takes shape.</p><p>Whether this is your first FM event or you are a regular, attendees can expect to network, connect, and meet the following participants: </p><ul><li>     Forex/CFD Brokers</li><li>Institutional Brokers</li><li>Affiliates &amp; IBs</li><li>Traders &amp; Investors</li><li>Educators &amp; Market Experts</li><li>Fintech &amp; Payments Brands</li><li>     Crypto &amp; Digital Assets Businesses</li><li>     Technology &amp; Liquidity Providers</li><li>     Press/Media</li><li>     Regulators</li><li>     Start-ups</li><li>     Investors/VCs</li></ul><p>With nearly one month to go, make sure to  head on over to FMAS:24 registration page and <a href="https://events.financemagnates.com/event/aad8d48a-17e5-426c-8e9f-8faedd80b023/regProcessStep1">sign-up today</a>! Registering online ensures you can skip the wait and queues on-site, giving you more time to enjoy the event.</p><p>Master Trading at FMAS:24</p><p>Online trading is a huge area of focus in Africa in 2024, characterized by strong growth, a large pool of potential traders, and interest from brokers in the region. FMAS:24 will be examining the space throughout the event via big-name speakers, talent, and more.</p><p>The event features an impressive lineup of panel sessions, workshops, seminars, and more, all devoted to this sphere, part of a two-day content track. This includes the notable session, Strategies for Trading Mastery: Pitfalls &amp; Solutions, which will take place on May 22, 15:30-15:50 at the Trader Zone.</p><p>Featuring Elsy Rayess, Chief Business Development Officer at FxPro, the session, will dive into the top mistakes that traders make. Additional consideration and emphasis will be spent on providing participants with actionable strategies to overcome them. </p><p><a href="https://events.financemagnates.com/event/aad8d48a-17e5-426c-8e9f-8faedd80b023/regProcessStep1" target="_blank">Register Today for the Biggest Event of the Year in Africa!</a></p><p>Whether just embarking on a trading journey or looking to refine any existing strategies, Ms. Rayess will go through the main pitfalls traders face and equip each of these individuals with essential know-hows and the mindset to excel.</p><p>This session is geared for traders of all experience levels, helping set a nice baseline for success and what to avoid. Join Ms. Rayess as she empowers traders with key strategies moving forward, bringing actionable insight from one of the largest brokers in the region. </p><p>Face-to-Face Networking Opportunities </p><p>FMAS:24 is all about networking and engagement. This means all attendees can connect, interact, and speak face-to-face with other participants and the most reliable brands in the industry. For newer traders looking to make a splash, this is the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fm-events/fmas24-session-spotlight-hfcopy-your-guide-to-copy-trading-success/" target="_blank" rel="follow">ideal opportunity</a> to build trust.</p><p>Overall, the event looks to explore a total of four distinct tracks such as the online trading, blockchain &amp; digital assets, fintech, and payments sphere. Look for FMAS:24 to build on last year’s impressive numbers, seeking upwards of 3,000 attendees, 120 exhibitors, 150 speakers, and more.</p><p>This is one event where attendees can expect anything the exhibition floor over two days. See you in Sandton City this May!</p>

This article was written by Jeff Patterson at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[eToro UK Concludes Directorship of Shalom Berkovitz after Seven Years]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/director-shakeup-etoro-terminates-shalom-berkovitzs-appointment/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/director-shakeup-etoro-terminates-shalom-berkovitzs-appointment/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 10:08:05 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executives]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//executives/director-shakeup-etoro-terminates-shalom-berkovitzs-appointment</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>eToro (UK) Limited has concluded the appointment of one of
its directors, Shalom Berkovitz. After 7 years at eToro and 30 years of
working, Berkovitz retired at the end of February 2023. He continues to act as
a director of a number of the eToro Group's subsidiaries.</p><p>Highlights of Leadership
Roles before eToro</p><p>Prior to joining eToro, Berkovitz held executive positions,
including CEO at DSNR Media Group for 5 years, CEO at d-Group for 3 years, CFO
at Golden Pages Israel for 2 years, and VP of Economics and Business
Development at Eurocom Communications for 9 years.</p><p>Expanding Reach with Key Appointments and Approvals</p><p>eToro has made strategic moves to bolster its operations in
key regions, appointing seasoned professionals to key positions and securing
 regulatory approval.</p><p>In France, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/etoro-appoints-ins-de-dinechin-as-special-adviser-in-france/">Inès
de Dinechin has joined eToro as a Special Adviser</a>, leveraging her extensive
boardroom experience from roles at Quintet Private Bank and Bank of America
Europe DAC. Dinechin will collaborate closely with eToro's management and the
local French team, led by Emmanuel Sackman, to drive the company's growth
strategy forward.</p><p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/executives/etoros-expansion-in-italy-new-regional-manager-takes-the-helm/">eToro
is strengthening its presence in Italy by promoting Massimo Citoni</a> to the
role of Regional Manager. With a background that includes starting as an
Account Manager in 2015 and rising to Head of the Italian Desk in 2023, Citoni
is well-equipped to fortify eToro's position in Italy. His focus will be on
building strategic partnerships, overseeing marketing efforts, and enhancing
customer retention to elevate the experience for Italian clients and eToro Club
members.</p><p>On the regulatory front, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/etoro-solidifies-mena-strategy-with-abu-dhabi-license/">eToro
has received approval from the Abu Dhabi Global Market</a> to operate as
a broker dealing in securities, derivatives, and crypto assets in the United
Arab Emirates. This approval marks a significant milestone in eToro's global
expansion efforts, with the CEO, Yoni Assia, expressing enthusiasm about Abu Dhabi's
burgeoning reputation as a fintech hub.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[$41 Million Crypto Investment Scheme Collapses in Australia]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/41-million-crypto-investment-scheme-collapses-in-australia/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/41-million-crypto-investment-scheme-collapses-in-australia/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 07:35:52 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/41-million-crypto-investment-scheme-collapses-in-australia</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In Australia, a massive cryptocurrency investment scheme involving approximately US$41 million and over 450 investors has collapsed. The country’s financial market regulator successfully obtained a court order to appoint receivers for the digital currency assets held by a group of three crypto mining companies, collectively known as NGS Companies, and their sole directors.</p><p>Bust of a Crypto Investment Scheme</p><p>The court order, issued on Wednesday, was part of the civil proceedings initiated by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC) against NGS Crypto Pty Ltd, NGS Digital Pty Ltd, and NGS Group Ltd, along with their respective sole directors Brett Mendham, Ryan Brown, and Mark Ten Caten.</p><p>Additionally, the court has restricted Mendham from traveling outside Australia.</p><p>NGS Companies offered investment packages supported by their <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/crypto-miner-sells-data-center-for-61m-as-its-shares-plunge-55-in-2024/">cryptocurrency mining activities</a>. These packages guaranteed fixed-rate returns as high as 16 percent annually, according to the company's website, with a minimum fixed return promised at 6 percent.</p><p>The regulator highlighted that the schemes particularly encouraged investors to transfer funds from regulated superannuation funds to self-managed super funds (SMSFs), which were then converted into cryptocurrency. The promotional material on the company’s website, including “testimonials” and “stories,” seemed to specifically target elderly investors.</p><p>Regulator Gets Wary</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/aussie-court-orders-cfds-broker-prospero-markets-to-shut-down-appoints-liquidators/">ASIC's </a>action was prompted by concerns that the invested funds in these cryptocurrency schemes were at risk of dissipation. Notably, none of the three implicated companies possessed the necessary financial services licenses to operate legally in Australia. ASIC is now holding them accountable for illegally marketing crypto mining-backed investment products.</p><p>“Australians who choose to self-manage their superannuation should carefully consider the risks before using their SMSF to invest in crypto-related investment products such as blockchain mining,” advised Joe Longo, the Chair of ASIC. “These proceedings should also serve as a warning to the crypto industry that ASIC will continue to scrutinize products to ensure compliance with regulatory obligations and to protect consumers.”</p><p>Earlier this year, the Australian regulator <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/australian-regulator-clamp-down-on-super-fund-scam-and-unlicensed-crypto-services/">dismantled similar crypto-backed schemes</a> that promised astronomical profits and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/regulation/8-million-loss-instead-of-150-profit-crypto-fund-director-banned/">banned a director of a crypto fund for dishonest operations</a>.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[CFDs Broker Axi Maintains Sports Presence: Extends Deal with Top Brazilian Football Club]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/cfds-broker-axi-maintains-sports-presence-extends-deal-with-top-brazilian-football-club/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/cfds-broker-axi-maintains-sports-presence-extends-deal-with-top-brazilian-football-club/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 06:31:03 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Brokers]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/cfds-broker-axi-maintains-sports-presence-extends-deal-with-top-brazilian-football-club</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Australia-headquartered Axi has seen the value in sports sponsorship and has extended its existing deal with the Brazilian football club Esporte Clube Bahia. Announced today (Friday), the renewal will extend the partnership between the two for the 2024 season.</p><p>Axi Sees Value in Football Deals</p><p>The forex and contracts for differences (CFDs) broker first secured its <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/brokers/axi-inks-sponsorship-deal-with-brazilian-football-club-bahia/">sponsorship deal with the Brazilian football club</a> in May last year. Under the agreement, the broker has gained the status of an Official Online Trading Partner of the football club, a standard title for such sports deals.</p><p>Additionally, the Axi branding appears on several physical and digital infrastructures of the football club. However, neither the broker nor the football club disclosed the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/the-skys-the-limit-the-cost-for-brokers-to-turn-clubs-into-cfds-partners/">financial details of the deal</a>.</p><blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C5m1NaVN1Qh/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"><p>View this post on Instagram</p><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C5m1NaVN1Qh/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank">A post shared by Esporte Clube Bahia (@ecbahia)</a></p></blockquote><p>“We are very excited about this renewal, which has been in development for some time,” said Hanah Hill, Axi’s Head of Brand and Sponsorship. “When we initiated this collaboration in 2023, we had no idea how receptive the Bahia fans would be. As we move forward into a new season, our commitment to bringing the worlds of trading and football closer together remains unchanged.”</p><p>A Top Brazilian Football Club</p><p>Esporte Clube Bahia, founded in 1991 in the capital of the Brazilian state of Bahia, plays in the top domestic league, Campeonato Brasileiro Série A. The club's home stadium, Arena Fonte Nova, has a capacity of about 48,000.</p><p>The club also has a substantial reach on social media, with 1.5 million followers on Instagram, 1.6 million followers on X (formerly Twitter), and 1.1 million followers on Facebook. In comparison, Axi's official Instagram handle has about 29,800 followers.</p><p>Sponsoring Bahia was an extremely strategic business decision for Axi. The broker is also a sponsor of English football club giant Manchester City, which owns 90 percent of Bahia. Additionally, the Aussie broker's focus on sports marketing channels became highlighted when it secured a <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/axi-solidifies-latam-presence-as-girona-fcs-first-regional-sponsor/">third sports deal with the Spanish football club Girona FC</a>.</p><p>“Helping our traders and clients unlock their trading potential is fundamental to us, and through our collaboration with Bahia, we hope to continue growing awareness in the LATAM region, while continuing to offer unforgettable football moments to our traders and partners,” added Hill.</p><p>Meanwhile, the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/exclusive-crypto-cfds-on-axi-jumps-60-in-march-nears-17-billion/">cryptocurrency CFDs trading volume on Axi reached $16.7 billion in March</a>, a 60 percent increase from the previous month, Finance Magnates reported exclusively. The demand soared as about 25 percent of the broker’s active client base traded crypto CFDs last month.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Sam Bankman-Fried Appeals Conviction Only 2 Weeks after Sentencing]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/sam-bankman-fried-appeals-conviction-only-2-weeks-after-sentencing/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/sam-bankman-fried-appeals-conviction-only-2-weeks-after-sentencing/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 05:36:22 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/sam-bankman-fried-appeals-conviction-only-2-weeks-after-sentencing</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sam Bankman-Fried, the Founder and former CEO of the collapsed FTX, has challenged his conviction and sentencing for conspiracy and fraud by filing an appeal in court yesterday (Thursday). The appeal was filed just hours before the deadline.</p><p>SBF Appealed</p><p>Earlier, the judge had ordered Bankman-Fried to be remanded to a low or medium-security prison in Northern California. This facility is near his parents’ house, and the judge cited concerns for his security at a maximum-security prison due to his autism. Interestingly, during his trial and while awaiting sentencing, Bankman-Fried had requested to be kept in the notorious Manhattan Detention Center. Previously, he was an inmate at the Metropolitan Detention Center in Brooklyn.</p><p>The appeal came two weeks after a US court <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/breaking-sam-bankman-fried-sentenced-for-25-years-in-prison/">sentenced him to 25 years in prison</a>, along with three years of supervised release. He is also required to forfeit $11 billion.</p><p>Billionaire to Convict</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/sam-bankman-fried/">Bankman-Fried</a> was once regarded as the messiah of the cryptocurrency world, known for his altruistic vision, signature T-shirt, and shorts outfit. He became one of the youngest self-made billionaires through his FTX empire, which collapsed overnight following the discovery of his dubious business practices.</p><p>After a high-profile trial, Bankman-Fried was <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/ftx-trial-sam-bankman-fried-found-guilty-of-all-7-criminal-charges/">convicted last November on multiple charges</a>, including wire fraud and conspiracy to commit wire fraud and money laundering. Although the total maximum prison time for all the convictions could amount to 115 years, the prosecutors were seeking 40 to 50 years. Bankman-Fried’s legal team requested six-and-a-half years, but the court ultimately sentenced him to 25 years.</p><p>During the trial, several close associates of Bankman-Fried testified against him. They all pleaded guilty to their roles in the shady operations at FTX and are now awaiting sentencing.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Charles Schwab Diversifies Offerings with Futures and Forex Trading]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/schwab-diversifies-offerings-with-futures-and-forex-trading/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/schwab-diversifies-offerings-with-futures-and-forex-trading/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 19:50:08 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/schwab-diversifies-offerings-with-futures-and-forex-trading</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Charles Schwab has integrated futures and forex trading into
its thinkorswim platform. This expansion marks the debut of forex trading
within Schwab's ecosystem with the aim of boosting the platform's derivatives trading.
With these new offerings, Schwab aims to provide traders with a range of
investment opportunities and risk management tools.</p><p>James Kostulias, the Managing Director and Head of
Trading Services at Charles Schwab mentioned: "Adding these capabilities
builds upon an already strong offer for traders, and in particular,
derivatives traders, which includes the thinkorswim platforms, Schwab's
trading capabilities on Schwab.com, and Schwab Mobile."</p><p>Schwab Unveils New Opportunities</p><p>Previously available only through its StreetSmart
platforms, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/futures/" target="_blank" rel="follow">futures</a> trading enables traders to speculate on the future price
movements of commodities or indices. With access to a variety of futures
contracts, traders can now diversify their portfolios and capitalize on
opportunities around the clock, the company mentioned.</p><p>The introduction of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/f/forex/" target="_blank" rel="follow">forex</a> trading at Schwab is a
significant milestone for the company. With over 65 tradable currency pairs
available on the thinkorswim platform, the new offering allows traders to hedge
against currency and interest rate risks, as well as geopolitical events.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Schwab clients are already deeply engaged with thinkorswim since it became available to them last fall, and with futures and forex trading along with portfolio margin now available on the platforms, we are ideally positioned to welcome the final group... <a href="https://t.co/BVRCmjJgWT">https://t.co/BVRCmjJgWT</a></p>— Jared Kirui (@JaredLopta79285) <a href="https://twitter.com/JaredLopta79285/status/1778519658708316331?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 11, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Schwab has committed to providing support from <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/f/forex/" class="terms__main-term" id="6faa6714-7f7b-4d23-b1c5-c0d40807d613">forex</a>
specialists 24/5, with commission-free trading and built-in educational
resources. Another key addition to Schwab's thinkorswim platform is portfolio
margin.</p><p>According to the press release, portfolio margin is an
alternative calculation method for determining <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/m/margin-requirements/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="ce1e536c-768f-44fd-ba84-7bff3f643ea9">margin requirements</a>. Unlike
traditional margin calculations, this method considers the risk of an entire
portfolio rather than individual positions.</p><p>Enhancing Retail Trading</p><p>Last year, Charles Schwab and TD Ameritrade <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/charles-schwab-and-ameritrade-collaborate-on-retail-trader-focused-platform/" target="_blank" rel="follow">partnered to launch a retail trading platform</a> named "Schwab Trading Powered
by Ameritrade." This platform features educational resources and
specialized services for retail traders.</p><p>Speaking about the launch, Kostulias said: "Schwab Trading Powered by Ameritrade is
much more than just the merging of great trading functionality that already
existed at Schwab and TD Ameritrade. It's a super-charged, holistic retail
trading experience that surpasses its predecessors and makes Schwab the clear
destination for trading."</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[OPZ Token Presale: 96% of Stage 1 Sold, Launched World's First AI Powered Wallet & DEX]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/opz-token-presale-96-of-stage-1-sold-launched-worlds-first-ai-powered-wallet-dex/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/opz-token-presale-96-of-stage-1-sold-launched-worlds-first-ai-powered-wallet-dex/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/opz-token-presale-96-of-stage-1-sold-launched-worlds-first-ai-powered-wallet-dex</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">OPZ Token ($OPZ) is an all-in-one solution that integrates a wallet on iOS &amp; Android, decentralized exchange, advanced AI trading, and NFC technology. It offers 1,000,000,000 tokens for traders. Employing ERC-20, this token utilizes sophisticated AI trading technology to manage users' trades efficiently. Traders buy and hold the tokens, allowing the AI system to continuously trade across 10,000+ cryptocurrencies, including Bitcoin, Ethereum, Solana, etc.</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ-AI: AI Analysis</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ Token leverages blockchain technology and advanced Artificial Intelligence (AI) to expedite and secure transactions. The team champions the fusion of AI with cryptocurrency, emphasizing its capacity to analyze data, anticipate trends, and autonomously execute buy or sell decisions based on market patterns and price predictions.</p><p class="MsoNormal">The synergy between AI and blockchain in cryptocurrencies forms a formidable alliance. Blockchain ensures security and transparency, while AI aids consumers in making educated decisions regarding cryptocurrency trading. Together, they boost the efficiency and risk awareness in trading.</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ-AI revolutionizes cryptocurrency analysis by delivering exhaustive, real-time insights and trend analyses for over 10,000 coins.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Participating in the OPZ Token Presale is simple. Prices start at $0.028, with the launch price at $0.1.</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ Wallet</p><p class="MsoNormal">The OPZ Wallet meets the increasing demand for an intuitive and secure self-custodial solution in the cryptocurrency domain. Utilizing the innovative KeyFusion protocol, a Multi-Party Computation (MPC) technology variant, the OPZ Wallet merges top-notch security features with intelligent, AI-powered insights, providing a self-custody experience.</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ-DEX: Revolutionizing Bitcoin DeFi</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ-DEX introduces a pioneering platform for decentralized trading that capitalizes on the robustness of Bitcoin's Layer 2. It integrates the Chronicle Matching Engine for high-performance, low-latency trading and adopts Zero-Knowledge Rollups to boost transaction throughput and privacy.</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ Token: Revolutionizing DeFi with Advanced AI Integration</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ Token marks a significant advancement in cryptocurrency. It combines a supercharged wallet and exchange with advanced AI technology. OPZ is well-positioned to gain a substantial share of the rapidly growing DeFi market.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Moving forward, OPZ Token aims to push the boundaries of technological innovation while empowering users and driving positive transformations.</p><p class="MsoNormal">About OPZ</p><p class="MsoNormal">OPZ's (https://www.opz.com) mission is to accelerate the transition to self-ownership of assets by bridging the gap between the cryptocurrency industry and the traditional financial world.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[The Great APP Heist: Rethinking Responsibility in a Digital Age of Deception]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-great-app-heist-rethinking-responsibility-in-a-digital-age-of-deception/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-great-app-heist-rethinking-responsibility-in-a-digital-age-of-deception/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-great-app-heist-rethinking-responsibility-in-a-digital-age-of-deception</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Wild West wasn't
tamed by pronouncements; it was wrangled by sheriffs with grit and a
six-shooter. The online frontier, however, seems content with pronouncements,
leaving the digital equivalent of tumbleweeds – authorized push payment (APP)
fraud – to roll unchecked. Until now. New regulations in the UK aim to be the
posse riding into town, but will they be enough to truly corral this cyber
cattle rustle?</p><p>APP fraud thrives on a
simple deception: tricking victims into authorizing payments to fraudsters.
It's a confidence trick for the digital age, and just like their historical
counterparts, these online swindlers prey on trust and exploit vulnerabilities.
The fallout, however, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/retail-hemorrhage-global-fraud-eats-429-billion-while-consumers-take-a-beating/">transcends the individual</a>. It erodes confidence in the
very systems that underpin our digital interactions.</p><p>The UK's new regulations
are a response to this erosion. </p><p>Previously, a voluntary code offered some
protection, but it was akin to a town marshal with a single-shot derringer –
limited in scope and effectiveness. <a href="https://www.thomsonreuters.com/en-us/posts/investigation-fraud-and-risk/app-fraud-uk/">The new rules, coming into effect this October</a>,
are a legislative six-shooter. They mandate reimbursement for victims of APP
fraud, placing the onus on payment service providers (PSPs) to act as digital
sheriffs, responsible for identifying and stopping the heist before it happens,
or reimbursing the victim if they fail.</p><p>This shift in
responsibility is significant.</p><p> Previously, the onus often fell on the victim to
prove they weren't somehow complicit in their own defrauding, much like in a Wild
West scenario where the bank, upon discovering a stolen sack of gold, demanded
the depositor explain why they weren't more vigilant in guarding it. The new
regulations dismantle this skewed logic. They recognize the inherent power
imbalance between a sophisticated fraudster and an unsuspecting victim
navigating the complexities of online transactions.</p><p>The success of these
regulations hinges on two key factors: robust fraud detection by PSPs and a
clear definition of "consumer standard of caution." The former
demands a proactive approach from PSPs. </p><p>Gone are the days of reactive measures
– deploying technology and human expertise to identify and flag suspicious
transactions before the money leaves the victim's account. The latter, the
"consumer standard of caution," is a delicate dance. It must be
stringent enough to deter negligence while remaining flexible enough to
acknowledge the realities of human fallibility, particularly when dealing with
vulnerable customers.</p><p>The UK's approach isn't
a silver bullet. </p><p>Just as the Wild West still had its share of outlaws after the
sheriffs arrived, online fraudsters will undoubtedly adapt their tactics.
However, these regulations represent a critical step forward. They move the conversation
from victim-blaming to proactive security. They incentivize PSPs to invest in
robust defenses, ultimately fostering a more secure online ecosystem for
everyone.</p><p>This isn't just a UK
story. The rise of APP fraud is a global phenomenon. The UK's approach serves
as a test case, a potential model for other countries grappling with the same
issue. Will it be enough? Only time will tell. But one thing is certain: the digital
frontier demands a new kind of law enforcement, one that understands the
complexities of online deception and is equipped to protect citizens in this
new virtual landscape.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[The Data Highway: Open Banking and the Road Less Traveled in American Payments]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-data-highway-open-banking-and-the-road-less-traveled-in-american-payments/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-data-highway-open-banking-and-the-road-less-traveled-in-american-payments/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pedro Ferreira]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/the-data-highway-open-banking-and-the-road-less-traveled-in-american-payments</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>American consumers,
accustomed to cruising down the well-paved highway of credit card payments,
enjoy a smooth ride filled with loyalty program points and convenient one-click
purchases. But <a href="https://www.capgemini.com/insights/research-library/payments-top-trends-2024/">new on-ramps are emerging</a> and Open Banking, a seemingly uncharted
road, is promising a more direct and potentially more efficient journey.</p><p>Open Banking, much like
a high-speed rail system bypassing congested tollbooths, <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/financial-services/our-insights/the-role-of-us-open-banking-in-catalyzing-the-adoption-of-a2a-payments">facilitates
Account-to-Account (A2A) payments</a>. Consumers can transfer funds directly from
their bank accounts to a merchant's account, bypassing the card networks and
their associated fees. This holds the potential for a smoother ride for both
merchants, who can potentially reduce their transaction costs, and consumers,
who may benefit from lower prices or special A2A-only discounts.</p><p>However, the American
consumer, comfortable in their high-occupancy vehicles (credit cards) and
accustomed to the familiar rewards program exits, may not be easily persuaded
to switch lanes.</p><p>Insights from the Worldpay Global Payments Report 2024:</p><p>Sponsored by the World
Bank and other key players, <a href="https://corporate.worldpay.com/news-releases/news-release-details/worldpay-global-payments-report-2024-digital-wallet-maturity">the Worldpay Global Payments Report 2024</a> highlights the growing popularity of A2A payments.
Back in 2022, only half of the jury members predicted A2A networks and mobile
money would compete with cards within five years. However, just two years later,
the picture has changed dramatically. Over two-thirds of jurors now believe A2A
and mobile money will be the fastest-growing retail payment methods in their
home markets. This trend is particularly pronounced in the Global South
(Africa, Middle East, South America, Asia Pacific), where card networks haven't
established a dominant position. Here, only 13% see cards holding sway, while
54% predict A2A or mobile money taking the lead. Existing examples like
Brazil's PIX, which surpassed credit and debit card market share in 2023,
showcase this trend's potency.</p><p>The Global North
presents a more nuanced picture. Here, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidbirch/2024/04/10/the-verdict-a2a-payments-will-be-huge-in-the-global-north-and-south/">expert opinions are divided</a> between
cards and the A2A/mobile money combination. While A2A payments have gained
traction in Europe (Poland's Blik, Netherlands' IDEAL, Sweden's Swish), some
experts believe cards will retain dominance. However, a third of jurors foresee
ongoing competition with no clear winner.</p><p>The
Driving Forces:</p><p>Several factors are
fueling the rise of A2A payments:</p><ul><li>Open Banking: Open Banking
     regulations allow third-party providers to access customer financial data
     with consent, facilitating A2A transactions.</li><li>Instant Payments: The rise of
     instant payment networks enables faster and more efficient A2A transfers.</li><li>Strong
     Authentication: Improved authentication methods enhance security and consumer trust
     in A2A transactions.</li></ul><p>Potential
Benefits:</p><ul><li>Lower Transaction
     Costs: A2A payments generally involve lower fees compared to card
     transactions, potentially benefiting both businesses and consumers.</li><li>Improved Customer
     Journeys: Streamlined checkout processes and in-app payments can enhance the
     customer experience.</li><li>Greater Consumer
     Choice: A2A payments offer consumers an alternative to traditional payment
     methods, fostering competition and innovation.</li></ul><p>Industry
Response:</p><p>The rise of A2A has
spurred action from key players. Even in North America, where cards reign
supreme, <a href="https://b2b.mastercard.com/news-and-insights/blog/a2a-payment-trends-risks-and-fraud-solutions/">companies are taking notice</a>. McKinsey highlights the potential for A2A
to offer banks a "more competitive way of making payments" while
providing consumers and merchants with more options. Visa and Mastercard are
investing in A2A plays, and TrueLayer's new A2A payments app allows merchants
to integrate A2A options into their checkout processes.</p><p>Conclusion:</p><p>Open Banking and A2A
payments represent a significant shift in the global payments landscape. While
the pace of adoption may differ across regions, the potential for A2A to become
a mainstream payment method is undeniable. As the technology matures and consumer
trust grows, A2A payments have the potential to revolutionize the way we pay,
fostering a more transparent, efficient, and rewarding financial ecosystem.</p><p>Yet, the revolution
faces a more significant obstacle: the inertia of established infrastructure.
</p><p>Change, particularly when it involves money, is often met with resistance.
Drivers, accustomed to the ease of swiping plastic, may be hesitant to navigate
a new and potentially unfamiliar road system as it would be like asking drivers to switch
from their favorite, well-lit highway to a less-traveled backroad – a more
direct route, perhaps, but lacking the familiar rest stops and roadside
attractions.</p><p>The battle for the
future of payments in America is not a race to a single destination, but a
reimagining of the entire transportation network. </p><p> Consumers, enticed
by <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/beyond-transactions-crafting-value-in-a2a-dynamics/">the promise of a more personalized and potentially cheaper experience</a>, could
become the loyal riders. But the established card networks, the seasoned
highway authorities of the financial landscape, will not relinquish their
control easily. They will unleash their marketing campaigns, wielding the
glittering lure of rewards points as a well-advertised scenic byway.</p><p>The outcome of this
digital revolution remains unwritten.</p><p> Will Open Banking and A2A payments become
the preferred route for American consumers, ushering in an era of financial
transparency and lower costs? Or will the inertia of the status quo and the allure
of plastic's rewards prevail? Only one thing is certain: consumers are holding the steering wheel. Will
they remain content with the familiar highway, or will they embrace the new
on-ramp and become active participants in a financial revolution? Only time
will tell who will reach their destination first in this high-stakes race for
payment supremacy.</p>

This article was written by Pedro Ferreira at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Interactive Brokers Introduces New Services Catering to US Hedge Funds]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/interactive-brokers-introduces-new-services-catering-to-us-hedge-funds/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/interactive-brokers-introduces-new-services-catering-to-us-hedge-funds/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/interactive-brokers-introduces-new-services-catering-to-us-hedge-funds</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Interactive Brokers, a global electronic broker, has
announced the launch of two new services, High Touch Prime Brokerage and Global
Outsourced Trading, aimed at assisting select US hedge funds in managing and
expanding their operations. These services are designed to complement
Interactive Brokers' existing suite of offerings tailored for active traders
and institutional investors, including a prime brokerage solution encompassing
trading, clearing, custody, reporting, and other features.</p><p>Enhanced Support for Hedge Funds</p><p>High Touch Prime Brokerage provides eligible hedge fund
clients with personalized support, offering access to a dedicated Relationship
Manager who serves as a central point of contact. This manager is equipped to
address inquiries, resolve issues promptly, and facilitate special requests,
drawing upon a deep understanding of the client's trading strategy and
requirements. </p><p>“Hedge funds select Interactive Brokers for our automated
systems and advanced trading technology, which can help keep costs low.
However, we recognize that many hedge funds appreciate having a single contact
familiar with their trading objectives and business strategies,” said Milan
Galik, the Chief Executive Officer of Interactive Brokers. “High Touch Prime
Brokerage enables <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/interactive-brokers/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Interactive Brokers</a> to compete with large prime brokers and
removes a potential barrier for hedge funds who want to move to a low-cost
platform but are accustomed to personalized service.”</p><p>Additionally, clients have access to Subject Matter Experts
across various departments within Interactive Brokers, providing operational expertise
to enhance business management efficiency.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Interactive Brokers Introduces High Touch Prime Brokerage Service and Global Outsourced Trading for US Hedge Funds <a href="https://t.co/BKFE3ghLvo">https://t.co/BKFE3ghLvo</a> <a href="https://t.co/Gy3ZSI6O6O">pic.twitter.com/Gy3ZSI6O6O</a></p>— Latest News from Business Wire (@NewsFromBW) <a href="https://twitter.com/NewsFromBW/status/1778424590408282605?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 11, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Extending Trading Reach with IBKR Outsourced Trading Desks</p><p>Furthermore, clients availing of High Touch Prime Brokerage
service gain access to IBKR Outsourced Trading desks in Europe and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/asia/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Asia</a>,
extending high touch trading capabilities beyond North America. This expansion
enables portfolio managers to collaborate with experienced IBKR traders around
the clock, crafting <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/e/execution/" class="terms__main-term" id="60010adb-9e25-4bff-9822-c9210deec853">execution</a> strategies and placing orders for a variety of
instruments including domestic and international stocks, options, bonds, and
more.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Buying Coins is so 2023: Brokerage Accounts as a Gateway to Bitcoin Investment]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/buying-coins-is-so-2023-brokerage-accounts-as-a-gateway-to-bitcoin-investment/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/buying-coins-is-so-2023-brokerage-accounts-as-a-gateway-to-bitcoin-investment/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:10:20 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Nibley]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/buying-coins-is-so-2023-brokerage-accounts-as-a-gateway-to-bitcoin-investment</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>With Bitcoin being the best-performing asset of the year
more often than not during the last 15 years, many investors want to gain
exposure but doing so can be tricky.</p><p>For retail and institutional investors alike, questions of
regulatory and tax compliance can be puzzling. Then, there’s the challenge of
learning to navigate a new ecosystem. Using exchanges, sending transactions,
and taking custody of coins can take significant time to learn.</p><p>Fortunately, there are ways to gain exposure to Bitcoin
without purchasing and holding the asset itself. This can be done in a standard
brokerage or retirement account.</p><p>This article will explore the avenues available for tapping
into the Bitcoin market in this way, including exchange-traded Funds (ETFs),
public companies with Bitcoin holdings, and mining companies.</p><p>Bitcoin ETFs: A Gateway to Cryptocurrency Markets</p><p>ETFs in general have become a popular vehicle for investors
looking to diversify their portfolios without directly purchasing the
underlying assets. <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/spot-bitcoin-etf/">Spot Bitcoin ETFs</a>
offer a straightforward way to invest in Bitcoin through a regulated framework,
and have been very successful since their initial launch in the US on January
10, 2024. The first gold ETF took 2 years to reach $10 billion in AUM.
Blackrock’s IBIT accomplished the same in just 2 months.</p><p>Investors track the price of Bitcoin and trade on traditional
stock exchanges, providing liquidity and accessibility to investors who may not
otherwise be able to access <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/cryptocurrency/">cryptocurrency</a>
markets or don’t want to hold Bitcoin itself. Some of the most dominant spot ETFs in the US include <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/blackrock/">BlackRock’s</a> IBIT,
Fidelity’s FBTC, and ARK’s 21 Bitcoin Shares. </p><p>Here are some important things to
think about when it comes to selecting a spot Bitcoin ETF:</p><ul><li>Custodian: How does the issuer store their coins? All
the ETFs use <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>
as their custodians, with a few exceptions: </li></ul><ol><li>Fidelity secures their own
Bitcoin internally,</li><li>VanEck uses BitGo rather than Coinbase, </li><li>Hashdex
selected <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/bitgo/">BitGo</a> as its
custodian. </li></ol><ul><li>Fees: What expense ratio does the fund charge?
BitWise has garnered attention for having the lowest fee at just twenty basis
points. On the other end of the spectrum, Grayscale charges 1.5%.</li><li>Transparency: How much do you value transparency when
it comes to your funds’ holdings? So far, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/bitwise/">BitWise</a> is the only
fund that has published the public key to its wallet, allowing anyone to view
the blockchain transactions that prove the fund holds what it claims to. </li></ul><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/fidelity/">Fidelity</a>
stands out, as being a veteran in the digital asset space that allows them to
self-custody their Bitcoin holdings. BitWise shines for its low fees and
transparency. Some investors see these funds as preferable. Others
may opt for the reputation of firms like BlackRock or ARK. </p><p>Public Companies with Bitcoin Holdings: Investing in
Corporate Believers</p><p>A number of forward-thinking public companies have added
Bitcoin to their balance sheets, recognizing its potential as a store of value.
By investing in these companies, investors indirectly gain exposure to
Bitcoin's price movements. This approach allows investors to benefit from the
company's broader business performance while aligning with their innovative
stance on Bitcoin.</p><p>MicroStrategy (MSTR) was the first and still is the most
well-known company to adopt a Bitcoin treasury strategy. The company currently
holds over 1% of the entire supply of BTC. Shares of MSTR have also seen
impressive appreciation in recent years, even outperforming Bitcoin at times.</p><p>Here is a partial list of other companies that have decided
to put Bitcoin on their balance sheets:</p><ul><li>Coinbase</li></ul><ul><li>Galaxy Digital Holdings</li></ul><ul><li> Marathon Digital Holdings</li></ul><ul><li>Block</li></ul><ul><li>Tesla</li></ul><p>In addition to companies that hold Bitcoin, mining stocks
can also provide BTC exposure.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">CRYPTO MARKET COULD DOUBLE TO $5 TRILLION: RIPPLE CEORipple CEO Brad Garlinghouse predicts the crypto market could surge to $5 trillion by year-end, fueled by U.S. approval of spot Bitcoin ETFs and an upcoming mining-reward halving. His optimism is based on the entrance of… <a href="https://t.co/gFUv1rIgi8">pic.twitter.com/gFUv1rIgi8</a></p>— Crypto Town Hall (@Crypto_TownHall) <a href="https://twitter.com/Crypto_TownHall/status/1778308602425708781?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 11, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Mining Companies: The Backbone of Bitcoin's
Infrastructure</p><p>Bitcoin mining companies are at the heart of creating new
Bitcoin and securing the network. Investing in these companies represents an
investment in the infrastructure of the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/bitcoin/" class="terms__main-term" id="261088a9-0f41-4202-a73c-31f75ba6bd93">Bitcoin</a> network. As the demand for
Bitcoin grows, these companies may see increased profitability, making them an
attractive option for investors looking to get involved in the cryptocurrency
space.</p><p>The recent rise in Bitcoin’s price has been accompanied by
an increase in the network’s hash rate, as miners can create profitable
operations with greater ease.</p><p>Many mining companies hold some of the Bitcoin they
mine on their balance sheets, making them a way to gain exposure to both
Bitcoin and its infrastructure. A few popular Bitcoin mining stocks in 2024
include:</p><ul><li>Hut8</li></ul><ul><li>Riot Blockchain</li></ul><ul><li>Hive Blockchain</li></ul><ul><li>Bitfarms Limited</li></ul><ul><li>Cipher Mining</li></ul><ul><li>CleanSpark</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">CRYPTO BREAKING NEWSThe Bitcoin ETFs Help Money Flow Into Smaller Projects And Their ICOs. Bitcoin (BTC) ETFs have become a gateway for traditional investors to enter the crypto space, resulting in a substantial influx of capital that is... check us out @… <a href="https://t.co/crjqUU7gh2">pic.twitter.com/crjqUU7gh2</a></p>— InnovatekMobile (@Neome_com) <a href="https://twitter.com/Neome_com/status/1776941554747265261?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 7, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Strategic Considerations for Bitcoin Exposure</p><p>Each of these securities has benefits and
drawbacks. For example, mining stocks can be very volatile, even more so than
Bitcoin. Yet they can outperform Bitcoin by a significant margin at times.
Such securities require the highest risk tolerance and greatest conviction in
the promise of Bitcoin. They can be thought of as a speculative play on
Bitcoin, which may be too speculative for some.</p><p>Public companies that hold Bitcoin provide a blend of
exposure to the company’s operations and their Bitcoin holdings. In general,
the larger the Bitcoin holdings, the more the share price tends to be
correlated to the Bitcoin price. These can be a great choice for more
traditional investors who feel safer holding <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/e/equities/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="d6e02698-4c6b-44dd-ab57-9ff12763325c">equities</a> with earnings, cashflows,
dividends, etc. The downside is they may underperform the other securities
available. </p><p>Bitcoin ETFs represent the purest Bitcoin exposure that a
brokerage account can have. There’s not much to be said here, as these shares
represent ownership of a portion of the fund’s BTC holdings. There has even
been talk of ETFs eventually allowing shares to be redeemed for spot Bitcoin,
although this is unlikely in the USA, as the SEC has required ETFs to be
settled in cash only. The drawback is that each ETF issuer charges fees,
which can eat into profits over time.</p><p>When considering exposure to Bitcoin through your brokerage
account, it's important to evaluate your investment goals and risk tolerance.
Bitcoin and related investments can be volatile, and a strategic approach
should involve due diligence and a clear understanding of the underlying market
dynamics.</p>

This article was written by Brian Nibley at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Philippines Flags XM for Offering Unauthorized Securities]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/philippines-flags-xm-for-offering-unauthorized-securities/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/philippines-flags-xm-for-offering-unauthorized-securities/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 13:50:20 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/philippines-flags-xm-for-offering-unauthorized-securities</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Philippines' securities regulator recently issued a warning
against XM, the online trading platform for forex and crypto CFDs, for offering unauthorized securities in the country. According to an advisory dated April 4, the
Philippines' Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) mentioned that XM is
“not authorized to sell or offer securities to the public in the Philippines.”</p><p>Unregistered Trading Practices</p><p>According to the regulator, XM has more than 1,000
trading instruments, 24/7 trading of crypto <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/cfds/">CFDs</a>, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/l/leverage/" class="terms__main-term" id="df61d302-43af-41c3-a06a-e37426a0c2c0">leverage</a> of up to 1000:1, and
bonuses of up to $10,500 US dollars. An investigation by the SEC revealed that <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/xm/" target="_blank" rel="follow">XM</a>
has been running promotional campaigns on various social media platforms to
lure investors, including Filipinos, into trading activities on its platform.</p><p>"Based on the commission’s database, the operator of the
platform XM is not registered as a 
corporation  in  the  Philippines  and 
operates  without  the 
necessary  license  and/or authority to sell 
or  offer  any 
form  of  securities 
as  defined  under 
section  3.1  of 
the  securities regulation code (SRC),
to engage in the business of buying or selling securities, or as a broker, or
dealer," the SEC wrote. Finance Magnates contacted XM for comments and will update this article once we receive their feedback. </p><p>According to the Philippines’ regulations, securities
being offered to the public must be registered with the SEC, issued by a
registered corporation or licensed dealer, and the issuer must possess a
secondary license to sell or offer securities. In light of these findings, the SEC has warned
individuals acting as salesmen, brokers, dealers, promoters, or recruiters for
XM within the Philippines of criminal liability.</p><p>Philippines SEC Warns XM's Promoters</p><p>"Those who act as salesmen, brokers, dealers
or agents, representatives, promoters, recruiters, influencers,  endorsers, 
and enablers of the
XM platform in selling or convincing people to invest in this platform within the Philippines even through online
means may be held criminally liable under Section 28 of the
SRC  and be penalized with a maximum fine of five million pesos 
(P 5,000,000.00) or imprisonment
of 21 years or both," the regulator mentioned.</p><p>Similarly, the SEC recently <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/etoros-promoters-in-the-philippines-risk-up-to-21-years-in-jail/" target="_blank" rel="follow">issued a warning</a> against eToro, the global investment platform. The regulator cautioned of consequences for eToro’s promoters operating in the country. Despite the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/t/trading-platform/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="f85800b2-ccf5-4f50-9e8e-780d32afc6f6">trading platform</a>’s global presence, the Filipino authorities emphasized its lack of authorization within their jurisdiction, issuing a regulatory advisory note against the platform on March 14.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Crypto CFD Volume on Axi Jumps 60% in March, Nears $17 Billion]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/exclusive-crypto-cfds-on-axi-jumps-60-in-march-nears-17-billion/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/exclusive-crypto-cfds-on-axi-jumps-60-in-march-nears-17-billion/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 13:42:23 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Brokers]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/exclusive-crypto-cfds-on-axi-jumps-60-in-march-nears-17-billion</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The trading volume on Axi with crypto contracts for differences (CFDs) soared to US$16.7 billion in March, the broker revealed exclusively to Finance Magnates. The figures stood at US$7.6 billion in January and US$10.4 billion in February.</p><p>“We saw a pretty decent amount of crypto volume growth month-on-month from January and a huge increase in the last five or six months,” said Louis Cooper, the Chief Commercial Officer at Axi. He added that the broker executed 1.5 million crypto CFDs trades last month. As much as 10 percent of the trades executed in March were crypto trades.</p><p>A Significant Increase in Crypto CFDs Volume</p><p>The monthly crypto CFDs volume on Axi for March marked a tenfold increase from the average of the three months between July and September, the first quarter of the ongoing fiscal year.</p><p>As reported earlier by Finance Magnates, the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/brokers/exclusive-crypto-cfds-volume-on-axi-nears-12-billion-in-january/">monthly crypto CFDs volume on Axi</a> ranged between AU$1 billion (approximately US$0.7 billion) and AU$2 billion (US$1.3 billion) for most of 2023. In December, the volumes surged dramatically to reach up to AU$6 billion (about US$4 billion), continuing the growth trend.</p><p>The growth can be attributed to 25 percent of Axi’s active client base, translating to over 9,000 traders, who traded crypto CFDs, marking a threefold growth from the first quarter of the fiscal year.</p><p>The CCO of the brokerage highlighted that “as an asset class, we now have more active Crypto CFD traders than we do <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/a-shift-from-cfds-to-futures-a-hype-or-a-viable-option/">trading Index CFDs and Futures</a>.”</p><p>He further revealed that markets in Asia and the Middle East have a “big concentration of volume and customers,” although “there is a huge amount of activity happening in other parts of the world, too.”</p><p>He added that “the vast majority of the growth came from our current clients who migrated towards crypto CFDs because of a moving market and increased volatility.”</p><p>“We're seeing new customers who are joining to trade crypto CFDs as their first. Although that's growing, it's still the smaller percentage.”</p><p>The Growing Demand for Crypto CFDs</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/axi/">Axi</a> offers crypto CFDs featuring “30 of the most popular cryptocurrencies,” including Bitcoin, Ethereum, Litecoin, Ripple, and Bitcoin Cash. Cooper revealed that 96 percent of the crypto trading volume on Axi comes from Bitcoin CFDs.</p><p>“The approval of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/spot-bitcoin-etfs-which-offers-the-lowest-fees/">Bitcoin exchange-traded funds</a> (ETFs) in the US has been a huge instigator of the growth of crypto,” said Cooper. “It's a validation of regulation in the US, and this is also a mark of perception from the market that there will be more institutional flow going into cryptos and particularly Bitcoin.”</p><p>Other factors that have propelled the demand for crypto CFDs are the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/what-is-the-bitcoin-halving-unveiling-the-most-important-event-in-bitcoins-history/">upcoming halving event </a>and “price stability,” according to Cooper. “By its own standards, BTC has been incredibly stable the last 6 months,” he added. “Clients are attracted to BTC/USD because there is enough volatility for speculation, but it’s not as daunting as it was 12 to 24 months ago to speculate using leverage.”</p><p>Crypto CFDs are over-the-counter leveraged derivatives that allow traders to speculate on prices by taking either long or short positions. Although other crypto derivatives offer leveraged trading, the leverage with CFDs can go higher. Axi offers a maximum of 200:1 leverage on its crypto CFDs.</p><p>“Commissions are pegged to the asset price, so transactional costs would have doubled over the last quarter,” Cooper highlighted the advantages of trading costs with crypto CFDs. “We have resisted increasing our spreads as much as we can, which has given us a competitive advantage and our clients a trading edge trading CFDs vs. Perpetual Futures.”</p><p>“The costs, particularly cost to hold, are more transparent – with CFDs, you get one overnight fee based on your borrowing, for perpetual swaps, you get charged every 8 hours based on market volatility and trading demand – this can be quite low when markets are quiet but equally more expensive when the markets are moving (which arguably is when clients want to trade).”</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
</channel></rss>