<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"

	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.newsbtc.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/</link>
	<description>Bitcoin &#38; Cryptocurrency News Today</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:09:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/cropped-cropped-cropped-favicon.png?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>NewsBTC</title>
	<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">221170450</site>	<item>
		<title>Brazil Wants BTC: 7,400 Bitcoin Futures Contracts Created On First Day Of Trading</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/brazil-btc-7400-bitcoin-futures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 12:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After announcing in March its plans to include Bitcoin futures in its offerings, B3, a Brazilian stock exchange, has officially opened up trades, achieving a significant milestone on its very first day of trading Bitcoin futures.  B3 Bitcoin Futures Sees Surge In Demand Following its launch of Bitcoin futures on April 17, B3 experienced a massive wave of demand and interest from cryptocurrency enthusiasts eager to trade the newly listed Bitcoin futures. The stock exchange reported that on the debut trading day, more than 7,400 Bitcoin futures contracts were actively traded.  Related Reading: Shiba Inu Burn Rate Sees 81% Daily Increase, But Why Is Participation Low? This unprecedented trading volume underscores investors&#8217; strong interest in cryptocurrency derivatives as well as the increasing demand for BTC exposure among Brazilian cryptocurrency traders and enthusiasts.  Notably, B3 disclosed that the demand for Bitcoin futures on its exchange was so profound that it had hit 111,000 buy or sell orders on the trading screen. The market had displayed intense participation in the newly launched contracts, with the Director of Listed Products at B3, Marcos Skistymas, affirming that the heightened demand resulted from B3’s introduction of its first-ever derivative linked to a cryptocurrency.  The introduction of Bitcoin futures marks a significant step forward for the stock exchange, aligning with its vision to expand its offerings to cater to users&#8217; needs. Skistymas has also indicated that the market’s response to the recently listed Bitcoin futures was overwhelmingly positive, reflecting a significant potential for these contracts within the Brazilian market.  BTC Futures To Act As A Hedge Against Market Volatility According to Skistymas, Bitcoin futures were a “suitable instrument” that could become a hedge against Bitcoin, potentially providing Brazilian investors a means to manage the flurry of risks associated with Bitcoin’s price fluctuations. For more clarity, a Bitcoin future is a contract between investors who wager on the future price of the pioneer cryptocurrency, providing exposure to Bitcoin without the need to purchase it. Given btc’s high volatility and price fluctuations during certain market conditions, accurately predicting the price of the cryptocurrency can be challenging. Additionally, only a handful of crypto analysts and investors have managed to forecast Bitcoin’s price actions with precision.  Related Reading: Ripple CEO Walks Back $5 Trillion Crypto Marker Prediction, Unveils New Target At the beginning of the year, the price of BTC surged from below $50,000 to an all-time high of more than $75,000 in March 2024. As of writing, the cryptocurrency is trading at $66,129 after witnessing a major price correction and plummeting by 0.09% over the past month, according to CoinMarketCap.  Irrespective of BTC&#8217;s unpredictability and price variations, the launch of Bitcoin futures on B3 has the potential to bring in a new era of adoption among Brazilian investors, providing them with fresh opportunities to diversify their portfolios with these regulated financial instruments. BTC price falls below $66,000 &#124; Source: BTCUSD on Tradingview.com Featured image from Business Post Nigeria, chart from Tradingview.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After announcing in March its plans to include Bitcoin futures in its offerings, B3, a Brazilian stock exchange, has officially opened up trades, achieving a significant milestone on its very first day of <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-futures-cme-q3-breaks-all-time-highs/" rel="nofollow">trading Bitcoin futures. </a></p>
<h2>B3 Bitcoin Futures Sees Surge In Demand</h2>
<p><a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-futures-approved-for-trading-on-brazil/" rel="nofollow">Following its launch of Bitcoin futures on April 17</a>, B3 experienced a massive wave of demand and interest from cryptocurrency enthusiasts eager to trade the newly listed Bitcoin futures. The stock exchange <a href="https://valor.globo.com/financas/criptomoedas/noticia/2024/04/19/em-dia-de-estreia-74-mil-contratos-futuros-de-bitcoin-sao-negociados-na-b3.ghtml" rel="nofollow">reported</a> that on the debut trading day, more than 7,400 Bitcoin futures contracts were actively traded. </p>

<p>This unprecedented trading volume underscores <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-futures-open-interest-cme-record-highs/" rel="nofollow">investors&#8217; strong interest in cryptocurrency derivatives</a> as well as the increasing demand for BTC exposure among Brazilian cryptocurrency traders and enthusiasts. </p>
<p>Notably, B3 disclosed that the demand for Bitcoin futures on its exchange was so profound that it had hit 111,000 buy or sell orders on the trading screen. The market had displayed intense participation in the newly launched contracts, with the Director of Listed Products at B3, Marcos Skistymas, affirming that the heightened demand resulted from B3’s introduction of its first-ever <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/topic/most-common-types-of-cryptocurrency-derivatives/">derivative linked to a cryptocurrency. </a></p>
<p>The introduction of Bitcoin futures marks a significant step forward for the stock exchange, aligning with its vision to expand its offerings to cater to users&#8217; needs. Skistymas has also indicated that the market’s response to the recently listed Bitcoin futures was overwhelmingly positive, reflecting a significant potential for these contracts within the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/brazil-to-introduce-tougher-crypto-regulation/" rel="nofollow">Brazilian market.</a> </p>
<h2>BTC Futures To Act As A Hedge Against Market Volatility</h2>
<p>According to Skistymas, Bitcoin futures were a “suitable instrument” that could become a hedge against Bitcoin, potentially providing Brazilian investors a means to manage the flurry of risks associated with <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-could-drop-to-52000-if-price-breaks-below-this-mark-cryptoquant/">Bitcoin’s price fluctuations.</a></p>
<p>For more clarity, a Bitcoin future is a contract between investors who wager on the future price of the pioneer cryptocurrency, providing exposure to Bitcoin without the need to purchase it. Given <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-futures-overheating-volatile-storm-ahead/" rel="nofollow">btc’s high volatility</a> and price fluctuations during certain market conditions, accurately <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/historical-trends-bitcoin-price/">predicting the price of the cryptocurrency</a> can be challenging. Additionally, only a handful of crypto analysts and investors have managed to forecast Bitcoin’s price actions with precision. </p>

<p>At the beginning of the year, the price of BTC surged from below $50,000 to an <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-price-surges-to-new-all-time-high-is-100000-in-sight/" rel="nofollow">all-time high</a> of more than $75,000 in March 2024. As of writing, the cryptocurrency is trading at $66,129 after witnessing a <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-price-suffers-sharp-decline/" rel="nofollow">major price correction</a> and plummeting by 0.09% over the past month, according to CoinMarketCap. </p>
<p>Irrespective of <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-futures-frenzy-fizzles-out-as-price-plunges-below-26000/">BTC&#8217;s unpredictability</a> and price variations, the launch of Bitcoin futures on B3 has the potential to bring in a <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/is-brazil-ready-for-the-crypto-economy-the-data-agrees-vehemently/" rel="nofollow">new era of adoption among Brazilian investors</a>, providing them with fresh opportunities to diversify their portfolios with these regulated financial instruments.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/VBRGqvNt/" alt="Bitcoin price chart from Tradingview.com" width="3286" height="1530" loading="lazy"/></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin-Small-2.jpeg?fit=320%2C180" width="320" height="180" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604451</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Analyst Outlines XRP Price Scenarios Ahead Of Ripple-SEC Case Update</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/xrp-news/xrp-price-scenarios-ahead-of-ripple-sec-case-update/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 11:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XRP News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple VS SEC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRP Price Prediction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a chart analysis shared via X, the crypto analyst Dark Defender provided insight into the potential price movements of XRP ahead of this week’s Ripple-SEC case update. The analysis, conducted on a monthly time frame, reveals that XRP has been holding above a critical support trend marked in blue. With the crypto community&#8217;s eyes set on the new Ripple filings expected next week, there&#8217;s a mix of anticipation and caution. XRP Price Enters Potentially Crucial Week Dark Defender notes that although market news does not typically have a direct correlation with price movements, the &#8220;last puzzle piece&#8221; pertaining to the Ripple case may add a layer of enthusiasm to the market sentiment surrounding XRP. The question posed is: What could happen if XRP fails to maintain its position above the blue support line? According to the analysis, if XRP breaks below this blue support line, it will likely approach the two critical Fibonacci retracement levels at $0.4623 (38.2% retracement level) and $0.3917 (23.6% retracement level). These figures are derived from the swing high and low points on the chart, traditionally considered potential support levels where the price could stabilize or bounce back. Related Reading: XRP Bulls Roar: Analyst Foresees Explosive Surge With ‘God Candle’ On The Horizon In the context of the current chart, a drop below these levels, particularly if the price closes under $0.3917 for two to three days consecutively, would invalidate the bullish five-wave structure that Dark Defender suggests could propel XRP to a high of $5.85. On the flip side, should XRP reclaim the 61.8% Fibonacci level at $0.6044, it could signify a first step towards a strong upward move. Between the price range of $0.6649 and $0.3917, any price movement is considered a sideways trend. A breakout above the 70.2% level at $0.6649 would likely confirm a bullish trend, with the analyst highlighting this as a significant threshold for a positive price trajectory. Above this level, XRP would then eye the next Fibonacci extension levels of $1.8815 (161.8% extension) and potentially $5.8563 (261.8% extension), which are ambitiously projected targets. The chart also highlights a &#8220;Main Resistance Trend&#8221; line that has capped the price since the peak of early 2018, and the current price action is pinched between this descending resistance and the ascending support trend lines, forming a converging pattern that traders often interpret as a potential breakout signal. Related Reading: XRP Whales Are On The Move Again, But Are They Bullish Or Bearish? A breakout could be the first bullish indication of a larger rally, with at least one monthly close above the line required. In the past, several attempts at a breakout have failed, and even one monthly close was followed by a fall back below the trendline the following month. Ripple Vs. SEC: What To Expect This Week Ripple Labs is gearing up to file its response to the US Securities and Exchange Commission’s (SEC) remedies briefing on April 22, a pivotal moment in their protracted legal battle. This response from Ripple is in reaction to the SEC&#8217;s briefing that put forth potential remedies including disgorgement of profits derived from XRP sales and civil penalties. The financial stakes are high, with the SEC calculating fines that could reach around $2 billion, claiming that Ripple engaged in an unregistered securities offering with its XRP sales. The legal and financial communities expect Ripple to mount a formidable defense against the SEC&#8217;s claims. Key to this counter-argument will be undermining the SEC&#8217;s assertion of the necessity for disgorgement, given the alleged lack of demonstrable financial harm to XRP purchasers. Furthermore, Ripple is likely to leverage favorable recent legal decisions and regulatory developments, aiming to weaken the SEC’s position. According to the schedule, Ripple is expected to submit a public redacted version of its opposition brief along with associated declarations and exhibits today, if these materials are devoid of any SEC-designated confidential information. If confidentiality is a concern, Ripple will file the documents under seal and submit a redacted public version by April 24. Following this, the SEC will have the opportunity to reply, with their response anticipated to be filed under seal by May 6. At press time, XRP traded at $0.53. Featured image from NameCoinNews, chart from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a chart analysis shared via X, the crypto analyst Dark Defender provided insight into the potential price movements of XRP ahead of this week’s Ripple-SEC case update. The analysis, conducted on a monthly time frame, reveals that XRP has been holding above a critical support trend marked in blue. With the crypto community&#8217;s eyes set on the new Ripple filings expected next week, there&#8217;s a mix of anticipation and caution.</p>
<h2>XRP Price Enters Potentially Crucial Week</h2>
<p>Dark Defender notes that although market news does not typically have a direct correlation with price movements, the &#8220;last puzzle piece&#8221; pertaining to the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ripple/ripple-ceo-sec-2-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Ripple case</a> may add a layer of enthusiasm to the market sentiment surrounding XRP. The question posed is: What could happen if XRP fails to maintain its position above the blue support line?</p>
<img decoding="async" class="wp-image-604448 size-full" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLnlV-PXMAETGws.jpg?resize=1366%2C768" alt="XRP price analysis" width="1366" height="768" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLnlV-PXMAETGws.jpg?resize=1366%2C768?w=1366 1366w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLnlV-PXMAETGws.jpg?resize=1366%2C768?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLnlV-PXMAETGws.jpg?resize=1366%2C768?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLnlV-PXMAETGws.jpg?resize=1366%2C768?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLnlV-PXMAETGws.jpg?resize=1366%2C768?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GLnlV-PXMAETGws.jpg?resize=1366%2C768?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" loading="lazy" data-recalc-dims="1"/>
<p>According to the analysis, if XRP breaks below this blue support line, it will likely approach the two critical Fibonacci retracement levels at $0.4623 (38.2% retracement level) and $0.3917 (23.6% retracement level). These figures are derived from the swing high and low points on the chart, traditionally considered potential support levels where the price could stabilize or bounce back.</p>

<p>In the context of the current chart, a drop below these levels, particularly if the price closes under $0.3917 for two to three days consecutively, would invalidate the bullish five-wave structure that Dark Defender suggests could propel XRP to a <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-bulls-roar-analyst-foresees-explosive-surge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">high of $5.85</a>. On the flip side, should XRP reclaim the 61.8% Fibonacci level at $0.6044, it could signify a first step towards a strong upward move.</p>
<p>Between the price range of $0.6649 and $0.3917, any price movement is considered a sideways trend. A breakout above the 70.2% level at $0.6649 would likely confirm a bullish trend, with the analyst highlighting this as a significant threshold for a positive price trajectory. Above this level, XRP would then eye the next Fibonacci extension levels of $1.8815 (161.8% extension) and potentially $5.8563 (261.8% extension), which are ambitiously projected targets.</p>
<p>The chart also highlights a &#8220;Main Resistance Trend&#8221; line that has capped the price since the peak of early 2018, and the current price action is pinched between this descending resistance and the ascending support trend lines, forming a converging pattern that traders often interpret as a potential breakout signal.</p>

<p>A breakout could be the first bullish indication of a larger rally, with at least one monthly close above the line required. In the past, several attempts at a breakout have failed, and even one monthly close was followed by a fall back below the trendline the following month.</p>
<h2>Ripple Vs. SEC: What To Expect This Week</h2>
<p>Ripple Labs is <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-lawsuit-ripple-sec-agreement-schedule/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">gearing up to file</a> its response to the US Securities and Exchange Commission’s (SEC) remedies briefing on April 22, a pivotal moment in their protracted legal battle. This response from Ripple is in reaction to the SEC&#8217;s briefing that put forth potential remedies including disgorgement of profits derived from XRP sales and civil penalties. The financial stakes are high, with the SEC calculating fines that could reach around $2 billion, claiming that Ripple engaged in an unregistered securities offering with its XRP sales.</p>
<p>The legal and financial communities expect Ripple to mount a formidable defense against the SEC&#8217;s claims. Key to this counter-argument will be undermining the SEC&#8217;s assertion of the necessity for disgorgement, given the alleged lack of demonstrable financial harm to <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/xrp-news/ripple-major-xrp-price-discounts-select-investors/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">XRP purchasers</a>. Furthermore, Ripple is likely to leverage favorable recent legal decisions and regulatory developments, aiming to weaken the SEC’s position.</p>
<p>According to the schedule, Ripple is expected to submit a public redacted version of its opposition brief along with associated declarations and exhibits today, if these materials are devoid of any SEC-designated confidential information. If confidentiality is a concern, Ripple will file the documents under seal and submit a redacted public version by April 24. Following this, the SEC will have the opportunity to reply, with their response anticipated to be filed under seal by May 6.</p>
<p>At press time, XRP traded at $0.53.</p>
<img decoding="async" class="wp-image-604449 size-full" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673" alt="XRP price" width="3628" height="1673" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3628 3628w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1140 1140w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRPUSD_2024-04-22_12-29-17.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" loading="lazy" data-recalc-dims="1"/>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/XRP-price-predictions.jpg?fit=460%2C239" width="460" height="239" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604437</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Miners Strike Gold: $107 Million Profit From Runes-Fueled Minting Spree</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin-miners-strike-gold-107-million-profit-from-runes-fueled-minting-spree/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ordinals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Runes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin miners have struck a proverbial goldmine, reaping an astonishing $107 million in profits, according to data from Glassnode, a leading analytics platform. This unprecedented windfall, amassed on April 20th, underscores a significant shift in the revenue dynamics of Bitcoin mining operations. Related Reading: Will Celestia (TIA) Hit $130? Analyst Makes Bold Prediction The meteoric rise in transaction fees serves as a bellwether for the evolving economic landscape of Bitcoin mining. As the network adapts to new market demands and technological advancements, transaction fees have emerged as a crucial revenue stream for miners. This trend is particularly noteworthy given the scheduled reductions in block rewards, highlighting the resilience and adaptability of Bitcoin&#8217;s economic model. According to glassnode, affected by the Runes minting activity, on April 20, Bitcoin miner revenue reached US$106.7 million, of which 75.444% came from network transaction fees, both reaching record highs. https://t.co/lVSyqn1UaE pic.twitter.com/xjkkTor2I9 — Wu Blockchain (@WuBlockchain) April 21, 2024 Runes-Fueled Minting Spree Boosts Miner Revenue Driving this surge in profitability is a recent minting spree focused on Runes, a pivotal development that has left a tangible mark on the network&#8217;s dynamics. Reports indicate that a staggering 75% of the total profits stemmed from transaction fees, marking a new pinnacle in the distribution of revenue among BTC miners. Runes is similar to Ordinals; they both let users permanently store data directly on the Bitcoin blockchain, like an inscription etched in stone. But there&#8217;s a key distinction in what they store: Ordinals are one-of-a-kind digital collectibles, similar to fancy trading cards. Runes, on the other hand, are designed to act more like meme coins, those widely tradable and often humorous tokens that have been a recent craze in the crypto world. BTCUSD trading at $66,144 on the weekly chart: TradingView.com This paradigm shift in income composition underscores the growing importance of transaction fees as a vital income source, especially as block rewards face planned reductions in the context of Bitcoin&#8217;s halving system. This financial triumph comes amidst ongoing debates surrounding the sustainability and profitability of mining activities. With escalating energy demands and mounting regulatory scrutiny, the viability of mining operations has been called into question. However, the recent data paints a reassuring picture of the economic vitality of Bitcoin mining, demonstrating its resilience in the face of external pressures. Implications For Bitcoin&#8217;s Future Beyond the immediate financial gains, the surge in transaction fees holds profound implications for the future trajectory of Bitcoin. The unprecedented collection of fees signifies robust network activity and user engagement, indicating strong demand and utilization of the Bitcoin blockchain. This bodes well for the long-term sustainability and development of Bitcoin as a prominent digital currency, bolstering confidence among stakeholders and enthusiasts alike. Related Reading: Ethereum Fueled Up: Will 320 Million USDT Inflow Ignite Price Surge? Featured image from VistaCreate, chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin miners have struck a proverbial goldmine, reaping an astonishing $107 million in profits, according to <a href="https://studio.glassnode.com/metrics?a=BTC&amp;c=usd&amp;category=&amp;m=mining.RevenueSum&amp;s=1278892800&amp;u=1713571200&amp;zoom=" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">data from Glassnode,</a> a leading analytics platform. This unprecedented windfall, amassed on April 20th, underscores a significant shift in the revenue dynamics of Bitcoin mining operations.</p>

<p>The meteoric rise in transaction fees serves as a bellwether for the evolving economic landscape of Bitcoin mining. As the network adapts to new market demands and technological advancements, transaction fees have emerged as a crucial revenue stream for miners. This trend is particularly noteworthy given the scheduled reductions in block rewards, highlighting the resilience and adaptability of Bitcoin&#8217;s economic model.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">According to glassnode, affected by the Runes minting activity, on April 20, Bitcoin miner revenue reached US$106.7 million, of which 75.444% came from network transaction fees, both reaching record highs. <a href="https://t.co/lVSyqn1UaE" rel="nofollow">https://t.co/lVSyqn1UaE</a> <a href="https://t.co/xjkkTor2I9" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/xjkkTor2I9</a></p>
<p>— Wu Blockchain (@WuBlockchain) <a href="https://twitter.com/WuBlockchain/status/1781878036947976672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 21, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<h2><strong>Runes-Fueled Minting Spree Boosts Miner Revenue</strong></h2>
<p>Driving this surge in profitability is a recent minting spree focused on<a href="https://www.coingecko.com/learn/what-are-bitcoin-runes" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> Runes</a>, a pivotal development that has left a tangible mark on the network&#8217;s dynamics. Reports indicate that a staggering 75% of the total profits stemmed from transaction fees, marking a new pinnacle in the distribution of revenue among BTC miners.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-604409" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_67a3bf.png?resize=748%2C390" alt="" width="748" height="390" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_67a3bf.png?resize=748%2C390?w=748 748w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_67a3bf.png?resize=748%2C390?w=460 460w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
<p>Runes is similar to Ordinals; they both let users permanently store data directly on the <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bitcoin</a> blockchain, like an inscription etched in stone. But there&#8217;s a key distinction in what they store: Ordinals are one-of-a-kind digital collectibles, similar to fancy trading cards.</p>
<p>Runes, on the other hand, are designed to act more like meme coins, those widely tradable and often humorous tokens that have been a recent craze in the crypto world.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/BrzkRcQ5/" width="2475" height="1163"/></p>

<p>This paradigm shift in income composition underscores the growing importance of transaction fees as a vital income source, especially as block rewards face planned reductions in the context of Bitcoin&#8217;s halving system.</p>
<p>This financial triumph comes amidst ongoing debates surrounding the sustainability and profitability of mining activities. With escalating energy demands and mounting regulatory scrutiny, the viability of mining operations has been called into question. However, the recent data paints a reassuring picture of the economic vitality of Bitcoin mining, demonstrating its resilience in the face of external pressures.</p>
<h2><strong>Implications For Bitcoin&#8217;s Future</strong></h2>
<p>Beyond the immediate financial gains, the surge in transaction fees holds profound implications for the future trajectory of Bitcoin. The unprecedented collection of fees signifies robust network activity and user engagement, indicating strong demand and utilization of the Bitcoin blockchain.</p>
<p>This bodes well for the long-term sustainability and development of Bitcoin as a prominent digital currency, bolstering confidence among stakeholders and enthusiasts alike.</p>

<p><em>Featured image from VistaCreate, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_cbc8cd.jpg?fit=460%2C306" width="460" height="306" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604406</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shiba Inu Team Fixes Shibarium Outage As SHIB Readies For Potential Surge</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/shiba-inu/shiba-inu-team-fixes-shibarium-outage-shib-surge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jake Simmons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SHIB price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiba Inu Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shibarium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shibarium Outage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a recent update, Shiba Inu developer Kaal Dhairya (@kaaldhairya), confirmed that a temporary outage affecting the Shibarium network has been resolved. The outage, triggered by networking issues among validators, briefly disrupted services within the Shiba Inu ecosystem, specifically the layer-2 blockchain solution, Shibarium. Kaal detailed the cause and the subsequent resolution of the problem, stating, &#8220;There was a temporary Shibarium outage caused because of networking issues amongst the validators. Network is back up and running now.&#8221; He also noted that while the primary network functionality has been restored, some ancillary services such as Shibariumscan or external Remote Procedure Calls (RPCs) may continue to face disruptions until additional remedial steps are completed. Related Reading: Shiba Inu (SHIB) Price Jumps On Growing Support From 1.4 Million Holders Kaal emphasized the importance of collaboration among infrastructure teams to enhance communication and streamline operations. He urged external teams working on infrastructure-level elements such as RPC to coordinate closely with the Shibarium team. &#8220;If you’re an external team working on infrastructure level for Shibarium (e.g., RPC, etc.), please reach out so that we can streamline comms with you over shared telegram / slack channels,&#8221; he said. There was a temporary shibarium outage caused because of networking issues amongst the validators. Network is back up and running now, some services like shibariumscan or external RPCs can still remain down until the steps provided are implemented. If you’re an external team… &#8212; Kaal (@kaaldhairya) April 22, 2024 Shiba Inu Price Unfaced The recent price movements of Shiba Inu (SHIB) show no impact of the Shibarium outage. The four-hour chart for SHIB/USD illustrates a symmetrical triangle pattern that has governed the asset&#8217;s movement over the past several weeks. Contrary to a direct bullish sentiment, the price initially broke to the downside of the triangle on April 12, which typically signals a looming downtrend. However, in a swift change of fortunes, SHIB found substantial support at the 100-day EMA and is now testing the extended lower trendline of the once-confining triangle. At present, the price has surpassed the crucial resistance-turned-support level marked by the 0.236 Fibonacci retracement level at $0.00002472. Notably, SHIB is also trading above all EMA’s in the 4-hour chart. The 200 EMA (blue line) is currently serving as crucial support after the first attempt to break above the extended trendline (black) failed. Related Reading: Shiba Inu Insider Reveals Top 5 Shibarium Investment Rules A decisive and sustained break above this level could invalidate the prior bearish breakout, positioning SHIB for a potential bullish move to the north. However, volume activity on the chart indicates a tempered trading environment, lacking the aggressive spikes typically associated with decisive breakouts. This could suggest that the market is in a state of contemplation, with traders awaiting further confirmation before committing to a clear directional bias. Lastly, the RSI sits at a reading of 67, which is just shy of the overbought threshold. This placement implies that there is room for upward movement before the market becomes overextended. If SHIB battles above the extended lower trendline, the case for an imminent surge grows stronger, potentially leading to a rally towards the Fibonacci levels of 0.382 ($0.00002867), 0.5 ($0.00003203) and 0.618 ($0.00003527). Featured image created with DALL·E, chart from TradingView.com]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a recent update, Shiba Inu developer Kaal Dhairya (@kaaldhairya), confirmed that a temporary outage affecting the Shibarium network has been resolved. The outage, triggered by networking issues among validators, briefly disrupted services within the Shiba Inu ecosystem, specifically the layer-2 blockchain solution, Shibarium.</p>
<p>Kaal detailed the cause and the subsequent resolution of the problem, stating, &#8220;There was a temporary <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/company/shibarium-activity-skyrockets-by-30-with-shiba-inus-soaring-prices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Shibarium</a> outage caused because of networking issues amongst the validators. Network is back up and running now.&#8221; He also noted that while the primary network functionality has been restored, some ancillary services such as Shibariumscan or external Remote Procedure Calls (RPCs) may continue to face disruptions until additional remedial steps are completed.</p>

<p>Kaal emphasized the importance of collaboration among infrastructure teams to enhance communication and streamline operations. He urged external teams working on infrastructure-level elements such as RPC to coordinate closely with the Shibarium team. &#8220;If you’re an external team working on infrastructure level for Shibarium (e.g., RPC, etc.), please reach out so that we can streamline comms with you over shared telegram / slack channels,&#8221; he said.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">There was a temporary shibarium outage caused because of networking issues amongst the validators. Network is back up and running now, some services like shibariumscan or external RPCs can still remain down until the steps provided are implemented. If you’re an external team…</p>
<p>&mdash; Kaal (@kaaldhairya) <a href="https://twitter.com/kaaldhairya/status/1782200776443715882?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 22, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<h2>Shiba Inu Price Unfaced</h2>
<p>The recent price movements of Shiba Inu (SHIB) show no impact of the Shibarium outage. The four-hour chart for SHIB/USD illustrates a <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/matic-analysis/polygon-breaks-symmetrical-triangle-analyst-target/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">symmetrical triangle </a>pattern that has governed the asset&#8217;s movement over the past several weeks.</p>
<p>Contrary to a direct bullish sentiment, the price initially broke to the downside of the triangle on April 12, which typically signals a looming downtrend. However, in a swift change of fortunes, SHIB found substantial support at the 100-day EMA and is now testing the extended lower trendline of the once-confining triangle.</p>
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-604395 size-full" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673" alt="Shiba Inu price" width="3628" height="1673" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3628 3628w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=2048 2048w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=1140 1140w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SHIBUSD_2024-04-22_07-54-25.png?resize=3628%2C1673?w=3000 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/>
<p>At present, the price has surpassed the crucial resistance-turned-support level marked by the 0.236 Fibonacci retracement level at $0.00002472. Notably, SHIB is also trading above all EMA’s in the 4-hour chart. The 200 EMA (blue line) is currently serving as crucial support after the first attempt to break above the extended trendline (black) failed.</p>

<p>A decisive and sustained break above this level could invalidate the prior bearish breakout, positioning SHIB for a potential bullish move to the north. However, volume activity on the chart indicates a tempered trading environment, lacking the aggressive spikes typically associated with decisive breakouts.</p>
<p>This could suggest that the market is in a state of contemplation, with traders awaiting further confirmation before committing to a clear directional bias. Lastly, the RSI sits at a reading of 67, which is just shy of the overbought threshold. This placement implies that there is room for upward movement before the market becomes overextended.</p>
<p>If SHIB battles above the extended lower trendline, the case for an <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/shiba-inu-surges-10-open-interest-explodes-on-top-exchanges-is-this-the-comeback/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">imminent surge</a> grows stronger, potentially leading to a rally towards the Fibonacci levels of 0.382 ($0.00002867), 0.5 ($0.00003203) and 0.618 ($0.00003527).</p>

]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-22-08.23.09-A-wide-image-featuring-a-Shiba-Inu-dog-a-popular-breed-known-for-its-fox-like-appearance-holding-a-wrench-in-its-mouth.-The-background-shows-a-large.png?fit=460%2C263" width="460" height="263" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604389</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DOGE Price Prediction – Dogecoin Recovery Could Stall At $0.170</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/doge/dogecoin-recovery-stall-0-170/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aayush Jindal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 05:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE/BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogeusdt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dogecoin is attempting a recovery wave above the $0.150 resistance zone against the US Dollar. DOGE could struggle to clear the $0.170 resistance zone. DOGE started a recovery wave from the $0.1280 support zone against the US dollar. The price is trading above the $0.1500 level and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours). There is a key bearish trend line forming with resistance at $0.170 on the 4-hour chart of the DOGE/USD pair (data source from Kraken). The price must settle above $0.170 to move into a positive zone and start a fresh surge. Dogecoin Price Faces Hurdles After a major decline, Dogecoin price found support at $0.1280. A low was formed at $0.1283 and DOGE started a decent recovery wave, like Bitcoin and Ethereum. There was a move above the $0.1350 and $0.140 resistance levels. The price climbed above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the downward wave from the $0.2093 swing high to the $0.1283 low. However, the bears are still active and protecting more gains. There is also a key bearish trend line forming with resistance at $0.170 on the 4-hour chart of the DOGE/USD pair. Dogecoin is also below the $0.1650 level and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours). On the upside, the price is facing resistance near the $0.1690 level or the 50% Fib retracement level of the downward wave from the $0.2093 swing high to the $0.1283 low. Source: DOGEUSD on TradingView.com The next major resistance is near the $0.170 level. A close above the $0.170 resistance might send the price toward the $0.1880 resistance. The next major resistance is near $0.200. Any more gains might send the price toward the $0.220 level. Another Decline in DOGE? If DOGE’s price fails to gain pace above the $0.170 level, it could start another decline. Initial support on the downside is near the $0.1525 level. The next major support is near the $0.1475 level. If there is a downside break below the $0.1750 support, the price could decline further. In the stated case, the price might decline toward the $0.1280 level. Technical Indicators 4 Hours MACD – The MACD for DOGE/USD is now gaining momentum in the bullish zone. 4 Hours RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for DOGE/USD is now above the 50 level. Major Support Levels – $0.1525, $0.1475 and $0.1280. Major Resistance Levels – $0.1690, $0.1700, and $0.200.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dogecoin is attempting a recovery wave above the $0.150 resistance zone against the US Dollar. DOGE could struggle to clear the $0.170 resistance zone.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>DOGE started a recovery wave from the $0.1280 support zone against the US dollar.</li>
<li>The price is trading above the $0.1500 level and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours).</li>
<li>There is a key bearish trend line forming with resistance at $0.170 on the 4-hour chart of the DOGE/USD pair (data source from Kraken).</li>
<li>The price must settle above $0.170 to move into a positive zone and start a fresh surge.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Dogecoin Price Faces Hurdles</h2>
<p>After a major decline, Dogecoin price found support at $0.1280. A low was formed at $0.1283 and DOGE started a decent recovery wave, like <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-pump-66k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin</a> and <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-buy-dip-3150/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Ethereum</a>. There was a move above the $0.1350 and $0.140 resistance levels.</p>
<p>The price climbed above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the downward wave from the $0.2093 swing high to the $0.1283 low. However, the bears are still active and protecting more gains. There is also a key bearish trend line forming with resistance at $0.170 on the 4-hour chart of the DOGE/USD pair.</p>
<p>Dogecoin is also below the $0.1650 level and the 100 simple moving average (4 hours). On the upside, the price is facing resistance near the $0.1690 level or the 50% Fib retracement level of the downward wave from the $0.2093 swing high to the $0.1283 low.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604383" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461" alt="DOGE Price Prediction" width="1024" height="461" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1835 1835w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Doegcoin-DOGE_9bba45.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/DOGEUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">DOGEUSD on TradingView.com</a></p>
<p>The next major resistance is near the $0.170 level. A close above the $0.170 resistance might send the price toward the $0.1880 resistance. The next major resistance is near $0.200. Any more gains might send the price toward the $0.220 level.</p>
<h2>Another Decline in DOGE?</h2>
<p>If DOGE’s price fails to gain pace above the $0.170 level, it could start another decline. Initial support on the downside is near the $0.1525 level.</p>
<p>The next major support is near the $0.1475 level. If there is a downside break below the $0.1750 support, the price could decline further. In the stated case, the price might decline toward the $0.1280 level.</p>
<p>Technical Indicators</p>
<p>4 Hours MACD – The MACD for DOGE/USD is now gaining momentum in the bullish zone.</p>
<p>4 Hours RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for DOGE/USD is now above the 50 level.</p>
<p>Major Support Levels – $0.1525, $0.1475 and $0.1280.</p>
<p>Major Resistance Levels – $0.1690, $0.1700, and $0.200.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/shutterstock_259487336.jpg?fit=460%2C297" width="460" height="297" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604382</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum Price Hints At Potential Fresh Rally, Buy The Dip?</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-buy-dip-3150/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aayush Jindal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 04:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethbtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETHUSDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ethereum price is moving higher above the $3,120 resistance zone. ETH could start a fresh rally if it clears the $3,280 resistance zone. Ethereum is recovering higher and approaching the $3,280 resistance zone. The price is trading above $3,100 and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average. There was a break above two connecting bearish trend lines with resistance at $3,070 and $3,150 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD (data feed via Kraken). The pair could gain bullish momentum if it closes above the $3,250 zone. Ethereum Price Regains Strength Ethereum price formed a base above the $2,850 level and started a recovery wave, like Bitcoin. ETH cleared a few key hurdles near $3,000 to enter a positive zone. There was a break above two connecting bearish trend lines with resistance at $3,070 and $3,150 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD. The pair surpassed the 50% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $3,278 swing high to the $2,867 low. Ethereum is now trading above $3,120 and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average. It is also consolidating above the 76.4% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $3,278 swing high to the $2,867 low. Immediate resistance is near the $3,200 level. The first major resistance is near the $3,250 level. The next key resistance sits at $3,280, above which the price might gain traction and rise toward the $3,350 level. Source: ETHUSD on TradingView.com A close above the $3,350 resistance could send the price toward the $3,420 pivot level. If there is a move above the $3,420 resistance, Ethereum could even climb toward the $3,550 resistance. Any more gains could send Ether toward the $3,880 resistance zone in the coming days. Another Decline In ETH? If Ethereum fails to clear the $3,250 resistance, it could start another decline. Initial support on the downside is near the $3,150 level. The first major support is near the $3,120 zone and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average. A clear move below the $3,120 support might increase selling pressure and send the price toward $3,020. Any more losses might send the price toward the $2,965 level in the near term. Technical Indicators Hourly MACD – The MACD for ETH/USD is gaining momentum in the bullish zone. Hourly RSI &#8211; The RSI for ETH/USD is now above the 50 level. Major Support Level – $3,150 Major Resistance Level – $3,280]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Ethereum price is moving higher above the $3,120 resistance zone. ETH could start a fresh rally if it clears the $3,280 resistance zone.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Ethereum is recovering higher and approaching the $3,280 resistance zone.</li>
<li>The price is trading above $3,100 and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average.</li>
<li>There was a break above two connecting bearish trend lines with resistance at $3,070 and $3,150 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD (data feed via Kraken).</li>
<li>The pair could gain bullish momentum if it closes above the $3,250 zone.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Ethereum Price Regains Strength</h2>
<p>Ethereum price formed a base above the $2,850 level and started a recovery wave, like <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-pump-66k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">Bitcoin</a>. ETH cleared a few key hurdles near $3,000 to enter a positive zone.</p>
<p>There was a break above two connecting bearish trend lines with resistance at $3,070 and $3,150 on the hourly chart of ETH/USD. The pair surpassed the 50% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $3,278 swing high to the $2,867 low.</p>
<p>Ethereum is now trading above $3,120 and the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-faces-test-2850/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">100-hourly Simple Moving Average</a>. It is also consolidating above the 76.4% Fib retracement level of the downward move from the $3,278 swing high to the $2,867 low. Immediate resistance is near the $3,200 level.</p>
<p>The first major resistance is near the $3,250 level. The next key resistance sits at $3,280, above which the price might gain traction and rise toward the $3,350 level.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604379" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461" alt="Ethereum Price" width="1024" height="461" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1835 1835w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Ethereum_664f33.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/ETHUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ETHUSD on TradingView.com</a></p>
<p>A close above the $3,350 resistance could send the price toward the $3,420 pivot level. If there is a move above the $3,420 resistance, Ethereum could even climb toward the $3,550 resistance. Any more gains could send Ether toward the $3,880 resistance zone in the coming days.</p>
<h2>Another Decline In ETH?</h2>
<p>If Ethereum fails to clear the $3,250 resistance, it could start another decline. Initial support on the downside is near the $3,150 level. The first major support is near the $3,120 zone and the 100-hourly Simple Moving Average.</p>
<p>A clear move below the $3,120 support might increase selling pressure and send the price toward $3,020. Any more losses might send the price toward the $2,965 level in the near term.</p>
<p>Technical Indicators</p>
<p>Hourly MACD<strong> – </strong>The MACD for ETH/USD is gaining momentum in the bullish zone.</p>
<p>Hourly RSI<strong> &#8211; </strong>The RSI for ETH/USD is now above the 50 level.</p>
<p>Major Support Level – $3,150</p>
<p>Major Resistance Level – $3,280</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/iStock-947893644.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604378</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Price Approaches Breakout, Can BTC Pump Above $66K?</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-pump-66k/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aayush Jindal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 03:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcusd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSDT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xbtusd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bitcoin price recovered and climbed above the $64,000 resistance zone. BTC is now facing hurdles near the $65,500 and $66,000 levels. Bitcoin is now struggling to gain pace for a move above the $65,500 resistance zone. The price is trading above $64,000 and the 100 hourly Simple moving average. There is a key contracting triangle forming with resistance at $65,100 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair (data feed from Kraken). The pair could start a fresh surge if it clears the $65,500 resistance zone. Bitcoin Price Starts Increase Bitcoin price found support above $60,000 and started a fresh increase. BTC climbed above the $62,500 and $63,500 resistance levels. The bulls even pushed the price above the $65,000 level. However, the bears seem to be active near the $65,500 zone. The recent high was formed at $65,598 and the price is now consolidating gains. There was a drop below the $65,000 level, but the price is still above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $59,666 swing low to the $65,598 low. Bitcoin price is trading above $64,000 and the 100 hourly Simple moving average. Immediate resistance is near the $65,100 level. There is also a key contracting triangle forming with resistance at $65,100 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair. The first major resistance could be $65,500. The next resistance now sits at $66,000. If there is a clear move above the $66,000 resistance zone, the price could continue to move up. In the stated case, the price could rise toward $67,500. Source: BTCUSD on TradingView.com The next major resistance is near the $68,500 zone. Any more gains might send Bitcoin toward the $70,000 resistance zone in the near term. Downside Correction In BTC? If Bitcoin fails to rise above the $65,500 resistance zone, it could start a downside correction. Immediate support on the downside is near the $64,500 level. The first major support is $64,000. If there is a close below $64,000, the price could start to drop toward the 50% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $59,666 swing low to the $65,598 low at $62,500. Any more losses might send the price toward the $61,200 support zone in the near term. Technical indicators: Hourly MACD – The MACD is now losing pace in the bullish zone. Hourly RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for BTC/USD is now near the 50 level. Major Support Levels – $64,500, followed by $64,000. Major Resistance Levels – $65,100, $65,500, and $66,000.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Bitcoin price recovered and climbed above the $64,000 resistance zone. BTC is now facing hurdles near the $65,500 and $66,000 levels.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Bitcoin is now struggling to gain pace for a move above the $65,500 resistance zone.</li>
<li>The price is trading above $64,000 and the 100 hourly Simple moving average.</li>
<li>There is a key contracting triangle forming with resistance at $65,100 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair (data feed from Kraken).</li>
<li>The pair could start a fresh surge if it clears the $65,500 resistance zone.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Bitcoin Price Starts Increase</h2>
<p>Bitcoin price <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-risk-60k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">found support above $60,000</a> and started a fresh increase. BTC climbed above the $62,500 and $63,500 resistance levels. The bulls even pushed the price above the $65,000 level.</p>
<p>However, the bears seem to be active near the $65,500 zone. The recent high was formed at $65,598 and the price is now consolidating gains. There was a drop below the $65,000 level, but the price is still above the 23.6% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $59,666 swing low to the $65,598 low.</p>
<p>Bitcoin price is trading above $64,000 and the <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-at-break-moment-60k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">100 hourly Simple moving average</a>. Immediate resistance is near the $65,100 level. There is also a key contracting triangle forming with resistance at $65,100 on the hourly chart of the BTC/USD pair.</p>
<p>The first major resistance could be $65,500. The next resistance now sits at $66,000. If there is a clear move above the $66,000 resistance zone, the price could continue to move up. In the stated case, the price could rise toward $67,500.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604373" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461" alt="Bitcoin Price" width="1024" height="461" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1835 1835w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1536 1536w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=750 750w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Bitcoin_a384e6.png?resize=1024%2C461?w=1140 1140w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">BTCUSD on TradingView.com</a></p>
<p>The next major resistance is near the $68,500 zone. Any more gains might send Bitcoin toward the $70,000 resistance zone in the near term.</p>
<h2>Downside Correction In BTC?</h2>
<p>If Bitcoin fails to rise above the $65,500 resistance zone, it could start a downside correction. Immediate support on the downside is near the $64,500 level.</p>
<p>The first major support is $64,000. If there is a close below $64,000, the price could start to drop toward the 50% Fib retracement level of the upward move from the $59,666 swing low to the $65,598 low at $62,500. Any more losses might send the price toward the $61,200 support zone in the near term.</p>
<p>Technical indicators:</p>
<p>Hourly MACD – The MACD is now losing pace in the bullish zone.</p>
<p>Hourly RSI (Relative Strength Index) – The RSI for BTC/USD is now near the 50 level.</p>
<p>Major Support Levels – $64,500, followed by $64,000.</p>
<p>Major Resistance Levels – $65,100, $65,500, and $66,000.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/shutterstock_1037439613.jpg?fit=460%2C322" width="460" height="322" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604372</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Celestia (TIA) Hit $130? Analyst Makes Bold Prediction</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/will-celestia-tia-hit-130-analyst-makes-bold-prediction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christian Encila]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 17:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celestia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[price analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TIA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Celestia (TIA), a red-hot cryptocurrency in the modular blockchain space, has experienced a rollercoaster ride in recent weeks. After reaching a peak of nearly $16, TIA underwent a correction, plummeting to $7.5 according to CoinMarketCap data. However, the token has displayed remarkable resilience, bouncing back to $11.50 and showcasing strong trading volume – a sign that investors haven&#8217;t abandoned ship. Related Reading: Ethereum Fueled Up: Will 320 Million USDT Inflow Ignite Price Surge? Celestia&#8217;s Rebound And Investor Optimism The past 24 hours have been particularly kind to Celestia. The token price surged by a significant 6.20%, indicating a shift in investor sentiment towards optimism. This bullish momentum is further bolstered by analyst predictions and market psychology. TIA&#8217;s price action reveals a struggle between bullish and bearish forces. While the Fear &#38; Greed Index sits at 72 (&#8220;Greed&#8221;) and price predictions lean bullish, the current price of $11.70 remains significantly lower than its February 10th, 2024 ATH of $20.85. This signals a potential continuation of the downtrend. However, a key technical detail to note is the price staying above the cycle low of $7.61. This could indicate the beginning of a price recovery, but further technical analysis is necessary to confirm this. Some 46 cryptocurrency exchanges, including Binance and KuCoin, allow traders to trade Celestia. Celestia changed hands for $549.60 million in the previous day. TIA is currently trading at $11.7. Chart: TradingView Celestia: Long-Term Potential And A Bullish Breakout Crypto analyst CryptoBullet has offered a long-term perspective on Celestia&#8217;s trajectory, focusing on its one-week chart. The analyst predicts a consolidation phase where TIA will likely trade below its previous high of $20 for an extended period. $TIA #Celestia 1W chart I think #TIA will consolidate below the $20 high for quite a while (maybe it will print a giant Symmetric Triangle, who knows) In my opinion, only after this re-accumulation $TIA will be ready to go much higher 📈 🎯 Macro target 1 &#8211; $70 🎯 Macro target… pic.twitter.com/xiFzY3CQEc — CryptoBullet (@CryptoBullet1) April 18, 2024 This consolidation could potentially form a bullish &#8220;Symmetric Triangle&#8221; pattern, a technical indicator often seen before significant price breakouts. CryptoBullet believes that after this consolidation and re-accumulation period, TIA will experience a substantial rise, with ambitious macro price targets set at a staggering $70 and even $130. While these targets are lofty, they highlight the analyst&#8217;s belief in Celestia&#8217;s long-term potential. Celestia&#8217;s Underlying Value Proposition The recent bullish sentiment surrounding Celestia isn&#8217;t solely driven by speculation. Celestia is a modular data availability network, a foundational technology that underpins the scalability and security of blockchains. By offering a secure platform for developers to launch their own blockchains, Celestia positions itself as a crucial piece of infrastructure in the burgeoning blockchain ecosystem. This underlying value proposition, coupled with the recent positive market forces, is propelling Celestia into the spotlight. Related Reading: Shiba Inu (SHIB) Price Jumps On Growing Support From 1.4 Million Holders Will TIA Reach $130? While predicting specific price points like $130 is inherently difficult in the volatile cryptocurrency market, Celestia&#8217;s future trajectory remains intriguing. Bullish sentiment and a Greed market mood suggest potential for price appreciation. However, the significant drop from its all-time high and the unknown influence of future news and developments necessitate caution. Technical analysis using indicators and monitoring upcoming events can provide more clarity on Celestia&#8217;s price direction. Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:404">Celestia (TIA), a red-hot cryptocurrency in the modular blockchain space, has experienced a rollercoaster ride in recent weeks. After reaching a peak of nearly $16, TIA underwent a correction, plummeting to $7.5 according to CoinMarketCap data.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="3:1-3:404">However, the token has displayed remarkable resilience, bouncing back to $11.50 and showcasing strong trading volume – a sign that investors haven&#8217;t abandoned ship.</p>

<h2 data-sourcepos="3:1-3:404"><strong>Celestia&#8217;s Rebound And Investor Optimism</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="7:1-7:550">The past 24 hours have been particularly kind to Celestia. The token price surged by a significant 6.20%, indicating a shift in investor sentiment towards optimism. This bullish momentum is further bolstered by analyst predictions and market psychology.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:288">TIA&#8217;s price action reveals a struggle between bullish and bearish forces. While the <a href="https://coincodex.com/crypto/celestia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fear &amp; Greed Index</a> sits at 72 (&#8220;Greed&#8221;) and price predictions lean bullish, the current price of $11.70 remains significantly lower than its February 10th, 2024 ATH of $20.85.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:288">This signals a potential continuation of the downtrend. However, a key technical detail to note is the price staying above the cycle low of $7.61. This could indicate the beginning of a price recovery, but further technical analysis is necessary to confirm this.</p>
<p>Some 46 cryptocurrency exchanges, including Binance and KuCoin, allow traders to trade Celestia. Celestia changed hands for $549.60 million in the previous day.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/8fl5fso9/" width="1835" height="883"/></p>

<h2 data-sourcepos="9:1-9:62"><strong>Celestia: Long-Term Potential And A Bullish Breakout</strong></h2>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:694">Crypto analyst CryptoBullet has offered a long-term perspective on Celestia&#8217;s trajectory, focusing on its one-week chart. The analyst predicts a consolidation phase where TIA will likely trade below its previous high of $20 for an extended period.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24TIA&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$TIA</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Celestia?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#Celestia</a> 1W chart</p>
<p>I think <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TIA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#TIA</a> will consolidate below the $20 high for quite a while (maybe it will print a giant Symmetric Triangle, who knows)</p>
<p>In my opinion, only after this re-accumulation <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24TIA&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$TIA</a> will be ready to go much higher <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f4c8.png" alt="📈" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f3af.png" alt="🎯" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Macro target 1 &#8211; $70
<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f3af.png" alt="🎯" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Macro target… <a href="https://t.co/xiFzY3CQEc" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/xiFzY3CQEc</a></p>
<p>— CryptoBullet (@CryptoBullet1) <a href="https://twitter.com/CryptoBullet1/status/1780962294601482648?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 18, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:694">This consolidation could potentially form a bullish &#8220;Symmetric Triangle&#8221; pattern, a technical indicator often seen before significant price breakouts. CryptoBullet believes that after this consolidation and re-accumulation period,</p>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:694"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-604347" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5b7187.png?resize=1024%2C549" alt="" width="1024" height="549" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5b7187.png?resize=1024%2C549?w=1099 1099w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5b7187.png?resize=1024%2C549?w=460 460w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5b7187.png?resize=1024%2C549?w=768 768w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5b7187.png?resize=1024%2C549?w=860 860w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5b7187.png?resize=1024%2C549?w=750 750w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
<p data-sourcepos="11:1-11:694">TIA will experience a substantial rise, with ambitious macro price targets set at a staggering $70 and even $130. While these targets are lofty, they highlight the analyst&#8217;s belief in Celestia&#8217;s long-term potential.</p>
<strong>Celestia&#8217;s Underlying Value Proposition</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:527">The recent bullish sentiment surrounding Celestia isn&#8217;t solely driven by speculation. Celestia is a modular data availability network, a foundational technology that underpins the scalability and security of blockchains.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="15:1-15:527">By offering a secure platform for developers to launch their own blockchains, Celestia positions itself as a crucial piece of infrastructure in the burgeoning blockchain ecosystem. This underlying value proposition, coupled with the recent positive market forces, is propelling Celestia into the spotlight.</p>

<strong>Will TIA Reach $130?</strong>
<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:288">While predicting specific price points like $130 is inherently difficult in the volatile cryptocurrency market, Celestia&#8217;s future trajectory remains intriguing. Bullish sentiment and a Greed market mood suggest potential for price appreciation.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:288">However, the significant drop from its all-time high and the unknown influence of future news and developments necessitate caution. Technical analysis using indicators and monitoring upcoming events can provide more clarity on Celestia&#8217;s price direction.</p>
<p data-sourcepos="21:1-21:288"><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_e24da4.jpg?fit=460%2C303" width="460" height="303" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604339</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum Enters Accumulation Phase As $500 Million ETH Leave Exchanges</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/ethereum-enters-accumulation-phase-as-500-million-eth-leaves-exchanges/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altcoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[price analysis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investors are accumulating Ethereum in droves amidst what could become a return to bullish sentiment for the cryptocurrency. Ethereum is currently ranging around $3,170, with its price undergoing volatility in the past seven days. Amidst this price volatility, on-chain data has revealed an accumulation trend from Ether investors during the week. Additionally, transaction data has shown an uptick in whale movement of ETH to and from exchanges, with recent market happenings indicating a transformation in the price of the crypto asset. Related Reading: All Quiet On The Bitcoin ETF Front – Should You Be Paranoid? Ethereum Sees Major Accumulation As Investors Stock Up Ethereum is now at a fundamental junction which could see its price surging in the new week and beyond. This fundamental catalyst for a price surge has come through the recent entry of Spot Ether ETFs into the Asian market. Regulators in Hong Kong have greenlit the launch of Spot Ethereum ETFs along with Spot Bitcoin ETFs in the country, prompting investors to make strategic ETH movements in light of an incoming price surge.  Particularly, on-chain data from IntoTheBlock shows a strategic accumulation pattern from ETH investors, with over $500 million worth of ETH leaving centralized exchanges in the past week. Interestingly, this surge in movement is the highest single-week outflow from exchanges recorded on the Ethereum network since February.  Half a billion $ETH was withdrawn from CEXs this week, the highest since February pic.twitter.com/rwvftXjiOz — IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) April 19, 2024 When investors withdraw crypto from exchanges, it usually means they’re looking to hold it for the long term. This behavior shows that these investors have confidence that the price of ETH will increase in value in the near future.  Similarly, data from whale transaction tracker Whale Alerts shows an uptick in ETH whale transactions during the week, with whale outflows from exchanges outpacing inflows. 🚨 🚨 10,119 #ETH (31,855,489 USD) transferred from #Binance to unknown wallethttps://t.co/OKoF8E5Q4Z — Whale Alert (@whale_alert) April 20, 2024 Total crypto market cap currently at $2.322 trillion. Chart: TradingView What’s Next For Ether? Despite the outflows from exchanges, a concurrent selloff in exchanges drove the price down below $3,000 during the week to bottom out at $2,878. However, the currency has since reversed to the upside and is showing signs of a bullish momentum. At the time of writing, Ethereum is trading at $3,180 and is up by 4% in the past 24 hours.  Fundamentals surrounding Ethereum point to steady price growth during the weeks as the bulls look to clear the $3,200 price hurdle. One example of such catalysts is a new draft bill aimed at legitimizing stablecoins in the United States. As the blockchain network with the biggest stablecoin market, Ethereum is set to benefit from a clear-cut positive regulation regarding stablecoins.  Related Reading: Ethereum Fueled Up: Will 320 Million USDT Inflow Ignite Price Surge? While the US SEC continues to hesitate about the approval of Spot Ethereum ETFs in the country, this investment class is set to be launched at the end of April in Hong Kong. Ethereum ETFs hitting the Asian market signals growing institutional interest in the altcoin in all corners of the globe. This, in turn, could lead to the price of Ethereum surging past its current yearly high of $4,066. Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Investors are accumulating Ethereum in droves amidst what could <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/ethereum-fueled-up-320-million-usdt-inflow-could-ignite-price-surge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">become a return to bullish sentiment</a> for the cryptocurrency. Ethereum is currently ranging around $3,170, with its price undergoing volatility in the past seven days. </p>
<p>Amidst this price volatility, on-chain data has revealed an accumulation trend from Ether investors during the week. Additionally, transaction data has shown an uptick in whale movement of ETH to and from exchanges, with recent market happenings <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-fees-lowest-since-january-bottom-signal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">indicating a transformation</a> in the price of the crypto asset.</p>

<h2><b>Ethereum Sees Major Accumulation As Investors Stock Up</b></h2>
<p>Ethereum is now at a fundamental junction which could see its price surging in the new week and beyond. This fundamental catalyst for a price surge has come through the recent entry of Spot Ether ETFs into the Asian market. </p>
<p>Regulators in Hong Kong <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/spot-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-approved-hong-kong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">have greenlit the launch</a> of Spot Ethereum ETFs along with Spot Bitcoin ETFs in the country, prompting investors to make strategic ETH movements in light of an incoming price surge. </p>
<p>Particularly, on-chain data from IntoTheBlock shows a strategic accumulation pattern from ETH investors, with over $500 million worth of ETH leaving centralized exchanges in the past week. Interestingly, this surge in movement is the highest single-week outflow from exchanges recorded on the Ethereum network since February. </p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Half a billion <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24ETH&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">$ETH</a> was withdrawn from CEXs this week, the highest since February <a href="https://t.co/rwvftXjiOz" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/rwvftXjiOz</a></p>
<p>— IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1781298658945728786?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>When investors withdraw crypto from exchanges, it usually means they’re looking to hold it for the long term. This behavior shows that these investors have confidence that the price of ETH will increase in value in the near future. </p>
<p>Similarly, data from whale transaction tracker Whale Alerts shows an uptick in ETH whale transactions during the week, with whale outflows from exchanges outpacing inflows.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> 10,119 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ETH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#ETH</a> (31,855,489 USD) transferred from <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Binance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">#Binance</a> to unknown wallet<a href="https://t.co/OKoF8E5Q4Z" rel="nofollow">https://t.co/OKoF8E5Q4Z</a></p>
<p>— Whale Alert (@whale_alert) <a href="https://twitter.com/whale_alert/status/1781755412368310312?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 20, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/16xWeHl4/" width="1835" height="883"/></p>

<h2><b>What’s Next For Ether?</b></h2>
<p>Despite the outflows from exchanges, a concurrent selloff in exchanges <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-faces-test-2850/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">drove the price down below</a> $3,000 during the week to bottom out at $2,878. However, the currency has since reversed to the upside and is <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/eth/ethereum-price-holds-strong-3k/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">showing signs of a bullish momentum</a>. At the time of writing, Ethereum is trading at $3,180 and is up by 4% in the past 24 hours. </p>
<p>Fundamentals surrounding Ethereum point to steady price growth during the weeks as the bulls look to clear the $3,200 price hurdle. One example of such catalysts is <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/stablecoins-us-senators-unveil-new-regulations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a new draft bill</a> aimed at legitimizing stablecoins in the United States. As the blockchain network with the biggest stablecoin market, Ethereum is <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-wins-big-new-us-stablecoin-draft-bill/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">set to benefit </a>from a clear-cut positive regulation regarding stablecoins. </p>

<p>While the US SEC continues to <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/spot-ethereum-etf-delay-is-a-good-thing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">hesitate about the approval</a> of Spot Ethereum ETFs in the country, this investment class is set to be launched at the end of April in Hong Kong. Ethereum ETFs hitting the Asian market signals <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/coinbase-sec-5-arguments-spot-ethereum-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">growing institutional interest</a> in the altcoin in all corners of the globe. This, in turn, could lead to the price of Ethereum surging past its current yearly high of $4,066.</p>
<p><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_21afd9.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604344</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Were Bitcoin Miners Behind The BTC Price Crash Below $60,000?</title>
		<link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/were-bitcoin-miners-behind-the-btc-price-crash-below-60000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Matherson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto mining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.newsbtc.com/?p=604334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The price of Bitcoin fell drastically towards the $60,000 mark in the days leading up to the just concluded halving. On-chain data has shed light on what could very well be the reason for this price dip in the middle of all the excitement around the halving. Related Reading: Ethereum Fueled Up: Will 320 Million USDT Inflow Ignite Price Surge? Particularly, data has revealed that some miners have been selling their holdings in the days leading up to the halving event, with the entire BTC holdings of miners hitting a 12-year low.  Miners&#8217; Bitcoin Holdings Hit 12-Year Low On-chain analytics platform IntoTheBlock noted this interesting trend amongst Bitcoin miners. According to the platform&#8217;s &#8220;Miners&#8217; Bitcoin Holdings,&#8221; the collective BTC reserve across various miners has now dropped below 1.9 million BTC, its lowest in over 12 years. Interestingly, the metric shows that miner reserves have been on a continued trend of outflows since the beginning of the year, just after the approval of Spot Bitcoin ETFs. This means the outflow from miner wallets can be linked to increased demand from the various Bitcoin ETF wallets, with the latter now controlling over 4.27% of the total circulating wallets. As Bitcoin goes into the halving, miners&#8217; BTC holdings hit 12 year low. This indicates that miners have been net sellers leading up to the halving. pic.twitter.com/WNi74RkluG — IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) April 19, 2024 At the time of writing, CryptoQuant data puts the total number of miner reserves at 1.818 million BTC, a decrease of 22,000 BTC from 1.84 million on January 3. Additionally, this outflow from the miner reserves was exacerbated in the days leading up to the halving, as noted by IntoTheBlock. “This indicates that miners have been net sellers leading up to the halving,” IntoTheBlock said in a social media post. The persistent selling pressure exerted by miners may have been a contributing factor in Bitcoin&#8217;s stagnant pace between $65,000 and $70,000 over the past weeks. This outflow of BTC from miner wallets into the market seems to have flooded the market with more than enough BTC, which in turn contributed to a crash to $60,000 during the week.   Bitcoin is now trading at $64.906. Chart: TradingView What’s Next For Bitcoin? The practice of Bitcoin miners selling their holdings in the days leading up to the halving is not unusual, as demonstrated by their actions in past halving events. At the time of writing, Bitcoin is trading at $64,978, up 8% after rebounding up at $60,000. The much anticipated fourth Bitcoin halving has now been completed and the industry looks forward to its effect over the next few months.  Related Reading: Shiba Inu (SHIB) Price Jumps On Growing Support From 1.4 Million Holders The halving is ultimately a balancing act for miners. Although miners’ revenues are cut in half, the reduced Bitcoin supply and possible price increase can help offset some of the losses over time. According to a report, Bitcoin miners could sell up to $5 billion worth of BTC after the halving, with the price of the cryptocurrency potentially falling to $52,000. Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The price of <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/bitcoin-rebounds-strongly-after-59579-rejection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bitcoin fell drastically</a> towards the $60,000 mark in the days leading up to the just concluded halving. On-chain data has shed light on what could very well be the reason for this price dip in the middle of all the <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/scaramucci-sets-bitcoin-long-term-growth-at-200000/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">excitement around the halving</a>. </p>

<p>Particularly, data has revealed that <a href="https://bitcoinist.com/by-the-numbers-much-profits-bitcoin-whales-miners/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">some miners</a> have been selling their holdings in the days leading up to the halving event, with the entire BTC holdings of miners hitting a 12-year low. </p>
<h2><b>Miners&#8217; Bitcoin Holdings Hit 12-Year Low</b></h2>
<p>On-chain analytics platform IntoTheBlock noted this interesting trend amongst Bitcoin miners. According to the platform&#8217;s &#8220;Miners&#8217; Bitcoin Holdings,&#8221; the collective BTC reserve across various miners has now dropped below 1.9 million BTC, its lowest in over 12 years. </p>
<p>Interestingly, the metric shows that miner reserves have been on a continued trend of outflows since the beginning of the year, just after the approval of Spot Bitcoin ETFs. This means the outflow from miner wallets can be linked to increased demand from the various Bitcoin ETF wallets, with the latter now controlling over 4.27% of the total circulating wallets.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">As Bitcoin goes into the halving, miners&#8217; BTC holdings hit 12 year low. This indicates that miners have been net sellers leading up to the halving. <a href="https://t.co/WNi74RkluG" rel="nofollow">pic.twitter.com/WNi74RkluG</a></p>
<p>— IntoTheBlock (@intotheblock) <a href="https://twitter.com/intotheblock/status/1781352959927783861?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">April 19, 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p>At the time of writing, CryptoQuant data puts the total number of miner reserves at 1.818 million BTC, a decrease of 22,000 BTC from 1.84 million on January 3. Additionally, this outflow from the miner reserves was exacerbated in the days leading up to the halving, as noted by IntoTheBlock.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-604335" src="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5bd0c4.png?resize=670%2C363" alt="" width="670" height="363" srcset="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5bd0c4.png?resize=670%2C363?w=670 670w, https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_5bd0c4.png?resize=670%2C363?w=460 460w" sizes="(max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
<p>“This indicates that miners have been net sellers leading up to the halving,” IntoTheBlock said in a social media post.</p>
<p>The persistent selling pressure exerted by miners may have been a contributing factor in Bitcoin&#8217;s stagnant pace between $65,000 and $70,000 over the past weeks. This outflow of BTC from miner wallets into the market seems to have flooded the market with more than enough BTC, which in turn contributed to a crash to $60,000 during the week.  </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full" src="https://www.tradingview.com/x/QlKIMjYY/" width="1835" height="883"/></p>

<h2><b>What’s Next For Bitcoin?</b></h2>
<p>The practice of Bitcoin miners <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-miners-sell-halvings-time-different/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">selling their holdings</a> in the days leading up to the halving is not unusual, as demonstrated by their actions in past halving events. At the time of writing, Bitcoin is trading at $64,978, up 8% after rebounding up at $60,000. The much anticipated <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/halving-block-bitcoin-840000/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">fourth Bitcoin halving</a> has now been completed and the industry <a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/fourth-bitcoin-halving-completed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ">looks forward to its effect</a> over the next few months. </p>

<p>The halving is ultimately a balancing act for miners. Although miners’ revenues are cut in half, the reduced Bitcoin supply and possible price increase can help offset some of the losses over time. <a href="https://x.com/10x_Research/status/1781125421477876191" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">According to a report</a>, Bitcoin miners could sell up to $5 billion worth of BTC after the halving, with the price of the cryptocurrency potentially falling to $52,000.</p>
<p><em>Featured image from Pexels, chart from TradingView</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content medium="image" url="https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a_3e80ac.jpg?fit=460%2C307" width="460" height="307" /><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">604334</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
