<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<description>Neutral and Authentic News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:08:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cropped-Dark_CP_Symbol-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Tracking UK&#8217;s inflation: How we doing over there?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/tracking-uk-inflation-how-we-doing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jai Hamid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inflation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK economy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UK investors are tuning in this Wednesday to grab the latest on inflation data, which will paint a picture of where interest rates might head this year. According to the economists surveyed by Reuters, they&#8217;re predicting that the UK&#8217;s annual inflation is going to chill a bit to 3.1% in March, down from February’s 3.4%. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>UK investors are tuning in this Wednesday to grab the latest on inflation data, which will paint a picture of where interest rates might head this year. According to the economists surveyed by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/poll-bank-england-start-cutting-rates-q3-most-likely-august-2024-02-20/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Reuters</a>, they&#8217;re predicting that the UK&#8217;s annual inflation is going to chill a bit to 3.1% in March, down from February’s 3.4%. That’s the lowest it’s been since the middle of 2021. </p>



<p>But let’s not throw a party yet, guys, because even with this drop, inflation’s still sitting higher than the Bank of England’s comfort zone at 2%.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Keeping an Eye on the Core</h2>



<p>Not just the regular numbers, but the core inflation, which basically ignores the up and down drama of food and energy prices, is also expected to take a small step back to 4.3% from last month&#8217;s 4.5%. What this means is the Bank of England might not get too happy with slashing rates too much this year. </p>



<p>Just last week, those who bet on these things pushed their expectations of a rate cut from June to August. Why? Because the <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/fed-itself-cant-make-sense-of-us-inflation/" data-type="post" data-id="510944">U.S.</a> dropped a surprise with stronger-than-anticipated inflation for the third time in a row.</p>



<p>Tuesday’s also a big day with labour market stats hitting the stands. Everyone’s watching this because it’s got a lot to say about wage growth. Hot wages have been keeping the service sector inflation a bit too lively at 6.1% in February. </p>



<p>Good news might be on the horizon, though, as experts think earnings growth might cool off a touch to 5.5% in the three months to February, a slight dip from 5.6% in the previous period. This could give policymakers a bit of breathing room.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is the UK Economy Doing a Slow Dance?</h2>



<p>Let’s talk GDP. </p>



<p>The UK’s GDP nudged up by just 0.1% in February, says the Office for National Statistics. It’s a tiny bump, but it’s in line with what folks were expecting. This number comes after a bit of a slump in the last half of 2023, where the economy shrank, slipping the UK into a technical recession.</p>



<p>But there was a small win in January with a growth revision up to 0.3%. Not everything’s looking up though—construction output wasn’t doing too hot, dropping 1.9% in February. On the flip side, production output was the star of the show, climbing 1.1% in the same month, but growth in the big-shot services sector barely moved from 0.3% to 0.1%.</p>



<p>Some economists are not all that optimistic about a strong bounce back. They think it might not be enough to keep inflation and interest rates from tumbling down like what’s happening over in the U.S.</p>



<p>In fact, British inflation took a bigger dive than folks expected in March, hitting a near 2½-year low of 3.4%. But over in the U.S., prices climbed higher than expected at 3.5% this week, making some rethink when those interest rate cuts might start—pushing guesses from summer to September.</p>



<p>And this has got some wondering if what’s happening with the Federal Reserve will make other central banks, including the Bank of England, pump the brakes on any early rate cuts, especially if the U.S. dollar starts flexing.</p>



<p>Goldman Sachs even tweaked their forecast last Friday, dropping their prediction of Bank of England rate cuts from five down to four for the year, seeing them starting in June and then maybe easing into a quarterly rhythm.</p>



<p>Simon French, the chief economist at Panmure Gordon, chatted on <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/squawk-box-europe/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">CNBC’s “Squawk Box Europe,”</a> pointing out that the Bank of England likes its independence but can’t ignore the upcoming UK national election hinted for later this year. </p>



<p>The heat’s on, especially with some talk from the governing party expecting rate cuts soon. He said this could push the Bank to get those rate cuts out of the way before voters hit the polls.</p>



<p>French wrapped it up by noting the numbers show the recession might be done, but it’s not exactly time to throw a party. The UK&#8217;s growth is still limping behind its pre-pandemic pace and lagging the U.S., but it’s keeping up with much of Europe and showing some spunk in areas like manufacturing and car production.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-00.21.24-Design-an-analytical-and-informative-image-that-tracks-the-trajectory-of-the-UKs-inflation-over-time.-Visualize-a-scene-with-a-graph-or-charts-that-r.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-00.21.24-Design-an-analytical-and-informative-image-that-tracks-the-trajectory-of-the-UKs-inflation-over-time.-Visualize-a-scene-with-a-graph-or-charts-that-r.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is the deal with Serbia and the BRICS bunch?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/the-deal-with-serbia-and-the-brics-bunch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jai Hamid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 23:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BRICS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Serbia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Serbia is all eyes on the BRICS bunch lately, and it looks like the feeling is mutual. The BRICS, which has been on a roll adding new countries since the start of 2024, might just swing its doors wide open for Serbia. There’s a growing trend among nations to ditch the U.S. dollar as the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Serbia is all eyes on the BRICS bunch lately, and it looks like the feeling is mutual. The <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/how-us-be-affected-when-brics-ditch-dollar/" data-type="post" data-id="504791">BRICS</a>, which has been on a roll adding new countries since the start of 2024, might just swing its doors wide open for Serbia. </p>



<p>There’s a growing trend among nations to ditch the U.S. dollar as the world’s reserve currency, and BRICS is smack in the middle of it, handing out invites to those who are down with this plan.</p>



<p>So, is Serbia about to become the first Balkan star in the BRICS sky? </p>



<p>Well, the word out is that BRICS rolled out the red carpet for Serbia to join them at their next summit in Russia later this year. This is huge because Serbia has been hanging around, waiting to get into the European Union since 2009, without much luck. Looks like they might just pivot to a different crew.</p>



<p>Last year, Serbia’s Movement of Socialists got parliament to give the thumbs up to apply for BRICS membership. They were like, “Most of our folks think joining BRICS is the best move.” </p>



<p>If Serbia shows up at the summit and gets in, they’ll be the first European country to crack into this group. Whoop, whoop!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Let’s Talk Numbers</h2>



<p>This just in from the <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/immersive-story/2024/01/24/incubating-innovation-in-serbia-for-global-success" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">World Bank</a> on Thursday. </p>



<p>They’re bumping up Serbia’s economic growth forecast for 2024 to 3.5% from the earlier 3.0%. And it doesn’t stop there—things are expected to speed up to 3.8% in 2025 and hit 4.0% in 2026. But here’s the kicker: the Serbian economy&#8217;s got to pull off some serious structural moves to keep this party going, especially with the EU income levels in sight.</p>



<p>And it’s not just about growth. </p>



<p>The World Bank’s betting on a 5% inflation rate for Serbia this year, but they think it’ll chill out to 3.5% by 2025 and 3.2% the year after. As for the current account gap, that’s gonna widen to 3.6% of GDP this year from last year&#8217;s 2.6%, and don’t expect it to shrink anytime soon. On the flip side, Serbia’s fiscal deficit is set to shrink from 2.2% of GDP last year to 2.0% in 2024, and then down to 1.5% for the next couple of years.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">BRICS Going Big</h2>



<p>BRICS isn’t just Brazil, Russia, India, China, and South Africa anymore, you know. They’ve welcomed Egypt, Ethiopia, Iran, and the UAE into the fold. </p>



<p>Now since its start in 2009, BRICS has been sort of China-heavy on the trade front, with everyone else just tagging along. But lately, India’s started to catch up, thanks to its booming economy.</p>



<p>But here’s the tea. Even though they’re tight, the rest of the BRICS gang doesn’t really trade much with each other compared to how much business they do with China. Interesting, huh? And with China pushing hard on the foreign policy gas pedal, they’ve been the big boss at the United Nations too, except for that one time Brazil didn’t toe the line on Ukraine in 2022.</p>



<p>Okay so, China wants to expand BRICS even more to include a mix of countries that are either loaded with cash or seriously strapped for it, plus some major oil players like Saudi Arabia and the UAE. The big question is what BRICS can really pull off with such a mixed bag of countries and whether they can keep their goals straight post-expansion.</p>



<p>They’re also hollering for some major changes at big institutions like the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank, wanting a setup that really speaks for everyone, not just the big guns. Plus, they’re all about using local currencies for trade, especially with China, to keep things clear and fair in global trade.</p>



<p>How this BRICS expansion turns out depends a lot on how they handle their internal stuff and what the rest of the world thinks about it. Whether the boys can keep up the momentum depends on a lot of things, like how China’s power plays out and how the rest of the BRICS members feel about it. </p>



<p>With the diversity in the group, it could either be a huge win for everyone or a tricky path to tread, especially for India, feeling the heat from China.</p>



<p>So, that’s the lowdown. Will my girl Serbia end up with a new set of powerful pals? I sure hope so! But let&#8217;s see.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-00.20.53-Create-an-engaging-and-informative-image-that-explores-Serbias-relationship-with-the-BRICS-countries-Brazil-Russia-India-China-South-Africa.-Vi.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-00.20.53-Create-an-engaging-and-informative-image-that-explores-Serbias-relationship-with-the-BRICS-countries-Brazil-Russia-India-China-South-Africa.-Vi.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tether&#8217;s New Non-Custodial Tokenization Platform Set to Transform Digital Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/tethers-custodial-tokenization-platform/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haseeb Shaheen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tether]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tether (the most recognizable and well-known name in the digital currency) makes a splash after the CEO Paolo Ardoino announced an update. Ardoino announced Tether recently developed a tokenization platform which is non-custodial; easy to use and highly configurable; it will be available to the masses. The platform has support for many blockchain networks and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tether (the most recognizable and well-known name in the digital currency) makes a splash after the CEO Paolo Ardoino announced an update. Ardoino announced <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/us-russia-is-using-tether-to-evade-sanctions/">Tether</a> recently developed a tokenization platform which is non-custodial; easy to use and highly configurable; it will be available to the masses. The platform has support for many blockchain networks and a wide range of assets including futures, options, and commodities making it one of the tools that is at the verge of changing the asset control and trade operations in the financial sector.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">GM<br><br>Tether&#39;s tokenisation platform will soon be available to everyone.<br>A masterpiece.<br>Fully non custodial.<br>Multi chain.<br>Multi asset type.<br>Super customizable.<br><br>+T</p>&mdash; Paolo Ardoino 🍐 (@paoloardoino) <a href="https://twitter.com/paoloardoino/status/1779429601707425957?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 14, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Features of the platform</h2>



<p>The feature that attracts many users the most is that it is categorized as non-custodial platform so that they possess all their tokens and do not depend on Tether as their storage provider. Such a feature not only serves to increase the security but also to give the users an absolute ownership and control of everything digital they own in the blockchain.</p>



<p>Another thing of interest is its capability to connect with many chains which further increases its power and gives users the opportunity to pass information on other currencies or blockchains. Much to this, the platform provides a wide customization and supports users to convert it to their special needs from investment, operational and compliance aspects.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">An ecosystem constitutes a digital asset.</h2>



<p>The community&#8217;s ability to leverage Tether&#8217;s platform, in contrast, is expected to importantly define the platform&#8217;s service range and thus, probably its entirety. Besides the dissemination of the sophisticated tokenization functionality, Tether also has a vast appeal to crypto adopters and investors; and is also giving a chance to the non-crypto businesses and enterprises to come acquainted with blockchain technology. This decision will change blockchain technology usage in general, will increase the security of the digital transactions, and will result in higher technologies in crypto assets management.</p>



<p>The most impressive achievement of the cryptocurrency market is the straightforward transition to an open and accessible tokenization platform with Tether deploying the project, which paves the way for more innovative options and services that might be the foundation for brand new applications and cases.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-02.43.15-A-futuristic-digital-command-center-representing-Tethers-new-tokenization-platform.-The-scene-shows-a-high-tech-environment-with-people-interacting-w.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-02.43.15-A-futuristic-digital-command-center-representing-Tethers-new-tokenization-platform.-The-scene-shows-a-high-tech-environment-with-people-interacting-w.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogecoin&#8217;s Co-Founder Responds to Recent Crypto Market Crash</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/dogecoins-co-founder-responds-crypto-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haseeb Shaheen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogecoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Billy Markus who is also known as the &#8216;Shibetoshi Nakamoto&#8217; on social media and is one of the co-creators of DogeCoin recently commented on a very sharp decline in cryptocurrency values of such cryptocurrencies as Bitcoin (BTC), Ethereum (ETH) and Dogecoin (DOGE). It is Markus&#8217; tendency to sarcastically comment on volatile market and he plays [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Billy Markus who is also known as the &#8216;Shibetoshi Nakamoto&#8217; on social media and is one of the co-creators of DogeCoin recently commented on a very sharp decline in cryptocurrency values of such cryptocurrencies as Bitcoin (BTC), Ethereum (ETH) and <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/dogecoin-whales-transfer-massive-amounts/">Dogecoin (DOGE)</a>. It is Markus&#8217; tendency to sarcastically comment on volatile market and he plays a troubled market in a humorous way, his Twitter post during the crash. This post,&#8221; oh no everything died we are dead&#8221; focused on the general nature of people&#8217;s misconceptions about the market, illustrating the overreactions made by investors when major cryptocurrencies underwent massive drops.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">just landed after an 11 hour flight did we all die</p>&mdash; Shibetoshi Nakamoto (@BillyM2k) <a href="https://twitter.com/BillyM2k/status/1779481549286592634?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 14, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Detailing the crash</h2>



<p>The recent decisions which were not expected brought to market drop in value in the top cryptocurrencies. During the course of the last 24 hours, Bitcoin has fallen sharply from the highs of $70,760 to the current level of $67,490, which constitutes about a 7% downwards movement. In the same manner, after a fallover of more than 10% that started from $3,525, Ethereum was trading at $3,161. </p>



<p>Despite a slight recovery that led Ethereum to $3,259 and BTC to $67,472, the sharped decline spilled over into the market with some of the smaller players having to sell their holdings. Cryptocurrency liquidation totaled approximately $735 million overnight in a sign that this downturn has affected everybody regardless of what they trade in.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Venues and the expected BTC halving.</h2>



<p>The timetable of this crash is very interesting as it falls on the brink of the bitcoin halving event which is set to take place on 21st, April. This event, which slashes the number of new bitcoins produced per block by 50%— from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC—is monitored carefully by the crypto community. Conventionally, halving moments usually are digits of rising market mood, mainly, people dream of the same situation. After the recent drop, a correction might take place, potentially leading to an increase after halving. Dogecoin could be one of the crypto’s that profit from this event.</p>



<p>Markus’s remark is simply a short line with the purpose to remind us of us always-present volatility within crypto market combined with humorous portrayal of it, which spice it all up. In light of the coming halving event, his way of thinking provides the community with a distinctively upbeat view from the usual turmoils that continuously rock the virtual crypto world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-01.28.30-A-subtly-abstract-depiction-of-a-scene-representing-a-crypto-enthusiast-responding-to-a-market-crash-without-specific-logos.-The-character-symbolizi.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-01.28.30-A-subtly-abstract-depiction-of-a-scene-representing-a-crypto-enthusiast-responding-to-a-market-crash-without-specific-logos.-The-character-symbolizi.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EigenLayer Launching Its First Decentralized Application EigenDA on Ethereum Mainnet</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/eigenlayer-first-decentralized-app-eigenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haseeb Shaheen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EigenLayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first EigenLayer initiative implemented on one of the biggest keys in the cryptocurrency world is called Available Validator Service (AVS) and is known as EigenDA. It is a huge implication for Ethereum as a project in development. EigenDA does not limit itself to the role of a validator service. It is a new mechanism [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The first EigenLayer initiative implemented on one of the biggest keys in the cryptocurrency world is called Available Validator Service (AVS) and is known as EigenDA. It is a huge implication for Ethereum as a project in development. EigenDA does not limit itself to the role of a validator service. It is a new mechanism that has improved the operation of the Ethereum validation systems as a whole.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="de" dir="ltr">Announcing: EigenLayer ♾ EigenDA Mainnet Launch <a href="https://t.co/bTp5BfnsKE" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/bTp5BfnsKE</a></p>&mdash; EigenLayer (@eigenlayer) <a href="https://twitter.com/eigenlayer/status/1777757913718899074?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 9, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The impact of EigenDA</h2>



<p>At the end of the line, EigenDA has already prompted over 4.1 million ETH staked on <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/eigenlayer-ethereums-ecosystem-six-services/">EigenLayer</a> which is the community&#8217;s indictment of trust and the likelihood of the value of the offered service. To an extent that will astound you, 70% of the newly recognized Ethereum validators have chosen to restake at EigenLayer by giving their assets to the AVS. Being capable of staking is taking advantage of interacting with other protocols with one&#8217;s staking position on Ethereum intact. Such adaptability is of extreme value for backing the main Ethereum chain as well as smaller blockchains running on it that need the highly reliable security layer of Ethereum.</p>



<p>Thus, EigenDA works as a middle layer, attaching itself to Ethereum miners, their tokens, and stakes to back up the next-gen blockchains as they emerge. In doing so, trust and security are increased, and different blockchains are interconnected in a resilient network. This ensures network stability and continuity across the board. This practice additionally covers core elements such as neutrality and decentralization in order to allow anyone to become a staking provider.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Technological advances and needs of the near future</h2>



<p>As well as essential validation services, EigenDA is intended for providing extended scalability, as well as cost-efficiency and ease of integration for various rollup and blockchain applications, and operators. The Relayers or the Rollups, as they are widely popular, are now able to attach to the main EigenDA net effortlessly, thereby increasing the transactions’ potential. A year down the line, this integration will have stabilized, giving way to a more robust cycle of operators and delegators to provide added-value solutions of data storage on Ethereum.</p>



<p>EigenDA and likewise AVS would be developed not only for technical improvement reasons but also to reconfirm Ethereum as a trustworthy and multi-purpose blockchain system. Ethereum&#8217;s staking functionality, deploying approximately a quarter of the entire network circulating supply (32.2 million ETH) in the staking pool, is making a way for EigenDA to wield key influence on the network in a time to come. At the moment, the total value of staked ETH stands higher than $112 billion &#8211; the coin that supports more than one million validators, such fact makes the Ethereum blockchain probably one of the most secure in the whole cryptocurrency industry.</p>



<p>With the advent of crypto and blockchain landscapes turning out to be dynamic, the involvement of creative solutions such as EigenDA will be highly relevant in shaping the destiny of decentralized networks. Lido is today the undisputed Ethereum liquid staking leader with its inventory worth $33.2 billion, or 29% of the total staked amount &#8211; such is a vibrant and competitive landscape that EigenLayer will be entering. That is not only infrastructure improvement but also stimulates the validator services development within the blockchain industry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-01.53.08-A-futuristic-digital-artwork-depicting-the-Ethereum-blockchain-network-with-an-emphasis-on-EigenDA-a-new-decentralized-application.-The-scene-shows-.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-01.53.08-A-futuristic-digital-artwork-depicting-the-Ethereum-blockchain-network-with-an-emphasis-on-EigenDA-a-new-decentralized-application.-The-scene-shows-.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EigenLayer Removes LST Caps: Building block of Ethereum DeFi Ecosystem</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/eigenlayer-lst-caps-building-block-ethereum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haseeb Shaheen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EigenLayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511364</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The implementation of a good update on the Decentralized Exchange (DeFi) of Ethereum Blockchain was introduced by the community governance of EigenLayer, the initiative started by Eigen Lab. All caps on the Liquid Staking Tokens (LST) were removed and depositors were allowed to resume restaking their deposits from the 16th of April. This milestone is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The implementation of a good update on the Decentralized Exchange (DeFi) of Ethereum Blockchain was introduced by the community governance of EigenLayer, the initiative started by Eigen Lab. All caps on the Liquid Staking Tokens (LST) were removed and depositors were allowed to resume restaking their deposits from the 16th of April. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Unpausing Restaking Deposits on April 16th!<br><br>Huge news! EigenLayer is removing ALL LST caps and unpausing deposits starting April 16th, 9:00 AM PST.<a href="https://t.co/wGCs01UDYY" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://t.co/wGCs01UDYY</a></p>&mdash; EigenLayer (@eigenlayer) <a href="https://twitter.com/eigenlayer/status/1778885106960081116?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">April 12, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>This milestone is a worthy one for EigenLayer because, among others, it is the sign of completion of the project phases and that may be seen as a major project of the year of crypto. The removal of the stocking limit time constraints is forecasted to facilitate a more self-sustaining system and more dynamism in staking. Therefore, larger number of participants within the system will be generated and this will result in more chances for them.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Enhancing stability and growth</h2>



<p>The scheme of EigenLayer&#8217;s evolution is composed to drive stability and build up the platform ecosystem around Ethereum. Thus, the initial period is reflected through stages 1, 2, and 3, which are the vital days of the system that involved the positive development of restakers, operators, AVSs (Actively Validated Services), and rollups. Contrastively, the previous LST cap, which meant less room for the network to grow, is now the promoter of the activation of the network and also, because the protocol awards try to balance the neutrality and the decentralization at the network, by suggesting a 33% cap for users.</p>



<p>The methodology thus conceived by EigenLayer will effectively mean that the same ETH staked now can be repurposed or used to safeguard other parts of the ecosystem as well. The idea of cryptography security another setting emerges in Ethereum main chain. The protocol has already received 3,880,000 ETH (equivalent to $12,670,000,000 of market value) to be staked by restakers meaning that the number of these stakers is only growing as the protocol becomes more relevant to them. The employment of main players such as Coinbase Staking as operators highlight the oncoming restaking industry faith, however, supervisory activities must also be on top of it, since its rapid growth gives way to financial and security risks.</p>



<p>The fundraising program of EigenLayer does not only serve as the reinforcement of Ethereum network but it also initiates simpler infrastructure for the development of decentralized and permissionless apps based on Ethereum network. This definitely may have strong influence within the entire DeFi domain, and can as a result result in advancement of more precise security solutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-02.06.45-A-conceptual-representation-of-the-EigenDA-application-on-the-Ethereum-Mainnet-depicted-as-a-futuristic-cityscape.-The-scene-shows-a-bustling-digital.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-15-02.06.45-A-conceptual-representation-of-the-EigenDA-application-on-the-Ethereum-Mainnet-depicted-as-a-futuristic-cityscape.-The-scene-shows-a-bustling-digital.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>West Africa&#8217;s economy has never been as bad as it is right now</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/west-africas-economy-doing-so-bad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jai Hamid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 20:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[West Africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[West Africa is currently enduring a severe economic crunch, with a sharp rise in hunger among its populace. The World Food Program estimates that nearly 55 million people in the region will soon face difficulties feeding themselves, marking a 12% increase over last year and 4 million more than earlier forecasts. This crisis is propelled [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>West Africa is currently enduring a severe economic crunch, with a sharp rise in hunger among its populace. The World Food Program estimates that nearly 55 million people in the region will soon face difficulties feeding themselves, marking a 12% increase over last year and 4 million more than earlier forecasts. </p>



<p>This crisis is propelled by rampant inflation and significant currency devaluations.</p>



<p>Trade sanctions on military regimes are also making things worse, aggravating the food shortage, as stated in a recent announcement by a United Nations agency. Ollo Sib, a senior researcher at WFP, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-12/inflation-economic-turmoil-drive-west-african-food-crisis?srnd=undefined&amp;embedded-checkout=true" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">pointed out</a>, &#8220;The economic situation is now a major force driving the food crisis, especially in countries like <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/its-time-we-talk-about-nigeria-and-its-naira/" data-type="post" data-id="511215">Nigeria</a>, Ghana, and Sierra Leone, where inflation hits hardest.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Rising Costs and Economic Policies</h3>



<p>Staple grain prices have soared to ten times their five-year average due to the plummeting value of local currencies and escalated fuel and transport costs. This year, the region faces a daunting 12 million ton deficit in cereal production. Pandemic-era restrictions on food exports have also hampered trade, reducing food availability. Sib elaborated, &#8220;The spike in food and transportation costs is creating a long-term impact, as all these countries depend on imported food.&#8221;</p>



<p>Nigeria, the most populous country in Africa, reports over 26 million people struggling with food security, up from 25 million last year. Eastern Chad, usually sufficient in food, now reports record food insecurity levels due to the influx of refugees escaping the civil war in Sudan.</p>



<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has called on Nigeria to urgently address its escalating food insecurity, with nearly 10% of its population affected. The country&#8217;s ongoing economic reforms, such as eliminating fuel subsidies and loosening currency controls—though popular with investors—have accelerated inflation to the highest rate in nearly 30 years.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Economic Performance and Projections</h3>



<p>The IMF stresses, &#8220;Addressing rising food insecurity is now a critical policy priority.&#8221; Nigeria&#8217;s recent move to implement a cash transfer system for vulnerable households is a significant step, though its success depends on effective implementation. Amid a food price inflation rate of 35.4%, Nigeria has seen protests and looting in various parts, including Abuja. Over 40% of its population lives in extreme poverty.</p>



<p>To combat inflation and stabilize the currency, Nigeria’s central bank has increased interest rates to a record 22.75%. The naira has lost about 70% of its value against the dollar since mid-2023. More hikes in borrowing costs are expected.</p>



<p>The World Bank has flagged that sluggish growth in Nigeria could dampen the entire sub-region&#8217;s economic outlook. The lender&#8217;s report predicts an increase in economic activity in Western and Central Africa, from 3.2% in 2023 to 3.7% in 2024, and further to 4.2% by 2025–2026. However, growth is hindered by Nigeria&#8217;s lower-than-average performance. Excluding Nigeria, the sub-region could grow by 4.4% in 2024 and 5% in 2025–2026.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the West African Economic and Monetary Union is expected to see growth rates of 5.9% in 2024 and 6.2% in 2025, bolstered by strong economic activities in Benin, Côte d&#8217;Ivoire, Niger, and Senegal. </p>



<p>The World Bank notes that Nigeria’s growth is anticipated at 3.3% in 2024 and 3.6% in the following years, as reforms slowly take effect. It also expects a stabilization in the oil sector with a recovery in production and slightly lower prices, leading to a more stable macroeconomic environment and sustained growth in the non-oil economy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-13-22.53.41-Create-a-powerful-and-evocative-image-that-visually-represents-the-current-economic-struggles-of-West-Africa.-The-image-features-a-dark-stormy-sky-ov.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/DALL·E-2024-04-13-22.53.41-Create-a-powerful-and-evocative-image-that-visually-represents-the-current-economic-struggles-of-West-Africa.-The-image-features-a-dark-stormy-sky-ov.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI and Behavioral Science: A Unified Path to Innovation</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-and-behavioral-science-a-unified-path/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Mawira]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 20:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Innovators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Consequently, tech development benefits a wider range of analysis and social relativity techniques. Thus, the intertwining of AI and behavioral science infers that the future will depend on our will, meaning what we want out of life largely depends on all of us.&#160; Some things were presented in a movie adapted from the book Consilience, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Consequently, tech development benefits a wider range of analysis and social relativity techniques. Thus, the intertwining of <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/poll-related-information-in-kadapa-andhra/">AI</a> and behavioral science infers that the future will depend on our will, meaning what we want out of life largely depends on all of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some things were presented in a movie adapted from the book Consilience, chapter “Consilience,” where Edward O. Wilson brilliantly demonstrated the disciplines that sometimes are basically in the conflict in the book. This was the way of “joining disciplines” into a single scientific explanation of human existence, and the social complexities of evolution were shown. </p>



<p>Nevertheless, it is just a step towards smart dawn that raises many questions, the foremost of which is which roads are most likely to be followed. The other thing is that new marketing channels will cause automation promotion and behavioral decision-making. Also, the legality issue should not be overlooked because such an invention will surely make the world look quite different.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Unlocking insights: Behavioral data analysis</h2>



<p>Despite this fact, it is necessary to analyze the potential of AI in its capability of filling the huge void of behavioral data that cannot be disclosed as the very first and the very primary prerequisite that gives AI the ability to obtain amazingly accurate details of human life that the human eye just can not see. Regarding the novelty characteristics of AI, after the appearance of AI artifacts, the development of AI beings commences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If I were to name the AI artifacts that are AI&#8217;s offspring, I would call them AI child offspring. Another significant power for organizations is enriching the employees with knowledge and advanced things and selecting the topmost services. In computer science, using examples, they will be process-oriented and learned. They will also be grounded on rules and may be used for student studies or data processing.</p>



<p>Employing sensory science provides the means to influence the audience via sensory strategies that involve much of the central system or directly invoke psychological motivators, social units, and social facilitators.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The general outcome of these efforts is to hold each trait of <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/russian-oil-refineries-hit-ai-drones-threat/">AI</a>, ranging from artificial neural networks to machine vision or natural language processors, which improves the AI&#8217;s analytical powers. This can give customers highly sophisticated information that contrasts with operations and strategies presented in their businesses, boosting innovation and company growth.</p>



<p>People of this type were turning to progressively greater assimilation, resulting in the abundant wasting of their time and effort to only some small parts. It is also not to forget that the aim of today&#8217;s psychological content is devoid of the element of humanness. Psychology may be like a preventive mental health action with a mission to protect people’s welfare and the environment from harmful substances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Health instruction is an example of a system that, rather than allowing people to go on any sabotage, saves them in healthy ways to improve their mental health and apply customization and personalization, which are beneficial. In other words, despite a considerable gap (a result of the different number of years), we can recognize many similarities between the mankind of the past and us.</p>



<p>Mobile skills, combined with human mindset knowledge, make more complicated activities for psychologists – such as robot developers engaged in interventions and change corrections – and those organizations hire most often to introduce changes that will improve workplace satisfaction. This is also true because such changes will make the employees much more satisfied and depressed to a lesser extent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While these people whose lives are not just giving a pace as well as the progress of the universe, unending progress, and at the same time those people who are left abruptly are alone, it is a large number for that society. The two cases of society depicting the consequences of the revolt are the collapse of the societal arrangements and the order in the society being restored.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ethical integration: Ensuring human-centric AI</h2>



<p>Therefore, socially, the parts of the technology could be paired up in progress. Besides, modern bioethics will have to tackle moral issues that are more holistic than they used to. Therefore, the ethical engine somewhat inserts ethics when the ethics that AI has to adhere to by default are included in the condition of the machine’s operation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For society, a well-defined societal order and law would be the priority so that the immigration of people with different lifestyles and ways of living into the new environment could be smooth and easy. Finally, science deals with psychology, the domain we humans already know from the core. Furthermore, the other main constituents of such ethical science are the establishment of philosophy, the cognitive moral processes, and the social moral norms, which are undoubtedly of great value/significance.</p>



<p>Briefly, AI applications can even solve specific business ethics; so to speak, they can solve even ethical problems at an atomic scale. Similarly, presenting ethics&#8217; value and role while dealing with behavioral science during development will be a stepping stone toward more opportunities. </p>



<p>Last but not least is the issue of bias in algorithmic decision-making, which can, however, be successfully resolved with the following: Values-based AI, on the other hand, through the utilization of their lives to enhance the efforts aimed at diagnosis and finding solutions for more civility in the world, would always expect that peace had been well-maintained.</p>



<p>Artificial intelligence and behavioral science raise the speculative question: will we need people to use such devices with computers only managing the process helped with the data? AI and BD-oriented smart systems would be helpful for the administration in their quick assessment and in understanding the similar feelings of people undergoing different moods, especially the situations that would be politically transparent as to how they influence family life and society in general.</p>



<p>The sign on the door can say &#8216;Man-machine relationship&#8217; or &#8216;Man and machine.&#8217; However, this journey is also very interesting and sometimes challenging because many people have recently tried to figure out this connection between humans and machines. Our pondering about that can eventually grow to the scale of the universe, which is non-linear and full of chaos and freedom. </p>



<p>This may even result in a kind of foresight on the part of the companies that launch their naturalistic creations as a means of acquiring something deeper. This development comes with an economy of machines that excel in automation, and additionally, their manner of processing and production has become the season-controlling idea. Humans pull forward and rebuild their lives after the tragedy through this approach.</p>



<p>This article originally appeared in the<a href="https://www.incafrica.com/library/nick-hobson-im-a-psychologist-heres-1-thing-ai-is-missing?source_category=technology" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> Inc.Africa</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_AI_and_Behavioral_Science_A_Unified_Path_to_Innovation_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_AI_and_Behavioral_Science_A_Unified_Path_to_Innovation_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Tool &#8220;Election Mitra&#8221; Streamlines Access to Poll-Related Information in Kadapa, Andhra Pradesh</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/poll-related-information-in-kadapa-andhra/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benson Mawira]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 19:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Innovators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kadapa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Primarily, Kadapa Police successfully demonstrated their potential by implementing the latest technology, AI, and survey express application, which allows local people, specifically voters, to find their polling address. Where A.I. election aid tasks such as unexpressed expressions that a person is depressed or suicidal, and these expressions are the core reasons the elections came to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Primarily, Kadapa Police successfully demonstrated their potential by implementing the latest technology, <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ai-threatens-top-executives-survey-of-600-ceos-reveals/">AI</a>, and survey express application, which allows local people, specifically voters, to find their polling address. Where A.I. election aid tasks such as unexpressed expressions that a person is depressed or suicidal, and these expressions are the core reasons the elections came to light were the main priorities. It is vital to reach out to more people, educating them about voting day and discussing the election system and results because we do this through straightforward inquiries.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Efficient information retrieval</h2>



<p>Assume that Election Mitra is the research body for the documentary. AI allows us to hack data systems and filter data by authorizing us to review the source database we managed to collect. Now, the actual method of this process is that it renders this data functionally unintelligible for anyone attempting to decrypt it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The pamphlets depict printed material of RULs with textbooks and images, which have proven to be an insightful glimpse into the trends in this fashion world market. We propose employing AI systems like self-governing and fact-checking services to ensure that Election Mitra provides proper and relevant solutions to the voters quickly, specifically during the election season. Electors won&#8217;t read such debates that are election-oriented when they can sooner reach articles in an easy form, and that accentuates.</p>



<p>The array of problems that of the purpose of &#8220;Election Mitra&#8221; is not limited to local bodies; however, it also provides its members with the acts drafted by governmental bodies and the speeches of different civil organizations for the construction of a fair society by skill the gap between electorate and politician this will be done through the adoption of different clauses. He will put it that way: the Atrocity Acts for SC/ST, people&#8217;s Representation, and Excise Acts will be among the few debated in this session.</p>



<p>As training progresses through layers of simple to complex, the learner is provided with a guided model police agency even where issues span different fields and sciences, including problem areas like data disruptions and disciplines, among other fields. Mitra, the impartial universal housing location that deals with many other issues related to the last elections, will surely be your new cool place that will push your information to those you don’t know.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">User-friendly interface</h2>



<p>On the other hand, personalized software is developed to provide the voters with a simple and easy operation, which is fulfilled by the offering of an interface that gives a chance to people with different knowledge levels to have a role in the whole thing by way of creating the interface being friendly to the users which is understandable and easy to use will be done by creating the platform of interaction which is friendly to the people with access to various skills Thus, the function of navigating will be supported mainly by screens in devices rather than burdening the user’s mind when she is using desktop and her pocket device.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Visuals that do not have a tone that is too ‘corporate-like’ and are a ‘simple’ platform meet this one criterion: the learning process should be effortless. With a Live active learning model being discussed, the few crucial parts, such as the sentiment analysis piece of the application, are having the intelligent reply with the sentence that making the application does not have to deal with boring content for the users.</p>



<p>The period called Election Mitra is solely focused on making a section of the future process that will eventually be accessible to many people so that they have just mobile phones to know the necessary election data. Like bookshops, these online facilities help restrict the reach of reading material to different book genres for some people and just position their readers&#8217; large appetites with the different makes available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thus, the connection between peace deputies and individuals grows, thus humanizing the police, electoral bodies, and political parties. With this <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/intel-unveils-gaudi-3-to-bridge-ai-tech/">technology</a>, the people can now understand the elections&#8217; rules and, simultaneously, give the officials a chance to conduct the elections on time. In Weinstock, Weiber, and Vindel &#8216;s words, electoral management is an instrument of transformation of democracy. Consequently, it cannot take place due to the operational objectives of a polity as it is citizens-oriented, transparent, or accountable.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Future prospects</h2>



<p>A major part of what charges the mobile app called the Election Mitra is the awesome public openness towards using the app. Also, the more the app picks up and gets a gripping following, the more it boasts the app development company to add more features to the liking of political parties. On the other hand, the midterm electoral report will include newswire reports and presentations about the election process, election procedures, and the admission of polling booth locations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Furthermore, e-modules will be woven into the talk to improve the understanding process, and the concept idea will be presented apart from the accountability. On top of this, incorporating the element of the &#8220;human&#8221; facet to the &#8220;will of the Election Mitra&#8221; is tasked with humanizing it. Therefore, the allegiance of Kadapa voters to its essence and processes will be cultivated. Being a media for the entire electoral conduct of Kadapa, the radio is thus expected to aid in various aspects of the future electoral conduct. At the same time, it may be applied in such a way as to overshadow most of the known conduct of elections.</p>



<p>Subsequently, the model of a new Police station serving the district of Kadapa has been built on the principle of new concept innovation, the process of which will be vaulted and supported by the policy-makers who are willing to step another stage forward in the bottled ballot, meaning that an election will be opened in Maavra, another place in which the whole process will start. The wide range of issues presented as arguments may be varied in information; still, there is a spreading of views during this point that needs to be considered. </p>



<p>This element is the key factor that generates a source of sustaining and encouraging all the stakeholders, empowering and activating them to make it possible and maintain democracy. The infrastructure will be user-oriented and unified – so the users can grasp the idea of compactly campaigning as a whole. This kind of innovation provides us with a space arch, which is the goal of society, and current politics are factors that will affect the further advancement of the platform. Upshot: The tactic I consider is the end-user&#8217;s convenience, and you should ensure the interface is used comfortably and conveniently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whatever the plan, be it a solvable problem, it will never remain with holes or loopholes. Whatever the loopholes are, all the good ideas, if not all, will be used to develop a plan for implementing good strategies and removing the problems from the community.<br></p>



<p>This article originally appeared in the <a href="https://www.deccanherald.com/india/andhra-pradesh/andhra-pradesh-police-develops-ai-tool-to-answer-poll-related-queries-2977798" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Deccan Herald</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_specifically_voters_to_find_their_polling_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_specifically_voters_to_find_their_polling_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solana experiences price slump as open interest sheds $440 million</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/solana-price-slump-sheds-440-million/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Owotunse Adebayo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 19:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptomarket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=511316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The price of Solana has fallen sharply, showing the current trend in the cryptocurrency market. Consequently, open interest in Solana has also followed the trend of the digital asset. According to data from CoinGlass, open interest in Solana is down by 21% at $1.6 billion in the last 24 hours. Solana price slump leads to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The price of Solana has fallen sharply, showing the current trend in the cryptocurrency market. Consequently, open interest in Solana has also followed the trend of the digital asset. According to data from CoinGlass, open interest in Solana is down by 21% at $1.6 billion in the last 24 hours.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Solana price slump leads to drop in open interest</h2>



<p>Open Interest is the total value of Solana Futures contracts across exchanges yet to be settled. Presently, Solana is down by 11%, trading around $136 according to <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/solana" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">data</a> from CoinGecko.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1136" height="445" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7748.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-511321" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7748.jpeg 1136w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7748-300x118.jpeg 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7748-768x301.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1136px) 100vw, 1136px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">                                   <strong>Solana futures open interest. Source: CoinGlass</strong></figcaption></figure>



<p>The drastic slide in the price of Solana also erased long positions held by traders worth around $36.55 million. The affected traders anticipate the asset’s massive price spike before the upcoming Bitcoin halving.</p>



<p>The bearish trend in the market is also obvious in the performance of other cryptocurrencies in the top 10. XRP experienced a drop of about 12.12% with Dogecoin following closely with a 10.86% drop in the last 24 hours. Cardano also dropped by 10.20%. Despite the market being volatile, traders are still confident about the overall outlook in the coming days.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Traders and analysts discuss their perspectives</h2>



<p>The general market decline has also led popular traders and analysts to urge investors to scale into tokens with high convictions. Others also think this is the best opportunity to hold spot positions and not capitulate. Popular trader GCRClassic <a href="https://x.com/GCRClassic/status/1779266762493563303" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">advised</a> traders on X to see out the market turbulence and not be shaken out as the future is still bright.</p>



<p>Furthermore, some traders feel that the change in the fortunes of altcoins is closer than most people feel. For example, crypto entrepreneur Kyle Chasse expects a surge of about 20-30% in the altcoins market by Monday. However, analysis firm Glassnode has <a href="https://x.com/glassnode/status/1778798514639634583" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">noted</a> that this might not be the case due to the trend of Bitcoin drops in previous market cycles. The firm also explained that traders have always used that as an indicator to assess the rest of the market.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7744.jpeg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7744.jpeg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
