<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<description>Neutral and Authentic News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:02:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/cropped-Dark_CP_Symbol-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cryptopolitan</title>
	<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Price Prediction 2024-2033: Will Bitcoin Bulls Rally?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/bitcoin-price-forecast/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shayan Chowdhury]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto Price Predictions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Industry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=84135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BTC Price Predictions 2024-2033 How much is Bitcoin (BTC) worth? Today, the price of Bitcoin stands at $61,896, with a trading volume over the past 24 hours reaching $24 billion. Its market capitalization is $1.3 trillion, and it currently commands 54% of the market share. Over the last 24 hours, the BTC price has experienced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3 class="wp-block-heading">BTC Price Predictions 2024-2033</h3>



<ul>
<li><a href="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2023" data-type="internal" data-id="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2023">B</a><a href="#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2024" data-type="internal" data-id="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2023">itcoin Price Prediction 2024 &#8211; up to <strong>$1,10,203</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2027" data-type="internal" data-id="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2026">Bitcoin Price Prediction 2027 &#8211; up to <strong>$3,43,302</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2029" data-type="internal" data-id="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2029">Bitcoin Price Prediction 20</a><a href="#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2030" data-type="internal" data-id="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2029">30 </a><a href="#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2029" data-type="internal" data-id="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2029">&#8211; up to <strong>$11,22,987</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2033" data-type="internal" data-id="#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2032">Bitcoin Price Prediction 2033- up to <strong>$31,09,892</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How much is Bitcoin (BTC) worth?</h3>



<p>Today, the price of Bitcoin stands at $61,896, with a trading volume over the past 24 hours reaching $24 billion. Its market capitalization is $1.3 trillion, and it currently commands 54% of the market share. Over the last 24 hours, the BTC price has experienced a 1.2% increase. As for its circulating supply, 19.46 million BTC are in circulation out of a maximum possible supply of 21 million BTC.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin price analysis: BTC price declined heavily as it dropped below $60K</h2>



<p><strong>TL; DR Breakdown</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>BTC price analysis shows that Bitcoin faced a bearish pattern as the price dropped below $60K</li>



<li>Resistance for BTC is present at $64,438</li>



<li>Support for BTC/USD is present at $59,771</li>
</ul>



<p>The BTC price analysis for 19 April confirms that bears sparked a solid selling pressure as BTC price plunged buying confidence by heading below the $60K mark. However, BTC price is facing a minor upward correction now.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">BTC price analysis 1-day chart: Bitcoin price faces intense bearish pressure</h3>



<p>Analyzing the daily price chart of Bitcoin, BTC’s price faced a robust selling pressure as the price continued to decline below immediate Fib channels and headed below the $60K level. However, the price quickly rebounded and gained the $63K level. The 24-hour volume has surged to $22 million, showing an increased interest in trading activity today. BTC price is currently trading at $61,896, increasing by over 1.2% in the last 24 hours.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1200" height="524" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-49-00-1200x524.png" alt="" class="wp-image-513582" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-49-00-1200x524.png 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-49-00-300x131.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-49-00-768x335.png 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-49-00-1536x670.png 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-49-00.png 1815w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure>



<p>The RSI-14 trend line has declined from its previous level and currently trades below the midline at level 40, hinting that a bearish pressure is on the edge. The SMA-14 level suggests volatility in the next few hours.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">BTC/USD 4-hour price chart: Bulls aim for an immediate correction above moving averages</h3>



<p>The 4-hour Bitcoin price chart suggests that bears are strengthening their position as they are aiming to send the price below the Fib lines. However, bulls are maintaining buying confidence and are aiming to hold the price above the EMA20 trend line.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="524" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_12-31-55-1200x524.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-513583" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_12-31-55-1200x524.jpg 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_12-31-55-300x131.jpg 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_12-31-55-768x335.jpg 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_12-31-55-1536x671.jpg 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_12-31-55.jpg 1814w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure>



<p>The BoP indicator is trading in a positive region at 0.91, showing that short-term buyers are taking a chance to accelerate an upward trend.</p>



<p>Additionally, the MACD trend line has formed bullish candles above the signal line and the indicator aims for a positive momentum, strengthening long-position holders’ confidence.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What to expect from BTC price analysis next?</h3>



<p>The hourly price chart confirms that Bitcoin attempts to drop below the immediate support line; however, bulls are eyeing for further recovery rally in the upcoming hours. If BTC’s price successfully holds its momentum above $64,438, it will fuel a bullish rally to $68,705.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="524" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-47-36-1200x524.png" alt="" class="wp-image-513584" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-47-36-1200x524.png 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-47-36-300x131.png 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-47-36-768x335.png 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-47-36-1536x670.png 1536w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-19_11-47-36.png 1815w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure>



<p>If bulls fail to initiate a surge, BTC price may drop below the immediate support line at $59,771, which may begin a bearish trend to $53,746.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Bitcoin A Good Investment? </h2>



<p>Bitcoin has historically presented the opportunity for significant returns due to its decentralized nature. Bitcoin also holds the potential to act as an asset that does not correlate with the broader market trends, akin to gold. This characteristic suggests that it could move independently of other assets such as stocks. Additionally, the recent launch of spot Bitcoin ETFs has made it a good investment option with bright market potential. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recent BTC News/Opinions</h2>



<p><strong>Blackrock&#8217;s IBIT</strong>: Blackrock has a Bitcoin fund called the Ishares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT). This fund, which deals with Bitcoin directly, has increased its Bitcoin holdings to more than 252,011 BTC. This means the fund&#8217;s Bitcoin is worth about $18 billion now. There&#8217;s a big increase in interest from small investors, more than what Blackrock&#8217;s boss thought would happen.</p>



<p><strong>Morgan Stanley In Bitcoin ETF</strong>: Morgan Stanley is planning to add Bitcoin funds to its brokerage platform. This comes after the SEC approved spot Bitcoin ETF in January.</p>



<p><strong>SEC Approves Spot Bitcoin ETF:</strong> The U.S. has approved spot Bitcoin ETF. The Securities and Exchange Commission announced this decision on 11 January.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Predictions 2024-2033</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Price Predictions By Cryptopolitan</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/4BqshIwugq7JHdvwYuK5HT71ZAVufDGUllcVDvSF7JaEr_Ks9ANXsouVL5H9lNO0BLjWVsnq_xO4dfS9J7NhCTQIDAjTa4MkMp5djwFYStJCYJusc8oTP_GkKpflV1e7Y_-JRlsJZH_mvmk_IGlfPlA" alt="" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td>Year</td><td>Minimum ($)</td><td>Average ($)</td><td>Maximum ($)</td></tr><tr><td>2024</td><td>93,269.00</td><td>96,768.00</td><td>1,10,203.00</td></tr><tr><td>2025</td><td>1,35,384.00</td><td>1,39,255.00</td><td>1,58,198.00</td></tr><tr><td>2026</td><td>1,95,360.00</td><td>2,02,323.00</td><td>2,39,224.00</td></tr><tr><td>2027</td><td>2,92,569.00</td><td>3,02,686.00</td><td>3,43,302.00</td></tr><tr><td>2028</td><td>4,36,287.00</td><td>4,48,394.00</td><td>5,08,574.00</td></tr><tr><td>2029</td><td>6,33,596.00</td><td>6,51,532.00</td><td>7,60,170.00</td></tr><tr><td>2030</td><td>8,93,504.00</td><td>9,19,565.00</td><td>11,22,987.00</td></tr><tr><td>2031</td><td>12,90,182.00</td><td>13,36,160.00</td><td>15,24,028.00</td></tr><tr><td>2032</td><td>18,50,345.00</td><td>19,03,792.00</td><td>22,29,599.00</td></tr><tr><td>2033</td><td>26,17,633.00</td><td>27,12,822.00</td><td>31,09,892.00</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction 2024</h4>



<p>The BTC price is expected to hit a minimum of $93,269 in 2024, with the potential to reach up to $110,203. The average price forecast stands at $96,768.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction 2025</h4>



<p>The forecast for 2025 suggests Bitcoin could reach a low of $135,384 and may climb to a high of $158,198, with an average price of $139,255.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">BTC Price Forecast for 2026</h4>



<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s value in 2026 is anticipated to fall not lower than $195,360, with a ceiling of $239,224. The expected average price is $202,323.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin (BTC) Price Prediction 2027</h4>



<p>In 2027, Bitcoin is forecasted to have a minimum price of $292,569 and may reach a maximum of $343,302, averaging at $302,686.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction 2028</h4>



<p>Predictions for 2028 indicate a minimum Bitcoin price of $436,287, with the potential for a high of $508,574. The average price is expected to be $448,394.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction 2029</h4>



<p>The minimum price for Bitcoin in 2029 is forecasted at $633,596, with a maximum potential of $760,170. The average price is anticipated to be $651,532.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin (BTC) Price Prediction 2030</h4>



<p>For 2030, Bitcoin is expected to reach a minimum of $893,504 and could rise to $1,122,987, with an average trading price of $919,565.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Forecast 2031</h4>



<p>By 2031, Bitcoin&#8217;s price could hit a minimum of $1,290,182 and a maximum of $1,524,028, with the average price projected at $1,336,160.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin (BTC) Price Prediction 2032</h4>



<p>The forecast for 2032 suggests a minimum price of $1,850,345 for Bitcoin, with a potential high of $2,229,599. The average price is expected to be $1,903,792.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction 2033</h4>



<p>In 2033, Bitcoin&#8217;s price is predicted to be at least $2,617,633, with the possibility of reaching $3,109,892. The average trading value is forecasted at $2,712,822.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction By Coincodex</h3>



<p>According to the current Bitcoin price prediction by Coincodex, it is forecasted that the price of Bitcoin will increase by 27.37% to reach $89,852 by May 1, 2024. Technical indicators suggest a bullish sentiment, while the Fear &amp; Greed Index indicates extreme greed at a level of 79.</p>



<p>Over the past 30 days, Bitcoin has seen 17 out of 30 days (57%) in the green, with a price volatility of 4.18%. Coincodex&#8217;s forecast suggests that it is currently a favorable time to purchase Bitcoin. Reflecting on historical price trends and BTC halving cycles, Coincodex estimates the yearly low for Bitcoin in 2025 to be around $71,247, with a potential high reaching up to $160,024 the following year.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction By Digital Coin Price</h3>



<p>According to Digital Coin Price, there is a forecast suggesting that Bitcoin could surpass the $181,098.63 mark and sustain its market position by the end of 2025. It is estimated that the lowest Bitcoin price may range between $151,521.25 and $181,098.63, with the most probable price stabilizing at approximately $165,414.37 by the close of 2025. Despite the significant fluctuations in its value and the debates over its environmental impact due to energy consumption, billionaire venture capitalist Tim Draper maintains his forecast that Bitcoin will hit $181,098.63 by the end of 2025 or early in the year.</p>



<p>Further predictions by Digital Coin Price indicate that by 2032, Bitcoin&#8217;s price could minimally reach $968,037.25, with an average trading price throughout the year of $999,217.60, potentially peaking at $1,013,559.06. Experts from Digital Coin Price anticipate the maximum trading price to hover around $999,217.60.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Price Prediction By CryptoPredictions.com</h3>



<p>Cryptopredictions.com forecasts that Bitcoin will begin May 2024 at a value of $51,587.956 and conclude the month at $51,833.923. Throughout May, the maximum projected BTC price is anticipated to reach $68,302.039, while the minimum price could drop to $46,445.386.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">BTC Price Overview</h2>



<p>The price of Bitcoin had experienced notable peaks and troughs in its value. Despite this volatility, the unique nature of the Bitcoin network and its limited supply of coins has attracted the attention of investors and traders worldwide. The blockchain technology underlying Bitcoin enables secure and transparent transactions without the need for intermediaries, making it an attractive alternative to traditional financial systems.</p>



<p>In recent years, Bitcoin has trended upwards, with significant increases in value occurring in 2017 and 2021. This growth has been driven by a variety of factors, including increased adoption and acceptance of Bitcoin as a form of payment, as well as speculation by investors and traders. Today, Bitcoin is trading at +56654654.6% above its all-time low in July 2010.</p>



<p>While the future of Bitcoin&#8217;s price remains uncertain, many experts predict that the trend towards increased adoption and acceptance of digital currencies will continue to drive demand for Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">BTC Price history</h2>



<p>Bitcoin’s (BTC) price again reached an all-time high in 2021, as values exceeded over 65,000 USD in November 2021. That particular price hike was connected to the launch of a Bitcoin ETF in the United States, whilst others in 2021 were due to events involving Tesla and Coinbase, respectively.</p>



<p>Tesla’s announcement in March 2021 that it had acquired 1.5 billion U.S. dollars worth of the digital coin fueled mass interest.&nbsp; The market was noticeably different by the end of 2022, however, with Bitcoin prices reaching roughly $17194.91 as of January 10, 2023, after another crypto exchange, FTX, filed for bankruptcy.</p>



<p>Large BTC holders – ‘whales’ – are said to make up two percent of anonymous ownership accounts, and own approx 92 percent of BTC. As most people who use cryptocurrency-related services worldwide are retail clients rather than institutional investors, Bitcoin prices are difficult to measure, as movements from one large whale already have a significant impact on this market.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on Bitcoin</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is Bitcoin?</h3>



<p>Launched in 2009, Bitcoin is a decentralized digital currency powered by blockchain technology. Satoshi Nakamoto created the coin to overcome the shortcomings of government-issued currencies without requiring a controlling authority.</p>



<p>Bitcoin (BTC) was created out of the need for a cryptography-based e-payment system rather than the conventional trust-based system. Cryptocurrency acts as a store of value and a payment method for any transaction process in the crypto space. It is often dubbed &#8220;digital gold.&#8221;</p>



<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s current cryptography is based on an impenetrable algorithm (SHA-256) designed by the United States National Security Agency (NSA) in 2016, after the collapse of the SHA-1 algorithm. This algorithm makes it impossible to crack the Bitcoin network.</p>



<p>Since the launch of Bitcoin in 2009, its value has risen dramatically, from less than 0.01 USD in May 2010 to over 67,000 USD in November 2021. Bitcoin is expected to attain newer feats in the coming years as more institutional investors and traders continue to turn to cryptocurrency.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What Influences Bitcoin&#8217;s Price?</h3>



<p>The world&#8217;s premier cryptocurrency, Bitcoin, has recently taken a substantial hit, dipping below the $25.5K threshold and reaching its lowest value in three months. This downward trend follows a lawsuit initiated by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) against Binance, a leading cryptocurrency exchange, and its founder and CEO, Changpeng Zhao (CZ).</p>



<p>The news of this legal dispute sparked a swift wave of Bitcoin selling, causing a ripple effect across the majority of other cryptocurrencies. The market strain has escalated as the SEC has expanded its legal pursuits to encompass Coinbase, another key contender in the cryptocurrency exchange market.</p>



<p>Crypto experts posit that if Bitcoin can hold its resistance level at $26,000, we might see a bounce back in the coming months. However, if this level is breached, Bitcoin could potentially tumble to its lowest ever value of $20,000.</p>



<p>Yet, the experts also caution that the current rise in interest rates and a more stringent monetary policy might hinder Bitcoin from making a significant recovery in the near term.</p>



<p>Despite these hurdles, the year 2023 holds promise for Bitcoin advocates who see it as a &#8220;digital safe-haven&#8221; or &#8220;virtual gold&#8221;. These enthusiasts are confident that Bitcoin can offer investors a substantial hedge or attractive yields during periods of market instability.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Challenges</h3>



<p>Despite its success, Bitcoin has faced several criticisms, especially its energy-hungry mining system. According to an energy consumption tracker developed by the University of Cambridge, Bitcoin mining was estimated to consume 100 TWh per year, about one-third of the UK&#8217;s total energy consumption in 2016.</p>



<p>In addition, BTC&#8217;s criminality potential has positioned it for more scrutiny, as it has facilitated numerous dark web dealings, such as acquiring illegal weapons, money laundering, etc.</p>



<p>The most significant and long-standing challenge of Bitcoin is scalability. Bitcoin&#8217;s underlying technology limits its performance in terms of transaction completion timeframe, with an insufficient capacity of 3-7 TPS. As more transactions are initiated on the network, processing delays will surface. Several proposals have been put forward to nip this concern in the bud, but a favorable long-term fix remains unclear.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How do you buy and sell Bitcoin?</h3>



<p>You can buy and sell Bitcoin through cryptocurrency exchanges or peer-to-peer platforms. To purchase Bitcoin, you typically need to create an account with a cryptocurrency exchange, fund your account, and place an order to buy Bitcoin.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is Bitcoin&#8217;s role in the broader financial system?</h3>



<p>Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies are seen by some as a disruptive force that could challenge traditional financial systems and provide greater financial freedom and autonomy for users.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Where to store Bitcoin?</h3>



<p>The best ways to store Bitcoin include hardware wallets, paper wallets, and software wallets. Hardware wallets are considered the most secure, as they store private keys offline and require physical confirmation of transactions. Paper wallets, which involve printing out private keys and keeping them in a secure location, are also considered secure but require careful handling. Software wallets, which run on computers or mobile devices, are a great option, but more vulnerable to hacking and malware attacks.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What drives the value of BTC?</h3>



<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s value is determined by supply and demand factors, such as market sentiment, adoption rates, regulatory changes, and investor speculation. Bitcoin&#8217;s decentralized nature, scarcity, and high-security features also contribute to its value in the market.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Bitcoin has gained the mainstream adoption following massive interest from institutional giants. Some companies, like the Spanish firm Telefonica, now accept Bitcoin. Telefonica even works with a cryptocurrency exchange called Bit2Me to let people pay with Bitcoin.</p>



<p>Looking ahead, Bitcoin seems to have a bright future with potential for its price to go up. This prediction is based on Bitcoin&#8217;s past prices and current market sentiment. Adding Bitcoin to your investment portfolio could be a good move, but it&#8217;s important to do your research and understand the risks before buying Bitcoin or any other cryptocurrency</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p7n-qA-uPp8" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p7n-qA-uPp8" />
			<media:title type="plain">Bitcoin BTC Price News Today - Technical Analysis and Elliott Wave Analysis and Price Prediction!</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Trade on Bybit:Receive an up to $30,000 bonus (see terms on Bybit)https://partner.bybit.com/b/MCOBitcoin BTC Price News Today - Technical Analysis and Elliot...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/bitcoin-btc-price-news-today-tec.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bitcoin-V1_featured-image_1140x815.png" medium="image"  type="image/png" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bitcoin-V1_featured-image_1140x815.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK Ministers Advised to Use AI Facial Recognition for Screening Migrants in Kent</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/uk-ministers-to-use-ai-for-screening/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Glory Kaburu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=513579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The need to unite the nation through Jonathan Hall KC, an individual who reviews terrorism laws in the UK, is evident. At the moment of fuss and angst over European immigrants, Mr. Hall will suggest the application of AI facial recognition technology at Kent migrant facilities.&#160; This statement forms part of the biannual initiative to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The need to unite the nation through Jonathan Hall KC, an individual who reviews terrorism laws in the UK, is evident. At the moment of fuss and angst over European immigrants, Mr. Hall will suggest the application of AI facial recognition technology at Kent migrant facilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This statement forms part of the biannual initiative to improve the process of migrants boarding small boats, with the main goal of assessing individuals for any reported threats. Using facial recognition technology will provide the border officers with a platform through which they will promptly have the terror suspects identified as soon as they disembark in the database, streamlining the process. The technology will help prevent individuals who have been found to present security threats.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Challenges at migrant processing centers</h2>



<p>The suggestion comes from some inefficiency evident at the processing centers, which results in overcrowding at camps like the Manston, where Hall said that the volumes of migrants were released before the thorough check could be conducted. The center, besides, puts Western Jet Foil in Dover to be on the receiving end, especially when there is a surge, and the number of migrants is more than anticipated, which would fragment the screening process and compromise its efficiency.</p>



<p>As he did, Hall pointed out that the confinement of prisoners in these places is geographically limited and that there are ethical standards of behavior they should maintain. Closing my tent doesn&#8217;t help, whereas if I&#8217;m jamming everyone into the same tent, they can stay there only for a day. Additionally, speedy screening methods that do not infringe on people&#8217;s basic rights are a dire issue that needs to be addressed now.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Implementation of facial recognition technology</h2>



<p>Implementation of facial recognition technology will soon be part of a trial carried out at Border Force, which is at the Western Jet Foil, a primary vitality intake in Dover. It sets up a process that immediately checks the face of the person in real-time against the integrated database containing the images recorded as suspected to be of terrorists. &#8220;In a matter of weeks, it’ll be in print. However, in my report, I’ll posit that WJF should use facial recognition at the time of boarding so they can screen them off as soon as passengers disembark.&#8221; Hall declared it in the LBC interview.</p>



<p>These tests will thus be conducted immediately following arrival. They will address a present gap caused by income processing delays and the large numbers of immigrants continuously arriving in Europe. Hall’s plan offers to impart skills to border officials, thereby enabling them to make conscious decisions and do so rapidly, which consequently leads to apprehending suspects on watch lists before they gain access to the country.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Balancing security with Humanitarian Concerns</h2>



<p>Technology being used in this process raises the important issue of wanting to secure the migrants while keeping them humane. Hence, the UK government needs to walk the fine line between taking robust security measures while respecting international human rights standards to come up with the middle option, which appeared to be the core of Hall’s advice.</p>



<p>This year, the Home Office has revealed plans to use facial recognition technology while continuing to implement a wider legislative package designed to guide and limit cross-Channel migration. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak frequently emphasizes his intention to put a stop to the boats, and his government closely follows these declarations by introducing appropriate laws. Some of them, like the plan for deportation to Rwanda, prove to be very controversial. Yet despite these movements&#8217; aims and achieving to some extent, they have remained stalled in the final stages of the legislative issues, thus showing the complicated and sometimes conflict-prone policy nature of immigration.</p>



<p>More than 6,200 of those crossings were recorded from the start of the year, which was already more than what we had in previous years. The reality of the need for proper border management systems is now more evident than ever. The suggested use of AI-based facial recognition as a surveillance measure at the most critically guarded access points in Kent could become a decisive trend in how the border area of the UK is managed against impending and possibly dangerous intruders.</p>



<p>The government&#8217;s responses to this system, when it analyzes Hall&#8217;s rapport, are doubtful in the context of the use of these technologies, and the smooth fitting of the processes of security deterrence with the ethical and legal concerns is unbeautiful. This acts as a precursor for other nations huddled up with the same security dilemma in the middle of the extreme migration tendencies across the globe.</p>



<p>This article originally appeared in <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/government-kent-david-lynch-dover-lbc-b2531197.html" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">The Independent</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_UK_Ministers_Advised_to_Use_AI_Facial_Recognition_for_0.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_UK_Ministers_Advised_to_Use_AI_Facial_Recognition_for_0.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple plans global expansion and US Dollar stablecoin launch by 2027</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ripple-plans-global-expansion-and-us-dollar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emman Omwanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ripple News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=513572</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A detailed interview with the CEO of Ripple, Brad Garlinghouse, explained the future-looking growth strategy of the cryptocurrency company within the next three years on FOX Business. The plan includes expanding into many international locations and releasing a newly designed stablecoin US dollar-backed product to further extend its role in the global cryptocurrency market while [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A detailed<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n_OZ2LypphE" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> interview</a> with the CEO of Ripple, Brad Garlinghouse, explained the future-looking growth strategy of the cryptocurrency company within the next three years on FOX Business. The plan includes expanding into many international locations and releasing a newly designed stablecoin US dollar-backed product to further extend its role in the global cryptocurrency market while attending to an intriguing challenge of the regulatory framework, especially in the States.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ripple eyes expansion with US dollar-backed stablecoin launch</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/ripples-strategic-xrp-release-fuels-rumors/">Ripple</a> is setting its aim beyond the United States, but this doesn&#8217;t mean it will supersede the markets (95% of its customers are currently international) where it does the bulk of its business around the globe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This strategic shift addresses the slower U.S. market adoption issue, which is primarily caused by the tighter and more extensive regulatory framework. Garlinghouse highlights the dramatic growth in these markets overseas and its importance in driving the company&#8217;s globally focused expansion.</p>



<p>Expansion becomes the next plan for the company as it may launch the US dollar-backed stablecoin. By adopting a new foreign currency, the bank reacts to the emerging trend of the stablecoin market, which is currently worth $150 billion and is expected to enjoy immense growth. The underlying focus of Garlinghouse’s claim is to integrate traditional banking with cutting-edge crypto technology by creating an instrument of security, regulation, and worldwide access.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Boosting XRP’s utility</h2>



<p>Ripple’s operation lies successively on XRP, the digital asset that acts as a startup’s payment protocol. Garlinghouse was convinced about the prospects of XRP, and he stressed at the same time that the star of Ripple as a brand depended on the widespreadness of its broader solution set. The XRP utilization in global payments and transfers to the advantage of Ripple results in the company&#8217;s staying power and relevance in digital currencies.</p>



<p>All this constitutes solely a part of Ripple’s plan to have its infrastructure become a formidable system across the world&#8217;s financial industry, and that is why efficiently working XRP is being looked after.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Navigating regulatory hurdles</h2>



<p>However, Ripple is grappling with constant regulatory issues, an environmental problem from the United States Securities and Exchange Committee (SEC) that forces them to make operational and strategic decisions differently. The still ongoing legal battles show that breaking blockchain and current financial regulation frameworks is not a simple matter to do.</p>



<p>Despite this,<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/brad-garlinghouse-hits-back-at-scammers/"> Garlinghouse</a> remained dedicated to compliance and regulatory engagement. He is convinced that such measures provide much-needed support for XRP&#8217;s high growth and would make the cryptocurrency appealing to investors searching for compliant virtual assets. </p>



<p>This approach is primarily targeted at maintaining Ripple&#8217;s existence and producing power within the financial ecosystem, which is increasing with scrutiny and calls for more regulations.</p>



<p>After three years of Garlinghouse’s leadership, Ripple will emphasize harnessing the opportunity the growing global market provides, the forthcoming strategic stablecoin, and the development and implementation of XRP’s utility. </p>



<p>Despite the roadblocks created by regulator prostrations, Ripple is prepared to pave the way to deal with these loopholes and set the standard example of compliance and innovations in the cryptocurrency industry. </p>



<p>This adaptive strategy is a testament to Ripple’s determination to serve as a pioneer for years to come in the constantly changing financial sector by offering cryptocurrency solutions that are technologically ahead and link traditional financial networks with modernly developed financial structures.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Ripple_plans_global_expansion_and_US_Dollar_stablecoin_0-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Ripple_plans_global_expansion_and_US_Dollar_stablecoin_0-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Announces Integration of Android, Chrome, Hardware, and AI Divisions</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/google-integration-of-hardware-and-ai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brenda Kanana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Innovators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=513569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of its strategic plan to boost its AI capacities, Google reported yesterday its intention to merge the software division, responsible for both Android mobile software and Google Chrome browser, with the hardware division, known for manufacturing popular Pixel smartphones and Fitbit wearables. With Rick Osterloh, who was previously an executive at Google, playing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As part of its strategic plan to boost its AI capacities, Google reported yesterday its intention to merge the software division, responsible for both Android mobile software and Google Chrome browser, with the hardware division, known for manufacturing popular Pixel smartphones and Fitbit wearables.</p>



<p>With Rick Osterloh, who was previously an executive at Google, playing the leadership part and the consolidation of the hardware group, the aim of this integration will be to clip the wings of any operational overshadow and fill every shade of innovation. Pichai, the company&#8217;s CEO, confidently stated that this integration dwarfs the Android and Chrome bases and will thus boost the aims of making artificial intelligence more broad in the organization.</p>



<p>The move not only reflects a change from Google&#8217;s previous opinion of separating androids from hardware but also shows a shift in its perspective. This strategic move started at the level of ensuring fair competition for all producers of Android-based phones. Nevertheless, over the present years, Google has decided to employ its Pixel devices <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/google-plans-over-billion-investment-in-ai/">as showcases for AI capabilities </a>with the intention of using hardware and software functions together in order to discover new horizons of possibilities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Leading the way in consumer technology innovation</h2>



<p>In an interview with The Verge, Osterloh noted that the AI technology will be leading all major integration for the phones, and will be shaping the future of mobile technology. The Pixel camera, however, acts as a key example for this purpose, drawing on AI algorithms to improve photos, particularly in low-light conditions and when selecting images. According to Osterloh, deep AI integration is critical, with evidence of how it has completely changed interactions and has influenced the way we perceive services.</p>



<p>Chirag Dekate, an analyst with Gartner, also indicated the fact that Google&#8217;s aim is not just to rule the AI world as a consumer as well as in a big enterprise sector. AI incorporation to all aspects of its products and services by Google is the crucial step towards its aim to be the top player in AI economy where things are beginning to move.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Leadership Restructuring and Prospects for Future</h2>



<p>One of such changes is the participation of Hiroshi Lockheimer, the head of Google software division having taken up no other title (so far) and is working on the project, which still unrevealed. Nevertheless, while Lockheimer and Osterloh still affirmed that their departures were made on strategic rather than working rival grounds, the rumors of a power struggle had still greatly spread.</p>



<p>In addition to merging the AI research and responsibility teams with the consumer-facing divisions, Google is also indicating deeper AI-driven innovation to be a part of their strategy. Although the effect of these organizational changes on consumer products in the present moment is hardly noticeable, its future implication for emerging AI-enabled technologies is evident.</p>



<p>This demonstrates that Google&#8217;s strategy to unify its software and hardware operations is evidence of the motion of AI towards its own entrant point. This will lead to the creation of a highly interdisciplinary team at Google, and in effect, it will help to accelerate innovations and make the company a market leader in the growing era of technology.</p>



<p>Google&#8217;s CEO, Sundar Pichai, letter to the<a href="https://blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/building-ai-future-april-2024/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> employees</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Google_Chrome_Desktop_to_Integrate_Gemini_AI_A_GameCha_0-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Default_Google_Chrome_Desktop_to_Integrate_Gemini_AI_A_GameCha_0-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft&#8217;s VASA-1 can generate realistic talking faces from just one image</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/microsofts-vasa-1-can-generate-talking-faces/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aamir Sheikh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 06:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Explained]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VASA-1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=513561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a recent white paper, Microsoft introduced a new AI model that produces a talking head that looks and sounds realistic and is generated by only uploading a still photograph and a voice sample. The new model is named VASA-1, and it requires only one portrait style picture and an audio file of voice and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a recent white paper, Microsoft introduced a new AI model that produces a talking head that looks and sounds realistic and is generated by only uploading a still photograph and a voice sample.</p>



<p>The new model is named VASA-1, and it requires only one portrait style picture and an audio file of voice and fuses them together to make a short video of a talking head with facial expressions, lip syncing, and head movements. The produced head can even sing songs, and that in the voice uploaded at the time of creation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Microsoft VASA-1 is a breakthrough for animation</h2>



<p>According to Microsoft, the new AI model is still in the research phase, and there are still no plans to release it to the general public, and only Microsoft researchers have access to it. However, the company shared quite a few samples of the demonstrations, which show stunning realism and lip movements that seem to be too lifelike.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="974" height="506" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-513564" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa.jpg 974w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa-300x156.jpg 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa-768x399.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 974px) 100vw, 974px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/vasa-1/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>The demo shows people who look real, as if they were sitting in front of a camera and getting filmed. The movements of the heads are realistic and look quite natural, and the lip movement to match the audio is quite outstanding, provided that there seems very little to be noted anything for not being natural. The overall mouth synchronization is phenomenal.</p>



<p>Microsoft said the model was developed to animate virtual characters, and it claimed that all the people shown in the demo are synthetic, as they said, the models were generated from DALL-E, which is the image generator of OpenAI. So we think if it can animate an AI generated model, then obviously there is much more potential in it to animate photos of any real person, which should be more realistic and much easier for it to handle.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Use cases of Vasa-1 and its potential misuse</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="326" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa2-1200x326.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-513563" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa2-1200x326.jpg 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa2-300x82.jpg 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa2-768x209.jpg 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/vasa2.jpg 1294w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/vasa-1/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>If we look at the potential of VASA-1 for practical usage, then on the baseline, it can be used to animate characters in animated movies, which will give characters a more realistic feel with natural facial expressions and head movements. Another use could be in video games, for the very same reason, think of Grand Theft Auto and the like. In the future it may be used for hyper realistic AI generated movies or series where characters can be generated from image generators and could be animated by VASA-1, and the audience may not even feel that the characters are not humans.</p>



<p>Along with creative use of the tool, it can also be leveraged to create content for malicious purposes. The potential misuse of VASA-1 could be its utilization for deepfakes, as it will make it easy for anyone involved in deepfake creations to scale up their bad tactics and generate more realistic misguiding content. Remember the robocall scandal involving Biden&#8217;s voice to refrain people from voting before a primary election? Now it could be a robovideo after the robocall, and that with very realistic human expressions.</p>



<p>The potential risk of misuse is may be the reason that Microsoft has limited its testing to its researchers only. According to <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/microsoft-tests-new-ai-copilot-in-edge-canary-for-enhanced-setting-navigation/" data-type="post" data-id="510592">Microsoft</a> researchers, the tool can be used for creating misleading and deceivable content for impersonating humans, like some other tools, but they are aiming for positive use applications. Nvidia and Runway AI have also released their models for the same function, but VASA-1 seems far more realistic and a promising candidate. </p>



<p>The research paper can be seen <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.10667" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>, and Microsoft&#8217;s <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/vasa-1/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">note</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/96e41fd7-d488-4194-9614-4c2477f14a3a.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/96e41fd7-d488-4194-9614-4c2477f14a3a.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlockDAG Mining Rigs Rise on the Moon, Dominates with $2.2M Sales, Outshining Cardano Whales, and Polkadot&#8217;s Turmoil</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/blockdag-mining-rigs-rise-on-the-moon-dominates-with-2-2m-sales-outshining-cardano-whales-and-polkadots-turmoil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guest User]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 06:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Corporate Press Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=513558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst market turbulence, the activities of Cardano Whales are a focal point, suggesting a strategic accumulation phase. Similarly, the Polkadot price has faced pressures, unable to breach crucial technical barriers. Contrastingly,&#160;BlockDAG&#160;emerges prominently, leveraging its innovative mining solutions to redefine cryptocurrency mining. With a whopping $18.1 Million raised in its presale and an additional $2.2 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amidst market turbulence, the activities of Cardano Whales are a focal point, suggesting a strategic accumulation phase. Similarly, the Polkadot price has faced pressures, unable to breach crucial technical barriers. Contrastingly,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://blockdag.network/%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1713511843537940%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw0z_w8BebmQzl2BYydtr0DD&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1713511843547263&amp;usg=AOvVaw1NgmxUADk2GaKTZx_9UvS0" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">BlockDAG</a>&nbsp;emerges prominently, leveraging its innovative mining solutions to redefine cryptocurrency mining.</p>



<p>With a whopping $18.1 Million raised in its presale and an additional $2.2 million from miner sales, BlockDAG positions itself as a top crypto for 2024. These advancements, coupled with a recent keynote teaser from the moon, underscore BlockDAG&#8217;s potential for a transformative 20,000x ROI, sparking substantial investor interest in this burgeoning sector.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h.30j0zll"><strong>Cardano&#8217;s Market Dynamics: Observing Whale Movements</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Recent trends have seen a notable decline in Cardano&#8217;s market value, with a 19.8% drop stirring concerns among investors. This downturn prompts a deeper analysis of the activities of Cardano Whales, whose recent behaviours suggest a strategic accumulation of ADA. Observations indicate that these large holders are purchasing substantial amounts of ADA.<br><br><a href="https://blockdag.network/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/dQtftRpaNzHhV7joAK87-fHPrkJBuEhatVdtk2aHrZ1EzTt1vOZ_HVPlcm3Z9ZyoTOuryQTnvo9cI6nVZyoY6UilLFQKPhVRGVJA6a6bMgIRb1mQfArZOm3mPyH3DiEhbhWWuuiTpebPxQoVSyWFEGdPj0qFM284=s320" alt=""></a></p>



<p>Despite these purchases potentially marking a price bottom for ADA, the intentions behind these movements remain crucial to understand. The surge in Cardano Whales&#8217; activity, particularly their timing, could signify a strong vote of confidence in Cardano&#8217;s future or a temporary strategic play. As Cardano fights to maintain its top-ten status by market cap, the actions of Cardano Whales will be instrumental in shaping its path forward in the competitive cryptocurrency landscape.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h.1fob9te"><strong>Polkadot&#8217;s Struggle Amid Market Uncertainty</strong></h2>



<p>Polkadot continues to face downward pressure, mirroring the broader crypto market’s reaction to geopolitical tensions. Despite starting the day at $9.05, the Polkadot price couldn&#8217;t surpass the 20-day SMA barrier and closed at $8.66 after a 4.31% drop. The subsequent days saw further declines, with Polkadot price breaching crucial support levels and dipping below $7 amid intensified bearish sentiment.<br><br><img decoding="async" alt="" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/MESiI5wkiVmK-XLhwtJyCGp6PPfbRwrjjNg5aIA_-4M690VOXCVnIOtkYIiMuxPwpmsI7_54UH7JubeyX0m6ab4_gEj9ECpLTkAOrK5gN-9KgB3Sunt2bNEUd4PzaJXebmETG4KIFWzgcLVCGhnMXCthlXuKwkO6=s320"></p>



<p>As the market fluctuates, Polkadot tests crucial support and resistance levels. If buyers regain strength, the next target could be the $7 resistance marked by the 200-day SMA, with the current price hovering around $6.70. However, failure to surpass this could lead to a fallback to $6.50, highlighting the ongoing tug-of-war between buyers and sellers in determining the future trajectory of the Polkadot price.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h.3znysh7"><strong>BlockDAG’s 20,000 ROI Leads the Charge in Crypto Innovation</strong></h2>



<p>BlockDAG is transforming the cryptocurrency mining landscape through significant advancements in mining technology. By successfully raising $2.2 million from the sales of over 4700 miners, BlockDAG has firmly established its commitment and serious approach towards innovating mining solutions.</p>



<p>With the introduction of user-friendly mining options like the BlockDAG x1 mobile application, which is readily available on both the App Store and Google Play, BlockDAG has made mining accessible to a broader audience. Users can now mine up to 20 BDAG coins daily, integrating crypto mining seamlessly into their daily routines without any hassle. This democratisation of mining extends further into home setups with the BlockDAG x10, x30, and x100 machines, designed to cater to varying mining expertise levels and commitment.<br><br><img decoding="async" alt="" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/ruEscgnPz8KFe5KADDI8MnRz9q5eTcdVa7BBM6Z3TdXzf8lP1jrxnvXuHvH42T3tffb-q3Fxhr4B3e-phLQErZtr1xXdEeDigHxdLdJQl52OLiLbKXrA2wnV3mGdHcX-HkcjVnXyogVZGUObYUck1GhSBFFOvfjZ=s320"></p>



<p>The energy efficiency and lucrative reward structure of BlockDAG&#8217;s mining rigs underscore a unique value proposition within the cryptocurrency community. As a result, BlockDAG is rapidly becoming a top crypto for 2024, with potential for substantial growth.</p>



<p>Fuelled by the success of its recent keynote address and backed by a projected 20,000x ROI, BlockDAG is poised for an explosive entry into the post-launch market, with its coin price expected to hit $10. These developments are drawing significant attention to BlockDAG, making it an exciting prospect for investors looking for groundbreaking opportunities in the cryptocurrency space.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h.2et92p0"><strong>Final Analysis</strong></h2>



<p>In a volatile market, Cardano Whales signal a cautious accumulation amid declines, while Polkadot struggles to overcome key resistance levels. Amid these challenges, BlockDAG shines with $2.2 million in miner sales and a promising presale, establishing itself as a top crypto for 2024. With advanced mining solutions and a recent moon keynote teaser, BlockDAG offers investors a compelling opportunity, boasting a 20,000x potential as the right investment choice in the evolving crypto market.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blockdag.network/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/ffixteU7a6RD3ZiDiwQhB0AEs7WxLPCeShTsekygb4QkrJb8ClfXp0A3RgtlaWbJNLohh1lFS-VrNA1FFPKEIDwN39nBY02EFT8sVwuRKu44PLNW3b1JKW_0AG6q2CJTNQNTaYe3oQ4nWf7RzNg-l-TUNQ9wxd75=s320" alt="" title=""/></a></figure>



<p><strong>Join BlockDAG Now!</strong></p>



<p>Website:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://blockdag.network/%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1713511843540324%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw28nQ5jJ83XyAyaqworp3IH&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1713511843548641&amp;usg=AOvVaw12lbf_77q7ZFdufl4kSWea" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://blockdag.network</a></p>



<p>Presale:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://purchase.blockdag.network/%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1713511843540659%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw1EwP3HDHhwVwehyuqulZb4&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1713511843548804&amp;usg=AOvVaw3eKxEhmDjlbtq9TbcQf9UN" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://purchase.blockdag.network</a></p>



<p>Telegram:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://t.me/blockDAGnetworkOfficial%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1713511843540954%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw1LDTISmFkGkyQFS1jF4DKt&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1713511843548901&amp;usg=AOvVaw3j7kS_TNufG96fOAK89Bny" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://t.me/blockDAGnetworkOfficial</a></p>



<p>Discord:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://discord.gg/Q7BxghMVyu%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1713511843541170%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw1r8EKwVySCbc4uvVNBeRal&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1713511843548978&amp;usg=AOvVaw1tESw77ticDd0dAM0kV7qJ" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://discord.gg/Q7BxghMVyu</a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image5-2.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image5-2.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SNX PRICE PREDICTION 2024-2033: IS SNX A GOOD INVESTMENT?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/snx-price-prediction-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Syra Iqbal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 06:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto Price Predictions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptomarket]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=455278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SNX Price Prediction 2024-2033 Synthetix is developing a decentralized liquidity provisioning protocol that is accessible to various platforms. It boasts substantial liquidity and minimal fees, making it an attractive backend for numerous protocols on both Optimism and Ethereum. Within the Synthetix ecosystem, platforms like Kwenta (offering Spot and Futures), Lyra (for Options trading), Polynomial (Automated [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>SNX Price Prediction 2024-2033</strong></h4>



<ul>
<li><a href="#1" data-type="internal" data-id="#1"><u>Synthetix Price Prediction 2024 – up to </u><strong><u>$4.22</u></strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#2" data-type="internal" data-id="#2"><u>Synthetix Price Prediction 2027 – up to </u><strong><u>$13.8</u></strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#3" data-type="internal" data-id="#3"><u>Synthetix Price Prediction 2030 – up to </u><strong><u>$39.34</u></strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#4"><u>Synthetix Price Prediction 2033- up to </u><strong><u>$128.40</u></strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>Synthetix is developing a decentralized liquidity provisioning protocol that is accessible to various platforms. It boasts substantial liquidity and minimal fees, making it an attractive backend for numerous protocols on both Optimism and Ethereum. Within the Synthetix ecosystem, platforms like Kwenta (offering Spot and Futures), Lyra (for Options trading), Polynomial (Automated Options), and 1inch &amp; Curve (for Atomic Swaps) leverage Synthetix liquidity to enhance their services.</p>



<p>SNX&#8217;s value worth is subject to market dynamics and can fluctuate based on demand, supply, and broader cryptocurrency market trends. As of [current date], SNX is trading at [current price] per token.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How much is SNX worth?</h3>



<p>Today’s live <strong>Synthetix price is $2.810</strong>, with a 24-hour trading volume of $38,599,687, an increase of 4.40% over the last 24 hours. <strong>Synthetix is up 0.42%</strong> in the last 24 hours. The current CoinMarketCap ranking is #85. The coin currently has a live market cap of $917,313,198 USD. It has a circulating supply of 327,769,196 SNX coins and the max. supply is not available.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Synthetix price analysis: Will the bears dominate the market?</h2>



<p><strong>TL;DR Breakdown</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Synthetix price analysis shows an downtrend today</li>



<li>Support for SNX/USD is present at $2.394</li>



<li>Resistance for SNX is present at $4.849</li>
</ul>



<p>As of April 19, 2024, the 21-hour and 4-hour charts indicate a downward trend on Synthetix SNX. The bears have been taking over the market over the past few days, while the bulls have a slight exception. Due to the bearish swing, the coin dropped to $2.810.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SNX price analysis 1-day chart: Bearish momentum builds</h3>



<p>The 1-day price chart of the SNX token displays a downward trend, indicating a bearish movement in the market. At its current price of $2.810, SNX finds itself in a dangerous position, with the chances of dropping further if the prevailing negative market sentiment persists.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/UgwM8RpiBUXqlJhx3gAE1l6nrHclu7XB8GLw_NeQoVbGjnF0PGp5ySAVjk2QLfz1oltvyh5E4ez2TfexsbeMC75Y_cpCfeptTBDL4BhzgyIWmapwj5CWRk81x_ujQMJGzeTdi4RCMu5VNKLdEs3IDq8" alt="" /></figure>



<p>The extensively expanding volatility indicates a bearish movement in the near future. Due to the rising volatility, the Bollinger bands have switched, with the lower Bollinger Bands at $2.810 and the upper Bollinger Bands at $4.849. The RSI value is in oversold territory, confirming the bearish wave, as it stands at 32.53.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SNX 4-hour price chart overview: SNX bulls dominate once again</h3>



<p>Over the last 4-hours, the SNX analysis has supported the crypto buyers. The bulls are now taking over the market once more as a strong bullish momentum is seen. Due to the bullish trend over the last four hours, the SNX price has surged to $2.810.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/vRiisY3gIlmMVOlbRZalKyyd9fQCWWTU7XxNaEG9e8sJTC6KMEDrBCzouBe7TeZcgOln8GO1TD9ZycH2Z8NRPKwcUPs2nOOmMXCz5vmD5tu9gyP9wtrbpRMiDUHLWNsQF6pTyEoGRfjWoZ8LQQ7oOXk" alt="" /></figure>



<p>The decreasing volatility indicates a bullish momentum for the upcoming hours. With the subsiding changes in volatility, the Bollinger Bands have shifted with higher Bollinger Bands to a high of $2.959 and the lower Bollinger Bands at $2.716. Additionally, the RSI shows a sharp bullish curve with its value up to 43.55.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Synthetix (SNX) a Good Investment?</h2>



<p>Synthetix (SNX) emerges as a compelling investment opportunity due to its innovative protocol and potential for growth. As a decentralized synthetic asset platform, Synthetix enables the creation and trading of synthetic assets representing various real-world assets, including fiat currencies, commodities, and cryptocurrencies. Its unique approach to tokenizing assets offers users exposure to a wide array of assets without the need for intermediaries or liquidity providers. </p>



<p>Synthetix leverages a decentralized governance model to ensure community participation and protocol upgrades. Synthetix continues to expand its ecosystem and user base. Our Cryptopolitan Price Prediction section can offer valuable perspectives on SNX&#8217;s future value trajectory, aiding investors in their decision-making process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Synthetix Recent News</h2>



<p><strong>Synthetix Founder Kain Warwick&#8217;s Initiative to Simplify DeFi Trading with Infinex</strong></p>



<p>Synthetix founder Kain Warwick is revolutionizing DeFi with a new initiative, Infinex, aiming to simplify trading experiences akin to traditional exchanges. Despite the high expectations for Synthetix Perps v2, Warwick observed traders&#8217; reluctance towards DeFi platforms. In response, Infinex promises a user-friendly interface, leveraging Synthetix Perps v3 capabilities while bypassing the complexities of DeFi transactions. Warwick&#8217;s pivot underscores his adaptability and commitment to innovation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction 2024 – 2033</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction by Cryptopolitan</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="596" height="366" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-18-at-14.47.02.png" alt="" class="wp-image-513056" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-18-at-14.47.02.png 596w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-18-at-14.47.02-300x184.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 596px) 100vw, 596px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td>Year</td><td>Minimum Price</td><td>Average Price</td><td>Maximum Price</td></tr><tr><td>2024</td><td>$3.63</td><td>$3.77</td><td>$4.22</td></tr><tr><td>2025</td><td>$5.38</td><td>$5.53</td><td>$6.51</td></tr><tr><td>2026</td><td>$7.89</td><td>$8.11</td><td>$9.37</td></tr><tr><td>2027</td><td>$11.12</td><td>$11.44</td><td>$13.8</td></tr><tr><td>2028</td><td>$15.57</td><td>$16.15</td><td>$18.94</td></tr><tr><td>2029</td><td>$22.36</td><td>$23.01</td><td>$27.05</td></tr><tr><td>2030</td><td>$34.17</td><td>$35.09</td><td>$39.34</td></tr><tr><td>2031</td><td>$49.58</td><td>$50.98</td><td>$58.87</td></tr><tr><td>2032</td><td>$72.03</td><td>$74.07</td><td>$86.19</td></tr><tr><td>2033</td><td>$110.37</td><td>$114.08</td><td>$128.40</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="1">SNX Price Prediction 2024&nbsp;</h4>



<p>Our SNX price prediction for 2024 is a <strong>maximum price of $4.22.</strong> The coin’s minimum price will be $3.63, and the average price will be $3.77.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction 2025</h4>



<p>According to our SNX price prediction for 2025, the <strong>maximum price is $6.51.</strong> The coin’s lowest price will be $5.38, and the average trading price of the coin is $5.53.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction 2026</h4>



<p>According to our SNX, the price prediction for 2026 is a <strong>maximum of $9.37</strong>. The minimum price the coin will have by the end of 2026 will be $7.89, while its average trading price will be $8.11.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="2">SNX Price Prediction 2027</h4>



<p>Our SNX price prediction for 2027 is a <strong>maximum price of $13.8 </strong>with a minimum price of $11.12. We also expect the coin’s average trading price to be $11.44.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction 2028</h4>



<p>According to our SNX price prediction for 2028, we expect a <strong>maximum price of $18.94.</strong> The minimum price of the coin by 2028 will be $15.57; the average trading price is forecasted to be $16.15.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction 2029</h4>



<p>According to our SNX price prediction for 2029, there is a <strong>maximum price expectation of $27.05 </strong>with an average trading price of $23.01. The coin will have the lowest price at $22.36.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="3">SNX Price Prediction 2030</h4>



<p>Our SNX price prediction for 2030 is a <strong>maximum price of $39.34</strong> with the coin’s lowest price at $34.17. The average trading price of the coin will be $35.09.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction 2031</h4>



<p>According to our SNX price prediction for 2031 is a <strong>maximum trading price of $58.87,</strong> with an average trading price of $50.98. The minimum price of the coin will be $49.58.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction 2032</h4>



<p>Our SNX price prediction 2032 is a <strong>maximum trading price of $86.19</strong>, with an average trading price of $74.07. The minimum price of the coin will be $72.03.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="4">SNX Price Prediction 2033</h4>



<p>According to our SNX price prediction for 2033, it could be a <strong>maximum price of $128.40</strong>. The minimum price is $110.37, and the average trading price of the coin will be $114.08.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction by Wallet Investor</h3>



<p>Based on Wallet Investor&#8217;s analysis of SNX&#8217;s price, it appears primed for substantial growth in the near term. They predict its value to potentially reach $3.249 within the span of a year, indicating a promising upward trajectory in the short run.</p>



<p>Looking beyond the immediate future, their five-year forecast paints an even more optimistic picture, suggesting a price target of $4.277. These projections not only convey a positive outlook for SNX but also underscore its potential attractiveness to investors and enthusiasts keen on closely tracking its progress.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction by CoinCodex</h3>



<p>CoinCodex&#8217;s price forecast for SNX is brimming with promise. Their prediction indicates that by the conclusion of 2025, the cryptocurrency could soar to a peak trading price of $10.82.</p>



<p>Delving deeper into the future, specifically to 2029, the outlook becomes even more upbeat. According to CoinCodex&#8217;s prediction chart, the price of SNX is anticipated to rise to $24.48. These projections offer a positive outlook for investors and SNX enthusiasts, hinting at substantial potential gains in the coming years.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction by DigitalCoinPrice</h3>



<p>According to Digitalcoinprice&#8217;s SNX price forecast, SNX is expected in 2025, to trade an average price of $6.90, with a potential high of $7.17 and a low of $6.02.</p>



<p>By 2027, SNX may see an average price of $12.45, with a maximum price of $12.79 and a minimum of $10.78. </p>



<p>Looking further ahead to 2030, SNX is forecasted to have an average trading price of $20.02, with a potential high of $20.99 and a low of $18.90.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price Prediction by Market Expert</h2>



<p>CoinBlast, a noted market expert, has made a compelling prediction regarding the trajectory of SNX, suggesting that it will surge to $65 by the year&#8217;s end. This forecast is underpinned by an expectation of bullish momentum within the market, signaling a positive sentiment towards SNX&#8217;s prospects. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Synthetix SNX MEGA Bullish Price Prediction" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaxFnNFhoDc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Moreover, there is a notable assertion that the price may surpass the $65 mark, indicating a heightened level of optimism regarding its performance. This prediction encapsulates the anticipation and potential for significant growth in the value of SNX, reflecting the dynamic nature of the cryptocurrency market and the evolving investor sentiment surrounding it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>SNX</strong> Overview</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Popularity</strong></td><td>#85</td><td><strong>Market Cap</strong></td><td>$917,313,198</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price Change (24 hours)</strong></td><td>+0.42%</td><td><strong>Trading Volume (24 hours)</strong></td><td>$38,599,687</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price change (7 days)</strong></td><td>-28.57%</td><td><strong>Circulating Supply</strong></td><td>327,769,196 SNX</td></tr><tr><td><strong>All-time low</strong>&nbsp;(Jan 05, 2019)</td><td>$0.03258</td><td><strong>All-time high</strong>&nbsp;(Feb 14, 2021)</td><td>$28.77</td></tr><tr><td><strong>From ATL</strong></td><td>+8490.73%</td><td><strong>From ATH</strong></td><td>-90.27%</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SNX Price History</h2>



<p>The Synthetix token was first listed on a crypto exchange for trading in March 2018. Until June 2020, the SNX was trading below $1.5, as seen in the chart below.</p>



<p>However, in July 2020, the Synthetix coin unleashed a monster bullish rally that continued until February 2021. And during the bullish momentum, the SNX hit an all-time high of $28.77.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After hitting an all-time high, the SNX price took a downward turn dropping to as low as $1.5 in 2023. It later began correcting and is trading at the $2.8 mark in 2024.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SNX_All_graph_coinmarketcap.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-513086" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SNX_All_graph_coinmarketcap.jpeg 1200w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SNX_All_graph_coinmarketcap-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/SNX_All_graph_coinmarketcap-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure>



<p>Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://coinstats.app/coins/havven/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u><em>coinmarketcap</em></u></a></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on the SNX&nbsp;</h2>



<p>SNX is the native cryptocurrency of the Synthetix network. The SNX token is an ERC20 token, and therefore it is compatible with ETH wallets. Besides facilitating activities (specifically to offer collateral) within the Synthetix network, SNX holders can become SNX stakers by staking their SNX coins to earn staking rewards.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Who is the Synthetix founder?</h3>



<p>Synthetix network was launched in September 2017 under Havven (HAV). Its founder is Kain Warwick. Havven (HAV) rebranded to the current Synthetix name a year later, a name it has maintained to date. Warwick is also the founder of Pouncer, a live auction Australian site, and a non-executive director at Blueshyft retail network.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is the Synthetix network?</h3>



<p>Synthetix Network is a decentralized finance (DeFi) protocol that allows users to trade synthetic assets (synths). The protocol is built on the Ethereum <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/blockchain/" target="_blank"><u>blockchain</u></a>, and it provides liquidity for synth tokens so that traders can seamlessly trade them.</p>



<p>The platform enables users to issue and trade synthetic assets — digital assets that represent other real assets like stocks, fiat currencies, commodities, or cryptocurrencies. It also has a staking mechanism that incentivizes users to provide liquidity and maintain the platform.</p>



<p>The Synthetix Protocol was originally conceived as Havven back in 2017 by Kain Warwick. Warwick is currently also a Non-Executive Director of blueshyft- a network of over 1200 retail locations around Australia.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SNX is a derivative product</h3>



<p>In a nutshell, synthetic assets are derivative products issued and traded on DeFi protocols. They are similar to traditional derivative products that derive their value from underlying assets like cryptocurrencies, fiat currency, commodities, precious metals, bonds, and stocks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The underlying assets are cataloged onto a DeFi protocol like the Synthetix network through tokenization by using smart contracts. Then the tokens, which represent a certificate of ownership of the real-world assets, are issued to investors and traders who can then go ahead and trade the derived assets without holding the real-world assets.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Synthetix&#8217;s unique features</h3>



<p>Synthetix network was among the first <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/blockchain/"><u>blockchain</u></a> protocols to introduce synthetic crypto assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The synthetic cryptocurrency assets minted via the Synthetix protocol are synths and have an ‘s’ at the beginning of their names. If the underlying asset is the USD, for example, the synthetic help on Synthetix would appear as sUSD, BTC would appear as sBTC, ETH would appear as sETH, and so on.</p>



<p>The community voted the synths for to exist on the Synthetix protocol.</p>



<p>The prices of the underlying assets of the synths are tracked using smart contract price delivery protocols known as oracles. This system ensures no slippage or liquidity issues when trading the synths.</p>



<p>To mint a synth on the Synthetix network, a user will have to lock up some SNX tokens in a smart contract.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How to Stake SNX</h3>



<p>If you truly want to make money staking SNX, there are a few easy steps involved.</p>



<ol>
<li>First, you need to buy Synthetix and connect to a web3 wallet.</li>



<li>Visit Mintr, the portal interface for minting and managing Synths.</li>



<li>Connect your web3 wallet to Mintr.</li>



<li>Click ‘Mint’ and choose what type of Synth you want to mint.</li>



<li>Remember to maintain the collateralization ratio.</li>



<li>Input the number of Synths you want to mint.</li>



<li>Click ‘Mint Now’.</li>



<li>Confirm the transaction in your web3 wallet.</li>
</ol>



<p>Afterward, your SNX token will automatically be staked. You will now be able to enjoy rewards generated from trading fees. Furthermore, you are also subject to inflation rewards.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In evaluating SNX&#8217;s worth, it&#8217;s essential to consider the broader market sentiment and recent trends. Despite intermittent bullish movements, the overall trajectory appears bearish, with indications of downward pressure. Factors such as oversold RSI values and increasing volatility suggest potential further declines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, Synthetix founder Kain Warwick&#8217;s initiative with Infinex highlights ongoing efforts to innovate and simplify DeFi trading, which could impact SNX&#8217;s long-term value. Therefore, while current market conditions may advise caution, broader ecosystem developments could play a significant role in shaping SNX&#8217;s future trajectory.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaxFnNFhoDc" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HaxFnNFhoDc" />
			<media:title type="plain">Synthetix SNX MEGA Bullish Price Prediction</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[In this video I will take a look at Synthetix. I&#039;ll show you what I am seeing on my charts and provide my long term price prediction. #crypto #coinbase #altc...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/snx1.webp" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/snx1.webp" medium="image"  type="image/webp" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/snx1.webp"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SPACE ID Price Prediction 2024 -2033: Is ID a Good Investment?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/space-id-price-prediction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Syra Iqbal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 05:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptomarket]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=300101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SPACE ID Price Prediction 2024 -2033 Decentralization and blockchain technology have transformed how we interact with the digital world, and the development of innovative projects like SPACE ID is evidence of this revolution. SPACE ID provides a universal name service network that enables decentralized domain registration, trading, and management across different blockchain networks. The ID [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2024 -2033</h4>



<ul>
<li><a href="#1">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2024 &#8211; up to <strong>$1.03</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#2" data-type="internal" data-id="#2">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2027 &#8211; up to <strong>$3.19</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#3" data-type="internal" data-id="#3">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2030 &#8211; up to <strong>$9.56</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="#4" data-type="internal" data-id="#4">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2033- up to <strong>$30.42</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>Decentralization and<a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/blockchain/"> blockchain</a> technology have transformed how we interact with the digital world, and the development of innovative projects like SPACE ID is evidence of this revolution. SPACE ID provides a universal name service network that enables decentralized domain registration, trading, and management across different blockchain networks.</p>



<p>The ID token also serves as a governance currency on the platform, providing users access to various ecosystem services. With <a href="https://space.id/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">SPACE ID</a>, users can create, sell, and manage them all in one place. Unlike the Ethereum Name Service (ENS), users need a different marketplace to buy and sell domain names.</p>



<p>Now that we understand the functionality and significance of SPACE ID let&#8217;s explore its current valuation. This will give us insights into its market dynamics and potential growth trajectory in the blockchain ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How much is ID (SPACE ID) worth?</strong></h2>



<p>The current <strong>Space ID price is $0.69496</strong> with a 24-hour trading volume of $54,356,453. <strong>ID is down 3.34%</strong> in the last 24 hours. The current CoinMarketCap ranking is #173, with a live market cap of $359,118,376 USD. It has a circulating supply of 515,500,876 ID coins and a max. supply of 2,000,000,000 ID coins.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Space ID price analysis: Bears take over the market</strong></h2>



<p><strong>TL;DR Breakdown</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>SPACE ID price analysis shows a downward trajectory</li>



<li>SPACE ID token key support level at $0.61300</li>



<li>ID/USD resistance level is present at $1.06735</li>
</ul>



<p>The latest updates on the 1-day and 4-hour as of 19 April 2024 shows that ID has been on a downward trend. The bears are ruling the price chart with slight exceptions of bullish resistance. The coin had dropped down to $0.69496 because of the bearish swing.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>ID/USD price action on a 1-day chart: SPACE ID bears take over the market</strong></h3>



<p>The 1-day price chart for the SPACE ID token shows a strong downward trend, indicating a bearish market sentiment. Currently priced at $0.69496, the token is precariously positioned, with a risk of falling below this level if the market sentiment continues to be negative.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/K_CdbAcaTDsIjkCeNHP0BCZ5o-_gRNl6jkCmflYp-qntPIDZ865ghV2ChJFbh8_5bQsy0zquqy76pI5F0IsRqxvn18pNCqDV98pFmfJH9mi0bcJ5rJWdwE1k_3fy7c2fILZnsjWWm2_xFd0vcB5jvZc" alt="" /></figure>



<p>We can see that the volatility is escalating, which means that there is a bearish signal ahead. Due to the escalating volatility, the Bollinger Band upper limit has moved to $1.0675, whereas the lower Bollinger Band limit has shifted to $0.61300. Moreover, the RSI value further confirms the bearish trend, indicating a value of 34.51; hence, Space ID is in oversold territory.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>SPACE ID token price action on a 4-hour price chart: Short-Term Bulls vs Long-Term Bears?</strong></h3>



<p>The 4-hour Space ID chart shows a decrease trend for crypto today. The bears seem to have taken over as the selling momentum is still on the rise. Due to the continuing decrease trend, in the last few hours, the coin is trading at $0.69020.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/7nR3SL2Hnz4l0xgrx9LAQs1RqRq6a78S7zMHLuV3HDYbzcta5I18O7sA3K1K-EF_Qb3iD75Op5KoqxtPkttxmGH_bSTJldSMP3aNJ3hg00n-KG3rMo7B-NATj1yOsMry10OQijlRksLFUfQaezaaNLs" alt="" /></figure>



<p>On the 4-hour chart, the coin shows a decline; hence, it has turned bearish. Volatility is also on the rise, which signals an impending downtrend. This is reflected in the shifting of the Bollinger Bands value, with the lower band at $0.67000 and the upper band at $0.75076. Additionally, the RSI value suggests a potential weakening in momentum and is at 43.06</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Space ID a good Investment?</h2>



<p>Space ID presents a compelling investment opportunity in the blockchain space. The Space ID ecosystem offers robust infrastructure tailored for realizing ambitious projects, providing all the necessary tools to materialize innovative ideas. With Space ID gaining traction in the crypto market, boasting an impressive user base of over 1.6 million active monthly users, and facilitating more than 427 million transactions, confidence in its potential continues to grow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Space ID token serves as the linchpin of the ecosystem, playing a central role in various applications spanning gaming, non-fungible tokens (NFTs), and decentralized applications (DApps) built atop the Space ID blockchain. Recognized by many retailers as a promising investment, Space ID is positioned to capitalize on the burgeoning blockchain industry. Our analysis in the Cryptopolitan Price Prediction section will delve into the projected value appreciation of the Space ID token over the coming years, further bolstering the case for its investment viability.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recent News/Opinion on SPACE ID Protocol</h2>



<p><strong>DWF Labs Deposits $7.67M Worth of ID $ID to OKX Following Binance Withdrawal</strong></p>



<p>DWF Labs recently made some significant moves in the cryptocurrency market. They first deposited 10.8 million ID tokens, valued at $7.67 million, into a market where each token was priced at $0.71. This suggests they&#8217;re actively engaging in trading and managing their assets strategically. Just 20 hours before this deposit, they withdrew tokens from Binance, totaling $8.2 million, at a rate of $0.743. These actions indicate that DWF Labs is actively involved in trading across various platforms, making strategic decisions to optimize their assets.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction by Cryptopolitan</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="595" height="364" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-17-at-08.20.36.png" alt="" class="wp-image-512385" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-17-at-08.20.36.png 595w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-17-at-08.20.36-300x184.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 595px) 100vw, 595px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><thead><tr><th>Year</th><th>Minimum Price</th><th>Average Price</th><th>Maximum Price</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>2024</td><td>$0.8825</td><td>$0.9099</td><td>$1.03</td></tr><tr><td>2025</td><td>$1.29</td><td>$1.33</td><td>$1.53</td></tr><tr><td>2026</td><td>$1.84</td><td>$1.9</td><td>$2.25</td></tr><tr><td>2027</td><td>$2.56</td><td>$2.66</td><td>$3.19</td></tr><tr><td>2028</td><td>$3.68</td><td>$3.79</td><td>$4.51</td></tr><tr><td>2029</td><td>$5.48</td><td>$5.67</td><td>$6.35</td></tr><tr><td>2030</td><td>$7.95</td><td>$8.24</td><td>$9.56</td></tr><tr><td>2031</td><td>$11.99</td><td>$12.32</td><td>$13.97</td></tr><tr><td>2032</td><td>$17.64</td><td>$18.26</td><td>$20.56</td></tr><tr><td>2033</td><td>$24.78</td><td>$25.51</td><td>$30.42</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="1">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2024</h4>



<p>Our Space ID price prediction for 2024 suggests a minimum price of $0.8825. According to the Space ID price prediction for 2024, the <strong>maximum price could reach $</strong>1.03, with an average price of approximately $0.9099 throughout the year.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2025</h4>



<p>According to our Space ID price prediction for 2025, it is expected to reach a minimum of $1.29. Our Space ID price prediction for 2025 suggests that it could attain <strong>a maximum level of $1.53,</strong> with an average value estimated at $1.33 throughout the year.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2026</h4>



<p>Our Space ID price prediction for 2026 could reach a minimum of $1.84, with <strong>a peak of $</strong>2.25. Space ID price prediction for 2026 also has an average trading price of $1.9.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="2">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2027</h4>



<p>According to our Space ID price prediction for 2027, Space ID is expected to reach a minimum trading value of $2.56, an average price of of $2.66, and with the <strong>maximum price of $3.19.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2028</h4>



<p>According to our Space ID price prediction for 2028, Space ID&#8217;s price may experience substantial growth. The projected minimum price is $3.68, and the average trading price is expected to be approximately $3.79. Furthermore, Space ID&#8217;s price could surge to a <strong>maximum of $4.51</strong> during the year<strong>.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2029</h4>



<p>Our Space ID price prediction for 2029 forecast that ID will have a minimum value of $5.48 and an average trading price at $5.67. ID is expected to reach a <strong>maximum price of $6.35.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="3">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2030</h4>



<p>According to the Space ID price prediction for 2030, the price of Space ID is predicted to reach a minimum value of $7.95. The Space ID price could have a <strong>maximum value of $</strong>9.56, with an average trading price estimated at $8.24 throughout the year.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2031</h4>



<p>Based on our current Space ID price prediction for 2031, ID is projected to be trading at a minimum price of $11.99. The average trading price is expected to hover around $12.32, and the <strong>maximum value to reach $13.97 </strong>on<strong> </strong>ID price prediction.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2032</h4>



<p>Our Space ID price prediction for 2032, the minimum price of Space ID is forecasted to be $17.64, with an average trading price of $18.26 and a <strong>maximum value of $20.56.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="4">SPACE ID Price Prediction 2033</h4>



<p>According to the Space ID price prediction for 2033, the minimum price of Space ID is forecasted to be $24.78, with an average trading price of $25.51. The Space ID cryptocurrency is also expected to attain a <strong>maximum trading price of $30.42.</strong></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction by DigitalCoinPrice</h3>



<p>According to DigitalCoinPrice, SPACE ID&#8217;s prices are expected to rise. In 2024, they anticipate the lowest price to be $0.68, the average to be $1.54, and the highest to be $1.68.</p>



<p>Looking ahead to 2027, the highest Space ID price prediction price is estimated to reach $3.50, with an average trading price of $3.19 and a minimum of $2.95. These price levels are forecasted to remain stable throughout 2027.</p>



<p>By 2029, there is a significant projected increase, with a forecasted maximum trading price of $4.17, an average of $3.92, and a projected minimum of $3.65. The outlook becomes even more optimistic as the forecast moves into the following decade.</p>



<p>In 2033, another surge is expected, with a projected maximum trading price of $14.95, an average of $14.84, and a minimum of $14.40.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction by Wallet Investor</h3>



<p>According to Wallet Investor&#8217;s on Space ID price prediction, it seems poised for significant growth in the near future. They anticipate its value to reach $2.274 within a year, indicating a promising upward trend in the short term.</p>



<p>Looking further ahead, their five-year forecast is even more optimistic, suggesting a price of $8.505. These predictions not only suggest a positive outlook for SPACE ID but also highlight its potential appeal to investors and enthusiasts interested in closely monitoring its performance.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction by CoinCodex</h3>



<p>CoinCodex&#8217;s price prediction for SPACE ID is full of promise. According to their Space ID price prediction, by the end of 2025, the cryptocurrency could reach a peak trading price of $3.35.</p>



<p>Looking further into the future, to 2030, the projections become even more optimistic. Based on CoinCodex&#8217;s prediction chart, the price of Space ID is expected to increase to $4.5. These projections paint a positive picture for investors and enthusiasts of SPACE ID, suggesting significant potential gains in the years ahead.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Price Prediction by Market Experts</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=41dyuJyD4Os" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Cilinix Crypto</a>, a respected market expert, has predicted a significant bullish trend for Space ID, suggesting its value could soar beyond $1. This forecast is likely to ignite optimism among investors, potentially driving increased interest and trading activity in the cryptocurrency.</p>



<p>However, it&#8217;s crucial to approach such predictions with caution, given the inherent volatility of the crypto market. Factors such as technological developments, project milestones, and overall market sentiment can influence the trajectory of Space ID.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="ID BULLRUN UPDATE!🔥 | SPACE ID PRICE PREDICTION &amp; NEWS 2024!" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/41dyuJyD4Os?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>While Cilinix Crypto&#8217;s forecast may offer valuable insight, it&#8217;s important for investors to conduct their own research and exercise prudent risk management strategies. The cryptocurrency landscape is dynamic and subject to rapid changes, making it essential to stay informed and adaptable in navigating investment decisions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Space ID Overview</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Popularity</strong></td><td>#173</td><td><strong>Market Cap</strong></td><td>$359,118,376</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price Change (24 hours)</strong></td><td>-3.34<strong>%</strong></td><td><strong>Trading Volume (24 hours)</strong></td><td>$54,274,089</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Price change (7 days)</strong></td><td>-20.70%</td><td><strong>Circulating Supply</strong></td><td>2,000,000,000 ID</td></tr><tr><td><strong>All-time low</strong>&nbsp;(Oct 20, 2023)</td><td>$0.1713</td><td><strong>All-time high</strong>&nbsp;(Mar 17, 2024)</td><td>$1.83</td></tr><tr><td><strong>From ATL</strong></td><td>+306.73%</td><td><strong>From ATH</strong></td><td>-61.92%</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Space ID (ID) Price History</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://images.surferseo.art/6dd24217-87d8-4f70-a0ff-b8e88d22a5c1.jpeg" alt="" /></figure>



<p><em>Source: <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/space-id/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Coinmarketcap</a></em></p>



<p>However, volatility followed; the token experienced a sharp decline, hitting an all-time low of $0.1763 by August 18. As of April 18, 2024, SPACE ID had stabilized somewhat, trading at $0.69819, which is still an impressive 679.19% above its initial IEO price.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">More on Space ID Network</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What exactly is SPACE ID (ID)?</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="768" height="431" src="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/space-id-Large-1-768x431-1.jpeg" alt="space id Large 1 768x431 1" class="wp-image-300192" srcset="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/space-id-Large-1-768x431-1.jpeg 768w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/space-id-Large-1-768x431-1-300x168.jpeg 300w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/space-id-Large-1-768x431-1-24x13.jpeg 24w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/space-id-Large-1-768x431-1-36x20.jpeg 36w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/space-id-Large-1-768x431-1-48x27.jpeg 48w, https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/space-id-Large-1-768x431-1-150x84.jpeg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: SPACE ID</figcaption></figure>



<p>SPACE ID is a universal name service network that offers a centralized platform for discovering, registering, trading, and managing web3 domains. The platform includes a multi-chain name service and a web3 name SDK and API for developers. In addition, SPACE ID uses a custom blockchain called &#8220;Lucas&#8221; that allows users to create bridges between blockchains and keep their data in one place.</p>



<p>The ID token is a governance currency on the SPACE ID network, facilitating staking, payments, and voting. It also provides access to various ecosystem services and helps manage users&#8217; digital identities. SPACE ID aims to provide a reliable and efficient decentralized name service network for the Web3 era, offering an all-in-one solution for domain management and identity verification.</p>



<p>The SPACE ID DAO serves as the governing body for the SPACE ID network, managing its infrastructure and protocols. As a decentralized autonomous organization, the DAO is run by ID token holders who have a say in the decision-making processes of the platform. It ensures the network is community-driven and transparent, with stakeholders having a voice in the platform&#8217;s development and growth.</p>



<p>SPACE ID recently announced a partnership with OpenDeFi, a decentralized finance platform offering cross-chain liquidity solutions. The partnership aims to provide seamless interoperability between the two platforms, enabling users to access decentralized financial services while managing their digital identities through the SPACE ID network. Furthermore, SPACE ID has also announced plans to launch an NFT marketplace on its platform, allowing users to trade non-fungible tokens securely and transparently. These developments demonstrate the project&#8217;s commitment to innovation and growth, positioning SPACE ID as a promising player in the decentralized name service market.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Founders of SPACE ID</h3>



<p>SPACE ID is a decentralized name service network founded by a team of experienced blockchain and software developers and successful entrepreneurs. The team is led by Co-founder and CEO of Salsita Software, Matthew Gertner, who brings over two decades of experience in software development and entrepreneurship to the project. Before founding SPACE ID, Gertner co-founded AllPeers, a peer-to-peer file-sharing application acquired by Opera Software in 2008.</p>



<p>Joining Gertner on the leadership team is COO Dan Zuller, who brings over 15 years of experience in software development and entrepreneurship. Before joining SPACE ID, Zuller co-founded and served as CTO of IP Gallery, a company that provided IP-based multimedia services to telecommunications providers.</p>



<p>Chief Technical Officer Eyal Toledano also brings a wealth of experience to the project, with over 20 years of experience in software development and entrepreneurship. Toledano has worked as a CTO for several successful startups, including SnapAppointments and Joopy.</p>



<p>Chief Strategy Officer Ali Safavi rounds out the leadership team, bringing over ten years of experience in corporate strategy and business development. Before joining SPACE ID, Safavi served as Director of Corporate Development for DocuSign, responsible for leading mergers and acquisitions and strategic partnerships.</p>



<p>Together, the SPACE ID founders bring diverse skills and experiences to the project, with a shared vision of creating a more secure and decentralized name service network for the Web3 era. With their leadership and expertise, SPACE ID is well-positioned to become a leading player in the decentralized name service market, offering an all-in-one domain management and identity verification solution.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SPACE ID Tokenomics</h3>



<p>SPACE ID token (ID) is the native token of the SPACE ID network, serving as a governance currency that enables token holders to participate in the decision-making processes of the decentralized autonomous organization (DAO). The token is also used for staking, payments, and voting, making it a critical component of the platform&#8217;s ecosystem.</p>



<p>The total supply of ID tokens is fixed at 1 billion tokens, with 40% of the total supply allocated to the initial coin offering (ICO) and private sale. The remaining tokens are distributed as follows:</p>



<ul>
<li>20% for the team and advisors</li>



<li>10% for ecosystem development</li>



<li>10% for marketing and partnerships</li>



<li>20% for community incentives</li>
</ul>



<p>Token holders can participate in the platform&#8217;s governance by staking their ID tokens to earn rewards and contribute to the decision-making processes of the DAO. Additionally, the token can be used for paying fees associated with domain registration and management on the platform.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How Does SPACE ID Operate?</h3>



<ul>
<li>SPACE ID is a decentralized and censorship-resistant universal name service network that aims to address the challenges of current Domain Name Services (DNS). The platform is built on a modular and scalable architecture consisting of three core components: the Space ID Protocol, the Space ID Platform, and the Space ID DAO.</li>



<li>The Space ID Protocol is a set of smart contracts that provide the core functionalities of the platform, including web3 domain registration, resolution, management, and governance. Through the Smart ID protocol, users can register web3 domains and bind them to blockchain-based addresses, ensuring secure and decentralized control of digital identities.</li>



<li>The Space ID Platform is a user-friendly interface that allows users to register and manage their web3 domains. It provides access to several features, including domain search, registration, transfer, and management, making it easy for users to manage their digital identities and domains in a secure and decentralized manner.</li>



<li>Space ID DAO is a decentralized autonomous organization that governs the Space ID protocol and platform. The DAO comprises ID token holders with voting rights to contribute their thoughts on how the project should evolve. By leveraging the community&#8217;s collective intelligence, the Space ID DAO ensures that the platform remains community-driven and transparent, providing a reliable and sustainable decentralized name service network for the Web3 era.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What exactly is a Web3 API?</h3>



<p>A Web3 API is a collection of guidelines and protocols facilitating seamless interaction between decentralized applications (dApps) and the underlying blockchain technology. This interface enables dApps to access and index blockchain data, broadcast new transactions, and scale efficiently to meet user demands.</p>



<p>By leveraging a Web3 API, developers can build decentralized applications that integrate with multiple blockchain networks, creating a more seamless user experience. The Web3 API provides a standardized framework for developers to build on, reducing the complexity and overhead of interfacing with different blockchain platforms.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding the Benefits and Functionality of Web3 Name SDK API</h4>



<p>Web3 Name SDK API is a software development tool set that enables developers to create decentralized name services on the Web3 ecosystem. This API provides developers with a standardized interface for interacting with various Web3 name services and decentralized domains.</p>



<p>The Web3 Name SDK API allows developers to create, manage and trade decentralized domains in a decentralized manner. Users can control their domains and identities without relying on third-party intermediaries. The SDK API also provides a secure and transparent platform for developers to build on, ensuring that users&#8217; data and identities are protected.</p>



<p>In addition, the Web3 Name SDK API simplifies the development process by providing a standard interface that allows developers to easily create decentralized applications on top of different Web3 name services. It reduces the barrier to entry for developers and enables them to focus on building innovative solutions instead of worrying about complex technical details.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What Purposes Does the Governance Token $ID Serve?</h3>



<p>The ID token is the native token of the SPACE ID network, serving as a governance currency that enables token holders to participate in the decision-making processes of the decentralized autonomous organization (DAO). One of the primary uses of the governance token, #ID, is to allow token holders to vote on important issues and decentralized proposals related to the project. These decisions can include network protocol changes, fees, and other critical matters affecting the project&#8217;s future.</p>



<p>Through the SPACE ID DAO, token holders have a say in the governance and direction of the network, ensuring that it remains community-driven and transparent. By participating in the voting process, ID token holders can help shape the project&#8217;s future and ensure that it aligns with the values and goals of the community.</p>



<p>Apart from its governance role, the ID token also serves several other functions within the SPACE ID ecosystem. For instance, the token can be used for paying fees associated with domain registration and management on the platform. Furthermore, ID tokens can be staked to earn rewards or provide liquidity for various ecosystem services, such as decentralized storage.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>The current state of Space ID reflects a volatile market with notable price fluctuations. Despite a recent decline in value, bullish trends observed in short-term analysis suggest potential upward movement.</p>



<p>However, long-term prospects are uncertain, with prevailing bearish sentiments and resistance levels potentially impeding significant price increases. Traders and investors are advised to consider support and resistance levels and recent market developments, such as DWF Labs&#8217; strategic asset management decisions, when making decisions regarding Space ID.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4oxdHvTcLtw" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4oxdHvTcLtw" />
			<media:title type="plain">Space ID Crypto Price Prediction. Zones to buy, zones to sell</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Space id coin technical analysis. Space ID Crypto Price Prediction. Zones to buy, zones to sell📥DM me &quot;4LIGHT&quot; -10% promo code, for Indicators set - https:...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/space-id-1.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/space-id-1.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/space-id-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Will Be the Role of Higher ED as AI Encroaches on Tasks Handled by College Grads?</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/role-higher-ed-ai-encroaches-tasks-college/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aamir Sheikh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 04:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI in Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher ED]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=513545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Higher Learning Commission’s (HLC) annual conference was held in Chicago to discuss various challenges higher ED institutions are facing. Experts shared strategies at the conference to help institutions move through a world that is being taken over by automation. The role of higher education is under threat as emerging technologies are threatening it, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Higher Learning Commission’s (HLC) annual conference was held in Chicago to discuss various challenges higher ED institutions are facing. Experts shared strategies at the conference to help institutions move through a world that is being taken over by automation. The role of higher education is under threat as emerging technologies are threatening it, and administrators and instructors are evaluating the ways about how to integrate AI into curriculum.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Daniel Susskind discusses the impact of AI on higher ED</h2>



<p>Daniel Susskind, writer of quite a number of books on the impact of tech on work and an economics professor from King&#8217;s College London, says that AI models like that of ChatGPT are here and they will interfere with executive and professional work. According to him, this disruption will impact colleges in many ripple effects, which have always provided a learning field for white collar workers.</p>



<p>He discussed current progress in fields like that of medical diagnostics and also gave examples of agriculture and manufacturing while discussing the impact of automation on different industries, where automation has increased production gains manyfold but created very lesser jobs. He was speaking at a keynote session at the Higher Learning Commission&#8217;s annual conference on Monday. Discussing the blue collar works, he said,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“We tend to think of the work that blue collar workers do as being relatively routine, relatively straightforward, relatively process-based, relatively easy.” </em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>While talking about white collar work or executive work, he added,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“Conversely, we think of what white collar workers do as requiring subtler faculties — things like creativity, judgment, empathy.”</em></p>
<cite>Source: <a href="https://www.highereddive.com/news/ai-white-collar-work-colleges-daniel-susskind-hlc-conference-2024/713654/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Highereddive</a>.</cite></blockquote>



<p>About the latter one he said, we presume that AI yet has to advance to recreate these functionalities that only the human brain is capable of. He pointed out that in architecture, medicine, law, and accounting, AI does not need to have this quality, at least for solving some of the issues.</p>



<p>Susskind pointed out that our ignorance of this very state of things adds up to the AI fallacy, as he calls it. According to him, our misconception of assuming that copying or replicating is the only way how tasks are performed at the human level, and then we try to develop systems using that approach.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI is encroaching on tasks previously assumed out of its reach</h2>



<p>Some of the tasks that were traditionally considered to be performed by individuals trained by higher education only, are now possible to be completed with AI due to its strong computing power for processing and analysis. So now there are many activities that we considered to be beyond the capabilities of these technologies that are now possible to be overtaken by them. According to Susskind, it is the domain of white collar work.</p>



<p>Susskind advises education and training as the only solution to these emerging changes by preparing people for duties that AI models are still not able to perform. Susskind said,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“There are large areas of human activity that lie beyond the reach of even the most capable technologies.”</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Susskind highlighted that judgment, empathy, and interpersonal communication are some of the sectors still not taken over by AI, and colleges can train people to build such AI systems that can usurp more activities of humans.</p>



<p>Higher education professionals are counting on <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/tech-emerge-to-tackle-higher-educations/" data-type="post" data-id="504682">AI&#8217;s capability</a> for the transition of the sector. Many panels at the conference were dedicated to this very topic, and the opportunities, threats, and promises that AI offers were at the top of the trends list of higher ed.</p>



<p>Grand Canyon College of Education&#8217;s dean, Meredith Critchfield, expressed his views that it does not matter how we perceive AI or how our perspective around it changes over time, what will not change will be the foundation of who we are as institutions.</p>



<p>Find the original story <a href="Highereddive.">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a23f7a3e-1c92-4138-bc95-a5dc467b2f31.jpg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a23f7a3e-1c92-4138-bc95-a5dc467b2f31.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google set to execute new layoffs in a bid to cut costs</title>
		<link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/google-to-execute-new-layoffs-to-cut-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Owotunse Adebayo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 03:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptomarket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cryptopolitan.com/?p=513540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Industry giant Google has announced a fresh round of layoffs in a bid to cut costs. According to a report from Reuters, the company is laying off some members and restructuring some of its team. The major layoffs will affect staff in the company’s real estate and finance departments. The company is axing employees who work in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Industry giant <a href="https://www.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Google</a> has announced a fresh round of layoffs in a bid to cut costs. According to a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/google-lays-off-employees-shifts-some-roles-abroad-amid-cost-cuts-2024-04-17/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">report</a> from Reuters, the company is laying off some members and restructuring some of its team. The major layoffs will affect staff in the company’s real estate and finance departments. The company is axing employees who work in the treasury, business services, and revenue cash operations of the finance department.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Google set to cut more jobs amid restructuring&nbsp;moves</h2>



<p>In an email to staff, the finance chief at Google&nbsp;Ruth&nbsp;Porath&nbsp;wrote that the company&nbsp;is looking&nbsp;to set up growth hubs in locations like Bangalore, Dublin, and Mexico City. This new development is in line with the company’s plans for restructuring. A spokesperson for Google confirmed that the layoffs are not across its global workers&nbsp;and&nbsp;employees affected could apply for internal roles. However, Google failed to disclose the total number of employees&nbsp;that were&nbsp;affected or the teams it is restructuring.</p>



<p>In the report, the spokesperson noted that&nbsp;some of the members would be relocated&nbsp;to these&nbsp;key&nbsp;hubs across the globe.&nbsp;The company&nbsp;is set&nbsp;to increase investments in specific areas worldwide, setting up shop in India, Chicago, Atlanta, and some other strategic locations. The report noted that teams across the company had changed since 2023 up till now to increase their efficiency and assign resources to the&nbsp;biggest&nbsp;priorities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Other tech giants announce&nbsp;layoffs</h2>



<p>This recent development is coming after a few layoffs at the firm earlier this year. Google <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/google-contemplates-layoffs-as-ai-advances-in-ad-sales-division/" data-type="post" data-id="435167">announced</a> the sack of specific employees including engineering hardware and assistant teams as it looked to focus on building the capacity of its artificial intelligence (AI). Its sister company Alphabet, through its CEO Sundar Pichai, <a href="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/google-ceo-staff-more-layoffs-at-the-firm/" data-type="post" data-id="446767">noted</a> that more jobs within Google will be affected. He noted that the firm was looking to create investment capacity, hence the need to make tough choices.</p>



<p>Apple announced the layoffs of about 600 employees at the beginning of this month in its self-driving cars and smartwatch screen teams. The layoffs became necessary after the company axed both programs. Amazon Web Services also cut some jobs as a part of its broader efforts to help its parent company. The company laid off&nbsp;more than&nbsp;hundreds of employees across several departments last month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7797.jpeg" medium="image"  type="image/jpeg" /><media:thumbnail url="https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_7797.jpeg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
