<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
            <rss version = "2.0"
                xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
                xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
                xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
                xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
                xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
                <channel>
                    <title>News &#8211; Finance Magnates | Financial and business news</title>
<atom:link href="https://www.financemagnates.com//feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//</link>
<description></description>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 15:36:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator></generator>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[UK Investigates Big Tech's AI Ventures over Competition Concerns]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/uk-investigates-big-techs-ai-ventures-over-competition-concerns/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/uk-investigates-big-techs-ai-ventures-over-competition-concerns/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:14:34 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Institutional FX]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/uk-investigates-big-techs-ai-ventures-over-competition-concerns</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The UK's competition regulator is scrutinizing the involvement
of big technology companies in the AI sector. Concerns over competition and
market dominance have prompted the Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) to
probe partnerships of major firms like Microsoft, Amazon, and AI startups.</p><p>Risks to Competition</p><p>According to the press release, the CMA is seeking
views specifically on the partnerships between Microsoft and Mistral AI, and Amazon and
Anthropic. Additionally, Microsoft's hiring of former employees
of Inflection AI is under scrutiny. The CMA
emphasized that it has not reached conclusions on whether these deals violate the UK's merger rules or pose competition concerns.</p><p>Joel Bamford, the Executive Director of Mergers at the
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/cma/" target="_blank" rel="follow">CMA</a>, mentioned: "Today we're inviting comments into the partnerships
between Microsoft and Mistral AI, Amazon and Anthropic, and Microsoft's hiring
of former employees and related arrangements with Inflection AI. We will assess, objectively and impartially,
whether each of these 3 deals fall within UK <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/m/merger/" class="terms__main-term" id="7631c19b-b9f3-43ee-a0cf-d4f8094270bc">merger</a> rules and, if they do,
whether they have any impact on competition in the UK."</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’re inviting comments on the partnerships, and other arrangements, between <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Microsoft?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mistral?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Mistral</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AI</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Amazon?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Amazon</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Anthropic?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Anthropic</a>, and Microsoft and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Inflection?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Inflection</a> AI. Read more: <a href="https://t.co/NlCXdHQjbw">https://t.co/NlCXdHQjbw</a></p>— Competition &amp; Markets Authority (@CMAgovUK) <a href="https://twitter.com/CMAgovUK/status/1783089190781018364?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 24, 2024</a></blockquote><p>A recent report by the CMA highlighted the risks to
fair competition in <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/artificial-intelligence/">AI</a> Foundation Models (FMs) markets. These risks include
concerns that partnerships among major players may strengthen existing market
dominance. Competition authorities worldwide are actively investigating AI-related activities due to their global implications.  </p><p>Global Competition Authorities Scrutinize AI</p><p>"Open, fair, and effective competition in
Foundation Model markets is critical to ensuring that the full benefits of this transformation are realized by people and businesses in the UK, as well as our wider economy, where technology has a huge role to play in growth and
productivity," Bamford added. CMA is also considering feedback on Microsoft's partnership
with OpenAI. </p><p>In September 2023, Amazon announced a $4 billion
investment in AI developer <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/anthropic/">Anthropic</a> to boost the development of advanced FMs. After fulfilling this commitment in March 2024, the e-commerce giant secured a minority stake in Anthropic and integrated AWS as its cloud service provider.</p><p>While the focus is on UK-based activities, companies
like Microsoft and Google have been investing billions of dollars in AI
development worldwide. These tech giants are expanding their AI footprint in
countries such as the United Arab Emirates, Spain, Germany, and France.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Strike's Expansion into Europe Accelerates Bitcoin Adoption]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/strike-expansion-into-europe-accelerates-bitcoin-adoption/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/strike-expansion-into-europe-accelerates-bitcoin-adoption/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:42:55 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/strike-expansion-into-europe-accelerates-bitcoin-adoption</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Strike, a payments application utilizing the Bitcoin
blockchain, has launched its services in Europe, enabling customers in the
region to engage in buying, selling, and withdrawing bitcoin (BTC). The
announcement was made today (Wednesday).</p><p>Expanding Operations Across Continents</p><p>Having recently expanded its operations to Africa, Strike
has already established its presence in Asia, the Caribbean, and Latin America.
However, availability may vary by country, and interested customers are
encouraged to check their local iOS or Android app stores for accessibility, as
some regions may be excluded from the expansion.</p><p>“As the third-largest economy globally … Europe presents
vast opportunities for <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/bitcoin/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="261088a9-0f41-4202-a73c-31f75ba6bd93">bitcoin</a> adoption,” Strike said in a press release.
“We’ve seen the demand and heard the feedback first-hand from the community.”</p><p><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/the-potential-of-blockchain-technology-in-revolutionizing-payment-systems/">Blockchain
technology is reshaping global payments</a> with its security and efficiency.
Unlike traditional methods prone to fraud, blockchain's decentralized ledger
ensures secure transactions. Advanced cryptographic techniques like digital
signatures bolster security further. </p><p>Eliminating intermediaries, blockchain enables direct
peer-to-peer transactions, expediting settlements and reducing costs.
Cross-border payments, often costly and time-consuming, stand to benefit
greatly from blockchain's streamlined approach. With its potential to simplify
and secure transactions, blockchain emerges as a disruptive force in the global
payment landscape.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🚨LATEST: Bitcoin Payment App Strike Expands to Europe, Boosting Crypto Accessibility  <a href="https://t.co/5p4jJ6qpDX">https://t.co/5p4jJ6qpDX</a></p>— CryptoCrunchApp (News Feed) (@GoCryptoCrunch) <a href="https://twitter.com/GoCryptoCrunch/status/1783135094166728928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 24, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Introducing Bitcoin-Powered Payment Solution for European
Market</p><p>Developed by Chicago-based Zap Solutions under the
leadership of entrepreneur Jack Mallers, Strike was initially introduced in the
United States in 2020. Similar to widely used online payment platforms such as
Cash App or PayPal, Strike facilitates global money transfers for its users.
Notably, Strike distinguishes itself by leveraging the Bitcoin <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/b/blockchain/" class="terms__main-term" id="be18ed01-45fc-4044-b447-06802a10dbcd">blockchain</a>,
which enables swifter and more cost-effective transactions compared to
conventional alternatives.</p><p>In Europe, customers will have the convenience of conducting
BTC transactions directly with euro deposits via SEPA, the region’s payments
provider. Recipients of these funds will have the flexibility to opt for
receiving the value in either bitcoin, euro, or, in select areas, Tether’s USDT
stablecoin.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[XTB Shares Hit New Peak Following Record-High Dividend of $195 Million]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/xtb-shares-hit-new-peak-following-record-high-dividend-of-195-million/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/xtb-shares-hit-new-peak-following-record-high-dividend-of-195-million/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 13:07:33 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Brokers]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/xtb-shares-hit-new-peak-following-record-high-dividend-of-195-million</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The management board of the publicly-traded broker XTB announced that it
recommends paying a dividend of over PLN 590 million ($146 million) per share, which is historically the highest portion of profit distributed
among shareholders.</p><p>In response to the news, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/xtb/">XTB's shares</a> on the Warsaw Stock Exchange (WSE) tested
historical highs on Wednesday.</p><p>75%
of XTB’s 2023 Profit Allocated for Dividend</p><p>According to information published by the company this week, the Management
Board of XTB adopted a resolution recommending the allocation of 75% of the
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/xtbs-revenue-rises-10-yoy-with-active-clients-doubling-in-number/">company's net profit for 2023</a>, amounting to PLN 787 million ($195 million), for
dividend payment. The remaining part, PLN 197 million ($49 million), will
supplement the company's reserve capital.</p><p>"The Management Board of XTB proposes a dividend record date of 5 June
2024 and a dividend payment date of 20 June 2024," the XTB statement read.</p><p>This means that XTB will pay PLN 5.02 ($1.24) per share, which gives a
dividend <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/y/yield/" class="terms__main-term" id="cfaa38df-248b-415d-a58f-1c65a6b5fdac">yield</a> of 7.2%. However, this yield is lower than in the previous year due
to the strong increase in the share price on the WSE.</p><p>XTB's shares grew by nearly 22% last year and are already growing by over 60% this year. The information about the dividend payment triggered
another growth impulse, and on Wednesday, the shares briefly gained almost 2%,
setting a new historical high at PLN 62.30.</p><p>However, the good streak does not only concern XTB itself. Plus, 500 shares on the LSE have been growing by 30% since the beginning of the year, and historical highs, around 2200 pence per share, have also been tested.</p><p>Net profit is not the only factor contributing to investors'
confidence in XTB. Primarily, it is the continuous increase in the number of
clients and plans for product and geographical expansion.</p><p>XTB
Has over One Million Clients</p><p>XTB, which no longer wants to be associated as an FX/CFD broker but as a
"global fintech," certainly has many reasons for this. At the
beginning of this month, the company announced that its number of clients had
exceeded <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/xtb-surpasses-one-million-customer-milestone-amidst-fintech-expansion/">the milestone of one million</a>, doubling over the past three years.</p><p>In the meantime, the company has introduced many new products, including
passive trading tools based on ETFs. In 2024, it already put <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/xtb-introduces-social-trading-focusing-on-investor-engagement/">a social trading platform</a> in users' hands. Soon, it will also offer the possibility
of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/xtb-to-launch-social-trading-and-bond-offering-in-2024-product-roadmap/">trading bonds</a>.</p><p>According to information from February, XTB counts on expansion in the
British market, where <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/xtb-aims-for-400-billion-market-in-the-uk-anticipates-strong-take-up/">it wants to join</a> the £400 billion Individual Savings
Accounts (ISAs) industry. The expansion also goes beyond the old continent, and
an example of this is the <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/a/acquisition/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="3180494d-8751-4a02-9476-86dc1cd4d2e2">acquisition</a> of a broker in Indonesia, which is to
become <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/brokers/exclusive-xtb-acquires-broker-in-indonesia-to-become-a-gateway-to-asia/">a "Gateway to Asia" </a>for the company.</p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[US Prosecutors Recommend 3-Year Prison Sentence for Binance's Changpeng Zhao: Report]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/us-prosecutors-recommend-3-year-prison-sentence-for-binances-changpeng-zhao-report/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/us-prosecutors-recommend-3-year-prison-sentence-for-binances-changpeng-zhao-report/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:55:29 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Kirui]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/us-prosecutors-recommend-3-year-prison-sentence-for-binances-changpeng-zhao-report</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>US prosecutors have proposed a 36-month prison sentence for Binance's former CEO, Changpeng Zhao. According to a report by
CNBC, the prosecutors argued that such a sentence, which is double the advisory
guidelines, reflects the seriousness of the charges against Zhao.</p><p>The recommendation, outlined in a sentencing
memorandum filed with the Western District Court of Washington, highlights the
severity of the accusations against Zhao, who stepped down from his position
last November following a plea deal with the US Department of Justice.</p><p>US Prosecutors' Charges Against Zhao</p><p>US prosecutors said a 36-month custodial sentence
is necessary to underscore the seriousness of the charges against Zhao, which
include failure to implement anti-money laundering measures as mandated
by the Bank Secrecy Act. The memorandum emphasized Zhao's alleged role in
allowing Binance to process transactions involving unlawful
activities, including those from sanctioned countries.  </p><p>The case against Zhao occurs amidst a backdrop of legal
challenges for <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/binance/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Binance</a>, with the exchange facing lawsuits from both the US
Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Commodity Futures Trading
Commission (<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/c/cftc/" class="terms__main-term" id="b5ae3af7-f418-4c65-9082-0c34b44bd668">CFTC</a>). </p><p>Allegations include mishandling customer assets and
operating an illegal, unregistered <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/e/exchange/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="b5da6e64-2afe-421d-9b81-16404b7d59d6">exchange</a> in the US. Authorities have also
ordered Binance to pay <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/binance-will-exit-the-us-paying-over-76-billion-in-settlements/" target="_blank" rel="follow">hefty fines</a>, with Zhao agreeing to a $50 million penalty
as part of the plea deal. However, he has not
publicly commented on the recent developments. Zhao's official sentencing is
scheduled for April 30.</p><p>Binance CEO's Legal Struggle</p><p>In January, a federal judge <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/binance-founders-travel-plea-denied-despite-45-billion-security-offer/" target="_blank" rel="follow">rejected a travel request</a>
from Zhao to visit his home in the United Arab Emirates for a family emergency. The judge deemed him a significant flight risk due to his immense
wealth and ties to the UAE, despite offering to post his $4.5 billion equity in Binance as security for his
return.</p><p>In November, Zhao pleaded guilty in a Seattle federal
court to failing to maintain an effective anti-money laundering program at
Binance. As part of the case, Binance agreed to pay $4.3 billion in penalties. </p><p>In a letter  to Judge Richard Jones dated December 22,
Zhao's lawyers requested permission for him to travel to Abu Dhabi on January 4
for one to four weeks due to a family emergency. However, federal prosecutors did not consent to Zhao's
request, leading to a hearing on December 29, where Judge Jones denied
the travel bid.</p>

This article was written by Jared Kirui at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Dubai-Based CoinW Unveils Rebranding and Prop Trading Product]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/dubai-based-coinw-unveils-rebranding-and-prop-trading-product/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/dubai-based-coinw-unveils-rebranding-and-prop-trading-product/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 12:21:54 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/dubai-based-coinw-unveils-rebranding-and-prop-trading-product</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>CoinW Exchange, a notable presence within the digital asset
trading domain, is undergoing changes as it observes its sixth-year
anniversary. Situated in Dubai, the exchange has revealed an exhaustive
rebranding effort alongside the debut of its Proprietary Trading (Prop Trading)
product. </p><p>Introducing Prop Trading for Profit Opportunities</p><p>Having cemented its position within the digital assets
trading industry, CoinW Exchange is now set to enter a fresh phase of
development. A centrepiece of its transformation is the launch of the Prop
Trading product, an offering aimed at providing traders with expanded avenues
for profit optimization. This new product is set to play a role in CoinW
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/e/exchange/" class="terms__main-term" id="b5da6e64-2afe-421d-9b81-16404b7d59d6">Exchange</a>'s strategic outlook for the future according to the firm.</p><p>According to Sonic, Director of CoinW PropTrading: "We
have a host of exciting plans in the pipeline that promise to revolutionize the
way digital assets are traded. We hope CPT can bring more opportunities to
talented traders who are short of fund. CoinW will be the place that they can
truly shine."</p><p>Challenges and Opportunities: UAE's Crypto Journey</p><p>A recent survey by KuCoin <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/uaes-crypto-landscape-thrives-as-59-embrace-long-term-view-kucoin-survey/">sheds
light on the growing cryptocurrency landscape</a> in the United Arab Emirates
(UAE), as reported by <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/">Finance
Magnates</a>. Despite challenges, 59% of UAE crypto users view it as a
long-term investment and 35% use it for portfolio diversification.
Additionally, 29% see crypto as a more convenient asset storage method than
traditional banks, and 22% use it for daily transactions. </p><p>Challenges include
market volatility (52%), trust issues with crypto platforms (48%), and a lack
of education (26%). However, the UAE benefits from strong financial
infrastructure, cultural openness, regulatory favorability, access to capital,
a skilled workforce, and global networks, positioning it as a promising hub for
crypto industry growth.</p><p>Amidst escalating tensions, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/prop-trading-firms-renaissance-cutting-us-clients-integrating-new-trading-platforms/">MetaQuotes
is reportedly tightening restrictions on the use of MetaTrader platforms</a>,
although no official confirmation has been issued. This has led to the abrupt
termination of partnerships between many proprietary trading firms and their
brokerage partners. The primary concern appears to be the presence of active US
clients onboarded by these platforms. </p><p>Proprietary trading has been predominantly linked with unregulated entities. However,
regulated brokerages such as OANDA, Axi, and Hantec Markets have recently
ventured into this space, keeping their services outside the US jurisdiction
and under offshore regulatory entities.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[5 Strategies That Drive Engagement for Financial Brands]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/5-strategies-that-drive-engagement-for-financial-brands/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/5-strategies-that-drive-engagement-for-financial-brands/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:37:37 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/5-strategies-that-drive-engagement-for-financial-brands</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Engaging customers, both new and existing, can feel like pulling teeth for financial companies nowadays. With the rise of the customer-centric economy, people expect personalized, on-demand interactions from all brands—not just the Big Tech players. So how can banks, fintech, credit unions, and even DeFI firms rise to meet these growing expectations and make their users excited to interact with their products/services? Let’s dive into a few strategies.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Segment and Specialize Your Marketing Outreach</p><p class="MsoNormal">Gone are the days where you can just send out blanket promotions and hope that they hit the mark. The customers of today demand a lot more than that, specifically when it comes to communications catering to their specific niches, needs, and interests. </p><p class="MsoNormal">If your target market is fintech adopters who prioritize sleek digital experiences, then it's going to be best if you tailor your marketing strategy to highlight intuitive mobile apps and seamless account opening experiences. </p><p class="MsoNormal">If you’re in the DeFi space, you're going to need a <a href="https://marketacross.com/blockchain-marketing-strategy-the-ultimate-guide/">blockchain marketing strategy</a> that speaks directly to their concerns. In this case, you may want to play up things like transparency and security for the crypto crowd, detailing blockchain protections and your decentralization efforts. At the same time, these messages will be completely lost to someone uninterested in the Web3 space. </p><p class="MsoNormal">As always, it pays to know your audience - so drill down into the key demographics. Young investors may be cost-conscious but risk-tolerant, valuing fractional share offerings from disruptors like Robinhood. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Near-retirees may want retirement planning and portfolio protection. Here, outline annuities and capital preservation funds that guarantee income for people depending on nest eggs in volatile times. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Consider diverse locations and languages as well - are you connecting with rural communities? Speaking to recent immigrant groups through multilingual touchpoints? The more you segment and specialize your marketing efforts, the better. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Add Interactive Elements and Gamification</p><p class="MsoNormal">Let’s be honest—static content doesn’t fully engage anymore in the TikTok era. Bring financial concepts to life through simulations, live quizzes, an <a href="https://www.finextra.com/blogposting/25083/10-best-practice-examples-of-gamification-in-financial-services#:~:text=Gamification%20can%20turn%20the%20act,makes%20investing%20approachable%20for%20everyone.">friendly competition through gamification. </a></p><p class="MsoNormal">To give some examples, investment apps could incorporate fantasy trading leagues where newcomers track other people’s portfolios. Get people active in the experience!</p><p class="MsoNormal">For account holders, create gaming aspects around saving goals too. Set up digital “jars” for vacations, weddings, etc. that people contribute towards for rewards. Encourage consistency through points systems that unlock real perks. Making progress visible and fun drives motivation. </p><p class="MsoNormal">One thing that many brands have found success with is tying rewards to financial literacy education for new account holders too. Not only does this help money concepts stick better, but it aids with compliance and demonstrates to regulators that you are taking user education seriously. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Facilitate Sharing and Conversation </p><p class="MsoNormal">Humans naturally want to connect with others regarding financial matters because money impacts almost all life pursuits, including well-being and security. Yet, discussing finances still feels taboo to some. That’s why branded online forums, webinars, and social media groups resonate by providing judgment-free spaces where people can open up.</p><p class="MsoNormal">To take it one step further, you could Invite account holders behind-the-scenes too with exclusive virtual events. Let them engage experts through live Q&amp;As and AMAs. Make it easy to participate through apps and tools with frictionless access.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Thought leadership positioning also helps to cement your role as a trusted advisor too. Share investment philosophies, fraud warnings, and tips aligned to audience values. Facilitating two-way conversations through consistent digital engagement makes your brand part of people’s financial lives.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Lead with Emotional Storytelling</p><p class="MsoNormal">Facts and figures don’t stick with people...but stories do. Plant memories by showing how you’ve helped everyday users overcome obstacles or achieve meaningful goals. Maybe it’s assisting special needs families with securing care resources through insurance proceeds. Or retirement planning that enabled a couple to finally sail their dream boat in the Mediterranean after years of working. When people see themselves in examples, that forges powerful connections.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Weave in how you navigated recent societal challenges too, like helping businesses access loans or other lines of credit during the pandemic. People invest in brands aligned with their values and principles, so showcasing your positive impacts through storytelling really helps to create those deep emotional bonds.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Adopt Cutting-Edge Technology</p><p class="MsoNormal">Today's customers expect financial products and services to continually upgrade technologically. After sticking with the same bank for 10 years, account holders don't want to log into an interface that hasn’t been refreshed since opening day. Nothing frustrates people more than outdated digital experiences in the era of lightning-fast innovation.</p><p class="MsoNormal">With this in mind, financial brands should obsess over CX improvement by rapidly adopting emerging innovations like <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/the-ai-effect-transforming-fintech-operations-for-better-customer-engagement/">AI and automation</a>. Chatbots utilizing natural language processing can provide personalized support and financial advice at scale. Intelligent algorithms can perform rapid fraud detection and hyper-customize product recommendations for each individual.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Be proactive here - run small beta tests with willing groups open to new technology. Involve users early for productive feedback, not just after the fact when they’re already irritated. The truth is, pursuing a culture of experimentation and adaptation sets firms up for long-term relevance, compared to rigid bureaucracies that always seem to lag behind customer expectations. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Final Word</p><p class="MsoNormal">The world of finance is evolving faster than ever before. If brands want to keep up, then they must abandon the old school way of thinking and start embracing the customer obsessed mindset of today's most successful companies. This means going beyond just offering financial products. Instead, this means offering hyper personalized experiences that are interactive and woven into the fabric of people's lives. </p><p class="MsoNormal text-align-start">By segmenting your marketing, adding gamified elements, sparking open conversations, and leading with cutting edge tech, you can transform your brand from a faceless money management service into a trusted partner.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[FBS Financial Market Analysts Forecast Gold Prices to Rise to $2,800]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/fbs-financial-market-analysts-forecast-gold-prices-to-rise-to-2800/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/fbs-financial-market-analysts-forecast-gold-prices-to-rise-to-2800/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:29:58 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/fbs-financial-market-analysts-forecast-gold-prices-to-rise-to-2800</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>FBS, a leading global broker that has recently launched an <a href="https://upgraded-app.fbs.com/?utm_source=prcomms&amp;utm_medium=pressrelease&amp;utm_campaign=gold" target="_blank" rel="follow">upgraded FBS app</a>, projects gold price surge to $2,800 per ounce by the close of 2024. FBS financial market analysts have identified the pivotal factors driving the bullish trend for gold and covered the potential strategies for CFD traders.</p><p>Gold is among the assets characterized by stability and resilience in the financial markets, making it an appealing instrument for investors. FBS analysts foresee an upward trend for gold in Q2 and on until the end of the year. They associate the bullish tendency with significant central bank buying, continued inflationary pressures in the global economy, and increased demand for gold from non-institutional investors.</p><p>Central banks worldwide are actively fortifying their gold reserves, signaling a strategic shift towards safer assets in the context of escalating geopolitical tensions. FBS financial market analysts point out that hedging and diversification of reserves has recently become typical of the People's Bank of China, the Monetary Authority of Singapore, the Reserve Bank of India, the Central Bank of Turkey, and others.</p><p>Inflationary pressures stemming from aftershocks of the global pandemic, military conflicts, rising oil prices, and complications within prominent maritime trade routes push gold prices further. According to FBS analysts, inflationary pressures are increasing the attractiveness of gold as a hedge against currency devaluation and declining purchasing power.</p><p>Non-institutional investors are increasingly gravitating towards gold as a store of value and a means of portfolio diversification. Total gold demand, including over-the-counter markets, surged to historic highs in 2023, fueled by economic uncertainty and evolving investment preferences, particularly in China.</p><p>Another critical factor affecting the increased demand for gold is the interest of non-institutional investors. Financial markets analysts from FBS indicate that the total gold demand, including OTC markets, reached a new annual record in 2023 at approximately 4,899 tons. FBS analysts suggest taking a closer look at China's gold market, which is experiencing a noticeable surge in demand, to understand the current trend better.</p><p>Looking closely at the XAUUSD trajectory in the weekly timeframe, FBS analysts underscore a bullish trend. Gold has updated its ATH, and the price is actively testing the $2,400 resistance, corresponding to 161.8 Fibonacci. If XAUUSD manages to break this level, investors can expect gold to rise further to $2,800, which coincides with the 261.8 Fibonacci level. However, if there is a correction, the price may fall to the support at $2,200 and then rush up to $2,800.</p><p>Regarding trading strategies, FBS’s experts stress the importance of prudent risk management amidst bullish market conditions. Strategies such as controlling position sizes, limiting trade deposits to 2-10% of the total portfolio, and employing stop-loss orders are recommended to safeguard capital and encourage diversification. These actions can be easily performed at the enhanced <a href="https://upgraded-app.fbs.com/?utm_source=prcomms&amp;utm_medium=pressrelease&amp;utm_campaign=gold" target="_blank" rel="follow">FBS app</a>, which allows traders to seize market opportunities on the go, anytime. Additionally, FBS analysts recommend aligning with the prevailing market trend and utilizing technical analysis tools like moving averages, RSI, and MACD.</p><p>Disclaimer: This material does not constitute a call to trade, trading advice, or recommendation and is intended for informational purposes only.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[FMAS:24 Session Spotlight - SuperApps: One App to Rule Them All?]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmas24-session-spotlight-superapps-one-app-to-rule-them-all/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmas24-session-spotlight-superapps-one-app-to-rule-them-all/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:19:21 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Patterson]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[FM-Events]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmas24-session-spotlight-superapps-one-app-to-rule-them-all</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">With only a few short weeks to go until the Finance Magnates Africa Summit (FMAS:24) is underway, the hype surrounding the event is real. Taking place in Sandton City, South Africa on May 20-22, this year’s event is going bigger and bolder than ever before. This includes more content, more live entertainment, more speakers, and most importantly, attendees.</p><p class="MsoNormal">The premium event will aim to unite the B2C and B2B space for three days, showcasing Africa’s potential as well as looking to inform, educate, and bring various elements of industries together. FMAS:24 will be focusing on the online trading, fintech, payments, and blockchain &amp; digital assets space.</p><p class="MsoNormal">The event is targeting upwards 3,000 attendees, 120 exhibitors, 150 speakers, and more. With constant action on the summit floor, chances to engage directly with speakers, and live entertainment, truly anything to happen at FMAS:24! </p><p class="MsoNormal">This year will also feature panels, sessions, workshops and more across not only the Centre Stage, but also the new <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fm-events/introducing-trader-zone-at-fmas24/" target="_blank">Trader Zone</a>. The innovative hub is tailored towards retail traders, providing a welcoming forum for attendees to network, connect, and learn from experts and speakers. In terms of sessions, one of the most anticipated will be the marquee panel, ‘SuperApps: One App to Rule Them All?’.</p><p class="MsoNormal">As a quick reminder, if you have not already done so, head on over to the registration page for FMAS:24 and <a href="https://events.financemagnates.com/event/aad8d48a-17e5-426c-8e9f-8faedd80b023/regProcessStep1">sign-up today</a>! Registering online ensures you can skip the wait and queue on-site.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Can SuperApps Reign Supreme?</p><p class="MsoNormal">As financial activity increasingly migrates to mobile, the emphasis on superapps will only grow in 2024 and beyond. Nowhere is this trend more salient than in Africa, where widespread mobile adoption exists alongside infrastructural challenges. </p><p class="MsoNormal">The upcoming session ‘SuperApps: One App to Rule Them All?’, will attempt to lay bare these challenges and figure out tangible solutions. Look for participating fintech leaders to discuss the efficacy of the superapps within this scope. Should these constructs be viewed as a panacea or is there a more layered set of constraints that must be compensated for?</p><p class="MsoNormal"><a href="https://events.financemagnates.com/event/aad8d48a-17e5-426c-8e9f-8faedd80b023/regProcessStep1" target="_blank">Register Today for the Biggest Event of the Year in Africa!</a></p><p class="MsoNormal">Taking place on May 22, 15:50-16:30, the panel session includes the following speakers:</p><ul><li>Vinoliah Martin, Client Executive, Microsoft </li><li>Marco Torrente, Executive Head of Marketing &amp; Digital, Vodacom Financial and Digital Lifestyle Services </li><li>Gour Lentell, CEO &amp; Co-founder, Datafree | Moya </li><li>Shaheen Khatieb, Senior Product Manager, ayoba</li></ul><p class="MsoNormal">Superapps have increasingly been gaining traction in Africa due to their ability to address various challenges and provide convenient solutions to users. In the African scope, where access to multiple services may be limited, these apps essentially can offer a one-stop platform for a wide range of needs.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Join the distinguished panelists for a deep dive into superapps and their impact on the African fintech space moving forward.</p><p class="MsoNormal">See you in South Africa next month!</p>

This article was written by Jeff Patterson at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Working from Home? The Ultimate Home Office Part 2]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//trending/working-from-home-the-ultimate-home-office-part-2/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//trending/working-from-home-the-ultimate-home-office-part-2/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:10:39 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Louis Parks]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Trending]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//trending/working-from-home-the-ultimate-home-office-part-2</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Remote work, or working from home, is here to stay for many of us. That
means that we all need a home office, or at least a corner where we can catch
up on vital tasks. Welcome to Part 2 of our ultimate home office setup guide. </p><p>Firstly, if you haven’t read <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/trending/the-ultimate-home-office-part-1/">Part
1</a>, go do that. You’re back? Great.</p><p>Let’s kick on.</p><p>Wi-Fi Router</p><p>OK, “I’ve got one,” I hear you cry. But does it reach the home office?
Are you getting the best possible service? There’s nothing more soul-destroying
than wasting time downloading files when you could be cracking on, so consider
investing in a decent router. If the router’s OK, you might look into signal
extenders or boosters to make sure you’re getting all the bars you need.</p><p>Desk Lamp</p><p>We’re not a fan of late nights while working from home, but they happen. Invest in a
decent desk lamp. You can go for an “angle-poise” style piece for a little charm,
one those fancy ones with a built-in phone charger or USB port, or a more modern
affair that clips onto your monitor. The choice is all yours, but you’ll need
one.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Complete Home Office, Alvin Rosenbaum, 1995 <a href="https://t.co/gSkKs2DkIP">pic.twitter.com/gSkKs2DkIP</a></p>— vintage.stuff (@vintagestuff4) <a href="https://twitter.com/vintagestuff4/status/1780875380301169014?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Pretty accurate, but I'd possibly be in my PJs.</p><p>Printer</p><p>I hate printers, they never work for me. They don’t connect, they jam,
they’re just a pain. Hopefully you’re almost paper-free, but we’d advise
getting a simple, wired printer that can sit close enough, but out of the way,
only turned on when you absolutely need it.</p><p>Headphone Stand</p><p>Absolutely optional, but a decent headphone stand will lift your headphones
off the desk, allowing you to reclaim a little real estate. Many of them also
come with built-in phone chargers, too. Alternatively, keep your headphones in
the draw and save a little money.</p><p>Cable Organizers</p><p>Get some. Mouse cables. Phone cables. Webcam cables. Cables, cables,
cables. You can get little Velcro wraps, or ones that stick on the backside of
your desk, or weighted ones to make sure nothing moves, or even entire trays
that stick on the underside of your desk. Visualize your desk, decide where
your cables need to be and get organizing. They're also known as "cable tidies" for when you're Googling. Less visual clutter = better mental
clarity.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🌸home office <a href="https://t.co/IUgx8ItSi7">pic.twitter.com/IUgx8ItSi7</a></p>— Elle Lookbook (@EvaLovesDesign) <a href="https://twitter.com/EvaLovesDesign/status/1782240585253847340?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></blockquote><p>She'd better have really good cable management.</p><p>Bluetooth Adapter?</p><p>If you don’t have wireless on your PC, you can easily buy a Bluetooth adapter
that’ll plug into a USB port to allow you to use wireless devices like mice,
headphones and keyboards. Just think, fewer cables, fewer cable organizers.</p><p>A Quality Coaster with a Lip</p><p>Get one. They’ll stop your “World’s Best Dad” mug from sliding around
or your Nescafe getting spilt.</p><p>A White Board?</p><p>Consider getting a small whiteboard. Use it as a to-do list or a
brainstorming aid. They’re surprisingly useful. Just make sure it has a little
pen shelf or pen clips on the side. And for your sake, get the correct pens
before you ruin it.</p><p>A Glass Mat</p><p>OK, this one is entirely “extra” as the cool kids say. If you’ve got a rolling
chair, a glass mat will help you roll around to your heart’s content while
being see-through so you can see your beautiful floor or mat underneath. But,
there’s a benefit for everyone, and it’s a bit weird. Glass mats stay quite
cool throughout the day, and they remain cold when cooled by, say, air
conditioning. Essentially, a glass mat is your own little refrigeration device.
Glass mats – Useful, if situational.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Do you have a spare room? Why not make it your home office? <a href="https://t.co/4vbItwn1NR">pic.twitter.com/4vbItwn1NR</a></p>— Designing with Tega (@interiorwittega) <a href="https://twitter.com/interiorwittega/status/1780552637554778163?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 17, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Now, that space could do with a glass mat.</p><p>Desk Toys</p><p>Newton’s Cradle? Magnetic balls? You know what we’re talking about.
Desk toys are a fun way of distracting yourself from what can very often be
quite a lonely experience. Consider a steel tumbler or a gyroscope. Whatever it
is, it’s just there to keep you entertained during your break, or while that
uncompressed presentation is downloading on your super-slow Wi-Fi that’s
punishing you because you haven’t sorted out your router (yet).</p><p>And there you have it. That’s our ultimate home office guide for 2024
done and dusted. We hope that it’s given you some ideas and that working from
home might just be a little more enjoyable going forward.</p><p>You won’t need everything, but we’re betting that you never knew how
cable organized you could be until you discovered under-desk cable management
and those little sticky things that hang on the back of your desk…</p><p>For more finance-adjacent pieces, follow our <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/trending/">Trending</a> section.</p>

This article was written by Louis Parks at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[White-Labelling at Finalto, in Conversation with Stanislav Bunimovich – Finalto Group COO]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/white-labelling-at-finalto-in-conversation-with-stanislav-bunimovich-finalto-group-coo/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/white-labelling-at-finalto-in-conversation-with-stanislav-bunimovich-finalto-group-coo/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:08:33 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/white-labelling-at-finalto-in-conversation-with-stanislav-bunimovich-finalto-group-coo</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="paragraph">Finalto Group takes immense pride in its award-winning, white-labelled brokerage solutions, which continue to set industry standards in innovation and service quality. Finalto sat down with Stanislav Bunimovich, Finalto's Chief Operating Officer, to explore what makes Finalto's white label solutions stand out in such an incredibly competitive market.  </p><p class="paragraph">Finalto's white-label solutions provide a comprehensive suite of capabilities for partners, including the ability to setup price feeds, margin controls, commission groups, trade routing, and risk settings, highlighting the system's flexibility in offering a wide range of options to support end clients. Partners can review their real-time risk against Finalto and their underlying clients, showcasing the system's emphasis on risk management. </p><p class="paragraph">The solutions also feature a web-based interface for setting up new client accounts and running daily reports, facilitating day-to-day business operations. Finalto white-label solutions give you access to a bespoke front-end trading platform available via Windows PC, web-based interfaces, and mobile apps for both iOS and Android; ensuring partners have the tools they need for trading regardless of their platform of choice. </p><p class="paragraph">This interview with Bunimovich is a unique opportunity to gain insights into the distinct advantages of partnering with Finalto.</p><p class="paragraph text-align-start vertical-align-baseline">How do Finalto's current white-label solutions stand out in the competitive market? What makes using white-labelled products with Finalto a unique experience?" </p><p class="paragraph">As our industry peers will know, the brokerage and liquidity spaces are incredibly fast moving; always innovating and moving forward. Building a reputation that has staying power for your clients is a task that takes unwavering dedication, meticulous planning and bold strategic choices. The journey that Finalto has undertaken as it has built its award-winning technology stack from the ground up is something that has given us a wealth of competitive advantages, invaluable experience, and an incredible depth of expertise.  </p><p class="paragraph">Foundationally, our liquidity and market-making capabilities are very strong. With access to our liquidity systems and connections, brokers are competitively equipped even as the industry propels itself forward. Our technology infrastructure is engineered to create seamless scalability on the front end without incurring exorbitant costs of in-house development. Our trading platforms cater to both institutional and retail clients, boasting powerful financial technology; comprehensive charting tools, news feeds, and sentiment analysis - all seamlessly integrated into a great user experience.  </p><p class="paragraph">Additionally, the exceptionally high quality of our customer flow analytics are the result of collaborative and mutually beneficial partnerships within the banking sector. Coupled with our data analytics facilities allow us to provide data that is on a par with leading investment banks, enabling us to share valuable and dynamic insights with our clients. We aren’t done making great connections and partnerships for our business either. Recently, we announced a strategic partnership with Solace, aimed at enhancing our technological capabilities even further. </p><p class="paragraph">All of this works together to truly distinguish the white-label offering we provide. Our clients inherit the years of experience and effort we have invested in technology, liquidity, and infrastructure. This allows them to focus on their core business, whilst being secure in the knowledge that critical aspects such as platforms, technology, and liquidity are expertly managed by Finalto in the background.  </p><p class="paragraph text-align-start vertical-align-baseline">How customisable are Finalto's white-label solutions for different client needs, and what are the key flexible features that you offer?</p><p class="paragraph">Our white-label solutions are API based, ensuring seamless integration with clients' existing systems. Designed to be platform-agnostic, our system can accommodate various trading platforms, offering flexibility at its core. Its foundational components—trading systems, FIX API connectivity, back-office functionalities, and reporting—are all accessible via API, facilitating smooth interactions. </p><p class="paragraph">Moreover, our platform is highly adaptable to clients' branding requirements. With swift and easy skinning capabilities, clients can align the platform's appearance precisely with their brand aesthetics, including colour schemes and branding elements. Integration with clients' systems is seamless, allowing for effortless account creation through simple API calls. </p><p class="paragraph">Clients requiring particular pricing configuration options have access to the creation of multiple pricing, commission, and markup profiles tailored to their specific business needs. This flexibility ensures that our solution caters to a diverse range of client requirements. </p><p class="paragraph text-align-start vertical-align-baseline">How easy is it to integrate Finalto white-label solutions into existing systems?</p><p class="paragraph">Our processes are highly efficient and seamlessly integrated. With comprehensive documentation and a team of expert support and technical staff available 24/5, we ensure any queries or issues are promptly addressed.  </p><p class="paragraph">We operate in close collaboration with our partners, giving them the freedom and customisability to take control in steering their business direction. Our role is to provide guidance and support without standing in the way of our client's vision; Finalto white-labelling is all about providing a platform that can easily slot in with client’s existing technology while also being flexible enough to align with their business objectives.  </p><p class="paragraph">What kind of support and training does Finalto offer to clients implementing your white-label solutions? How does Finalto help with onboarding? </p><p class="paragraph">Our support is tailored to the client's preferences. Despite our exhaustive documentation, we are more than willing to dedicate as much time as necessary to delve into every detail, providing thorough training and guidance throughout the journey. It's worth noting that our support isn't limited to onboarding; throughout the client’s lifetime with Finalto our team remains available to address any matter, communicate new features, or aid in platform migrations from other providers. </p><p class="paragraph">Staying attuned to the feedback and suggestions from our clients and partners is paramount to us. It serves as a catalyst for constant improvement of our offerings, as we recognise the value in continuously learning from our clients. This fosters a culture of curiosity and attentiveness towards our clients' needs and requests, ensuring that we evolve in tandem with their requirements. </p><p class="paragraph text-align-start vertical-align-baseline">How does Finalto ensure the security and regulatory compliance of its white-label solutions, especially in different geographical markets? </p><p class="paragraph">Finalto is a multinational business with a global presence. We provide services in established jurisdictions such as the UK, Australia, Cyprus, and Singapore, and adhere to stringent regulatory and security standards. We take immense pride in our proactive approach to regulatory compliance, spanning reporting, uptime, maintenance, and market abuse detection. </p><p class="paragraph">Our trading systems are housed in world-renowned data centres in LD4 (London), NY4 (New-York), SG3 (Singapore) and with presence in TY3 (Tokyo), ensuring top-tier security for trading, data, pricing, and access. These facilities are not only overseen by their respective teams but are also meticulously maintained by our experts, guaranteeing the highest standards of security as per industry requirements.  </p><p class="paragraph text-align-start vertical-align-baseline">What are the upcoming innovations or developments we can expect in Finalto's white-label solutions? </p><p class="paragraph">Our most recent development involves enhancing our system with cutting-edge architecture, incorporating elements directly into hardware rather than relying solely on software. This advancement enables our partners to maintain a competitive edge by offering a more comprehensive pricing stack, swiftly adapting to client behaviour, and detecting abusive patterns in near real-time. </p><p class="paragraph">We view this investment as strategic and are already witnessing the initial benefits of our engineers' hard work. It positions us to offer white-label solutions not only for trading technology but also for analytical capabilities, encompassing client flow analysis, abuse detection, and seamless risk management from any global location. </p><p class="paragraph text-align-start vertical-align-baseline">How does Finalto stay dynamic and agile with its solutions?</p><p class="paragraph">Clients seek sophistication combined with simplicity, operational and cost efficiency alongside robustness, and consistent uptime. They desire a unified platform and account encompassing all instruments—DMA, Futures, Options, FX, and Indices. Clients expect access to excellent and attentive support while retaining the independence to operate according to their preferences. They've invested considerable effort in building their businesses and shouldn't compromise due to limitations imposed by their White Label solution provider. </p><p class="paragraph">With over a decade of mutually beneficial collaborations and clients who have evolved with us, we maintain our curiosity and commitment to innovation. Continuously developing new products and exploring opportunities in emerging markets, we strive to ensure that our solutions evolve to meet the dynamic needs of our clients, fostering their continued growth and success. </p><p class="paragraph">If you would like to know more about how Finalto can benefit your business, you can contact us <a href="https://www.finalto.com/contact-us/">HERE</a>.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Virtu Financial's Q1 Net Income Hits $111.3 Million, Prepares for CFO Transition]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/virtu-financials-q1-net-income-hits-1113-million-prepares-for-cfo-transition/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/virtu-financials-q1-net-income-hits-1113-million-prepares-for-cfo-transition/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Institutional FX]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Executive Moves]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/virtu-financials-q1-net-income-hits-1113-million-prepares-for-cfo-transition</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In the latest financial report released by Virtu Financial,
Inc. (NASDAQ: VIRT), covering the first quarter of 2024, the company showcased
robust performance. Virtu reported a net income of $111.3 million, alongside a
notable Normalized Adjusted Net Income of $124.3 million. </p><p>Q1 Performance: Revenues Surge to $642.8 Million</p><p>Driving these figures was the company's total revenues,
which soared to $642.8 million, buoyed by a substantial trading income, net, of
$408.1 million. Virtu's net income margin was reported at 17.3%.</p><p>Further highlighting its financial strength, Virtu reported
an Adjusted Net Trading Income of $366.9 million. The company's operational
prowess was also evident in its Adjusted EBITDA figure, which amounted to
$202.8 million, accompanied by an Adjusted EBITDA Margin of 55.3%.</p><p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/institutional-forex/virtu-financial-and-360t-unleash-integrated-fx-trading-analytics-and-tca-services/">360T
and Virtu Financial have forged a strategic partnership</a> to provide
integrated FX Trading Analytics and Transaction Cost Analysis (TCA) services,
as reported by <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/">Finance Magnates</a>.
Through this collaboration, clients of 360T can leverage Virtu’s Trading
Analytics to monitor and analyze their trading activity on the platform.
Virtu's FX Trading Analytics and TCA offer data-driven insights aimed at
optimizing FX trading for corporate treasurers and asset managers.</p><p>Announcing CFO Transition, Senior Role Continues</p><p>Cindy Lee, currently Deputy Chief Financial Officer at <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/virtu-financial/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Virtu
Financial</a>, is set to assume the role of CFO on August 1, 2024. This transition
follows the company's long-term succession planning. Sean Galvin, the current
CFO since 2020, will continue with Virtu in a senior capacity to facilitate a
smooth leadership transition.</p><p>With a background in financial services, Lee joined
Virtu in 2011 and has held various positions in global finance. As Deputy CFO,
she has overseen global finance and corporate treasury functions. Lee played a
key role in automating financial processes and expanding the finance team. Her
contributions were vital to Virtu's IPO in 2015 and the integration of
acquisitions like KCG in 2017 and ITG in 2019.</p><p>Prior to joining Virtu, Lee worked at The Royal Bank of
Scotland and Deloitte &amp; Touche as an auditor. She holds Master’s and
Bachelor’s degrees in Accounting from the University of Connecticut.</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[From Skepticism to Adoption: How to Craft Press Releases That Address Crypto Concerns]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/from-skepticism-to-adoption-how-to-craft-press-releases-that-address-crypto-concerns/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/from-skepticism-to-adoption-how-to-craft-press-releases-that-address-crypto-concerns/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 09:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[FM Contributors]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/from-skepticism-to-adoption-how-to-craft-press-releases-that-address-crypto-concerns</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">When Bitcoin first came on the scene over a decade ago, most people kind of scratched their heads at the idea of digital money without a bank behind it. It seemed pretty out there, and a bit too risky for most people to entertain. But flash forward to today, and the crypto industry is now worth more than $2 trillion. Yet, even with that growth, many would argue that crypto adoption still has a long way to go before hitting the mainstream.</p><p class="MsoNormal">So, what is the main obstacle holding these blockchain-based assets from taking over the world? Well, the truth is that most people still have very little idea of what Bitcoin and its digital counterparts actually do (and how they work). This is especially true amongst the older generations who may feel alienated from the fast-paced and lingo-ridden communities that form the bedrock of Web3. </p><p class="MsoNormal">To put this into perspective, a recent survey found that<a href="https://www.fscs.org.uk/globalassets/industry-resources/research/fscs-consumer-research-attitudes-towards-investing-in-cryptocurrencies-april-2023.pdf"> only 11% of people admit they truly understand crypto</a>(23% of younger people). This knowledge gap, paired with the mixed messages about crypto in the media, makes many doubtful or hesitant to get involved.</p><p class="MsoNormal text-align-start">So, as the crypto space evolves, it's up to the projects actively involved in the space to tackle these lingering doubts and skepticism head on. One of the best ways to do this is through a well-crafted <a href="https://chainwire.org/">crypto press release</a> that aims to spread understandable, easily digestible, benefits-based information to a wider demographic. Let’s unpack this in a bit more detail. </p><p class="MsoNormal text-align-start">Explain Complex Concepts Simply</p><p class="MsoNormal">Let's face it, the technology power and cryptocurrency, blockchain, is not exactly the easiest thing to wrap your head around. Unless you're a software engineer or a text savant, distributed digital ledgers aren’t likely to be something that will come naturally to you. And that's without even mentioning things like cryptographic hashes, mining, wallets, private keys, and exchanges. The learning curve is steep.</p><p class="MsoNormal">In press releases, especially ones that are going out to mainstream publications and not just crypto native media, It's important to break down these complex topics into straightforward language. Don't mention buzzwords, define them in everyday terms and provide simple, relatable examples. </p><p class="MsoNormal">For example, Instead of saying something like "blockchain technology ensures the immutability of transactions," you could say something like, “imagine a shared digital notebook where everyone in the world can see what's written in it. Once something has been written down, it can't be changed, edited, modified, or removed. That's exactly how blockchain works.”</p><p class="MsoNormal">Of course, there's a balance to be had here. You want to try and simplify the concepts without oversimplifying them to the point where they lose their nuance. The goal is to convey the core concepts simply while keeping explanations accurate. This helps people that are just getting their feet wet understand in space understand what the basic mechanics behind this technology are.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Clear the Air on Misconceptions</p><p class="MsoNormal">We live in a world of fake news - a world where people deliberately go out of their way to misguide others. In the crypto sphere, this is done by both bad actors trying to scam unsuspecting users, and mainstream media that have an obvious negative agenda against crypto. To give another example, there is still plenty of news coverage going around that Bitcoin and other digital assets are solely used for things like money laundering, drug dealing and other illicit activities.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Press releases provide an excellent opportunity to directly address and debunk these misleading and extremely damaging claims. The key is to rise above the noise, take the high road, and take time to explain the fundamentals. </p><p class="MsoNormal">By clearing up these common misconceptions, companies can reassure people who may be hesitant to adopt crypto and jump on board. It also counters all the negative hype in the media. When people learn the facts through a trusted medium, they are likely to gain more trust in cryptocurrencies as legitimate technologies with incredible potential.</p><p class="MsoNormal text-align-start">Highlight Real-World Utility</p><p class="MsoNormal">One of the more common criticisms that crypto receives is that it doesn't have any real use case. On the one hand, this is more than fair if you're talking about the thousands and thousands of tokens that are simply made as gash grabs and pump and dump schemes. But of course, there's far more to blockchain technology than that.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Legitimate cryptocurrency projects solve real-world problems across a variety of industries - from <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/education-centre/the-promise-of-defi-use-cases-opportunities-and-risks/">finance</a> and healthcare to supply chain and identity. The key is showcasing these actual uses in a way that clearly conveys the benefits to end-users.</p><p class="MsoNormal">For example, a supply chain focused blockchain could demonstrate how it increases transparency, efficiency and trust between all parties involved. This eliminates issues like cargo theft, spoilage, unnecessary paperwork, and payment delays. Almost everybody is going to be able to see the profound benefits that this brings. When tangible improvements like these are presented, it becomes far easier for someone to recognize the utility and subsequently gain interest in utilizing crypto.</p><p class="MsoNormal text-align-start">Focus on Accessibility</p><p class="MsoNormal">As mentioned in the introduction, lack of technical knowledge poses a significant barrier to crypto adoption. If people don't understand how to acquire, store and use digital assets, they simply won't. Press releases present the perfect chance to educate readers on the proper procedures for getting started.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Rather than assuming any prior familiarity, pretend you're talking to a complete beginner. Provide step-by-step instructions for setting up a wallet, buying crypto on an exchange, storing private keys, and making basic transactions. You'd be surprised just how many people have no idea that you can purchase a fraction of Bitcoin rather than needing to buy a whole one. Small details like that can make all the difference.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Of course, it also helps to point people in the direction of useful educational resources where they can learn more at their own pace. Creating easily adoptable systems lays the groundwork for bringing more participants into the cryptoverse.</p><p class="MsoNormal text-align-start">Final Word</p><p class="MsoNormal">The journey from skepticism to adoption is definitely going to be a long one for crypto space. It's safe to say that great strides have definitely been made over the past 15 years, but more work needs to be done. For the companies that act as stewards to the blockchain industry, well-crafted press releases that address concerns head on, simplify complex concepts, and break down real life practical benefits will only help to bridge the gap between the crypto-curious and the crypto-confident.</p>

This article was written by FM Contributors at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Detained Binance Executives’ Bail Hearing in Nigeria Pushed to May 17]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/detained-binance-executives-bail-hearing-in-nigeria-pushed-to-may-17/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/detained-binance-executives-bail-hearing-in-nigeria-pushed-to-may-17/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 09:19:32 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/detained-binance-executives-bail-hearing-in-nigeria-pushed-to-may-17</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Tigran Gambaryan, the detained Binance executive in Nigeria, will remain in custody until a bail hearing on May 17. Meanwhile, his trial is scheduled for May 2.</p><p>More Jail Time in Nigeria</p><p>The extension of Gambaryan’s remand was granted by the Nigerian court yesterday (Tuesday) amid opposition from federal prosecutors to the appeal for bail. The crypto exchange’s executive has already <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/detained-binance-executive-in-nigeria-remanded-after-not-guilty-plea/">pleaded not guilty</a> to charges of tax evasion and money laundering.</p><p>Gambaryan holds the position of Head of Financial Crime Compliance at the crypto exchange. He and another fellow Binance executive, Nadeem Anjarwalla, who holds the position of its African Regional Manager, traveled to Nigeria in an official capacity earlier this year but were <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/binance-faces-regulatory-storm-as-executives-detained-in-nigeria-report/">detained by local authorities</a>.</p><p>Nigeria’s Economic and Financial Crimes Commission brought <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/nigeria-charges-binance-for-tax-evasion/">four counts of tax evasion charges</a> against the exchange and the two detained executives. The charges primarily blame the defendants for non-payment of value-added tax, income tax, and failure to file tax returns. The exchange has been accused of aiding Nigerians in evading tax through its platform.</p><p>In an earlier statement, the exchange made it clear that the two executives were wrongly blamed as they did not have any decision-making authority.</p><p>The Great Escape</p><p>Meanwhile, Anjarwalla, one of the detained defendants and a citizen of both the UK and Kenya, escaped detention earlier this month and reportedly fled the country. Although his UK travel documents were seized by Nigerian authorities, he allegedly used Kenyan credentials to flee the country on a Middle Eastern airline.</p><p>Several local Nigerian publications recently reported on Anjarwalla’s arrest in Kenya and possible extradition to Nigeria to face trial. However, Anjarwalla’s wife came out and denied all these reports.</p><p>Yuki Gambaryan, the wife of Gambaryan, launched a petition requesting the US State Department, Nigeria’s Economic and Financial Crimes Commission, the Nigerian government, and US President Joe Biden to return her husband to the US.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[India Catching Up on China Investment-Wise: What is Not Right?]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/india-catching-up-on-china-investment-wise-what-is-not-right/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/india-catching-up-on-china-investment-wise-what-is-not-right/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 08:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Clifford]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Thought Leadership]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//thought-leadership/india-catching-up-on-china-investment-wise-what-is-not-right</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Excessive taxation of foreign business, lack of intellectual property protection, and overregulated legislation that makes it next to impossible to defend your case in court – all of these make foreign companies, such as Tesla, Parimatch, Nokia refrain from investing in India or leaving this market altogether. If these roadblocks are resolved, India can become a $5 trillion economy by 2027, a Mecca for global business. </p><p class="MsoNormal">What stands in the way of business in India?</p><p class="MsoNormal">India can potentially become the USA of Asia, and compete with China in terms of investment. Multinational enterprises are expecting the said from India, for they see the potential of this market. However, hopes and dreams remain just that – hopes and dreams. But why is that so?</p><p class="MsoNormal">India’s business environment shows avid signs of hostility to both domestic businesses, and foreign capital, like moguls akin Tesla, Nokia, Parimatch. Firstly, exorbitant taxes and various tax bodies with own opinions on taxation rates. This trend is reflected in the studies that monitor taxation in the world. For example, according to the Paderborn University and the World Bank data on the Tax Complexity Index, India ranks 53rd out of 100 in terms of the tax code complexity, and 58th in terms of the tax system complexity. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Vakil Search, a project for investors and entrepreneurs, <a href="https://vakilsearch.com/blog/corporate-tax-in-india-why-companies-are-leaving/">illustrates</a> what tax rates for businesses in India look like.</p><p class="MsoNormal">It shows the tax load for non-residents is considerably above that of domestic companies. This is despite the fact that over 130 countries have agreed to adjust their taxation for multinationals. The global minimum tax rate is a minimum of 15% for multinationals with business revenues exceeding 750 million euros. In India, however, the corporate tax for international companies is above the average – 30% compared to 23% globally, <a href="https://blog.ipleaders.in/challenges-in-corporate-taxation-and-its-impact-on-ease-of-doing-business/">according</a> to Sagar Narendrakumar Surana, a certified specialist in fintech sector.  </p><p class="MsoNormal">On top of that, India’s taxmen have varying views on tax rates, with the tax administration system under constant reconstruction in attempt to bring all the moving parts to harmony. “India has a string of tax authorities on different levels. This means that oftentimes various tax bodies present contradictory requirements, resulting in legal disputes. Hovewer, the government can make this process way easier by introducing electronic solutions, such as filling tax reports and paying taxes online”, shares his expert opinon Mr. Surana. Business-friendly tax system could increase the investment influx into the country many times over. With Parimatch bookmaker being one of the first willing to invest in the Indian market.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Tesla didn’t make it in India</p><p class="MsoNormal">As a result of excessive taxation, India’s losing taxpayers that could significantly fuel the country’s economy. One such example is Tesla. This carmaker put its strategies of EV sales in India on ice, for the agreement to lower the import tax for the manufacturer could not be reached with the state officials. The Indian government chose to stick to its official policy, forcing such companies to pay 60% tax on budget cars, with the tax amounting to 100% of the cost of cars priced above Rs. 3,000,000 (over 30 thousand euros)</p><p class="MsoNormal">Which companies buckled under tax pressure?</p><p class="MsoNormal">Business views India as the state with the most difficult tax administration system in the world. Due to poor predictability of tax legislation, many enterprises simply fail to react to new changes and policies, which results in major fines and tax bodies persecuting the business. “Recent years have witnessed companies either move from India to other developing countries or downsizing their operational scale. This trend has not ceased to disappear even after our honorable Prime Minister invited companies from abroad to come and invest more capital in India’s developing economy”, it <a href="https://vakilsearch.com/blog/corporate-tax-in-india-why-companies-are-leaving/">goes</a> in a blogpost on the corporate tax in India.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Companies like Amazon, Foxconn, and several other enterprises from Japan and South Korea faced major fines for the alleged concealment of investments, tax evasion, and account falsification in India. Embroiled in high-profile tax investigations were transnationals like Shell, Nokia, IBM, Walmart, and Cairn Energy. Some companies, Parimatch included, could not launch in India at all. As a result of the mentioned factors, foreign business keeps packing up and leaving the subcontinent. Recently, a couple of major players – Foxconn Group and Wistron Group – left this promising market. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Indian courts still fighting to have the tax load reduced</p><p class="MsoNormal">Businesses take to local courts to fight fines and rising taxes, but the struggle’s been futile so far, <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/sc-transfers-to-itself-pleas-from-9-hcs-on-imposition-of-28-per-cent-gst-on-e-gaming-firms/articleshow/109059934.cms?utm_source=contentofinterest&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=cppst">says</a> The Economic Times. Indian state authorities raised the gaming tax from 18% to 28%, as the E-gaming Federation tries to appeal this decision in court, filing 27 pleas. The companies wish that online gaming, along with horse racing and gambling, are taxed differently. India’s government thinks otherwise. The parties keep butting heads. </p><p class="MsoNormal">In the meantime, gambling companies appeal for cancellation of unreasonable fines imposed by the taxmen. For instance, several e-gaming companies – Gameskraft, Dream 11, Games 24x7, Head Digital Works – went to court to challenge the collection of goods and services tax (GST). Specifically, the Karnataka High Court verdict quashed the GST intimation notice on the tune of Rs 21,000 crore ($2 billion) issued to online gaming form Gameskraft. Still, India’s Supreme Court suspended the enforcement of this decision, with the victory at arm’s length. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Business wants to protect intellectual property in India</p><p class="MsoNormal">On top of the puzzling and incoherent tax policy, there’s another obstacle in the way – lack of proper intellectual property protection. Counterfeits are common for the Indian market. International company Parimatch learned of this problem the hard way. The company is not officially represented on the Indian subcontinent, so the copycats waste no time hustling in India. Parimatch wants to invest in this market, pay taxes, and keep the gaming industry evolving through offering its own products and services. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Limp measures to counter piracy and counterfeits impede the enterprises’ attempts to invest in research and development, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/navigating-challenges-problems-indian-regulatory-vishwas-bhagwat/">believes</a> Vishwas Bhagwat, business head, educationist, computer network expert. He goes on to list the main obstacles for business in India that hinder the country’s economy: overcomplicated regulations, arduous registration process, inconsistent taxation policies, insufficient protection of intellectual property. Mr. Bhagwat considers the said factors to be the most damaging to innovations and conducting business in the Indian market.</p><p class="MsoNormal">Vietnam takes over Indian investments</p><p class="MsoNormal">Sadly, India’s current regulatory system hinders the accumulation of foreign capital, new jobs, savings, <a href="https://taxguru.in/">states</a>Taxguru publication. Meanwhile, cashflow from leading economies, like U.S. and China, moves to Vietnam, although it’s much needed in India. “We want the foreign direct investment from China to shift, but Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) is not flowing into India at the pace it should be. Instead, it’s going to countries like Vietnam. I would selfishly like to see more of that happening in India”, <a href="https://moderndiplomacy.eu/2024/02/20/indias-business-conundrum-regulatory-problems-and-foreign-investment-challenges/">said</a> Eric Garcetti, the U.S. Ambassador to India. </p><p class="MsoNormal">Still, both domestic and foreign companies, Parimatch among them, are more than willing to invest millions of dollars in the Indian economy today, should the government create a more favorable environment for international capital. </p>

This article was written by James Clifford at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Even Ministers Believe FCA's "Name and Shame" Policy Will Harm the City of London]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/even-ministers-believe-fcas-name-and-shame-policy-will-harm-the-city-of-london/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/even-ministers-believe-fcas-name-and-shame-policy-will-harm-the-city-of-london/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 08:28:16 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/even-ministers-believe-fcas-name-and-shame-policy-will-harm-the-city-of-london</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/f/financial-conduct-authority-fca/" class="terms__main-term" id="4c85a54d-15e0-4e44-a214-8c55f71cb286">Financial Conduct Authority (FCA</a>) has recently unveiled a contentious plan to
publicly disclose the names of companies under investigation, drawing sharp
criticism from industry experts and raising concerns about the potential impact
on businesses.</p><p>The
"name and shame" proposal is causing controversy and, as the
Financial Times claims, concerns in ministerial circles that it will lead to an
exodus of companies from London. Even without this, the City is already
increasingly losing ground to New York.</p><p>FCA's Controversial Plan
to Expose Companies under Investigation Sparks Outrage</p><p>Under the
proposed changes, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/fca/">the FCA</a> would abandon its long-standing practice of keeping
investigations confidential until a formal decision is reached. Instead, the
regulator aims to adopt a more transparent approach by naming and shaming
companies as soon as an investigation is launched.</p><p>In its <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/named-and-shamed-uk-regulator-to-publicly-reveal-probed-firms/">February release regarding the “name and shame” scheme</a>, the regulator emphasized that this move will enhance public trust and accountability, allowing consumers to make more informed decisions about the companies they engage with. However, critics argue that the plan could have severe unintended
consequences.</p><p>Various stakeholders, including legal experts, business leaders, and industry associations, have fiercely opposed the FCA's proposal.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">FCA faces backlash over plan to ‘name and shame’ companies under investigation <a href="https://t.co/GJaW57mxW7">https://t.co/GJaW57mxW7</a> via <a href="https://twitter.com/FT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ft</a></p>— John Davidson (@JohnDav79548222) <a href="https://twitter.com/JohnDav79548222/status/1782490309257003236?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 22, 2024</a></blockquote><p>"The
FCA says it’s thinking about competitiveness, but so often they take decisions
that harm the competitiveness of the UK," a senior government figure told the Financial Times. “They have got to stop.”</p><p>Industry
representatives argue that publicly naming companies under investigation could:</p><ol><li>Damage
reputations before any wrongdoing is proven,</li><li>disrupt
business operations and lead to loss of clients and revenue,</li><li>undermine
the presumption of innocence and due process, and</li><li>encourage a
culture of fear and risk aversion in the financial sector.</li></ol><p>Balancing Transparency and
Fairness</p><p>While the
FCA's intentions to promote transparency are commendable, many argue that the
proposed approach goes too far. Instead, they suggest that the regulator should
focus on improving its investigative processes and reducing the time taken to
reach decisions.</p><p>The legal
industry is also concerned, acknowledging that 65% of FCA investigations end
without any action being taken. Publishing information about these cases would
only result in reputational damage.</p><p>“It would
significantly and pointlessly damage a firm’s reputation and value,”  Miles Celic, the Chief Executive of TheCityUK,
told the Financial Times. “Especially given that FCA investigations take four years
on average and many conclude without requiring any action.”</p><p>Some have
also called for a more nuanced approach, where the FCA would only name
companies in exceptional circumstances, such as when there is a significant
risk to public safety or when the investigation has reached an advanced stage.</p><p>The Road Ahead</p><p>As the
debate continues, the FCA must balance the need for
transparency with the rights of companies under investigation. The regulator
has invited feedback from stakeholders and is expected to make a final decision
on the proposed changes later this year.</p><p>Official
voices are already being heard directly from the authorities. In March, Kemi
Badenoch, the Business Secretary and Equalities Minister, accused the FCA of
"regulatory over-reach" in an official letter. The outcome
of this controversy could have far-reaching implications for the financial
sector and how regulatory investigations are conducted in the
future.</p><p>On the other hand, the FCA wants to strengthen its reputation as an enforcement agency and deter misconduct within the UK's expansive financial services industry. In 2023, the institution achieved a new milestone <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/forex/fcas-2023-crusade-against-financial-fraud-hits-new-peak/">by issuing 2,286 scam alerts</a> on its public Warning List, an improvement of 21% from the 1,882 alerts
issued in 2022.</p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[FxGrow Chooses Integral's SaaS Solutions for Trading Infrastructure]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/fxgrow-chooses-integrals-saas-solutions-for-trading-infrastructure/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/fxgrow-chooses-integrals-saas-solutions-for-trading-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 08:21:25 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tareq Sikder]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//forex/fxgrow-chooses-integrals-saas-solutions-for-trading-infrastructure</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Integral, a currency technology provider catering to
financial markets, disclosed today (Wednesday) a development in collaboration
with global trading platform and brokerage firm FxGrow. Aiming at fortifying
its technological foundation, FxGrow has opted for Integral's Software as a
Service (SaaS) workflow solutions.</p><p>Trading Platform Adopts New System via Fixed Subscription</p><p>The integration entails FxGrow's adoption of Integral's platform,
facilitated through a fixed subscription model. This decision equips FxGrow
with an array of functionalities including enhanced liquidity connectivity, pricing
mechanisms, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/r/risk-management/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="aedb745c-adf9-415f-97e2-ee56a920f0f8">risk management</a> tools, integration with MT5 gateway, and business
intelligence capabilities.</p><p>“We are excited to support the growth of one of the leading
retail brokers in EMEA,” said Harpal Sandhu, the CEO of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/integral/" target="_blank" rel="follow">Integral</a>. “FxGrow’s
decision to partner with us is indicative of the growing advantage for brokers
to leverage tier one institutional grade technology, while maintaining control
over their own platform. Integral is well-positioned to provide the SaaS
solutions that will enable these businesses to better compete in the market.”</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">FxGrow taps Integral's SaaS brokerage workflow - “FxGrow’s decision to partner with us is indicative of the growing advantage for brokers to leverage tier-one institutional-grade technology while maintaining control over their own platform. Integral is well-positioned to pro... <a href="https://t.co/9YcLrZN2Ev">pic.twitter.com/9YcLrZN2Ev</a></p>— The Industry Spread (@industryspread) <a href="https://twitter.com/industryspread/status/1783043477967667642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 24, 2024</a></blockquote><p>Enhancing Operational Efficiency</p><p>By embracing Integral's technology, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/fxgrow/" target="_blank" rel="follow">FxGrow</a> aims to elevate
its operational efficiency and elevate the trading experience it offers to its
clientele. This move underscores FxGrow's focus on providing trading services
across a diverse spectrum of asset classes, spanning FX, precious metals,
energy products, cash indices, commodities, CFDs, and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/c/cryptocurrencies/" class="terms__main-term" id="b091101e-6e02-4b36-aa0e-7c972dfdd6ed">cryptocurrencies</a>.</p><p>Mahdi Mazeh, the Executive Director at FxGrow, emphasized:
“Our decision to implement Integral’s technology underscores our dedication to
evolving our offerings and delivering unparalleled service to our clients. With
state-of-the-art trading solutions and market insights, we are well-equipped to
meet our clients' evolving needs.”</p>

This article was written by Tareq Sikder at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[10% Profit Uptick Drives Visa to Highest Level in 30 Days]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/10-profit-uptick-drives-visa-to-highest-level-in-30-days/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/10-profit-uptick-drives-visa-to-highest-level-in-30-days/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:53:02 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fintech/payments/10-profit-uptick-drives-visa-to-highest-level-in-30-days</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Visa's
shares rose in after-hours trading on Wall Street in response to the news that
net revenue increased to $8.8 billion during the fiscal second quarter of 2024.
In the meantime, the company joined forces with Standard Chartered to enhance
cross-border payments.</p><p>The global
digital payments giant reported double-digit growth in revenue, net income, and
earnings per share, driven by steady increases in payments volume, cross-border
transactions, and processed transactions.</p><p>Visa Posts Strong Q2 2024
Results amid Stable Growth in Key Metrics</p><p>Net revenue
for the quarter rose 10% year-over-year to $8.8 billion, reflecting the
continued recovery in global economic activity. Visa's GAAP net income
increased 10% to $4.7 billion, while non-GAAP net income grew 17% to $5.1
billion. Diluted earnings per share (EPS) grew even stronger, with GAAP
EPS up 12% to $2.29 and non-GAAP EPS surging 20% to $2.51.</p><p>“As we head
into the second half of the year and beyond, we remain focused on the trillions
of dollars of opportunity in consumer payments and new flows,” commented Ryan
McInerney, the Chief Executive Officer of <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/visa/">Visa</a>.</p><p>Visa's core
business drivers demonstrated resilience, with payments volume increasing 8% on
a constant-dollar basis for the three months ended 31 March 2024. Cross-border
volume, excluding intra-Europe transactions, rose 16%, indicating a rebound in
international travel. Total processed transactions grew 11% to 55.5 billion,
underscoring the ongoing shift towards digital payments.</p><p>Strategic Acquisitions and
Partnerships</p><p>During the
quarter, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/visas-12-billion-move-unlocks-new-banking-and-payment-products/">Visa completed its acquisition of Pismo</a>, a cloud-native issuer
processing and core banking platform. This action enhances Visa's capabilities in
providing innovative solutions to its clients. Additionally, the company
reached <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/visa-strikes-deal-with-us-merchants-to-cap-interchange-rates-for-five-years/">a landmark settlement with US merchants</a>, agreeing to lower credit
interchange rates and implement rule changes that benefit small businesses.</p><p>In the latest move, the payments again teamed up with the local US fintech <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/payments/visa-teams-up-with-us-fintech-skipify-for-secured-digital-transactions/">Skipify for secured digital transactions</a>. The cooperation aims to blend Visa’s expertise
and Skipify’s innovative wallet solutions. Visa
returned excess cash to shareholders through its stock repurchase
program and quarterly dividends. The company repurchased 9.7 million shares of
Class A common stock for $2.7 billion and declared a quarterly dividend of
$0.520 per share, payable in June 2024.</p><p>Staying on
the topic of stocks, Visa's shares on Wall Street rose over 3% in after-hours
trading, reacting to better-than-expected results and testing the highest price
levels in over a month, around $284.</p><p>Visa and Standard
Chartered Partner to Streamline Cross-Border Payments</p><p>In the
meantime, Standard Chartered has joined forces with Visa to leverage the Visa
B2B Connect network. This multilateral payment network enables faster and more
cost-effective account-to-account payments for corporate clients worldwide.</p><p>The
partnership will initially benefit Standard Chartered's clients in Singapore,
with plans to expand the offering to additional entities in the coming months.
By integrating with Visa B2B Connect through API connectivity, transactions
will be routed directly to Visa for processing, eliminating the need for
multiple intermediaries and the associated costs and delays.</p><p>"Visa is committed to modernizing cross-border payments around the world, and the collaboration with Standard Chartered will extend our network even further," said Ben Ellis, the Senior Vice President and the Global Head of Visa B2B Connect at Visa.</p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[FMPS:24 – Introducing the Next Big Event in APAC]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmps24-introducing-the-next-big-event-in-apac/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmps24-introducing-the-next-big-event-in-apac/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:50:30 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Patterson]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[FM-Events]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//fm-events/fmps24-introducing-the-next-big-event-in-apac</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Finance Magnates Pacific Summit (FMPS:24) will kick off officially on August 27-29 in Sydney, Australia, looking to establish itself as the premier summit in the Asia-Pacific. FMPS:24 will focus on creating new opportunities and bridging key elements of the B2B and B2C financial services industry in an <a href="https://events.financemagnates.com/event/bfb8e41b-740c-4543-922d-9b0ab8e783de/summary?RefId=FM%20PR%20Announcement&amp;utm_campaign=fmps24-announcement&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_source=financemagnates">unforgettable three-day event</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">With over a decade of experience in hosting industry-leading summits in London and globally, the FMevents team is pleased to expand to APAC. FMPS:24 will emphasise four industry verticals, including online trading, payments, fintech, and crypto. Prospective attendees can expect the summit to address at length the most salient topics and trends from these verticals, as well as the areas of regtech, and cybersecurity.</p><p dir="ltr">FMPS:24 provides a number of exciting <a href="https://forms.monday.com/forms/8028143b46d438177c5926cb5bf659c8?r=use1">sponsorship and exhibiting opportunities</a>. Available slots are offered on a first-come, first-serve basis and are filling up quickly so contact sales@financemagnates.com for all marketing and branding queries today! Individuals interested in becoming a <a href="https://forms.monday.com/forms/a8ee49ce29311417ba55e5dd40c1a3f2?r=use1">speaker at FMPS:24</a> are also encouraged to apply today.</p><p dir="ltr">What to Expect from FMPS:24</p><p dir="ltr">As one of the most anticipated events of the year, FMPS:24 will be welcoming thousands of attendees globally, connecting them with global brands, individuals, and experts in the APAC region.</p><p dir="ltr">FMPS:24 will be the prime destination for senior executives and decision-makers to close deals. Regardless of your business specialization, this is where you can secure your future business partnerships. Prospective attendees can expect to engage, network, and connect face-to-face with the following participants:</p><ul><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation"> Forex/CFD Brokers</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Institutional Brokers</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Affiliates &amp; IBsTraders &amp; Investors</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Educators &amp; Market Experts</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Fintech &amp; Payments Brands</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Crypto &amp; Digital Assets Businesses</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Technology &amp; Liquidity Providers</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Press/Media</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Regulators</p></li><li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"><p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Start-ups Investors/VCs</p></li></ul><p dir="ltr"> FMPS:24 is all about expanding one’s global reach through unique networking opportunities. Nowhere else in APAC will participants have the chance to speak to so many different parties and talent, all under one roof.</p><p dir="ltr">Whether you are a broker looking to connect with individuals in APAC, launch or expand operations, or simply set up shop or do business in a new region, FMPS:24 has something for everyone.</p><p dir="ltr">The event is expected to attract upwards of 3000+ attendees, 80+ exhibitors, and 80+ speakers. Interested parties looking to explore branding or sponsorship opportunities are encouraged to reach out to sales@financemagnates.com.</p><p dir="ltr">One of the biggest draws of the event will be the launch of a curated content track, exploring each of the aforementioned industry verticals. This means more panels, sessions, workshops, and more, providing actionable insights and perspective from industry leaders.</p><p dir="ltr">Stay tuned over the next few months as the official agenda is released or join the conversation today surrounding FMPS:24.</p>

This article was written by Jeff Patterson at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Monex Group Bets Big on Crypto with 3iQ Acquisition and QMAP Investment]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/monex-group-bets-big-on-crypto-with-3iq-acquisition-and-qmap-investment/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/monex-group-bets-big-on-crypto-with-3iq-acquisition-and-qmap-investment/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:28:01 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Damian Chmiel]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[CryptoCurrency]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Retail FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//cryptocurrency/monex-group-bets-big-on-crypto-with-3iq-acquisition-and-qmap-investment</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Tokyo-based
financial services company Monex Group has completed its acquisition of a majority stake in 3iQ Digital Holdings, a Canadian crypto asset manager.
The acquisition, <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/japans-monex-acquires-majority-stake-in-crypto-asset-manager-3iq/">initially announced in December 2023</a>, has resulted in 3iQ and
its subsidiaries becoming part of the Monex Group. </p><p>Monex Group Acquires
Majority Stake in Canadian Crypto Asset Manager 3iQ</p><p>To support
3iQ's rapid business expansion, Monex Group has also invested $7.5 million in
3iQ's Managed Account Platform (QMAP). QMAP offers institutional investors
access to a diverse range of crypto hedge funds, featuring alpha-oriented
strategies tailored to meet the complex demands of global institutions. This
investment significantly strengthens 3iQ's institutional digital asset management position.</p><p>The company
was <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/news/3iq-lists-first-public-bitcoin-fund-on-toronto-exchange/">the first to launch a Bitcoin fund</a> on the Toronto Stock Exchange in Canada.
It further <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/news/coinshares-announces-partnership-with-3iq-to-launch-bitcoin-etf/">assisted CoinShares</a> in creating a cryptocurrency ETF. Now, it will expand its crypto services under the Monex umbrella.</p><p>QMAP employs
a stringent due diligence process to select fund managers with proven track
records of generating alpha and effectively managing risks across various
market cycles. These managers bring institutional backgrounds, specialized
expertise, and operational excellence to the table.</p><p>"I
have high [hopes] that QMAP will quickly become the leading platform for
sophisticated investors to invest in a diversified suite of crypto hedge funds,”
Yuko Seimei, the CEO of Monex Group, stated.</p><p>The
platform's managed account structure allows 3iQ direct control over assets,
enhancing transparency and <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/r/risk-management/" class="terms__main-term" id="aedb745c-adf9-415f-97e2-ee56a920f0f8">risk management</a> capabilities. This approach
eliminates the extra layer of fees typically found in traditional fund-of-funds
structures, enabling investors to customize their allocations or choose from
pre-designed model portfolios at no additional cost.</p><p>“Together
with Monex, we aim to create a superior investor experience that sets new
standards globally,” added Pascal St. Jean, the President of 3iQ. "With a
seasoned team, we remain committed to upholding our firm's decade-long tradition
of developing cutting-edge investment solutions for institutional investors.”</p><p>The
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/terms/a/acquisition/" class="terms__secondary-term" id="3180494d-8751-4a02-9476-86dc1cd4d2e2">acquisition</a> of 3iQ and investment in QMAP align with Monex Group's goal of
strengthening its asset management business. Recently, the company has 
<a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/fintech/monfx-expands-operations-with-new-singapore-office-hires-head-of-sales/">expanded its operations in the APAC region</a>, planning to increase employment in
the sales department by 80%.</p>

This article was written by Damian Chmiel at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[GCEX UK Turns Loss as 2023 Revenue Almost Halves]]></title>
<link>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/lars-holsts-gcex-turns-loss-as-2023-revenue-almost-halves/</link>
<comments>https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/lars-holsts-gcex-turns-loss-as-2023-revenue-almost-halves/#respond</comments>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 07:14:31 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arnab Shome]]></dc:creator>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[www.financemagnates.com]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Institutional FX]]></category>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financemagnates.com//institutional-forex/lars-holsts-gcex-turns-loss-as-2023-revenue-almost-halves</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The UK entity of GCEX, a prime brokerage for forex and cryptocurrencies led by Lars Holst, closed 2023 with an annual turnover of £2.3 million and a pre-tax loss of £387,429. The company’s turnover almost halved from the previous year’s £4.46 million. The numbers are for the UK-registered entity, and not the entire group.</p><p dir="ltr">A Significant Decline in Revenue</p><p dir="ltr">In the official announcement today (Wednesday), the company attributed the revenue decline to the long-standing effects of the “crypto winter” and also to the “exceptional growth” of the company in 2022.</p><p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, it highlighted that its revenue since the beginning of 2023 steadily increased month-over-month, and the trend remains intact even in the initial months of 2024.</p><p dir="ltr">“The crypto winter had a huge impact across the industry, and GCEX was no exception,” said Holst, the Founder and CEO at GCEX. “However, in response to the decline in revenue, we have been resilient and adaptive, navigating our costs effectively and diversifying revenue streams, such as introducing staking services for institutional and professional clients.”</p><p dir="ltr">An End to Two Profitable Years</p><p dir="ltr">The company further dived into losses after <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/institutional-forex/gcex-grows-2022-turnover-by-136-remains-profitable/">two consecutive profitable years</a>. As Finance Magnates reported earlier, the company generated £1.5 million in profits in 2022 and £1.42 million in 2021.</p><p dir="ltr">The company additionally pointed out that it distributed £1.8 million to its parent company, GCEX Holding Limited, aimed to support the ongoing international expansion of the group.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/tag/gcex/">GCEX</a> is headquartered in London but has offices in Copenhagen, Glasgow, Zug Crypto Valley, Kuala Lumpur, and Dubai. Last year, it obtained two regulatory licenses: an investment firm license in Denmark and a <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/gcex-cements-dubai-presence-gains-varas-digital-asset-license/">crypto license in the UAE</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">“We don’t run risk and don’t do lending or borrowing, and we continue to have significant excess Tier 1 capital in our UK entity. Following a successful Q1 2024, we are now back to profitability and continue to execute on our long-term plans, investing and expanding in our global business,” Holst added.</p>

This article was written by Arnab Shome at www.financemagnates.com.]]></description>
</item>
</channel></rss>